Assault on Drakenhof, Part 2: Forlorn Hope

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] Plan Two: We can't leave the 'Countess' in play. Strike at the town of Drakenhof. [*] By Van Hal's side, whatever happens. --- "Dwarves," you interject, breaking into the debate, and all eyes turn to you. "We've got almost fifteen thousand dwarves, including miners and engineers. Unleash them on the problem and they'll have a bridge up better than the one in Pfaffbach inside a day or two." There's a moment of silence as the others consider it. "And your opinion on our target?" Van Hal asks. "The town. The castle might be the base of operations of this 'Elector Countess', but the town is her base of power. We don't want whatever garrison she has there acting freely." Kasmir nods at you from across the table. "Well said. There's a dozen things an unfriendly town left to act freely could do, all of them bad for Stirland." Gustav scowls. "I don't like giving the Castle a warning." "Would they get one, necessarily?" Van Hal asks. "We don't have the light cavalry to round up any escapees, but we do have five thousand halfling skirmishers that could act as a picket." Gustav nods, reluctantly. "They could probably get into place without being seen... but it would only take one to get by them, and then we're rumbled. No way they'd be able to catch up to a runner, let alone a horseman." "Nothing in life is guaranteed." Van Hal looks to Schultz. "Thoughts?" He sighs. "I suppose I'm building another road, then." Van Hal smiles. "We're at an agreement, then. We march on the town of Drakenhof. Remember: outside of ourselves, the generals, and the leaders of the foreign troops, everyone believes we'll be purging the eastern fringe of the hills this season. Don't do anything to give any other impression." --- An army on the march, you feel, should be a dramatic sight. Tens of thousands of men marching in lockstep, banners flying and songs being sung and enemies quaking in the distance. What you've learned is that for an army, 'marching' isn't a state so much as a process. An army doesn't go from bed to the road: an army marches on its stomach, and breakfast is far easier said than done when you're cooking for fifty thousand, which consumes ten wagons of foodstuffs from storehouses in Southern Stirland and the Moot. Then tents need to be struck and units assembled to check that everyone is accounted for and a hundred other little tasks that need doing and by the time the army is ready to start marching, the sun is already high in the sky. Then they march, on foot, over the broken ground of the Haunted Hills, and on a good day they could be expected to make fifteen miles. Fifteen miles. You could cover that in half an hour! And they're not all travelling as one - in fact, they're so spread out that by the time the first men arrive at where they'll be camping for the night, the last men are only just leaving the previous day's camping grounds! And then ten more wagons of food are poured into the stomachs of the army, and sentries are posted, and tents are erected, and that's a full day's work done and it all repeats again tomorrow. On a map, Nachthafen and Drakenhof are practically next door, but it still takes the army three full days just to skirt the northeastern fringe of the Haunted Hills and make their way to the final staging point before the fording of the river and the assault on the town of Drakenhof. The river, which eventually turns into the Stir but here is called the Draken because of course it is, flows worryingly swiftly, but scouts have found a point where it widens and flows no more than thigh-deep. So on an uncharacteristically clear morning, the combined forces set off not for a day of marching, but for a day of battle. You had no trouble crossing the river, nor did anyone else with a horse, but the bulk of the army are not so fortunate. Progress across the river is agonizingly slow, as it seems the best that Stirland, Zhufbar and Karak Kadrin have to offer have forgotten how to stand upright - the halflings having already swum across and left to scout the terrain. Ropes are strung across the river for those crossing to steady themselves upon, but so many end up drenched that Van Hal is forced to allow for fires to be lit to let the men dry out. There's no possibility of getting the artillery over - not and have them dry enough to fire. It's nearing noon when enough of the army has crossed, and a team of dwarves set to work on erecting a permanent bridge as the army prepares to march to battle. The halfling scouts haven't seen any sign of sentries that could have spotted you, but that's of little comfort to Van Hal. But though the men are soggy, the knights remain undaunted and the dwarves refuse to show weakness. If there was any time to march on the town of Drakenhof, it is now. --- Meanwhile, not far away... To be a sentry on the gates of the town of Drakenhof is not an onerous job. The skeletons, tireless and omnipresent, do the bulk of the watching and the guarding; all a human sentry need do is provide the thinking. Traffic on the road is almost non-existent, and the occasional cart from nearby farms and villages needs little examining. So the two men at Drakenhof's southern gate are already deep in their cups when the sun nears its zenith. Thunk. Thunk. The skeleton watching the road is tapping its spear on the ground, in the only communication it has ever shared with them: traffic on the road. Twin groans answer, as the two men have a short and pointless argument until the loser is forced to find his feet and stagger out of the gatehouse. He peers down the road, the sun piercing the Sylvanian gloom with uncharacteristic vigor. Down the road, a column of night-black figures riding equally black horses are riding in silence. "Hey, boney," the man says, jabbing an accusatory finger at the skeleton. "Those're your type, not mine." The skeleton gives no comment on the matter, as its limited programming tries to come up with an answer to what it is seeing, and eventually it stands in the center of the road, spear extended towards the oncoming figures. "What is it!" cries the man still inside. "S'just the black knights," is the watchman's reply, with technical correctness. "Boney's getting upset at them for some reason." "Skeleton's broke again," is the input from the seated figure. "We'll report it later. He won't do no harm." The watchmen squints down the road at the figures, now advancing rapidly. Underneath the alcohol, some part of his brain is starting to clamour. "'Ere," he says at last. "Do you remember the Mistress having that many knights?" And those were to be his final words, as the Black Guards of Morr couch their lances in silence and charge through the still-open gates, neither skeleton nor man slowing them for an instant. --- "They're through," says Thori as he tucks the spyglass back into a pocket. "Now they just have to hold." "If anyone can hold it, the Knights of Morr can," Van Hal states, and nods of agreement come from the gathered leaders of the army. "Gustav, the floor is yours." "And no finer stage could a man hope for," replies Gustav with a savage grin, and hurries off to where his men are waiting - sword and spearmen gathered from every regiment in the Army of Stirland, hand-picked by their officers for their level of fitness. "Last one there buys the first round!" is his rallying cry, and Van Hal just rolls his eyes as Gustav charges, the men hot on his heels as they rush to join the knights holding the gatehouse. You notice flashes of orange in the crowd; the Slayers have joined this wave, it seems. Van Hal looks to the dwarf. "Sir Thori, the third wave is yours." "Right you are. Alright, lads!" he calls, his voice booming. "Are we going to let a bunch of manlings kill all the uzkular?" "Nai!" comes the response from a thousand throats, and in seconds you're treated to the rare sight of a Dwarvish charge. "The fourth is us," Van Hal states. "Assuming you're not to be swayed." "Of course not," you reply. You draw your flamberge, letting the familiar sensation of flowing Ulgu calm your nerves. He claps you on the shoulder, and walks to the assembled men; the rest of the army of Stirland, or at least those that have crossed the river and are dry enough to march and fight in the Spring chill. "Army of Stirland!" he calls, his voice carrying across the field. "No more do we wait for Sylvania to spew horrors into our land. Today, we shove our fist down Sylvania's throat and throttle the life out of anything we find!" There's a cry of agreement, though muted; Van Hal's not one for speeches at the best of times, and hasn't cultivated the love of the men that signifies a true leader. But these men are professionals, honed by a year and a half of constant skirmishes, and they don't need encouragement to be ready for the fight, and everyone you look hands tighten on hilts as the army awaits only the order. You notice some of the troops returning your look; you've always drawn looks, but the army recently has been treating you with something like awe, and you're not entirely sure how you feel about it. But that's something to consider another time, because Van Hal has given the nod to the generals, who have given nods to subordinates of their own, and eventually that'll filter down through gods know how many layers and lead to sergeants bellowing that now is the time to march. And in front of them all is Van Hal, sword in hand, and at his side is you. "How was it?" he asks casually as you begin the march down the road. You itch to break into a run, as you know the men behind you do, but the fourth wave is to arrive fresh and ready to relieve those that ran to the gate. So you approach in the most infuriating walking pace of your life. "Not bad," you say vaguely. "It's a good note to hit, Sylvanian proactivity. But reaching down the throat to throttle something inside that throat is a bit confusing." "I should just plagiarize," he says with a sigh. "'Remember, when you build a wall to shelter behind, you are also building a trap,'" he begins, and you smile as you recognize the quote. "'If the wall is strong, and flanked by towers, the enemies will be trapped. But if the wall is carried...'" you continue. He finishes the quote. "'Then the other walls will hem in your defenders, and leave them ripe for massacre.' Magnus the Pious." "May the earth rest lightly on him," you say, with feeling. There's a pause from Van Hal, before he says, "I suppose wizards have even more reason than most to venerate him." "Two hundred years ago, you would have been burning me at the stake," you state, managing with effort to keep the emotion out of your voice. Up ahead, the unmistakable clamour of battle can be heard, though it is almost drowned out by the thousands of feet marching in time behind you. "Then I am thankful we do not live two hundred years ago," he replies, drawing Orc Hewer. "As am I." The wall towers above, a daunting and terrible obstacle - except the gate was open. Silence stretches between the two of you, intruded on from both sides by the din of fighting and the tramp of boots. "Once more into battle," he says. "And then one more once more, and then another," you observe. You can see inside the gates, where a wall of backs holds back whatever inside is trying to fight its way back to the gatehouse, and to the windlass that would shut the portcullis. "Such is the world we live in." You murmur a few familiar words, and the Ulgu flowing through you rises to the surface, hardening into a protective layer. "Today we change the world we live in." "Damn right we do," Van Hal replies. "Men of Stirland, charge!" [Charge of Dame Mathilde Weber: Martial, 86+18=104] [Charge of Elector Count Abelhelm Van Hal: 53+28=81] [Charge of the Army of Stirland: 1] At long last you break into a run, Van Hal at the side, and men catching up to you on either side. The ranks filling the gateway part to allow you through, and you've a moment to glimpse a bleached-white skull grinning at you before your sword, propelled by instincts ingrained into you by months of training, has smashed into it, tearing it free of the spine it rested upon and propelling it over the ranks of skeletal warriors. But you've no time to admire the arc of the projectile because another has taken its place, and you strike it down like the first, and then another, and another. Too many, too many. You and Van Hal had discussed this beforehand, after the charge the two of you were to let the push of the men overtake you, a bit of showmanship and minimal risk to buoy morale, and besides the Greatswords would be coming in not far behind. But the push just isn't there, you cannot spare even an instant to look but every glimpse you catch is of rotted spears and rusted swords spilling blood, and the only human left in a sea of foes is Van Hal, his sword caught up in a ribcage, and in a motion that owes nothing to training and all to instinct, your bare knuckles connect with the shoulder of the skeleton about to impale him upon its spear, and only your magical armour protects you from shattering the bones in your knuckles but nothing protects the skeleton from the shattering of its clavicle. [Survive in the melee: 23+18=41 vs 59] You were a wizard, for Ranald's sake, you shouldn't be here. You should be leisurely forming spells to fling at these accursed, literally accursed skeletons from a battlefield away, not smashing through skeleton after skeleton until your muscles ached, and it seems barely minutes have passed but the ache is worse than any from your countless hours of practice. You can parry blows, you trained until you bled, but you can't block two blows at once and you choke back a cry as rust-red iron penetrates magic and robe and skin and scores a line of agony across your ribs, and seconds later you've smashed him asunder with your blade but there's always more to take their place, and the rest of the army is nowhere to be seen. "VICTORY OR DEATH!" cries Van Hal, the ancient battlecry of Stirland, and as the deafening noise of the melee drowns out his cry you fear you know which it will be. [Van Hal surviving in the melee: 1] And as though your thought was prophecy, Van Hal lies bleeding on the ground. One moment he was at your side, Orc Hewer tearing through bone with contemptuous ease, and the next you were straightening from your cleave through two of the skeletons and he's down. [Fight on: 18+18-2(wounded)=34 vs 46] You stand astride him, yelling in fear and defiance at the top of your lungs with breath you don't have, and pain shoots through your body time and time again as blows slip past your guard. There's nothing that can make your sword be in five places at once, and the skeletons just keep on coming, and some corner of your mind not lost in the battle wonders if that's why the army was able to purge the Haunted Hills, because they were all here instead of there. Is this where the Purge ends, in hubris? Is this the final chapter of an overambitious Elector Count, a harsh lesson to be handed down as to why one doesn't underestimate Sylvania, in which you exist only a footnote? [Is anyone coming to the rescue?: 8] [Fight on: 70+18-6(wounded)=82 vs 42] A second, a second, is all the lull you get between the endless onrushing of skeletal fiends, but it's enough to scoop Orc Hewer from where it fell. You can feel magic humming under your hands, and not wild, dangerous, treacherous magic you know so well but magic that has been broken and tamed and used against the enemies of man for thousands of years. It doesn't threaten to twist free of your grip if your attention wavers, but hums eagerly in your grip, and where you were battering the skeletons away you are now tearing them apart where they stand, and those that replace them stumble on fallen bones, the fell magic animating them too crude for them to be anything but clumsy. Contempt rises in you, contempt for the wizard who crafted these abominations - they fell to the temptations of dark magic for this? They succumb to the lure of Dhar and this is the best they can do with it? Ulgu envelops Orc Hewer, and though it can do nothing to add to the ancient power of the blade, you need your magic to be tearing through that of the so-called Elector Countess who can manage no better than these pathetic, mindless automatons. Blasphemy twice: once for falling to temptation, and once for doing so little with it. [Anyone at all? 46] [Fight on: 81+18-6(wounded)+3(Runefang)=96 vs 9] You're yelling again, but in rage this time, as the skeletons fall faster than their plodding march can replace them. Blood, your own and Van Hal's, coats the hilt of the Runefang but if anything your grip is surer for the reminder of the stakes, and for the first time in what feels like an eternity there's no white of bone in your peripheral vision, and the only skeletons are the ones directly before you. You itch to advance to meet them, but to do so would be to abandon your vigil over Van Hal, so you let them come to you, wading through piles of shattered bone to get to you only to be struck down like all the rest. If this is your doom then so be it, a hundred have fallen before you this day and a hundred more will be broken by your hands before they drag you down. [Anyone?: 68+10(previous roll)] [Rolling for who...] "KHAZUKAN KAZAKIT-HA!" For an instant confusion floods through you at the alien battlecry, but though the call is unfamiliar the charge that accompanies it is unmistakable. Thori Stoneheart, Thane of Zhufbar, and a relentless phalanx of dwarven warriors smashes through the amassed skeletons, pushing not so much through them as over them. You look left and right, and there's no animate bone left within striking distance, just the shattered remains of skeletons and men alike. You don't know what to do, robbed of all thought but that of combat. Two dwarves approach, and you blink at them confusedly. "Easy, lass," one of them is saying, approaching like one would a wild beast. "Your thane, we need to get him to safety." Oh. You gather what will you can, and stumble away from your stance astride Van Hal's fallen body, truly taking the sight in for the first time: the bloody leathers, the spear through his gut. The sight sets off a storm of emotion in you, but it's a storm you watch numbly from a distance, power and fury raging a long way away. You feel Orc Hewer slip from your fingers. "Hup, two!" the dwarves say, and Van Hal is lifted atop their shoulders as the motion jars the spear from him, and he is taken at impressive speed towards the gates you came through so long ago, and nothing in the world could stop you from following after. [Trait gained: Badly Wounded] --- The tent for the wounded and dying in a military camp is a terrible place; Van Hal, thankfully, is spared that, as he's brought to his own tent that some obliging camp follower had put up on the Drakenhof side of the river. Doctors are called for, such as they are; men who barely have the ability to wrap bandages around wounds and put food in someone until they get better or finish dying. One of them tries to eject you from the tent, and you grope for your absent flamberge for a moment, and are about to settle on punching him before his fellow pulls him away, whispering urgently. You let them hold their mumbled conversation, and sit by Van Hal's side. He looks gaunt, but he's always been thin; he looks pale, but you're not sure if it's more so than usual. His breathing is steady, though marred by the blood dripping from what looks like a broken nose - you wipe it as best you can with the sleeve of your robes. If he's dying, he's doing so peacefully, which completely fails to provide comfort. His leathers are cut from him by the doctors, as are his clothes, and you wish this was under circumstances where you had the attention to spare for that. But your entire focus is on the gashes criss-crossing his chest, and on the bloody wound in his stomach. The wounds are looked at, and the level of bleeding judged to be not dangerous, but they're bandaged anyway because the other alternative was their being murdered by you. And that's it, that's the limit of medical care that can be given; stomach wounds, one of them says with a shrug that says it all. He'll be fine, or he'll be dead. Only way to find out is to wait. You vaguely recall that Hysh can heal, so you send a runner to find the Light Wizard you recruited, though you haven't seen him since Nachthafen. The Amethyst Wizards are near the town, standing ready to counter any hostile magics that could be thrown into the fray, but their brand of help would be nothing of the sort. Jade Wizards. Why hadn't you insisted on Jade Wizards? They could be fixing this now, but instead they're all in Altdorf or gods know where, days away even for you, and by the time you could make a round trip it would be over, one way or the other. A battle is still raging. Where do you go from here? [ ] By Van Hal's side. Whatever happens. [ ] A battle still rages. Throw yourself into it. [ ] Somewhere in that town-turned-battlefield is Brother Kasmir. Leave Van Hal's side. Find him. Sigmar will heal Van Hal. [ ] The plan exists independently of Van Hal; if necessary, it will outlive him. Take command. [ ] Dhar lies thick in the air. You just need a little. Just enough to give a Grey Wizard the power to heal...

Turn 13: Blood And Bruises

Bloodied
+009.M42+
+They Shall Know No Fear+

“There is no clear path, not precisely,” Justinius had told you as you spoke before the assault force departed. “It is rather that we shall have to work in distracting the primitive inhuman minds which hold court there.”

“The stream of metal and flesh that pour from this place will be strong,” Codicier Nero had mentioned as he passed his hands over the vellum of a book of some sort or another, as if reading it with his fingers. “But can be diverted. Speed, and power. Like a stream.”

“It will be difficult, but it is possible.”

They had spoken for true.

Unlike the last daemonforge that you faced before, this is further in. It is newer as well. Corrupted but recovered records state that it was once within the personal domain of a Magos Biologis who was attempting to improve upon the basic design of the skitarii that serves the Adeptus Mechanicus even now. The only issue is that he was, according to what the Mechanicus adepts who have been working on Aerus all this time, one of those who fell to Chaos and those who aligned themselves with the traitor Horus. Xenos flesh, cloned and tested upon, found itself further tainted by the vulgar touch of the warp upon it. This, more than anything, is what you face. While the greater lost manufactorum spews forth its scrap metal creations in mindlessly productivity turned to the daemons within it’s insane wishes, the area itself is filled with the creatures. Maddened and twisted versions of skitarii leap forth out of the shadows in the shadows of armed formations, appearing from the wilderness all around you screeching scrap code into the air.

Yet you bear with you two of the mightiest vehicles ever devised by the minds of mankind. The noble land raiders. One of the Phobos-pattern, the other of the Crusader-pattern, both as the spear tip of the entire convoy. Melta fire fills the air to scorch flesh and corroded iron alike as your bikers weave in and out of sight. It is at their hands, as a group, that they again and again distract the oncoming tanks of absurd designs and mockeries of true vehicles blazing with empyreal light that flow both towards you as the intruders in their lands and towards the skitarii themselves. For you fight no tactician, no true leader, nothing more than an animalistic intelligence that has bent itself to constant war and destruction of any and all it can find.

During your grinding journey forth into the wastelands of Aerus, over shattered Titan hulks that were of true design and not the strange creatures that rise up like fungi occasionally from the corrupted lands and through broken manufactorum that were not possessed by anything but time and rust, you train your forces further. It is, after all, that long of a journey both on the way and will be on the way back. Simply because you carve your way through a dozen mutant nests, horrific abominable skitarii ‘barracks’, and small scrap creation convoys as well as the general river of such things heading towards the skitarii lines. It is just as well, for this is deeper in than the last you faced in comparative distance from the reclaimed areas and those that remained corrupted.

It is certainly deadly enough that once you actually get in sight of the manufactorum, metal being consumed for meals and then spat out by assembly lines of flesh and bone arms that bleed sparks and hate, that you have already had numerous casualties. None are dead, thus far, but both the 1st and 5th Company find themselves shouldering the weight of brothers brought down by explosives at one point, and a sheer weight of lasgun fire by a corrupted skitarii fireteam at another. Yet you push on, land raiders leading the way, as you push through. To your disgust, even the opening doors of its loading docks and entrances swirl with the unholy light of the warp that glimmer within as if they are in fact actual maws. From one instant to the next as you slam Godsplitter into and through five skitarii at once in a single horizontal sweep that you practiced daily with Apollo on the way to the daemonforge, you swear that it is in fact breathing almost as the rest of the 1st Company begin to make their way inward in a thickened mass, led by Captain Marcus and the not just the Chaplain of his Chapter but by your Master of Sanctity himself as well as Justinius going forth. More powerful than any other psyker in the chapter currently, your Chief Librarian’s efforts are to be not towards bringing down the malefic structure but instead to safeguard those that will plunge into its depths.

As for you and the rest of the 5th Company, you set yourselves and ready for the inevitable response of Aerus. It comes by screams through the air, stomping false dreadnoughts who bear not honored heroes but only the damned and worse, tanks that roar from the barrels of their guns with the screams of animals and dying children, with twitching and mutated skitarii swarming like flies to a corpse. And yet you possess more than enough firepower. Litany of Purgation and Tarantulus Ultima reap a bloody toll amongst all, dealing more death than even your predators or the vindicator, more than the razorbacks individually at the least. All the while, you lead your chapter, dividing points where your brothers either suffer more injuries or are near to falling between yourself, Apollo, and Tarkus who all at one time or another come rushing to the fore.

Only when you hear the signs of destruction behind you do you spare a single thought away from facing the onslaught before you. Hannibal is the first of your brothers you see, carrying the shattered yet still breathing body of Ares in his arms. Marcus limps forward as well, and yet you see much of the 1st Company being exiting not on their feet but in the arms of their brothers are carefully dragged behind to be loaded into the transports and razorbacks. The worst of them are deposited into the land raiders who twist about to afford the greatest possible protection for those that fell.

“Marcus,” you reach the 1st Captain where he grimly has already begun firing a heavy bolter at a group of smaller abominations of metal more the size of astartes than anything else, “What happened?”

“Daemons.”

============================================

The explanation given to you once you reach safe territory once more is more complete, of course. Whereas the last daemonforge was infested and filled with the uncontrolled energies of Chaos, it had been possessed by a daemon itself. But this place, where the 1st Company plunged into the fire, had been more than possessed machinery driven to infernal purposes but was in fact inhabited by actual daemons who had managed to manifest. Creatures of Nurgle, of rot and unholy life in equal measure, was it filled at its deepest point with plaguebearers and bloatflies that had over an unknowable amount of time. The great abundance of rotting flesh and weakened skeins of reality itself left over from the Horus Heresy in that place had allowed them to come through to feast on the pain and madness as the Forgeworld decayed for millennia.

And while the 1st Company slew them all, purged in flamer and melta and bolter fire, they had not done so with ease. Ares himself had found himself beset, crozius crushing and smashing giggling daemons large and small, and refused to die even when his body was lost beneath a crushing pile of the things. He lives, even now, and without the need for a dreadnought certainly, but he will not find himself on the battlefield for some time yet along with many of those not just within the 1st Company, but those within the 5th Company as well.

[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 0+78+Apollo(29)=107/800]
[Chapter Training – Toughness: 523+65+Amicus(25)=613/600]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill: 210+10+Macharius(25)=245/500]
[Chapter Training – Agility: 52+17+Kaius(25)=94/500]

==========================

Reports from elsewhere are of better news. With the inability to truly deploy with anything approaching certainty you ordered your Master of Fleets to take the not inconsequential fleet remaining to the Blood Ravens to patrol throughout Aralakh. And he did so with skill, chasing down a small smattering of pirates and xenos raiders who had certainly not expected to run into any true retribution for crimes that the Imperial Navy could not spare the effort to persecute. But Hadrian had the time, and the attention to spare in spades. You can only imagine the look on the face of his foes as a space marine fleet dropped out of the warp to face them. But more than that, of course, is that perhaps in a bit further of an extension of his orders than you necessarily asked, he ended up transitioning into the Caeserion System and offering the services of your ships against the positions held by the Hrud.

To perhaps some small amount of surprise, he was not refused despite vocal protests by the Order of the Lost Rosetta, and the vastly powerful bombardment weaponry of your battle barges were put to use against the Hrud. That also allowed your thunderhawks, reduced in numbers as they so badly are, to unleash themselves fully. Kept within their bays by the daemonic anti-air capabilities of Aerus’ surface, they perhaps almost too eagerly set themselves against the more comparative lacking defenses of the Hrud as they sluggishly marched forth from their dark spaces. At the least, while the leadership of the Guard and Navy might have been unhappy at the interlopers in their battling area, apparently by Hadrian’s reckoning the casualties their forces are taking not from injuries in battle but from the horrific rapid aging process of the entropic fields that the Hrud emanate was enough to gouge their pride so that the Blood Ravens could succeed.

As for Meridian, Derosa is more than happy to accept your aid in the form of the scout marines. And indeed, there are yet tyranids that have hidden themselves in the depths of her underhives, ork survivors of the past that have found themselves a place as gang enforcers and bloody small groups which kill and loot as they wish. But there are other things as well, loxoatl mercenaries working for nobles in their bloody games of politics that Derosa needed put down which provided their own challenges, and two specific occasions that Cyrus made particular note of to you. The first of these was in fact a small Hrud infestation, potentially as flotsam from what is going on in Aralakh, which had the perhaps unique danger of aging aspirants and neophytes too rapidly for proper gene-seed gestation and maturation and causing them to be rendered unusable, as well as one of the most insidious threats the Imperium faces – a genestealer cult. Most certainly another remnant of the tyranids who arrived in Aurelia so long ago, Cyrus himself brought down the Patriarch of the entire cult, setting the whole of the 10th Company with the aid of the Adeptus Arbites and PDF troops upon the entire cult, setting the underhive of one of Derosa’s cities as the battlefield.

Meridian was served well by Cyrus’ arrival, and the 10th Company in turn was granted the precious experience against more than simple orks in the course of the year as well. Hadrian’s assistance in Aralakh was most valuable indeed, you are told, even if some small parts of the continents that the ships flew over have several new craters in them. As for the ongoing fights along the skitarii lines, Martellus was pleased to find that none of his creations were destroyed this year, though some did sustain some minor damage that was fixed by the enginseers on-planet before he could get to them. But the fight yet continues, on Aerus and elsewhere, and you cannot afford to let up.

008.M42 Into 009.M42 Results:
- Ares Actus is Badly Injured, to recover in 010.M42
- 15 1st Company Veterans Badly Injured, to recover in 010.M42
- 2 1st Company Veterans Dead, +2 Gene-Seed
- 5 5th Company Battle Brothers Badly Injured, to recover in 010.M42
- 10 Scouts [1st Stage] Advance: 8 to Scouts [2nd Stage], Remainder Expired. +2 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 25 Scouts [2nd Stage] Advance: 19 Battle Brothers To Be Assigned, Remainder Expired. +6 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 35 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 33 to Scouts [1st Stage], Remainder Expired. +7 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 4 Lexicani Advance: 2 To Codicier, 1 Expires Due To Corruption And Execution, 1 Expires To Mutation And Execution.
- 5 Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 3 To Lexicani, 2 Expired. +1 Gene-Seed Required.
- 30 Aspirants Advance: 20 To Neophytes [1st Stage], Remainder Expired.
- 3 Psyker Aspirants Advance: 2 to Psyker Neophyte [1st Stage], Remainder Expired.

Aerus Warfare Decisions (55% of Aerus Reclaimed/Reclaimed Area rated as Extremis-grade Defenses By Mechanicus/Orbital Drop,Thunderhawk Transport Allowed Within Reclaimed Territory Due To Lack of Daemon-slaved AA Batteries):
[NO LONGER REQUIRED] Patrol the Reclaimed Zone - Is subject to semi-regular ambushes, machine creature infiltrators, mutated creatures appearing through ruined sewers and pipes. Recent aid by way of the numerous turrets of the Chapter's forges being put to use has greatly assisted in this. Relentless use of sentry turrets, and a much wider base of area for the Mechanicus to deploy themselves into including a deadly Myrmidon battle group have certainly well secured their territory, requiring no further aid from any source.
[] Target An Aerus Daemonforge - One of the tainted manufactorums which continually spill out a mixture of random possessed machinery, horrific cybernetic monstrosities, etc. behind the ‘enemy lines’ which are currently fighting against the streaming hordes of Skitarii. (Write-In Forces)
[] Break Mad Machine Mass, a grouping of insane tanks and armored carriers whose Machine Spirits have gone mad and are traveling as one mass and attacking everyone and everything they can, heading straight for the Skitarii Lines. The latest was slain with minor Mechanicus casualties, and so now the nearest is in the far distance within non-reclaimed Aerus territory. (Write-In Forces)
[] Attack Abominable Quasi-Titan – Aerus did not have a Titan Legion on its own, but apparently it’s twisted ghosts are determined to produce their own. Out of daemonflesh, rusted cable, and random scrap and weaponry scattered across the land, are titan-sized creatures crafted by mad machine spirits and corrupted programming. They are rare, but especially dangerous. A pair of these have arisen, of similar size to a Reaver Titan each, and are making their way towards the Skitarri lines. With each mile of land they progress across more and more scrap metal and material is growing onto them, increasing their size and deadliness. Around them have grown things that might almost be Knights or Dreadnoughts that trundle about as if attendants. (Write-In Forces)
[] Join The Lines - The Skitarii are currently in a seemingly endless back and forth with the rest of Aerus. While the penetrating spearhead strikes of the Blood Ravens have prevented the stalemate from falling in the wrong direction, some front-line assistance for properly equipped dreadnoughts and terminators could likely assist the Mechanicus forces in pushing further forward in general. With your own vehicles, and heavy weaponry, this could be made possible. The further the line stretches and expands, the better it will be for all. And at the least, you would not be sending astartes into enemy territory and instead they would be fighting alongside allies. A revivified and newly inspired 1st Meridian Consolidated have marshaled themselves along this line, granted the use of the newest Leman Russ battle tanks and other various types of Imperial Armor by the restored manufactorums of Aerus within their ranks by a grateful Adeptus Mechanicus. Said Mechanicus has recently landed one of Zerann's legendary Fellblades, Doom Of The Illogical to face any and all. The 1st Company has shifted themselves here to contribute as best as they can while awaiting their more injured brothers to rejoin them. (Write-In Forces)

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] A thought as struck you to negotiate with the Adeptus Mechanicus for use of their manufactorums in some small part of production value much like what you possess in deals with the masters of Angel Forge. Have you not greately contributed to the reclamation of this very world? Are not your brothers, even now, somewhere with one of their Explorator Fleets? (BP/Turn Value Possible To Be Gained Unknown)
[] Now that you know that Aralakh's commanders are at the least somewhat willing to accept the aid of the Blood Ravens due to the sheer casualties they are taking from the Hrud Infestation, you might contribute some measure of your forces to them if you should wish to - Hadrian's rather imaginative application of your orders aside. (Write-In)
[] Recall Brothers In The Deathwatch
- (Specify In Write-In)

[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.
- You have access to a number of veterans who could impart their knowledge and skills upon your ranks, an especially important thing now that it is likely that many scouts will soon be promoted to full battle brothers. Not just in one way, but more. You have the exceptional battle brothers for it, after all.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 1):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium really does need more, well, Apothecaries. The Companies we have should not be without! Especially on Aerus!
- In 012.M42, 22 Gene-Seed should be available from the Test-Slaves.
- Gracchus is currently studying the gene-seed of the Blood Ravens, to perhaps improve survival rates for implantation.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (250 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- I could use a few more peers in the forges. Or at least subordinates.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- Some of our most constant foes are the most numerous - orks, tyranids, the denizens of Chaos. Further firepower could surely assist, and one of the best examples of this are the Tarantula Turrets.
- While our thunderhawks are not of much use on Aerus at this point in time, they are most certainly quite depleted when it comes to our fleet. In the future, in combat both on the ground and in the void, we should work to ensure that our ships possess them in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Test the 10th Companies latest aspirants and neophytes upon the threats of the Sector
- [] The orks of Caepio, so that the 10th Company remains within the Brutalia System with the rest of the Chapter.
- [] The extremely numerous orks of System A4XX, perhaps even going after the warbosses there.
- [] Hive Gangers, remnant xenos, traitors, cultists, and other such potential things within the planet Meridian to ensure more than simple greenskin experience.
- [] Enact Blood Trials upon the planet of Meridian. Orks, tyranids, and Chaos have stripped the fat from their soft flesh. It is time we seek for those amongst them capable of joining the Blood Ravens.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.

009.M42 Interlude: The Liberation of Mordax

009.M42 Interlude: The Liberation of Mordax

“Yaahaaahaa, dis ‘Kroosadin’ fing dat you humies are always going on about are actually zoggin’ good fun, space marine!” cackled Warlord Gorkenok as he unleashed a massive wide-beam of lascannon dealt death Aramus, the Blood Raven just barely managing to dodge. “Aw come on now space marine, it ain’t no fun for Beamy if ya run outta da way! You fink I gave up me mega-shoota for you gits to not get all krumped?!”

Gorkenok did not wait for a response, merely firing off his lascannon weapon once more, while around him the rest of his orks cheered whilst fighting the screaming and indignant skitarii of Mordax Prime. The hate-filled chants by the Sisters of Battle present merely added yet another voice to the chorus of violence which filled the air of the Forgeworld. All around the duel the fighting continued, orks and humans and servants of the Omnissiah all doing their very best to kill their foes. Screams of blasphemy and xenos heresy were met with the racial warcry of the orks since before the Imperium existed at all. In the middle of it all, Gorkenok cackled as Aramus moved forward to meet him, hammer meeting power klaw again and again.

“Not a big talker, eh?” Gorkenok chuckled, “Dat’s all roight, I geddit. Tryin’ to go for da ‘strong and silent type’. Only problem iz, da only boyz what can pull dat bit off is dem Necron boys and I ain’t about to take my Kroosade into dose gits just yet.”

Aramus just growled, and hefted the Sunderhammer for another blow which crushed its way into the armor of the Warlord but stopped just barely short of the flesh beneath. But such was not needed, as the power field went into effect and crushed muscle and bone through sheer force. Gorkenot grunted as his organs pulped slightly, but instead merely shifted his feet slightly so that he could try to brain Aramus with the barrel of his looted lascannon.

“Still, yer doin’ a better job of it den dose spikey boyz. Dey wuz tinking dat we were gonna be nuffin but dere ‘cats paws’,” Gorkenok grunted as Aramus landed another blow yet managed to slice along the terminator armor that the Force Commander wore. “I dunno wot a cat iz, but I sure didn’t like dem talkin’ about me as wun, you know!?”

The space marine leapt back – as best as one could in terminator armor – in time to avoid another lascannon blast at close enough range that had he not been wearing a helmet the flesh of his head would have been set aflame or worse vaporized. In the midst of the greenskins, he heard the telltale throaty roar of Thaddeus’ twin chainswords as he set to work amongst the orks, another song sung in the war symphony that filled the ork-held manufactorum. While the Salamanders made their way assaulting Factorum Tertius and Betal, the Dark Angels who were supposed to be here in the first place had mysteriously disappeared for some reason or another that Aramus did not even bother considering.

“Aaagghh, stop dodging! Ya wanna see what happened to dem spikey boyz!?!” Gorkenok bellowed before, ludicrously, turning just to show off the half dozen or so spikes bearing the heads and helmets of both Night Lords and Alpha Legionnaires. “Ain’t dey pretty,” the Warlord chortled as he twisted his whole body to block the next blow with his power klaw even as Aramus attempted to capitalize on the vulnerable moment. “Yer ‘ead will look pretty dere too!”

“Do you ever shut up!?” Aramus finally screamed in frustration as he unleashed a flurry of lighting fast hammer blows on Gorekenok that kept being caught again and again on either the power klaw of the ork or the rapidly battered barrel of his looted lascannon.

“Nah, dah only time I go quiet…is when me GUNS GO LOUD!”

And then the leader of the Kroosade, who had dubbed his nearly conquered world MoreDakka, set his feet. From panels all over his armor, haphazardly and impossibly welded on, came dozens of guns all pointed forward. Cannons and rocket launchers, hellguns, bolters and bolt pistols, and plenty more orkish guns of indeterminate class besides, all of which began almost immediately to fire upon Aramus who for the first time found himself unable to dodge or move away from the sheer width of firepower unleashed upon him. There was nowhere he could reach, nothing around the rubble strewn area that he could defend himself with. Despite the sheer strength and durability of his armor, it found itself bitten into and then nearly cored completely as missiles mixed with lasfire mixed with bolter rounds mixed with hundreds of slugs thrown forth by checker-painted shootas that had been all welded together.

“Aramus!!” Thaddeus yelled as he leapt forth from behind, his chainswords plunging deep into the exposed eyesockets of the Warlord, for whom the sheer amount of bolter rounds, lasfire, and solid slugs flying forward had been rendered temporarily deaf.

Gorkenok screamed, flailed, and found himself twisted, all of his guns firing still all of the while and soon into his own very horde. Thaddeus, roaring in fury all the while, merely shoved the chainswords deeper and deeper, through the eyesockets, the brain, through the throat and further within. The wild movement and shuddering of the body caused by a set of armor that had been an armory in and of itself disguised the fact that by the time Thaddeus had gotten the chainswords down to the hilts that Gorkenok was long dead. Eventually, of course, even the insane amount of ammo shoved into the armor’s weapons ran out, and what few orks remained that had not been cut down by their own Warlord’s gunfire stared in horror as he fell forward onto his face.

But Aramus had already slowly tipped over backward, his eyes wide and lungs filling with blood, the impossible sudden single strike having breached his terminator armor in over two dozen different locations to rip and tear at the body within.

Thaddeus slowly dragged his gore-caked blades upwards and flicked them once to clean them only slightly as he glared at the greenskins before him, the surviving Sisters of Battle and Guardsmen watching in turn.

“Adrian,” he whispered, loud enough for the apothecary to hear and come to the fore, sprinting to the side of the fallen Force Commander who moved not an inch.

“Uh. Boss?” one of the orks said to the tallest amongst them. “I’ze think…dat we shud run.”

“Yes,” Thaddeus growled, his entire body trembling, “You should.”

And then he leapt upon them, while a frantically piloted Thunderhawk came flying down from the direction of the waiting strike cruiser in orbit.

=========================================

“Some may speak against the honor of the Blood Ravens,” Sergeant Myrn declared as he stood atop the still smoldering corpse of the latest leader of the collapsed ork forces of the Green Kroosade who had attempted to keep the WAAAGGH!! from totally falling to infighting, “But I will say unto them that they would speak only folly. Whatever your crimes to be sent on Penitent Crusade, what you have shown here proves – to me at least – your purity.

“I thank you for your words, Sergeant. I would say the same but all already know of the noble character of the Salamanders,” Thaddeus nodded his head deeply before straightening and looking back towards the waiting Thunderhawk.

“Your Force Commander,” the Salamander noted gently, “His injuries are severe?”

“Yes,” Thaddeus bit out, his teeth clenched, before he sighed and lowered his head. “I apologize for my temper. I have seen him clash hammer to blade against an Avatar of Khaine, and yet for an ork to bring him so close and perhaps even fully unto death…”

“I understand. You are true brothers,” Myrn clasped a hand onto the ork-blood covered pauldron of the golden armor that Thaddeus wore. “Some things come without warning, for this is a cruel universe. Even so, I can but offer my condolences.”

“Thank you, Brother Myrn. But we must away, now.”

Myrn frowned, his brow furrowing as he glanced at Thaddeus and then up at the approaching fleet of ships from the Adeptus Mechanicus and Imperial Navy in equal measure.

“…I see. May you live to see your Chapter again.”

Thaddeus’ smile was humorless.

“It stopped being about such a thing long ago. It is just that we would rather die in battle rather than expiring upon an apothecaries table, gasping for breath.”

With that, the Blood Ravens and their strange allied troops departed, leaving the planet, and much of its accolades, to the Salamanders. At least until the strong willed Salamander Sergeant made the deeds of Aramus known in slaying the Warlord who led the WAAAAGH!!! in the first place. As for the Dark Angels, none know where the promised assistance had disappeared, though rumors of Dark Angels ships across various flashpoints across the galaxy suddenly chasing after ghosts and shadows would propagate within the mouths and minds of those who dared to have them. MoreDakka was once more Mordax, and the hundreds of gargants under construction there were destroyed. The Green Kroosade, having slain it’s original masters, fell to infighting and ruin, Imperial reinforcements soon committing to cleansing and full reclamation of the whole of the Scarus Sector. And with its securing, yet more troops flooded into the Cadian system.

Assault on Drakenhof, Part 5: Thunder of Guns

Spoiler: Voting results [*] "We have the high ground. We have artillery. We level the town hall, and any other pockets of resistance, and the infantry pushes through the rubble." You're tempted, oh so tempted, to let Asarnil do what he and his partner do best and turn the entire town to ash. But good sense prevails. The short conversation you had with Van Hal before... well. Before. It rings in your mind; a quote from the greatest Emperor since Sigmar, Magnus the Pious. 'If the wall is carried, then the other walls will hem in the defenders, and leave them ripe for massacre.' The wall has been carried, the defenders are hemmed in, and that means that they are, indeed, ripe for massacre. You gave the order and it was accepted without question; with that, your position as de facto warleader has been cemented. Perhaps if Gustav had been around longer, had cemented his position as Marshall more, he might have resisted... but then, perhaps not. You know from your investigation into him that he's well respected as a cavalry leader, and from experience that he's gifted as a teacher, but it could be that his gifts just don't extend to being military leader for an entire province. It would likely be different if, instead, the knight had been given the role, the one you accidentally knocked out in the courtyard all those years ago... You shake your head, resisting the pull of nostalgia, and look down at the map, hastily sketched out from what could be seen from above. Sketched notations cover it, half of them crossed out and half of the rest with several question marks after them. Fog may be within the domain of Ulgu, but the fog of war bows down to no power, and it rules over this battlefield as it does every other. At least you can tell which parts of the town are lost to the flames, both magical and mundane, and as they send twin plumes into the sky you know for sure that any element of surprise that could be had against Drakenhof Castle is lost. You shrug to yourself. That was the decision Van Hal made when he chose to move on the town first, and it's one you supported. Outside, the distant clammer of battle starts to be overlaid with the hammer of masonry; you glance outside the door to see Dwarves erecting scaffolds of wood to dangle pulleys over the battlements. It would be easier than trying to carry a cannon up a staircase, you suppose. Practically anything would be. You return to the window, trying to see the view of the city with an artilleryman's eye. The entire town is laid bare before you, though smoke and distance renders all but the closest buildings anonymous, save for a few larger landmarks; the town hall, of course, and a severely decrepit building that may have once been a church. You daresay a ballistic arc could deliver a cannonball into any building one desired. The trick, you suppose, would be in identifying the correct building. Do Dwarves use cannonballs in their cannon, you wonder. There's a knock on the door and you whirl in shock. "Ma'am?" asks the Dwarf at the door, the distinct accent of Dwarf-spoken Reikspiel lying light upon his tongue. Discounting the Slayers, he's wearing less armour than any Dwarf you've seen in this whole campaign - only a single layer of chainmail is visible, which is practically casual dress for a Dwarf. "My name is Launy of Karak Kadrin. Thori asked that I speak with you, if I'm not interrupting." "Not at all," you say, waving him towards the chairs, he takes one and sits, and you resist the urge to pace as you sit across from him. If you're to lead this army, you'll have to make nice with your allies. "I am a..." he hesitates. "The word in my tongue is Barazul; Reikspiel has no equivalent, but you could consider me an appraiser of oaths." "Is Zhufbar reconsidering the alliance?" you ask, alarmed. That, more than anything could doom the campaign. "Not at all." You exhale, relieved. "What I wish to discuss is your Oaths to your fallen liege." Your thoughts must have shown on your face, because he holds up his hands conciliatorily. "Allow me to explain. You know the other name for Karak Kadrin?" "The Slayer Hold," you respond, trying to keep a level tone. "Aye, the Slayer Hold. And one of the more common reasons for a Dwarf to take the path of a Slayer is if an Oath they have taken is broken or rendered impossible. It is, of course, right and good that they do so; but not if the Oath has been fulfilled, or can still be fulfilled. And to help in this, we Barazul are called upon." "So..." You squeeze your eyes shut as you try to make sense of this glimpse into Dwarven psychology. "You're... worried I'm going to become a Slayer?" "Or some human equivalent," he says evenly. "We extend this to you as a courtesy. We witnessed your defence of your fallen liege, and have great respect for it. Some of us had taken to call you Govibarazak - she who makes an oath-stone of their liege - but with his passing, it seemed rather in poor taste." You grit your teeth and drum your fingers against the table, looking across it at this patient Dwarf with his neat clothes and well-groomed beard. You want to send him away, and you'd rather do anything than re-examine those events, but... Dwarves take oaths seriously. If you can get this 'appraiser' to vouch for you, it would likely keep the Dwarves happy. "Very well," you say. He nods. "Wanbarazek. What oaths bind you?" You take a breath. "Journeywoman's Oath to my Master. Wizard's Oath to the Grey College. The Oath of Service to Van Hal. And the Oath of Fealty as a Knight of Stirland, also to Van Hal." He nods thoughtfully. "Are the first two relevant to the matter at hand?" You consider. "The Wizard's Oath includes conditional loyalty to Elector Counts and to employers both, but it wouldn't apply here. So, no." "Very well. The Oath of Service. Does it call for you to physically defend his person?" You try to remember the wording. "No. To perform the duties given, and to work only in his interests." "And has he instructed you to physically defend his person?" You smile sadly. "He tried to talk me out of it a time or two, actually." The Dwarf lets you dwell for a moment, before gently continuing. "And the Oath of Fealty?" You close your eyes and let memory bring you back to the day that you were knighted, and the words leap to your lips as readily as when Anton taught them to you. "This day do I render homage and fealty to my Lord, the Elector Count Abelhelm Van Hal of Stirland, who will, from this day forward, be my Liege. I will remain true in all ways, serving him faithfully - this do I swear, by my life and by my Gods." You wipe at your burning eyes with a sleeve, angry at yourself. "So say I, Mathilde Weber." He ruminates on it. "A good Oath," he says eventually. "Nadammen - no insult is meant, an important word in such matters. Did you fight to the limit of your ability and strength, in defence of your Liege?" You grit your teeth. "I did." "Nadammen. Did you do all in your power to save his life?" "I did." "Nadammen. Do you intend to carry out your Liege's unfinished business, as best you understand it?" "I will." "Then I judge you Nubarazeni - one who is currently Oathbound, but fulfilment of the Oath is possible. Work to fulfil the unfinished business of your fallen liege and you will be Anadgirdbarazanui, one whose Oath shall soon be fulfilled." "Just like that?" you ask, put off-balance. "Just like that," he says simply. "Your word is sufficient." "And that would prevent..." you wave your hand in the vague direction of any Slayers that might be left fighting. "The Slayers?" He smiles, a little sadly. "The Dawi are Duri, people of stone. And just like stone, if we are caught alone and struck hard enough, we can crumble. A Dwarf who has lost those closest to him can be blinded by grief, unable to see a way to fulfil his Oaths and honour those he has lost, and thus many take the Slayer Oath and seek oblivion. Honourable, but often... wasteful." He taps himself on the chest. "It is the duty of many of we who serve the Karaz Ankor to take the raw ore of our people and smelt them into azul." He smiles. "Which is both our word for metal, and for dependable Dwarves." You do your best to tuck away the insight into the Dwarf psyche for future thought, when you're not... distracted. "I see," you say. He rises to his feet. "An honour to meet. And my condolences for your Liege. He was Anaddreki - destined for greatness. It is my thought that you will finish matters here and make him go down in history as Addreki, one who achieved greatness." "Thank you," you say, and find that you mean it. --- When you emerge, some minutes later, the walls are busy with Dwarven engineers running to and fro. The walls already bristle with cannon facing inwards, and more are being winched up by the minute. "Weber!" one calls, and you recognize Narfi at the center of activity. He waves you over to his island of tranquillity in the midst of all this business, and you maneuver through the toing and froing to reach him. "By Morgrim, you've given us the greatest firing gallery I've ever seen. This will be the volley that any cannoneer worth his beard has dreamt of." "Have you got initial targets picked out?" "Aye, we want to maximize the carnage before the enemy figure out what's going on and go to ground." He unrolls a parchment and holds it up for you to view; it's a miniature version of the map in the tower, though annotated in runes rather than Reikspiel. "The town hall, three barricades, and two points where a demolished house will allow for a badly-needed shortcut between streets. I've got some lads putting together smoke bombs that would give off smoke of different colours, to stand out against, well..." He waves a hand at the city in general, the district still burning with Hysh-white flames and one smouldering in a more conventional fashion, as well as a dozen smaller conflagrations scattered through the city. "Dawi, are we ready?" "Nearly!" cries a Dwarf hurrying past under a burden of strange, conical metal objects, and you watch him go thoughtfully. "What are they?" you ask. "Ammo, of course." "But the shape-" "Er, right, you lot still use the round ones. Forget I said anything, won't you? Secrets, and all that." He doesn't seem at all sheepish about it, though. "On an entirely unrelated note, I will share the observation that an arrow flies truer than even a spherical slingstone." "Noted," you say, watching as another cargo of the... cannonbolts? be carried past. "Right, might want to cover your ears," Narfi observes, and you follow his gaze to a long line of cannon, each with a Dwarf holding up a hand to signify his readiness to fire. You cover your ears with your hands. [Artillery of Zhufbar: 72] And the world becomes noise. As you gingerly release your grip on the sides of your head and check your palms for blood from what must surely be your burst eardrums, the cannon crews are reloading. In the city below, massive holes have been punched in the side of the town hall, and what you presume were the houses targeted for demolition are looking much the worse for wear. And in what feels like no time at all hands are already going up along the line of cannons, and you barely get your hands over your ears as Narfi barks the order and once more noise, noise that is felt rather than heard, batters you mercilessly. You're contemplating your retreat into the tower when you feel it - the feel and taste and smell like a disturbed swamp, as the Dhar that lies thick on the ground stirs in answer to a distant call. You gather your own will, ready to counter whatever is coming... [Magical counter-artillery: 34] And wait. And keep waiting. And cover your ears as another volley is fired, and the spell is still forming. You're disgusted at the fumble-handedness of whoever it is you're facing, and only the slightest bit intrigued that Dhar has made someone so incompetent into such a threat anyway. And finally the spell is formed and you instantly spot the manifestation - sickly-green bolts of dark magic shooting from a window of the devastated town hall, flying directly towards you, and you narrow your eyes as it as you recall the lessons you suffered as an Apprentice on the art of dispelling, confident that you can smash this spell asunder- [Hexensohn interrupt: 40+40=80.] And then, with barely a flash of amethyst light, the spell is snuffed contemptuously out. The Dwarves saw the projectile even if it didn't reach them, and all around you cannon swivel and minute adjustments are made as almost three dozen cannon are trained on the exact window where the dark magic was so ineptly cast from. Pity attempts to surface under the contempt you feel for whoever is within that town hall, and fails. [Dwarven cannon volley: 77] The entire front of the town hall is obliterated in an instant as some thirty odd cannonbolts plunge into and through the outer walls. For an instant it stands as a cross-section of a building, and then surrenders to gravity and starts to collapse in on itself at the point where the would-be necromancer had so foolishly tried to strike back from. Whether the collapse would have been total or partial would forever be unknown to you, because the Dwarves with their characteristic thoroughness had been preparing another volley, and the structure's fate is sealed. You think you're starting to get used to the noise, or at least you've been deafened enough that it doesn't bother you any more. "Here," Narfi says, passing you his spyglass, and with some difficulty you unfurl the the unfamiliar device and peer onto the battlefield. Men are charging into the heart of the town that had been spewing forth, and a ragged and desperate charge it is; the spyglass is powerful enough that you can see bloody bandages and the hesitation in their step from here. But they charge nonetheless, their backbone partially stiffened by the knights and slayers scattered among their number. [Infantry push - heart of the town: 55-10(poor morale)=45 vs 83-40(devastated)=43] [Infantry push - hotspots: 25-10(poor morale)=15 vs 4-20(pounded)=-16] [Infantry push - ???: 28-10(poor morale)+40(Amethyst trio)=58 vs 20] [Dwarves on the walls: 53 vs 52] The infantry are ragged, but their enemy so much more so, and their resistance is in the form of half-shattered skeletons and a few fresh zombies. The battle is bloody and gruesome, and only your own experiences with the human body in extremis gives you the stomach to keep from looking away, but in the end flesh and steel triumph over bone and darkness, and the infantry pour into the ruins of the building. You turn your eye to the streets and the barricades that the cannons were targeting, but the action there is already over, with the barricades torn apart and the few remaining skeletons smashed apart. You turn your eye to the walls on either side, and find the Dwarves guarding the approaches to your position caught in desperate battle against a tide of skeletons and fresh zombies, carving a terrible toll from their numbers but being pushed back nonetheless. Narfi has already spotted this, even without his spyglass, and a hurried burst of Khazalid orders has the cannons swinging around to fire on what looks like his own men. You cringe, expecting to see the horrible carnage of friendly fire... [DANGER CLOSE: 97] But it was foolish of you to expect shoddy craftsmanship from Dwarves. A single cannon barks, a cannonball plucking the head neatly from a skeleton, and seconds later the Dwarves disengage and fall back a dozen paces. Their foes would take only a few seconds to reach them once more, but that is all that is needed, as every other cannon sounds as one, and in a single very loud instant a tide of lead washes the walls clean of skeleton and zombie alike. The Dwarves take up defensive positions once more and stamp out a straggler or two foolish enough to still be moving, but it seems the danger on the walls, much like the resistance in the town below, is finished. [Town Hall siezed and looted: 91-40(devastated)=51] [Hotspots overrun: 49-20(pounded)=29] [Other discoveries: 88] [???: 1] The troops, freshly buoyed by victory, bring you gifts - wonderful gifts of paper, bound in leather you hope is pig. Tax records, census data, all the accumulated paperwork of centuries of functioning governance, which somehow survived unscathed despite the frankly stupendous amount of firepower that was directed at it. Also captured, and unconscious, is a man in dark black robes with skulls, actual full-size human skulls, dangling from the sash. The mind boggles. The results from the hotspots that, for whatever reason, the enemy attempted to defend is less grand - they received less of a pounding but whatever goodies they were protecting caught the brunt of it. Still, dead necromancers are their own reward. You're also brought word, as Gustav and the generals file in and report to you without even needing prompting, that the warehouses of the town have been captured intact. Inside is mostly the stored result of toiling the harsh Sylvanian soil in such amounts that feeding your army has now become a non-issue, but after taking you aside and glancing about for anyone that could overhear, Gustav drops a small pouch into your palm. Giving him a quizzical look, you pull it open and the unmistakable shine of whats inside causes your jaw to drop. Gold. Unworked, freshly mined gold. "This was all there was," he murmurs, and you're not sure whether to believe him. "But there was mining equipment too, picks and shovels and wheelbarrows and whatnot." Well. That complicates matters. When you've got a great deal more time on your hands, you'll have to go through every scrap of paper from the town hall and see if you can find where they've been hiding this literal gold mine of theirs. What also complicates matters is the sudden departure of Hexensohn and the Battle Wizards. You seek out the men that were with him, and they tell of a mad delve through tunnels underneath the town, crawling with undead. From what you can piece together, the three Amethyst Wizards seem to have been searching for something, and had commandeered a significant portion of your men in the town to fight a path through the undead. But when he found whatever it is he was looking for - a small stone structure embedded in the deepest part of the tunnels, deeper than the undead of the town above had penetrated - Hexensohn had gone in, but hadn't come out. Eventually his Battle Wizards had followed after him, and then come out again carrying their Patriarch, who was deathly pale and quite possibly dead - none of the men got a good enough look to tell. That was the last of the Battle Wizards any of the men saw, carrying Hexensohn into the darkness of the tunnels, and they had to make their own way out using chalk marks they had left in their path. How very confounding. And infuriating. At the end of the day, the town is, more or less, yours. There's still undead roaming the streets, but have seemingly lost any direction, not even attacking anyone they see. The surviving townsfolk are mostly penned up in one quarter of the town, and under heavy guard even though they seem to have stopped producing those ensorcelled berserkers. The mundane fires are under control, and the Hysh fire is at least not growing any further. The butcher's bill is heavy: a full quarter of the men that went into the town are dead or missing, with about the same wounded. The Greatswords appear to have been wiped out to a man, with Markus having led them into battle time and time and time again until there were none left, with Markus himself last being seen charging the town hall with only a few Slayers for company shortly before the cannons started firing. The Company of Honour, who featured heavily in the fourth wave that was supposed to support your charge into the city, are almost totally destroyed. And, of course, every single other Wizard has either died or left. On the bright side, the Dwarves took minimal casualties, having taken to the walls early and apart from a brief foray to come to your rescue, not having left it. The knights and halflings have taken only minor attrition. Your artillery is untouched. And Asarnil and Deathfang are as ready as ever. Kasmir still lives, though he's currently wandering the town and smashing skeletons apart in a brooding sort of way. And everyone looks to you for orders. Lords and Heroes Elector Count Abelhelm Van Hal Marshal Gustav von Jungfreud Brother Kasmir Journeywoman Mathilde Weber, Grey Wizard Magister Patriarch Viggo Hexensohn, Amethyst Wizard Lord Magister Sigismund Herwig, Amethyst Battle Wizard Magister Marike Grünberg, Amethyst Battle Wizard Magister Jovi Sunscryer, Light Wizard Asarnil the Dragonlord Thori Stoneheart, Dwarf Thane Narfi Hammerfist, Dwarf Engineer Giantslayer Bjorgvin, Dwarf Slayer Sir Markus von Pfaffbach Army of Stirland 12,000 9,000 spearmen 7,000 5,000 swordsmen 9,000 crossbowmen 800 pistoliers (dismounted) 500 greatswords 70 cannon 20 mortars Throngs of Zhufbar and Karak Kadrin 6,000 5,500 Warriors 2,000 Miners 4,000 Thunderers 1,500 Quarrelers 500 300 Slayers 40 cannon 30 grudge throwers 20 organ guns Other Black Guard of Morr, 1000 900 knights Talabeclander Knightly Orders, 400 350 knights Altdorf Company of Honour, 2,500 500 infantry Halfling Regiments, 5,000 4,800 archers What is to be done with the town? [ ] Leave a garrison; it is now de facto Stirland, not just de jure. -[ ] Heavy Garrison - 10k men, 40 cannon. -[ ] Medium Garrison - 6k men, 20 cannon. -[ ] Light Garrison - 4k men, 0 cannon. -[ ] Other Garrison (write in) [ ] Nothing good can grow in such tainted soil. Burn it to the ground. [ ] Abandon it to fend for itself. What is to be done with the captured Necromancer? [ ] Execute him at once, before he awakens. (+1 dead necromancer, 0 risks) [ ] Execute him publicly, in the traditional way. Burn him at the stake. (+morale) [ ] Spare some attention from matters of command to wake and interrogate him. (-your leadership, ???) -[ ] Focusing on the 'Elector Countess' -[ ] Focusing on the castle and its defences -[ ] Focusing on the gold mine -[ ] Focusing on the magic he wields [ ] Leave him hog-tied and under very heavy guard until this campaign is over and you have the attention to spare. What is your next step? [ ] Nothing has changed. We have cannon, we have dragon. Castle Drakenhof falls. [ ] We are no longer the force we were. We cannot risk attacking the Castle, not with our forces so devastated and our magical support gone and the element of surprise lost. The campaign is done, we return home. - The Barazul are my own invention and owe nothing to existing Dwarf lore, except that it strikes me as the sort of thing Thorgrim might try to implement to try to slow the decline of the Dwarves. I also want to point out that 'Barazul' translates as both 'Understanding of Oaths' and 'Gateway to Steadfast Dwarves', because I'm pretty proud of that double meaning. - Yep. Another nat 1. Though considering your concerns about the man, perhaps his nat 1 may not be considered entirely a bad thing for you.

999.M41 -> 009.M42 Interlude: On Wings Of White

999.M41 -> 009.M42 Interlude: On Wings Of White

It was sudden, and it was glorious.

A traitorous general seduced by Chaos who had led his armies in rebellion against the Imperium and his planet’s rulers.

A great series of worlds who had turned from the Emperor’s light albeit unknowingly after being lost by the Imperium a thousand years before.

A xenos empire which could not be allowed to live in case they ever threatened the Imperium itself.

All these and more, Wars of Faith fought across the entire galaxy. Orders upon orders, Majoris and Minoris, spread out in their glorious tens of thousands. Their hundreds of thousands. Once brought forth into existence by the lies of Goge Vandire, resolved and redeemed by the God-Emperor himself, did they march. By fire did they purge, by bolter did they battle, slaying all who would threaten the sanctity of the Imperium. To preserve not just the body of humanity, but to protect it’s very soul.

A shrine under assault by forces too powerful for its hundred Sisters to face alone.

A cruiser which had been swept aside by the currents of the warp, surrounded and attacked by Chaos raiders.

A fleet of refugees fleeing the tyranids who consumed their sector but were now hopelessly lost in the void.

One sister, the Inquisitor who had dragged her away from her convent slain and the rest of his retinue around him by the awakening necrons of the world they had awoken.

Too spread out to truly do the most important of works. Yet they possessed their orders, and could not divert from them for any less than the Divine Word of the Emperor himself.

==========================

“Come with me,” said the woman, her wings of white fluttering faintly behind her, a hand outstretched to the grime-covered Canoness who had been certain of death at the hand of Nurgle’s servants but moments before.

“Y-yes,” the Canoness said, taking the hand and finding the whole of her cleansed by simple proximity, the rest of her hundreds of sisters staring in turn.

==========================

“I see a light,” the navigator suddenly cried out, “I…I see a light!”

“Thank the Emperor,” the Captain groaned in happiness, letting his head loll back. “If we can just reach a planet within the Imperium…”

“It…it is not the Astronomicon…”

“What?”

“The light,” the navigator shook, “It’s…oh…her light…”

=======================

“Will you fight at the Emperor’s side?” she asked, and the Confessor felt himself drop to his knees, his hat and staff falling to the ground.

“Yes…yes!” he cried out, tears streaming down his face.

For ten long years had they struggled to bring this world back into the Emperor’s light, and in but a day it had been won. None could mistake her. Mistake her power. Mistake the Emperor’s touch upon her, and the holiness of her very presence. It had been enough to convert even those most die-hard of his foes upon this world, these heretics, and yet instead of death she granted them mercy in exchange for their aid. Aid they gave after she spoke to them in person, in secret, beyond the potentially fatal exchanges he would have brought them.

“Then ready your ships.”

=========================

“Thank you, my lady,” she whispered at the smiling woman who approached her on foot despite her wings.

“Thank me not, sister,” said the winged woman, as she lifted her out of her kneeling position. “It was you and your own convent which defended this place.”

“I…we thought that the orks had destroyed our communication arrays, how did you...,” she trailed off. “The Emperor?”

“The Emperor,” her savior nodded as she began to approach the sacred resting place of the Saint Ramona.

“W-what are you doing?”

“Arming you, my sister.”

And the sarcophagus was pulled to the side, revealing the golden armor within.

=================

“We cannot stop them,” Pedro Cantor bellowed to his brothers as they fought against the very tide itself, “But we shall hold them!”

The orks came, and they came, and they came. Hundreds died to the defenses of the Fortress-Monastery, and yet thousands more replaced them. Pedro roared as he slammed the back of his power gauntlet into an ork’s chest to pulverize it entirely, leaping forward to slay yet another nob as it savaged the corpse of another of his Crimson Fist brethren. He bled from a mortal wound, he knew, from an ork kommando’s assassination attempt of all things, and yet he fought on. Not until the last of the refugees of Rynn’s World were able to flee to safety into the ships which even now fought a desperate holding action in the stars above.

“For the Emperor, we shall slay the xeno, and for the Emperor, we shall not let up until the last of us falls!”

“AND NO MORE SHALL FALL TODAY!” came a booming voice, before Pedro saw the source, as thousands of flying Seraphim came down from the heavens, bombing runs by vessels of the Sororitas and Imperial Navy alike tearing apart the charging orkish armies.

Alighting near him, she swept her blade forth and obliterated the nearest orks with unforgiving zealous fury, before turning back to him with a look of tranquil concern.

“The last of those you protect are safe now, Chapter Master. And yet you need not remain any longer.”

“We…,” he grit out, “Cannot abandon Rynn’s World again. Not again!”

They could not lose what they had just reclaimed already!

“You shall return, Pedro,” she whispered his name, her hand upon his shoulder and with an aborted gasp he felt his wounds heal from her touch. “But you need not sacrifice yourself here and now.”

============================

“In accordance to the Decree Passive laid down by Sebastian Thor, for the folly of Goge Vandire the Ecclesiarchy cannot maintain any men under arms,” the Living Saint spoke from atop the ruined tank which had once born the servants of Chaos on a world now no longer under siege. “However…,” she slowly lifted her gaze towards all of the Sisters, all of the Guardsmen, all of the PDF, all of the citizenry who had come to see the planet’s savior, “I am not the Ecclesiarchy. I am but a servant of the Emperor and Imperium. I am but one of his humble servants!” she cried, lifting her burning blade aloft, “And yet I would ask of you, would you follow me to serve Him!?”

“Yes!”

“It is not a War of Faith, ordered by the Cardinals that I call upon you all to follow me into. It is a CRUSADE! Will you join me!??”

“YES!”

“For the Emperor, we do not crusade for anything less than the survival of THE IMPERIUM ITSELF!”

“FOR THE EMPEROR!!”

==========================================

From convent to convent.

From world to world.

From War of Faith won, to Wars of Faith that were won by Her arrival.

Men and women alike rose up across the Imperium rose up. Whole battle groups of Guard and Navy found themselves swayed into a religious fervor that they had not tasted or experienced in their entire lives. Orders to return for debriefing were ignored, for favor of following a true calling. It burned in them now, zealots from peasants, whispers to wild screams of joy and sermons of roaring righteous fury. Ships old and new, following a new beacon, through currents and warps becalmed and smoothed, flowing as one in a single mailed fist of faith.

There were times that She disappeared. Times that She returned. Throughout it all, they followed her, her words and deeds alike. Sometimes there were even tales spread that she had appeared at one end of the galaxy and then the next before bringing those she saved at both ends together through the passage of faith-girded travel. Distance and time, their meanings lost within what some referred to as the Great Ocean, worked towards their efforts rather than against them. It was as if their combined faith acted as a conduit in and of itself.

Others joined them as well. The Black Templars found their own Crusades not interrupted but aided by the faithful, arming and training themselves with the fervor of only the truly zealous can manage. And when they found that suddenly where there were but a few hundred bolters there were thousands, and when faced with the Living Saint who but begged them for their aid in service to the Emperor, they could not help but join her. There were none who begrudged this, joyous instead that the Angels of Death who worshipped the true God of Humanity. If anything, the fact that the Crusades they aided and that joined them in turn numbered so greatly was yet one more mighty buoy for them.

Pilgrims, volunteers, veterans, retired, and the young, all these and more would join her in number as the ships passed to and fro across the galaxy, an army in and of themselves. Yet they were no mere fighters of a War of Faith, as She had said. They were a Crusade, they fought a Crusade for the Imperium’s very survival.

And with every year, Celestine’s Crusade grew larger. It grew stronger. With fighting came experience. With experience skill. Those who had never held a lasgun or bolter in their lives before found their innocence burnt away upon the pyre for the Imperium’s soul, replaced with hard-bitten veterans of all ages. Armor that was naught but cloth and scrap were steadily replaced with that of the Guard, and many more found themselves near conscripted into the Sisters of Battle and trained as they would be. For to be put aside simply because they had not grown in the convents was no excuse, not when the Imperium was under such great threat. And they learned. They prayed. They fought. They died. And they killed.

It was a month after the Planet of Sorcerers had disappeared from the Fenris System.

It was one year to the day that Lord Castellan Creed had died at the hands of Abbadon the Despoiler.

But finally, did they arrive at their most final of destinations.

Cadia.

And so did tens of thousands of the Adepta Sororitas, regiment upon regiment of rescued Imperial Guard, battleships and cruisers and frigates, and five different unified Crusades of the Black Templars burst through the warp above the world of Cadia. With but three words did the Living Saint Celestine unleash them, troops to fly to the surface, to be deployed with holy fury, for ships to surge forward an assault the flotillas of chaos-tainted vessels which held themselves there. Did the pilgrims militant scream out in righteous exultation at the chance to fight and kill.

“FOR THE EMPEROR!!!!!!!!!”

Turn 14: Glory And Blood

Spoiler: Titanfall Plan

[X]Plan Prepare for Titanfall
-[X] Join The Lines - The Skitarii are currently in a seemingly endless back and forth with the rest of Aerus. While the penetrating spearhead strikes of the Blood Ravens have prevented the stalemate from falling in the wrong direction, some front-line assistance for properly equipped dreadnoughts and terminators could likely assist the Mechanicus forces in pushing further forward in general. With your own vehicles, and heavy weaponry, this could be made possible. The further the line stretches and expands, the better it will be for all. And at the least, you would not be sending astartes into enemy territory and instead they would be fighting alongside allies. A revivified and newly inspired 1st Meridian Consolidated have marshaled themselves along this line, granted the use of the newest Leman Russ battle tanks and other various types of Imperial Armor by the restored manufactorums of Aerus within their ranks by a grateful Adeptus Mechanicus. Said Mechanicus has recently landed one of Zerann's legendary Fellblades, Doom Of The Illogical to face any and all.
--[X]All Tarantula turrets.
--[X] Chapter Master Angelos (swap his default Bolt Pistol for a Plasma Pistol), Apollo Diomedes w/ Rogal's Fist, Chief Librarian Probalis, Master of Sanctity Palrun
--[X] 1st Company
---[X] Add another 3 suits of Terminator Armor, 3 Power Fists, 1 Assault Cannon, and 2 Storm Bolters to the 1st Company's standard loadout
--[X] 5th Company, + 2 Codiciers with Force Staves
--[X] Tarantalus Ultima, all our Predators & Razorbacks, 1 Vindicator, 1 Whirlwind
--[X] Bring all the Lascannons, Plasma Cannons & Multi-meltas. Every Marine trained in Heavy Weapons should be using one, and a Missile Launcher or Heavy Bolter if the special weapons run out. Tactical Marines bring Plasma Guns & Meltaguns.
-[X]Chapter Master Angelos:
--[X] Now that you know that Aralakh's commanders are at the least somewhat willing to accept the aid of the Blood Ravens due to the sheer casualties they are taking from the Hrud Infestation, you might contribute some measure of your forces to them if you should wish to - Hadrian's rather imaginative application of your orders aside.
---[X]Have Codicier Achillian search for where Hadrian can do the most good with the Fleet, without too much risk. If the results are inconclusive, Hadrian should use his best judgement.
--[X] Assign Chaplains Ravias to the 1st Company while Chaplain Antal heals. Keep Antonius with the 1st Meridian to uphold morale and battle corruption.
--[X] Assign the 19 fresh Battle Brothers to the 5th Company.
--[X] Have the veterans of the 1st Company survey the 5th for any that are worthy to join their ranks.
--[X] Speak with Governor Derosa, see if she's had any success in figuring out where the traitor Vandis has run off to. If her investigation is stalled due to lack of time, that's fine. if it's being stalled by Administratum intransigence, we're no help to her there. if it's due to a lack of tools or leads, perhaps we could put her in touch with some of the Chapter's contacts in the Adeptus Astra Telepathica? They're the ones who sent Vandis's mail for all these years, there could be some hints there.
-[X]Training With Apollo
--[X] Weapon Skill
-[X] Train Your Chapter
--[X] Primary: Ballistic Skill
---[X] Macharius Sicarius
--[X] Secondary: Weapon Skill
---[X] Hannibal Palrun
--[X] Secondary: Agility
---[X] Kaius Jacobus
-[X] Probalis – Chief Librarian
--[X] Scry for where and when the Quasi-Titans will hit the Skitarii lines.
--[X] Equip him with the Hauberk of Faith
-[X]Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary:
--[X] Implant Test-Slaves with 30 Gene-Seed
-[X]Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge:
--[X] 10 Tarantula Sentry Guns (Twin-Linked Lascannons) (100BP)
--[X] 5 Tarantula Sentry Guns (Multi-Melta) (50BP)
--[X] 5 Cyclone Missile Launchers (50BP)
--[X] Improve the Forges Of
---[X] The Litany Of Fury [/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn [50/500]
-[X]Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits:
--[X] Enact Blood Trials upon the planet of Meridian. Orks, tyranids, and Chaos have stripped the fat from their soft flesh. It is time we seek for those amongst them capable of joining the Blood Ravens.

Glory And Blood
+010.M42+
+Death Is Our Duty+

To the immense annoyance of your librarians, and likely the tactical analysts amongst the Guard and Mechanicus, there is no real way to be absolutely certain about the speed or strength of one of these strange masses of metal and warp which come charging out of the metal wilderness. In terms of what they face on the way towards the skitarii lines, in terms of their actual general speed which can be anything from lumbering to ludicrous, it is hard to predict. Worse due to the both chaotic and literal Chaotic nature of the things. And yet as you marshal your forces, both companies present dangerously vulnerable on a world such as this where a dozen plasma or melta weapons may by carried by cybernetic beasts in their dozens, you know no fear. Not simply because of your very nature, but of the fact that the Mechanicus, as their control over the planet increases, see fit to grant it an expanding amount of their effort. The Mechanicus Fleet high above was not of Explorator nature, but they were still of Zerann and bring with them the most sophisticated and most powerful of weaponry and troops that they can bring to bear.

This, in turn, takes the form of not only their incredibly powerful Fellblade tank, but the landing divisions of their Myrmidons and various other things. Two such tremendous pieces of armored death are two of the Macrocarid tanks, each individualized and different from one another to quite an extent. Both, however, are deliverers of complete and total death to whatever they are pointed at. You are personally invited by the Archmagos Prime put in charge of the entire force sent here by your allies in Zerann to view them as they step off of the dropships. The hulking and almost dreadnought shaped and sized Archmagos, named Theodosia and some long string of numbers, cheerfully and more than a little reverently points out not just the Macroarid tanks that come rolling out but whole sections of something you have never seen before. To hear Archmagos Prime Theodosia to tell it, they are called Kataphron Destroyers, and you have never seen more heavily equipped servitors in your life. Finally, behind them, come what Theodosia whispers – or at least tries to do so from within her utterly massive mechanical frame – that while what you see are a small handful of Minotaur Artillery Tanks they are in fact specially enhanced with targeting matrixes to make them her own personal project testing how one might go about defeating Titans from a distance at long range.

All of which is expertly deployed thanks to the scrying efforts of your Chief Librarian, who watches their path and the whims of the warp which draw them like flotsam forth. All the while, you train your brothers, and with Apollo as well. All in preparation for what you know you will face. For all that the last titan was distant and could be torn apart, these are if smaller then somehow more deadly perhaps. They are more dexterous, faster, and have their strange attendant-esque miniature perversions of true machines coming with them. And so you train, all of you, while bringing down every weapon that you can to aid you in the coming fight. In the meantime you fight off what else comes out of Aerus’ unclaimed lands, unpurified territories, and hone your skills there as well.

Then, when the scrap titans arrive at the lines, you see just how powerful the Mechanicus unleashed can be. In a disturbingly growing sense of intelligence and tactical sense, the two titans, some strange mixture between the size of a Reaver and a Warlord, send their slaved attendant false dreadnoughts and knights shifting forward to screen them, while one who has gained more close combat weaponry than the other comes charging to the fore while its ranged companion begins to unleash a vicious if haphazard bombardment upon the skitarii, Imperial Guard, and yes, some of your own lines as well. It is these that take the brunt of the fury of the blessed machines that the Mechanicus controls, and yet they possess their own daemonic powers as well.

One of the knights, uncaring of the damage continually dealt to it, a total lack of void shields apparently never forming upon its frame in favor of his warp-tainted reactor powering yet more weaponry, pushes through all of it. Four of the dreadnoughts die to gunfire, and yet the knight pushes forward to smash through three of the tarantulas only to be blasted apart at point blank range by the Minotaur Tanks firing at its center mass in one moment and both of the Macroarid tanks firing at it as well. All the while, the Fellblade at long range begins to pour fire into the chest of the Reaver Titan. It is one of the heavier armor-based engagements that you have partaken in, in quite a while at the least. Captain Thule leads the dreadnoughts of the 1st Company with him as he tears their mockeries apart at close range, before both you and Apollo lead by jump-pack and teleporter forth against the closer Reaver Titan.

It must also be remembered that they are but one of the threats you fight daily on Aerus. For all that they are false knights, scrap metal dreadnoughts, and daemon-infused mockeries of titans, there are more about that come charging alongside them like vermin escaping water. At the least, of course, many more of the twisted almost skitarii-like creations that have been flowing out of the land before you to come screaming gibberish as they are cut down by the forces assembled against them. But they provide enough of a screen that another of the tarantula turrets are destroyed as it provides cover to one of the 5th Company’s squads that are just barely able to maneuver out of the way against one of the enemy dreadnought creations, a machine dying a violent death to preserve the lives of your brothers. A worthy exchange, you think.

But, for once, the advantage is completely on the side of the Imperium. As eldritch tendrils of metal and gun begin to emerge from the scarred hide of the titan you find yourself on the shoulder of, Apollo destroying all around you, you open the way for Kaius Jacobus to deliver repeated payloads of detonator packs and krak explosives to begin to tear it apart. Such haphazard creations do not even possess a truly enveloping void shielding system, only segments of which that flicker into functionality and out again in the next moment. All the while, your assault troopers fly forth and around it, their increased maneuverability allowing your brothers to rapidly plant and launch explosives at the lumbering beast faster than it can target them all. Some are injured, though only to a minor extent, but most are simply out of the way before they can be struck.

And then comes the Fellblade, relentless in its continual assault on the more distant Reaver, and in point of fact before you can send any of your own forces forth through the distance to assault it and likely sustaining casualties from the machines everywhere, the Mechanicus fires upon it endlessly. First go its legs, and yet it begins to stomp and crawl itself forward on its arms, before its ‘head’ is obliterated as well by the glowing barrels of one of the heaviest and most powerful tanks in the arsenal of mankind. Such bombardment of its still twitching corpse is joined by Basilisk Earthshaker rounds as well as what the Minotaur Tanks themselves are capable of bringing forth. It is truly a display of explosive death as to almost awe even you.

[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 7: 107+6+Apollo(29)=142/800]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill From 4 to 5: 245+44+Macharius(25)=314/500]
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill From 4 to 5: 0+1+Hannibal(25)=26/500]
[Chapter Training – Agility From 4 to 5: 94+7+Kaius(25)=126/500]

==========================================

“Lady Governor,” the mutant hissed, drool dribbling down the chin of the grotesque creature.

Derosa gave none of her inherent distaste for the thing before her away, to the point that she even knew that one of her nearby sanctioned psykers was built wholly and entirely around such a thing. Those who possessed telepathic abilities were prized and despised in the higher echelons of nobility for their utility and potential to bring ruination on any who were left unguarded. But in turn, she merely bowed her head deeply as was befitting such an official who had come before her.

“My friend,” she lied to it, “Thank you for coming in person.”

“For too long,” its body trembled, the flesh weak compared to the inherent potential for insanity in its mind, “We served the traitor Vandis in his efforts, his messages to all, through our astropaths.”

The Adeptus Astra Telepathica and what they could do, and were responsible for, terrified her if she was honest with herself. Their influence unsurpassed by any others she had come up against until this point save perhaps for the Inquisition and the Blood Ravens. And yet it was the Blood Ravens themselves that were responsible for her getting this meeting in the first place. The adept before her had elected to come in person, likely just to get out from who knows wherever it was kept in a cell – she hoped at least – with its small guard of stormtroopers and one black armored and helmeted woman whose very presence had caused Derosa to recoil on sight. An unfortunate failure of her self-control, but the woman was…wrong…in a way that felt even worse to her than the close exposure to the adept before her.

“And yet we have discovered and analyzed the codes within what were but mundane messages otherwise through the warp,” the adept gurgled, before bowing deeply and revealing a series of vellum scrolls and a single dataslate from somewhere in its robes. “And we have felt the echoes of the signals from our brethren who he dragged with him into damnation.”

She felt her pulse quicken.

Did she truly have a chance? Even now, after purges and slaughters and years and the presence of the very Inquisition itself she had those who whispered in the shadows of her world of Vandis, of his return. Sycophants who did not know better, and yet she did not have the strength face as of yet. Someday, perhaps, but not just yet. If she had Vandis’ head on the other hand, then thing would most certainly change.

“The Blood Ravens…,” the adept spoke again as it handed her what might be the most valuable of treasures she’d ever handled, “Bid us welcome, and we bid them success as well. And as you asked why we would aid you in this way,” and then its head tilted and its malformed skull revealed slit eyes, “The traitor Vandis took of our astropaths, and we will not have such disrespect from a worm such as him.”

And then they were gone.

She barely made it back into her chambers, her guards instructed to halt anyone and anything outside which desired entry until she otherwise said so. Her servo skulls flittered around her, and she quickly scanned through what she had been given. Times, dates, names, such things that she had the implants and long experience to handle. For all that she had been his secretary, Derosa had learned likely more about administrative duties than the pompous Chaos-touched fool ever had.

And now, even now, he was using those which he had stolen with him to communicate with who knew what. While the adepts and astropaths did not dare attempt to take upon that knowledge into themselves lest they be corrupted by the very forces that Vandis bargained with, they could still look for them. They could still track them at least in general direction. And it was that, in the end, which gave her that which she had been seeking for so long.

“Cairos,” she murmured.

That unexplored distant realm, left fallow while the Imperium focused on other things, more profitable works, the focusing upon what worlds were already possessed. Was he still there, or were these but echoes? She did not know…but it was more than she had known before.

From there, of course, she allowed other matters to capture her attention for a time. The efforts of the Captain Cyrus upon Meridian had proven a great boon. Whenever a Blood Raven strike cruiser hung itself over her world, things were much quieter. A genestealer cult, from an idiot noble who sought originally to ‘tame’ the tyranids for his menagerie of curiosities, burnt out and the man himself as well as his house put to the flame. Gangers decimated as he sought out recruits. All that and more. Truly, it was a beneficial relationship she held with them, not least of which was the genuine gratitude she held for the ones who had saved her world time and again.

In fact, she could simply inform him here and now of what she had learned.

She had seen Vandis’ vaults. There remained much that had gone unrecovered just yet, both in more mundane things as well as she suspected more artifacts of the astartes. Besides which, it would make a good return of favor for them after the efforts of their Master of Fleets assisting with the reclamation of Toriel. An Agriworld returned to the control of the Imperium would be valuable indeed. She was getting tired of gunning down the food rioters, it was a pointless excursion of her own resources that could be put to use for more valuable things.

009.M42 Into 010.M42 Results:
- Ares Actus is recovered.
- 15 1st Company Veterans recovered.
- 5 5th Company Battle Brothers recovered.
- 20 Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 15 to Neophytes [2nd Stage]. Remainder expired. Gene-Seed Implantation Recommended Soon.
- 2 Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 2 to Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage]. Gene-Seed Implantation Recommended Soon.
- Extremely successful Blood Trials upon the planet Meridian garner the Chapter a large amount of aspirants culled from its gangers, youths, and a few of the sons of Spire inhabitants. +100 Aspirants
- Implant Test-Slaves with 30 Gene-Seed. Harvest To Take Place In 015.M42. -30 Gene-Seed
- Lost 4x Tarantula (Twin-Linked Lascannons)
- Lost 3x Tarantula (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons) of 1st Company equipment roster for Aerus campaign.
- Echoes of signals from the astropaths of Vandis have been tracked to the largely unexplored and untraveled Cairos system.
- Expert thunderhawk bombardments, fire support, and orbital contributions by Hadrian and the Chapter Fleet brought forth at a vulnerable points pointed out to him have allowed the Imperial Agriworld of Toriel to be largely reclaimed as the Hrud are focused on Alanara. Food resources flowing back into nearby Subsectors and worlds have saved literally millions of lives from starvation.
- Strike Cruiser - The Howling Hatred [Former 9th Company Flagship] has been fully repaired and can now be assigned as you see fit.

Aerus Warfare Decisions (65% of Aerus Reclaimed/Reclaimed Area rated as Extremis-grade Defenses By Mechanicus/Orbital Drop,Thunderhawk Transport Allowed Within Reclaimed Territory Due To Lack of Daemon-slaved AA Batteries):
[] Defensive: With the Mechanicus having finally and carefully assembled their might and now just beginning to unleash it, you should keep your brothers behind to patrol and defend what has already been claimed. The amicable Archmagos Prime Theodosia was clearly quite pleased with what you have done so far alongside the Mechanicus, and you believe you can tell that she would not begrudge you this while she exercises her own abilities upon Aerus. Your brothers have been getting injured enough thus far, perhaps some time to properly recover is in order?
[] Supplementary: Now that the Mechanicus has begun to land its own forces in extreme concentrations, led by things such as Fellblades and their more advanced weaponry and troops, they are leading their own expeditions out into Aerus to attack the daemonforges, strike down newly spawned quasi-titans, and generally other such things. In point of fact, they are practically leading the charge with both potency and quantity of forces. You should not allow yourself to be left behind, of course. Why not dedicate your own forces to fighting alongside their own as they go about their work?
[] Independent: Your forces are now fully healed and replenished as best they can be under circumstances. Lead them out once more upon the foe, and strike down those crucial targets beyond what the Mechanicus is fighting themselves. It is an aggressive stance to be sure, but the faster this is done, the faster Aerus will be reclaimed and your Chapter can go beyond what it is currently dealing with. There is more to the galaxy than this sector, is there not? At this point, Marcus has decided that he has led his company independent of your commands more than enough, and his brothers agree. He has more than proven himself, and so now the Blood Ravens upon Aerus shall follow your orders overall as you wish.
- [] Target An Aerus Daemonforge - One of the tainted manufactorums which continually spill out a mixture of random possessed machinery, horrific cybernetic monstrosities, etc. behind the ‘enemy lines’ which are currently fighting against the streaming hordes of Skitarii. (Write-In Forces)
- [] Break Mad Machine Mass, a grouping of insane tanks and armored carriers whose Machine Spirits have gone mad and are traveling as one mass and attacking everyone and everything they can, heading straight for the Skitarii Lines. The latest was slain with minor Mechanicus casualties, and so now the nearest is in the far distance within non-reclaimed Aerus territory. (Write-In Forces)
- [] Attack Abominable Quasi-Titan – Aerus did not have a Titan Legion on its own, but apparently it’s twisted ghosts are determined to produce their own. Out of daemonflesh, rusted cable, and random scrap and weaponry scattered across the land, are titan-sized creatures crafted by mad machine spirits and corrupted programming. They are rare, but especially dangerous. (Write-In Forces)
- [] Another Option - (Write-In)

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] A thought as struck you to negotiate with the Adeptus Mechanicus for use of their manufactorums in some small part of production value much like what you possess in deals with the masters of Angel Forge. Have you not greately contributed to the reclamation of this very world? Are not your brothers, even now, somewhere with one of their Explorator Fleets? (BP/Turn Value Possible To Be Gained Unknown)
[] Now that you know that Aralakh's commanders are at the least somewhat willing to accept the aid of the Blood Ravens due to the sheer casualties they are taking from the Hrud Infestation, you might contribute some measure of your forces to them if you should wish to - Hadrian's rather imaginative application of your orders aside. (Write-In)
[] Recall Brothers In The Deathwatch
- (Specify In Write-In)
[] Hunting Down Vandis - Governor Derosa has been delivered information from the Telepathica, surprisingly enough. Signals bearing his name have echoed out from the Cairos System, which at the moment is a total unknown to you. Perhaps it would be best to send those who can scout properly, in stealth and secret, or maybe he has a bastion there demanding unrelenting force? It is unknown, but as a thief of your own relics, he must be found...and interrogated. (Write-In Forces Sent To Cairos)
[] Assign The Howling Hatred, the former 9th Company Flagship now fully repaired, to the current fleet make-up.
[] A thought as struck you to negotiate with the Adeptus Mechanicus for use of their manufactorums in some small part of production value much like what you possess in deals with the masters of Angel Forge. Have you not greately contributed to the reclamation of this very world? Are not your brothers, even now, somewhere with one of their Explorator Fleets? (BP/Turn Value Possible To Be Gained Unknown)
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.
- You have access to a number of veterans who could impart their knowledge and skills upon your ranks, an especially important thing now that it is likely that many scouts will soon be promoted to full battle brothers. Not just in one way, but more. You have the exceptional battle brothers for it, after all.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 1):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium really does need more, well, Apothecaries. The Companies we have should not be without! Especially on Aerus!
- In 012.M42, 22 Gene-Seed should be available from the Test-Slaves.
- In 015.M42 60 Gene-Seed should be available from the Test-Slaves.
- Gracchus is currently studying the gene-seed of the Blood Ravens, to perhaps improve survival rates for implantation.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (250 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [50/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- I could use a few more peers in the forges. Or at least subordinates.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- While our thunderhawks are not of much use on Aerus at this point in time, they are most certainly quite depleted when it comes to our fleet. In the future, in combat both on the ground and in the void, we should work to ensure that our ships possess them in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Test the 10th Companies latest aspirants and neophytes upon the threats of the Sector
- [] The orks of Caepio, so that the 10th Company remains within the Brutalia System with the rest of the Chapter.
- [] The extremely numerous orks of System A4XX, perhaps even going after the warbosses there.
- [] Hive Gangers, remnant xenos, traitors, cultists, and other such potential things within the planet Meridian to ensure more than simple greenskin experience.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- Vandis is a treacherous wretch, but he cannot be underestimated. Let the 10th Company find him, and hunt him down. A scalpel is needed to cut out his rot, not a hammer.

Assault on Drakenhof, Part 8: Way Back Home

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] The campaign is over, but your duty to Stirland remains. Go home to Wurtbad. Part of you wants to pack up and leave Stirland behind, but pragmatism, duty and sentimentality combine to stop you. You've a base of power, you've a duty to at least see to a proper handover of power, and you've got friends in Stirland, albeit less than when the campaign started. So as the army packs up, you remain with them, technically still in command though there's no orders to give. You do note with some faint amusement that the carts that had delivered food, ammunition and blackpowder have been returning filled with freshly-cut lumber from the sightlines the dwarves cleared to bombard the former Castle; Wilhelmina never misses a trick. The first separation happens almost immediately, as the Third Division remain on the far side of the River Drak to garrison the 'annexed' Drakenhof. You travel with them to see the town that claimed Abelhelm one more time, and oversee the mounting of fifty greatcannon on the walls of Drakenhof - and not all of them facing outwards. The town is not going to fall out of Stirlandian hands without a fight. By the time you return to the bulk of the forces, they're splitting again. The Fourth Division and Schultz are staying behind to garrison and fortify what some are starting to call Abelhelm's Bridge, and some of the dwarves and halflings are staying with them, at least for now. On top of that, a contingent of the dwarves, mostly miners and quarrellers, are striking off south to blaze a trail to Zhufbar through the mountains. You spend a great deal of the next few weeks in the back of a wagon, holding court with the leaders of the forces that remain. You strike a pro tem agreement with the dwarves to delineate where the Haunted Hills end and the World's Edge Mountains begin, to be ratified by the incoming Elector Count, and generally spent a great deal of time reminiscing over dwarvern ale. Narfi is rapt with what he's calling the two greatest artillery campaigns he could have hoped for: bombarding an enemy-occupied town from their own walls, and the utter destruction of a pre-gunpowder castle. Thori has a section copied out of Zhufbar's Book of Grudges for reference purposes and is radiating sublime satisfaction as he makes notes as to how many could be considered Avenged by the campaign, not only against the von Carsteins and their ilk but also a few relatively minor matters they still considered outstanding against the von Draks. All in all, you seem to be getting along fairly well with the dwarves. [Previous Dwarf Rep: +1] [Govibarazak: +2] [Two sublime demonstrations of the power of artillery: +2] [Grudges Avenged: +8] [Adbarazi: Your Oath Fulfilled: +2] [Total: +15] Also occupying you on the long road from Drakenhof to Leicheberg is a side-project with your maps and a pot of glue. Spoiler: Map of Greater Stirland --- When you finally arrive in Leicheberg, most of the combined forces disappear - the Halflings heading home to the Moot, the Throng of Zhufbar to the Zhufbar Road in Southern Stirland, and the Second Division returning to Fort Redemption. In Zipf, the Black Guard of Morr head north to Siegfriedhof, the other Knightly Orders to Talabecland, and the Throng of Karak Kadrin home via Ostermark. It is only the First Division, some five thousand men, that remain for the rest of the trip to Wurtbad. With the good company of the dwarves gone, you spend a lot of time alone with your thoughts as you let your wounds slowly heal on the road to Wurtbad. You were exposed to a lot of information and revelations over the course of the campaign. But there's one thing that stands out above all the rest for you that strikes you as the greatest lesson of the Purge: ONE of the following will become a new trait: [ ] Artillery is the King of Battle. [ ] Dwarves are the greatest ally of humanity. [ ] The Halflings have proven themselves as a worthy neighbour. [ ] If such rank amateurs could rival the strength of an entire Province, imagine what a skilled hand could do with Dhar. [ ] The dead of Sylvania's prehistory deserve an undisturbed rest. [ ] Magic used recklessly has catastrophic effects; great care must be taken in it's handling. [ ] The best battle is one where the enemy never gets a strike in. [ ] The best counterspell is, in fact, a blackpowder projectile to the face. [ ] The Black Guard of Morr were the most dependable human asset across the entire campaign. [ ] Magic is unreliable, gods are doubly so: always have a mundane solution. [ ] It's not a great hero who carries the day, but a lot of small men working in concert. [ ] The fog of war is a bitch, to all involved. [ ] Expertise matters. And Stirland has precious little of it. [ ] Mathematics is universal. [ ] Complex problems, simple solutions. [ ] Unity brings Strength, Discord brings Failure. [ ] Other (write in) But as great an educational experience as the campaign could be considered, it was still a tragedy. There were a great deal of lives lost, and you can't help but brood over everything that went wrong and what could have been done better. As the walls of Wurtbad finally approach, there's one haunting thought that you simply cannot shake. ONE of the following will become a new trait: [ ] In the confusion of battle, even the greatest warrior can lose their life pointlessly. [ ] The Colleges of Magic act in their own interest, rather than that of the Empire. [ ] Sylvanians will meekly accept any tyrant, to the point of complicity in their actions. [ ] The Empire is a morass of self-interest, to the point of becoming a millstone around the neck of humanity. [ ] The Morrite compunction against mutilating corpses is the greatest gift necromancers could ask for. [ ] I, personally, failed to protect Abelhelm. [ ] What use are infantry, if all they can do is die in droves? [ ] Magic is a curse; Magisters and rogue mages alike will eventually die in it's handling. [ ] Sigmar abandoned his most worthy follower in his hour of need. [ ] Gods will not help us. [ ] Mysteries are not worth unraveling - just bury them deeper and call it a day. [ ] You can't trust people to have your back. [ ] I will never meet a man as worthy as Abelhelm was. [ ] Dwarven ale is a valid coping mechanism. [ ] Other (write in) - I've been working on and off on trying to join up the maps of Stirland and Sylvania since the start of the quest, and it's appropriate that I've finally learned enough about image editing to accomplish it now. - I'm allowing Approval Voting - feel free to vote for multiple items, but be aware that only one will win.

Turn 15 - 2477 - A Farewell to Arms

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] The fog of war is a bitch, to all involved. [*] Sigmar abandoned his most worthy follower in his hour of need. Ignorance. That was the greatest enemy and the most potent weapon of the campaign. During the Purge, a great deal of time and effort was frittered away where it wasn't needed because of unknowns. In the assault on the town of Drakenhof, striking quickly and without warning allowed the gate to be captured while wide open, and thus allowed you to take the walls and bombard enemy positions with impunity. You caught the garrison of the Castle napping, and trapped their forces inside by collapsing the gatehouse with artillery fire, where they were pounded for days by mortar and grudge thrower fire. A column of skeletons were found by your scouts moving through underground tunnels, and had the roof collapsed on them for no cost to your own forces; if they hadn't been spotted, they could have appeared where you least expected them and done terrible things to your forces. The Fog Of War. Such an evocative phrase. And who better than a Grey Wizard to master it, to banish it, to weaponize it? [Trait Gained: Warrior of Fog. +2 martial, bonuses to scouting and hidden gambits while in command, unlocks creation of battlefield spells for revealing or concealing troop movements.] But deeper than that is one burning memory that you will never be free of: Kasmir's bleak expression as he prays over Abelhelm's dying body. Sigmar's light does not shine here. Abelhelm and Kasmir are- were- great men. Together they had been giving you a new appreciation for Sigmar and his followers. But Sigmar had ignored the prayers of the latter and let the former die, and now you know that Sigmar is unworthy of the great men that have dedicated their lives to him. You remember Abelhelm's crisis of faith, the trust he lost in the institutions of the Sigmarite church and thus in Sigmar himself. You regret not reaching out to him, leading him to a faith more worthy of him - to a God that wouldn't abandon him. You'll never make that mistake again. [Trait Gained: Disdain for Sigmar. Piety +1, will not allow faith in Sigmar to flourish in the institutions under her control - will do her best to encourage faith in worthier gods, or face a heavy malus while it goes undone.] --- To your extreme relief, word has outrun your slow march to Wurtbad, at least to Anton and Wilhelmina. Both of them look stricken, but are carrying on with their duties nonetheless. First order of business: inheritance. Anton, his voice breaking every now and then, tells you he has left a letter in a drop box that Abelhelm gave him the location of, and he is to await a response. One will be forthcoming, apparently, within a few months, as news filters through the layers of protection around the Van Hal progeny, and then news will filter out once more as to whether said progeny will be making their existence known to the wider world, or whether the world will be allowed to think that Abelhelm's line died with him. For now, you are in limbo, and soon the rest of the Empire will step in to decide a new Elector Count. There's already an Elector's Meet scheduled for midway through the year, so it's likely they'll pick a candidate there, should no heir be forthcoming. Second order of business: Eagle Castle. Mothballed during the campaign, apart from the guards protecting it it has been uninhabited. You make your way through the silent corridors, your footsteps echoing around you, and open the door to Abelhelm's study with the key he gave you so long ago for you to borrow books from him. Slowly, agonisingly, you crate up his belongings and try to fight back memories. Books, trophies, weapons hidden in a dozen different locations, a bottle of the Ostland brandy the two of you would share during your twice-yearly meetings - you pour a glass for yourself, another for Abelhelm's spirit, and drink to his memory. The halberd that was his weapon of choice during his career as a Witch Hunter that was supplanted by his Runefang. A spare hat, hanging from a corner of a bookshelf, that added another foot to the height of an already towering man. The door itself, that once withstood the battering of an ensorcelled berserker as you stood there with Abelhelm in your underthings. You cry a lot in the process of cleaning out that study. Finally, as crate after crate is loaded into a wagon for you to tuck away in your hidden sanctuary until an heir arrives to claim it all, you find the hidden compartment in his desk. You knew it was there from about five minutes after inspecting the desk simply because of the amount of space unaccounted for by drawer depth, but it still took you days to find and you had to cheat by disassembling part of the desk to get at it. But finally it swings open, presenting an empty space about the size of the lead box that holds the Liber Mortis, and at the bottom of it, a letter. Addressed to you. You eventually crack the cipher - it's encrypted using the Epistolary of Kurt III, which Abelhelm recommended to you so long ago - and, you recall, who was the Grand Theogonist who read the Spell of Unmaking from a copy of the Liber Mortis during the Third Vampire War. Dame Weber, If you're reading this, you either succumbed to the temptation inherent in that key I lent you or I've fallen in battle. If the latter, I trust you've avenged me upon whatever entity orchestrated said death. I once told you that I have children; Anton has the details for contacting them, but should he have fallen also, then the experiment can be considered to have failed; let the Elector Counts choose another to sacrifice to Stirland. Likewise, if they are contacted and they respond with letter and not in person, leave them be. I hope to spend my life in lessening the hold of Sylvania over my line, not to strengthen it. Your company has been of great value and comfort to me. Yours, Elector Count Abelhelm Van Hal PS. I hope the books I have given you have been enlightening. The letter was the last blow to your faltering self control, and you spent more time than you care to admit blubbering alone in Abelhelm's study. But the last line itched at the back of your mind. He hadn't given you many books; he had given you a key, and recommended books in his office, but the only book he had given to you was the Liber Mortis. You return to your Sunken Palace and expose the letter to lights of various colours and strengths with the array of mirrors and prisms in your workshop, and find that pure sunlight does the trick, exposing a string of letters. With trepidation, you crack open the cover of the ancient grimoire. The title page, thankfully, is all that is necessary for the key, and you decrypt the string of letters. I am now free. You should be too. Tell your Magister this: And then a string of names, dozens long, each with a set of letters next to them - H-W and H-BM are the most common, but some have L and others vC. Most of them are unknown to you, but three leap from the page: GW M. Regimand Speiseschrank, H-BM GW D. Mathilde Weber, H-BM C. Gabriella v. Bundebad. vC(?) --- The meeting with the EIC Board of Directors is grim, since it consists solely of you and Wilhelmina. Wilhelmina says that she intends to buy out Markus' share of the EIC, and that she has the votes to force it through no matter what the heirs say - some cousins, apparently. She's offered you the chance to split the shares with her as a courtesy. If you accept, it will increase the size of your debt significantly, and you and Wilhelmina will each hold 36% of the company. Otherwise, Wilhelmina will hold 48% and you 24%. Either way, the two of you will have enough votes to overrule whoever the new Elector Count of Stirland turns out to be. She also mentioned that she is going to resign as soon as the new Elector Count takes up his position, and focus on the EIC and trying to rein in her sons. Her loyalty was always to Abelhelm personally, not Stirland. News from abroad trickles in, and Ostermark has apparently concluded its 'campaign' without setting a single foot in Sylvania, contenting itself with clearing the forests around Mordheim. You're less than impressed. Julia reports on her attempt at milking money from gossipmongering; she's broken even, but that's it. You filter through the information she presents to you, both written and verbal, and can't find any indication as to why the profits just aren't there. Infuriating, but at least you didn't lose money in the attempt this time, which means you've ended the war with a scant handful of coins left in your discretionary coffers. Without the burden of the Attachés, you'll be comfortably in the black once more. Jack reports the Watch's mood is acceptable for now, mollified as they were by internal training. The dogs are starting to join the patrols, too. You're currently in a healthy financial position with the Watch, but that was from Abelhelm's perspective. The new Elector Count will most likely take the status quo when he begins as the norm. Now might be the time to spend. It feels surreal. Not long ago you were in this very position and everything was different - there was a war on and Abelhelm was alive. But you will continue on nonetheless. ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIONS - pick ONE from each category. Spoiler: Organizational Actions Information Network - pick ONE (no action expenditure required): [ ] Expand your information network into another province (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into another county or barony (choose one) [ ] Expand your information network into the military (choose a Division) [ ] Expand your Intelligence Attaché program to another Division (choose one) [ ] Open a dialogue with Zhufbar, offering an information exchange. [ ] Off the Leash: Let Julia handle the network without your micromanagement from now on. Information Network finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above. [ ] Gossipmonger: Maybe it was just bad luck. A long streak of bad luck. Maybe this time it will work. [ ] Fixer: Work with the Wurtbad Thieves Guild, supplying them information in exchange for a portion of profits. [ ] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. [ ] Trade Delegation: Convince Wilhelmina to partner your network with the EIC based on the value of market information. Especially likely to work since Wilhelmina will soon be losing her position of power in Stirland's government. (NEW-ish) Stirland Watch - pick ONE (no action expenditure required), currently at +1 Budget Points: [ ] Expand the ranks of the Watch, so that they're able to start covering even the poorer parts of their covered area. (-1 Budget Point) [ ] Expand the Watch into a new county or barony (choose which) (No Budgetary Impact due to expanded Gong Farming) [ ] Expand the Special Branch into areas already covered by the Watch, so you have an additional pool of manpower you can call upon to supplement the full-time Watchmen. (-1 Budget Point) [o] Improve the training of the Watch further, hiring trainers and dedicating paid time each week to sharpening skills (LOCKED until administrative staff acquired) (-1 Budget Point) [ ] Integrate the Roadwarden network of covered areas into the Watch. [ ] Investigate the possibility of adding a River Warden branch of the Watch. [ ] Headhunt administrators from other organizations in Stirland. [ ] Attempt to hire administrators and clerks from Altdorf and Nuln. Stirland Watch finances - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above, will yield an unknown number of Budget Points. [ ] Set up saltpeter production facilities using the information Jack has gathered. (-1 Budget Point) (NEW) [ ] Set up saltpeter production facilities using headhunted experts from Nuln. (-2 Budget Points) (NEW) [ ] Set up saltpeter production facilities and call in favours to bring a dwarvern expert in. (-1 Budget Point, -2 Dwarf Favours) (NEW) [ ] Formalize and organize the payments people make for the Gong Farmers to perform their service, as well as having the Watch start enforcing existing laws against dumping human waste in the street or the Stir. [ ] Currently, solid waste is sent by cart and wagon out to the fields for a pittance. It could instead be used to create market gardens along the banks of the Stir (hopefully downwind) and increase revenue and provide jobs for the desperate by growing a variety of cash crops. [ ] Tanneries have a seemingly limitless demand for urine, which explains a lot about the smell. A bit of fragrant research would allow you to identify how much demand there is and how much of a profit you can wring from this. Stirland Watch faith - can be chosen INSTEAD of a selection from the above, penalty to any Watch actions Mathilde takes unless/until one is taken. Sigmarism must be driven out. (NEW) [ ] Verena is the Goddess of Justice. Enshrine her as the patron goddess of the Stirland Watch. [ ] Shallya is the Goddess of Mercy. An odd choice for the Watch, but it would ensure that they remember their duty to the common people. [ ] Ranald is the God of Thieves, yes, but he's also the God of protecting the common folk. It's worth a shot, right? [ ] Seppel is the Minor God of Vengeance, popular in Stirland. Vengeance is sort of like justice. [ ] Grungni, the principal Dwarf Ancestor God, actually has some following among the Stirlandian populace - and he is their Lawgiver to boot. Bring in a few priests to make it happen. (-1 Dwarf Favour) PERSONAL ACTIONS - CHOOSE BETWEEN FIVE AND SEVEN. ANY CHOSEN BEYOND THE FIRST FIVE WILL COME WITH RISKS - PLEASE SPECIFY THE 'ADDITIONAL' TASK: Spoiler: Personal Actions Aftermath (NEW): [ ] Abelhelm left you with a list of notarized names. Pass them on to your Master and let the fireworks fly. (does not take an action) [ ] As above, but insist on being a part of whatever happens. [ ] It may be a moot point, but you can still send off the entirety of information gathered on undead types in Sylvania to your string-pullers. (does not take an action) [ ] Concentrate the gathered information on undead types in Sylvania into a single dense tome and publish it. It's likely to be of some use and interest to Morrites and Amethyst Wizards. Not ground-breaking, but a nice feather in your academic cap nonetheless. [ ] Buy out half of Markus' shares in the EIC. (does not take an action; increases your debt to Stirland) [ ] Visit the Amethyst Wizards in Altdorf and ask what the hell they were playing at. [ ] Investigate the Valley of the Singing King. [ ] Investigate the underground tomb complex in the southeastern Haunted Hills. [ ] Investigate the very ruined ruins of Castle Drakenhof. Sure, there's several hundred thousand tons of rubble on top of anything interesting, and sure, the only tunnel you found to the castle catacombs was caved in by the dwarves, and sure, even if you do get in there's every likelihood that undead monsters still roam free in there and will eat you, but why not do it anyway? Power Vacuum (NEW): [ ] Your debt to Stirland is recorded in a handful of documents in the Archives, and the current Steward is leaving the position. If said documents were to be slightly altered at the right time, nobody would notice in the handover and your debt could evaporate. [ ] Though the Haunted Hills have always technically belonged to the Elector Count, they've suddenly skyrocketed in value. If you could backdate some purchases from the Elector Count, you could make a killing reselling them, and still retain your own slice of prime grazelands. [ ] There's never been less oversight on spending. Embezzlement now would be impossible to trace later. Scrape up whatever funds can still be found in the treasury, and pocket them. Groundwork - should Van Hal's heir decide not to make themselves known, the question of who would take power is a very interesting one (NEW). [ ] Spend time with Anton, possibly talking about how good a candidate he would be - local support, known to external powers, and a few powerful friends supporting him, and so forth. [ ] Spend time with Gustav, securing his subordination to you. [ ] Spend time with Wilhelmina. As emptied as the treasury of Stirland was by the campaign, the EIC may be the wealthiest institution in the province. [ ] Attend the Elector's Meet yourself, to take any opportunity that arises to manipulate events in your favour. Self-Improvement: Things have been going well so far, but the skills of a Journeyman Grey Mage can only go so far. [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). [ ] Combat Training, In The Free Market: The war cost you your combatant friends, but training is always for sale. Go out and buy some. (-personal gold) [ ] Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln or Zhufbar to upgrade. (will trigger a subvote next turn for what type and how many) (NEW-ish) [ ] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential. And also mud. [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-personal gold) [ ] Diggy Diggy Hole, Dwarf: You could call in some favours and get the entire place cleaned out with dwarven reticence and expertise (-personal gold for ale, -2 Dwarf Favours) (NEW) [o] Filled with Potential: You've got a room cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put there and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) (currently being used as a storage room) Research: [ ] Undead Research: You know the basics, now. Perhaps a great deal of effort will allow you to advance further. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got several gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. [ ] Read the Liber Mortis. (NEW) [ ] Your experience with the so-called Fog of War has given you a lot of ideas for new applications of Ulgu. (NEW) Influence: [ ] Information Network: Work alongside to Julia to administer the network. Choose another Organizational Action for the Network. [ ] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. [ ] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool. [ ] Non-Thief Guilds: Wurtbad, like all major cities, is home to a number of guilds. Reach out to them and enforce your will. Relations: [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with one of your fellow councillors, your liege, or any of the other important figures you've come to know, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one) (can be taken multiple times). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: Trust, but verify. Spend some of your time seeing what a certain person spends their time doing (choose one) (can be taken multiple times). [ ] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (does not take an action) Spoiler: Finances FINANCES LAST SIX MONTHS: Discretionary Income: +200g Information Brokerage: +100g Regional informants: -90g Watch informants: -10g EIC informants: -20g Julia: -30g Townhouse staff: -20g Attaché program: -120g Attempted expansion: -50g --- Net: -40g Personal Income: +50g Estate Profit: +10g Tithe: -6g Student Loans: -35g --- Net: +19g --- COMING SIX MONTHS: Personal Income: 60 gold/turn Discretionary Income: 200 gold/turn Informer Payroll unlocked Currently paying Grey College tithe (-6 personal gold/turn) Currently paying Grey College student loans (-35 personal gold/turn) Not currently embezzling Currently selling gossip (+50 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding regional informants (-90 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding Watch informants (-10 discretionary gold/turn) Currently funding EIC informants (-20 discretionary gold/turn) Currently employing Julia Massif (-30 discretionary gold/turn) Currently maintaining the staff of a townhouse in Wurtbad (-20 discretionary gold/turn) [ ] Begin plumping the informer rolls (choose ratio of real:fake informers. Almost impossible to detect, but also very difficult to increase or decrease the amount quickly) (does not take an action) [ ] Change tithe payment/loan payment/embezzlement (specify)(does not take an action) - Voting will be in Plan Format. If you've got a Cunning Plan regarding the succession, please explain what the plan is alongside the choices you make. - The Elector's Meet will begin at the end of this turn. - You currently have +15 Dwarf Rep. The explanation for how this works and a partial price list is in the Collection of Important Information threadmark. Feel free to ask for price-checks for anything not listed. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing! - There were a lot of balls up in the air and it's possible I missed one - let me know if I did. The Elf Books will come up at the end of this turn. - When the new Elector Count begins, the state of the watch's budget will be the New Normal, effectively resetting Budget Points to 0. Now might be the time to start spending relentlessly. - There would be a great many financial opportunities open to you right now if you were a non-silent partner in the EIC. Might want to consider Financial Jargon. - There are a lot of time-sensitive opportunities you could jump on during this power vacuum, if you're so inclined. Now might be the ideal time for overwork. - EIC shares: your current outstanding debt is 750 gold. Markus' share of the EIC is worth 1500, so if you accept Wilhelmina's offer to join in on the buyout our debt will double.

Turn 15 Results - 2477

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] Plan Protector Of Stirland -[*][Intel] Special Branch: Pull some financial trickery to get the information network classified as part of the Watch, so that their costs are covered by the Stirlandian treasury. -[*][Watch] Expand the Watch into a new county or barony (choose which) (No Budgetary Impact due to expanded Gong Farming) --[*] Drakenhof -[*][Free] Abelhelm left you with a list of notarized names. Pass them on to your Master and let the fireworks fly. (does not take an action) -[*][Personal] As above, but insist on being a part of whatever happens. -[*][Free] It may be a moot point, but you can still send off the entirety of information gathered on undead types in Sylvania to your string-pullers. (does not take an action) -[*][Free] Buy out half of Markus' shares in the EIC. (does not take an action; increases your debt to Stirland) -[*][Personal] Financial Jargon: Everything with the EIC flew right over your head last time. Try again. Succeeding here will mean that you can take a more active hand in the company, adding it to the organizational actions; failing or not attempting means Mathilde will remain a silent partner. -[*][Personal] Practice, Practice, Practice: Having been thrown into the deep end of imperial politics, it would probably be a good idea to brush up on your skills and internalize the lessons you've learned (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective if you've used the trait a lot lately). --[*] Martial --[*] Diplomacy -[*][Personal] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. --[*] Ranald is the God of Thieves, yes, but he's also the God of protecting the common folk. It's worth a shot, right? ---[*]Ranald's Blessing -[*][Overwork] Stirland Watch: Work alongside Jack to administer the Watch. Choose another Organizational Action for the Watch. --[*] Set up saltpeter production facilities and call in favours to bring a dwarvern expert in. (-1 Budget Point, -2 Dwarf Favours) (NEW) -[*][Social] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (does not take an action) --[*] Kasmir --- The expression on your Master's face as you gave him the decrypted list of names on top of the information garnered from Sylvania is gratifying - an instant of complete shock before being replaced by calculation. He opens his mouth to ask a question, then closes it again as his calculations skip ahead. He almost turns into a different person, when he's working for real instead of focused on being your Master, and the glimpses you get used to terrify you and now inspire you. "I want to be involved in- in whatever happens now," you say firmly. "Do you now?" your Master says, his eyes still locked onto the list of names you gave him. "Well, I would hope you're ready for it, because what happens now is a great deal of murder. Of the..." he scans the list. "Fifty-three names here, thirty-nine will die as a direct result of you handing this list to me." Despite all you've seen and done, you're still shocked, but refuse to show it. "Very well. Give me my half." He laughs, and long-dormant reflexes come to the fore as you duck his attempt to ruffle your hair. "Half? Not a task for a journeywoman. I'll be calling in a number of favours to go through the list in a timely manner. But if you insist..." he gives the list another look through. "Here. A peer of yours. Dame Sofia Hoffman, right here in Altdorf." --- You did this a hundred times in your teenage years. Your Master picked a random citizen, and you tailed them for a week or two, learning as much as you could about them and then coming up with plans to kidnap, kill, or suborn them. But you never actually went through with it. You've seen a lot of bloodshed since then, and caused your fair share of it and then some. Cold-blooded murder was not that far from the evils you'd paid unto evil in the past. You remind yourself of this often as you tail the young noblewoman, learning every intimate detail of her life. Her oddly formal and stilted relationship with her husband, her mornings sharing breakfast with young ladies of similar stature in the cafes of upper-class Altdorf, the needlework she's terrible at but perseveres at gamely. Nearly every detail of her life speaks of a normal girl of the middle nobility living a normal middle nobility life. The only missteps in her act are when she takes one of her friends aside for a brief but intense conversation, or the letters she pens in the middle of the night and then leaves wedged in a crack in the brickwork of her husband's manor. You don't even know what crime she's complicit in, save that it snared a Grey Wizard and forced him to send his apprentice to Stirland to act as their catspaw. You spend many days wondering whether that's enough, and in the end, you decide that it is. That, and that this is what Abelhelm knew would happen when he gave you that list of names. Luckily she doesn't share a bedroom with her husband. That would make things difficult. It had been some local festival or another, celebrating Sigmar if you had to guess, and she had partaken rather heavily in Bretonnian wines. There were a thousand different ways you could gain entry, but in the end you opted for walking on thin air up to a third-floor window that had been left open. The house staff were all out enjoying the festival in their own way, and the guards were all at the entrances. The only ones within the depths of the house were you and your target. You walk the halls of the manor like a ghost, pausing to admire the occasional painting. Finally, you reach the bedroom she has ensconced herself within, led by the sound of light singing. You slip silently into the room and observe your target as she tries clumsily to undo the intricate style her hair is bound in, and when she finally spots you in the mirror it's far too late. She tries to shriek, but Ulgu shrouds her in silence for just long enough. She stares at you in terror. "Tell me of your society and of your fellows within it, and you can live," you lie. Thankfully, she's too terrified to deny it. Information tumbles out, and you take mental notes. At first, a social club. Deeper, an organization for the mutual benefit of its members, trading favours in society. Deeper still, odd little rituals that bring luck and favour from frowned-upon Gods, tip-toeing on the edge of blasphemy in a manner designed to thrill, and you frown to hear Ranald mentioned. And deepest yet, the layer this woman exists within: scandalous and titillating rituals to a grab-bag of truly forbidden gods, to Khaine, to Stromfels, to Gunndred and Ahalt. What next, you wonder? Do they take the final terrible step into the worship of Chaos, or is all this designed to filter out those who would balk and drag people deep in before revealing to them their vampiric masters? Or is this a strange hybrid of chaotic and vampiric, or an intersection of two separate societies? Or did one suborn the other? It doesn't matter, not really. The cure is the same. The woman spills names and levels in the cult, and you memorise them eagerly. And as the last name hangs in the air and the woman is babbling pleas for her life, you inhale Ulgu and exhale forgetfulness. The woman freezes, then looks around the room, wiping confusedly at tears running down her face as her eyes slide right by you. She shakes her head and mutters something about wine before coming to her feet and staggering towards the bed, collapsing into it facedown. She's wriggling deeper into the sheets in an effort to get comfortable when your sword slices cleanly through her neck and deep into the mattress below. --- The next day, as the city swarms with alarmed activity at the murder of so many members of high society, you pass on the names extracted to your Master, get a nod of recognition of a job well done, and disappear from Altdorf without any of its citizens knowing you were there. By midsummer, the entire society will be eradicated root and branch, and you will be free of their damned instructions. [Tailing: Intrigue, Req 40, 73+17=90.] [Culmination: Intrigue, Req 40, 66+17=83.] --- When you return to Wurtbad and throw yourself back into work, it's the Stirland Watch that takes up a great deal of your attention. The burgeoning institution deserves better than Sigmar, so you act decisively. Craftsmen are commissioned, priests contacted, and a few holy icons are crafted and consecrated and shipped to every location the Stirland Watch is active in. Almost overnight, a shrine to Ranald the Protector is erected in every Watchhouse in Stirland. And just as quickly, almost all of them are torn down. And there's no witnesses, even when it happened in front of a crowded room. You're incensed, and your response is... less than measured. You order Jack to spread word that if the shrines are not restored and the men responsible for their defacing punished, you'll hold every man in each of the Watchhouses in question responsible. Slowly, sullenly, they obey. The shrines are restored, and men claim responsibility for the vandalism and are stripped of their position and expelled from the Watch. Morale hits a brand new rock bottom, and you doubt that any of the men are likely to embrace Ranald now... but the shrines are there, and they aren't openly revolting. It's a foundation you can build upon. [Enshrining Ranald: Piety, Breakpoints 50/80, 10+17+20(Ranald's Blessing)=47] [Rolling to keep your composure: 35. Composure lost.] [Watchmen reaction: 85. Complete disaster narrowly averted.] --- While the rank and file are dangling on the precipice of mutiny, the merely rank is humming along splendidly. A mid-level chemist has been sent from Zhufbar - why they leave the 'al' off alchemy, you've no idea - and after he performs a few tests to determine the difference between dwarven and human waste, he designs the entire facility from scratch, built outside the western gate of Wurtbad. It takes a great deal of intervention from you to make happen because he has no patience for or knowledge of human business practices, but you're hoping that it will be worth the effort. The initial process, you frown to discover, is not all that different to the methods Jack 'acquired' from Wissenland - business with clay floors and waterproof roofs and a great deal of busy activity over months - but where he shows his mastery is in the purification, a step completely missing from the Wissenland techniques. Filter through wood ash, then boiled and filtered through mesh, and needle-like crystals of pure niter are produced - worth their weight in gold for use as fertilizer or producing gunpowder. Not the prettiest of victories, but you'll take it nonetheless. --- With the factory churning out niter crystals, you turn to the other bizarre and inscrutable alchemy you've decided to master: that of economics. If anything, it's gotten even more difficult to learn as the EIC has grown in size, but you persevere anyway. The part where products are moved around and sold at a higher place where they're needed more, that much you understand, but it is the strange magic of ledgers and banking that eludes you. If you're going to double your debt and become even more interwoven with the EIC, you need to understand it. Eventually, it is magic of all things that allows you to understand it. You are well used to imagining things impossible under the rules of the mundane world, and your mistake with economics was trying to fit what was going on into what you understood of it. Once you started thinking of it as an outcropping of the real world where the normal rules have no sway, it became a great deal easier to start internalizing the bizarre alien logic used to juggle numbers. You wonder if this is what being a Gold Wizard is like. By the time you sign the documents to take on the debt to acquire Markus' stake, you understand the transfer of debt, the mechanisms by which it will be paid off, and the horrific spectre of compound interest that Wilhelmina has spared you from. You go back to the documents outlining your student loan, once completely inscrutable, and after a page of calculations find that you're actually paying off the very last of it now, and after midsummer you'll be freed of it. It's enough to make you feel giddy. You've not quite mastered economics just yet, but it's enough that you'll be able to meaningfully contribute to the EIC. [Economic understanding: Stewardship, Req 70, 89+14=103] --- With your newfound grasp of financial theory, you meet with three key figures in the production of the Memoirs of Asarnil the Dragonlord: Wilhelmina, the publisher selling it within the Empire, and the merchant that agreed to ship it to the elven isle of Ulthuan. "There's a great deal of interest in Stirland, after his contributions to the Siege of Drakenhof," Wilhelmina says. "The only real problem is that most of those interested can't read. Still, it's proven to be quite popular." Your share ends up being a good handful of coin; less than a year's pay, but still a decent handful of coin. You dutifully tithe a tenth of it to the Grey College and add the rest to your coffers at home. "Word did trickle out about events down south," the publisher says to you. "But really, it's Wizard Chic you've to thank for driving up interest in our Elven allies and magical creatures like dragons. Apparently they find it all rather romantic, the centuries-long quest to prove himself against those that cast him out by selling his sword to all the noble races of the Old World." You expected a handful of coin; you get a chest. You worriedly tithe, raising a few eyebrows at the Bursar's Office which leads you to write a report on the whole business to submit to the College, just in case questions start being raised about all this money. "There was barely any interest at all, then the King forbade its sale in Lothern," the merchant chortles to you. "So entire fleets of pleasure craft would sail out to our ships to buy copies before we made port, just for the thrill of it. Then word reached Caledor, and a bloody dragon flew out to buy out an entire shipment." You expect a coffer; you got a crate, and the loan of a wheelbarrow and pair of bodyguards until you found somewhere to stash it. The Bursar is openly staring as you tithe near a year's pay, and you submit receipts and a copy of the memoirs along with the tithe. [Does it sell in Stirland? Roll: 93] [Stirland sales: 44+40=84] [Does it sell in the Empire? Roll: 50] [Empire sales: 84+10=94] [Does it sell in Ulthuan? Roll: 73] [Ulthuani sales: 66-20=46] When you get home to the Sunken Palace, you carefully separate your savings: on one side, what you've saved from your income and the accumulated dragonfunds. On the other, the proceeds of your accumulated embezzlement. Better not to risk tripping yourself up. Seeking to distract yourself from having been too successful, you attempt to reach out to Kasmir. The man was failed by Sigmar just as much as you were, after all. And find, to your shock, that he's nowhere to be found. None of your fellow councillors have seen him, none of the castle guards have seen him. You check the gate records the Watch keeps and find that he never returned to Wurtbad. You reach out through your information network, and get nothing but silence in return. [Finding Kasmir: Intrigue, Req ???: 19+17=36] --- With that attempt at self-distraction failed, you turn to memory. The campaign was a fantastic trial by fire for your nascent career as a general, after all, and you want to capitalize on that. Time is spent with the General of the First Division, whose name you'll certainly get around to remembering one of these days, as well as delving through the books that Abelhelm left behind. Scraps of information you would have skimmed past before become vital in the light of what you learned. The Purge of the Haunted Hills and the Sieges of the Drakenhofs were campaigns full of great victories and terrible failures, and you seek to learn from every one of them, both under Abelhelm's command and your own. [Martial: Breakpoints 30/70, Roll: 56. Martial +2] [Diplomacy: Breakpoints 50/90, Roll: 72. Diplomacy +2] It's when you're lost in your reminiscing that word is passed through your network and the innkeeper you befriended so long ago knocks on the trapdoor to your Sunken Palace: Anton is looking for you. --- "Is that-" you begin, looking at the letter in his hands. "It is!" he says. You're in the council room, despite it being abandoned to dust. He insisted. Wilhelmina, Gustav and Schultz have also been summoned, but Anton is apparently as clueless as to Kasmir's location as you are. "So what does it say?" you press. "I haven't opened it yet," he admits. "I wanted to wait until everyone was here." "Close enough," you say, with nods from the others, and Anton buckles and slides his knife under the wax seal of the letter. [Will Abelhelm's heir take up the mantle?] [Base: Req 50. Inglorious death, +20. Campaign completed, -10. Letters to them spoke well of his councillors, -10. Result: 50/50.] [Die Roll: 98] Anton's mouth moves as he reads through the document. "Out loud!" you hiss at him, and he nods and returns to the start. "To the Council of Stirland. I will be arriving forthwith to continue my father's legacy. Yrs - it says 'yrs' instead of yours - R v Hal." There's exhales all around. "Laconic," you note. "They can be mute, for all I care," Wilhelmina muses. "I honestly didn't think that one of his children would take the role. I might have to rethink my resignation." "Might not have a choice," Schultz notes. "New Elector Count, new council." "Best foot forward, it's time for interviews," Gustav says, to strained chuckles all around. --- As midsummer, the Elector's Meet, and the arrival of the new Van Hal approach, you check in with your underlings. The expansion of the Watch into Drakenhof is hampered threefold: by the truculence of the Watchmen, by the size of the town, and by the low-level hostility between Stirlanders and Sylvanians. Jack reports apologetically that if he has another six months he can guarantee that Drakenhof will be brought under the control of the Stirland Watch. Julia and Jack have worked together to bring the Information Network payroll onto that of the Stirland Watch, finally relieving your strained discretionary budget from carrying the entirety of the ever-growing Network. The result would be painful for the Watch's budgetary impact under normal circumstance, but without an Elector Count it goes gloriously uncommented upon. You consider preparing a report of your activities to date for the incoming Elector Count, both to fill them in and make a good impression to retain your position. You've built quite a power base here, but with your string-pullers being utterly devastated by your Master (mysterious deaths are still being reported) and your loans almost paid you wonder if you even want to continue as the Spymistress of Stirland. Report for the incoming Elector Count: [ ] You'll not beg for your own job. No report. [ ] Sketch out in broad strokes your activities over the past eight or so years. [ ] Write a detailed report covering every major operation you performed under Van Hal's orders. [ ] Write in. Your attitude towards retaining your position: [ ] You will serve the heir of Abelhelm as you did Abelhelm himself. [ ] Even if you do not continue as Spymistress, perhaps you could find another job on the Council. Your talents have flourished since you arrived in Stirland, and you could perform near any of them satisfactorily, thanks to Stirland's lowered standards. [ ] If they wish you to retain the position, very well. If not, that's fine too. You do not feel strongly one way or the other. [ ] You will make sure there's a secure handover of power, brief your successor, attend the long-delayed funeral of Abelhelm, and then finally give up the burden of Spymistress. You've also got to consider your financial windfall. The Grey Order is yet to comment, but their gears grind slow but fine and this is too much for them to ignore. They'll soon ask pointed questions as to which of the cavernous loopholes in the Grey Order's Vow of Poverty you'll be shoving the funds through. [ ] All but eliminate your debt from the EIC purchases. [ ] Inject into your Discretionary Fund. [ ] Label it a Rainy Day fund, deposit it in the Grey College's coffers, and withdraw it at a later date when liquid funds are needed. [ ] Donation to some institution (choose one) [ ] Improve your land near Sonningwiesse. - [ ] Improve the arms and armour of the local populace for when they are called as militia. - [ ] Rebuild the local manor house, complete with fortifications to shelter the locals should danger threaten. - [ ] Closely investigate the area for any mineral wealth. - [ ] Build farms and import farmers to compliment the herdsmen. - [ ] Other (write in) [ ] Other (write in) Finally, as the day that your new boss arrives approaches, word reaches you from Altdorf. The Elector's Meet, originally called to discuss the possibility of Imperial contribution to the Dwarven reconquest of Karak Eight Peaks, has turned completely from that to address the growing crisis between Middenland and Nordland. Entire towns between the rivers Salz and Demst have been razed to the ground with their populace disappeared, and though no evidence is present Nordland is accusing Middenland, who in turn neither claims nor denies responsibility, but instead are once more accusing Nordland of stealing land they have no claim to. The Elector Counts near came to blows in the Meet, with the Ar-Ulric and the Grand Theogonist almost following suit as they backed their respective sides. The Empire seems to teeter on the brink of civil war, as the Elector's Meet stretches on and the Emperor tries to soothe tempers. Belegar Ironhammer, heir to the throne of Karak Eight Peaks, has abandoned Altdorf in disgust and is calling for any who seek their fortune to join him. Skill Acquired: Economics (Advanced) Memoirs of Asarnil the Dragonlord - Stirland sales: +76g Memoirs of Asarnil the Dragonlord - Empire sales: +423g Memoirs of Asarnil the Dragonlord - Ulthuan sales: +792g Total: 1,291g Skill Increase: Martial +2 Skill Increase: Diplomacy +2 Trait Lost: Student Loans Motivation Lost: Sleeper Agent Spoiler: Finances Discretionary Income: +200g Information Brokerage: +50g Julia: -30g Townhouse staff: -20g --- Net: +200g Personal Income: +50g Estate Profit: +10g Tithe: -6g Student Loans: -35g --- Net: +19g - It was possible to redeem Ranald the Protector in this way. But trying to do so with Mathilde's motives compromised and the Watch's morale already low was risky, and then the roll was flubbed. Things only narrowly avoided being even worse. Still, nothing ventured, nothing gained, and all that. - The plan for the funds doesn't need to begin immediately, but should you choose one then the funds will be earmarked for that and you should probably show some progress towards it in a timely fashion. - There is no wrong choice as to whether you continue as Spymistress or whether you find another path. Despite the title, this is the story of Mathilde Weber, whether she is an advisor or not.

A Fateful Meeting

Spoiler [*] Sketch out in broad strokes your activities over the past eight or so years. [*] Even if you do not continue as Spymistress, perhaps you could find another job on the Council. Your talents have flourished since you arrived in Stirland, and you could perform near any of them satisfactorily, thanks to Stirland's lowered standards. [*] Plan Dame Weber -[*] Improve your land near Sonningwiesse. --[*] Rebuild the local manor house, complete with fortifications to shelter the locals should danger threaten. --[*] Closely investigate the area for any mineral wealth. --[*] Build farms and import farmers to compliment the herdsmen. You sketch out your plans for investing the money in the lands of House Weber, building a protective keep and investigating the mining and farming possibilities that the treacherous land may yield, and because this is officially official business instead of the playful parry and thrust of your relationship with your Master, you seal it with your coat of arms and send it to the Grey College by post. You receive no response from the Bursar; or to put it another way, their lack of response is, itself, a response. You've no doubt they'll be checking up on you to make sure you follow through on your plans for the wealth. It's something of a reassurance to bring your lands to the attention of the Grey Order and to receive no censure for it, glad that your separation of Journeyman Weber from Dame Weber was accepted. The Vow of Poverty is easily sidestepped with a hundred possible excuses, but that just means they come down all the harder when someone flouts it. Also put to paper is a summary of your activities over the past eight years, which leads to quite a bit of reminiscing on your part. The trouble with your predecessor, the raid on the Mound, the retrieval of the Stirland Archives, the elimination of the former Count of Leicheberg. The founding of your Intelligence Network, the rounding-up of infiltrators in Eagle Castle (the details of which are very much left out), the revelation of the so-called Elector Countess, and the rolling mass arrest of the Stirlandian League and the seizing of their assets, which led to your Knighthood. The founding of the Stirland Watch and its expansion underground, and then the Purge, a year and a half of bloody battles and minimal oversight. And then, capping it all off, the Siege of the Drakenhofs. One annexed, one obliterated. Near a decade of your life spent thusly, and with all you've achieved and learned that you wouldn't have if you'd followed the traditional career arc of a Wizard... you find that it was well worth it. You and your fellow councillors gather in the hall of Eagle Castle, where you first met Abelhelm all those years ago, and looking much the same as it did since it's seen little use these past two years while everyone was off on the Purge. Anton is practically bouncing on his feet, he's so nervous, and it seems that he's the only one nervous about keeping his job. Wilhelmina is on the brink of resignation, Schultz has been bemoaning his work on field fortifications and roads instead of the glorious fortresses he imagined, Gustav let you of all people take the lead on the assault on Drakenhof and has been lost in thought whenever you saw him ever since, and Kasmir remains absent. You would like to continue as Spymistress, but you'd also fancy your chances trying any of the other positions, or shutting yourself away in your Sunken Palace for a while and getting to work on a hundred different projects that have been gathering dust for years, or going back to Altdorf and finally going for your Magister rank, or even answering the call of Belegar Ironhammer and venturing beyond the borders of the Empire. Those and hundreds of other possible roads are open to you, all of them enticing, and that you can only take one of them is galling. You wonder about the person you're to meet, this 'R v Hal'. You don't even know for sure if it's his eldest child, or merely the one that decided to answer the call. Abelhelm said that his wife died in childbirth in '66, so they must be at least eleven, but could be as old as... early twenties, you suppose? Depends how young Abelhelm was when he fathered them. Surely not as old as you. Surely. Finally, the gate guard gives the signal that Anton convinced him to pass on and Anton quickly shuts the door he had been peeking through. "They're here!" he says excitedly. You give yourself a final once-over, despite wearing the same robes and hat and sword you always do. First impressions count, after all. After a moment that stretches for an eternity, the door swings open, and for a heartbreaking instant you think Abelhelm has returned. Then your senses return, and you study the Witch Hunter that stepped through the door and is scanning the room; shorter than Abelhelm, more scarred, older. Not his ghost returned, and not his heir, either. A bodyguard, perhaps. The man gives you an extra-hard stare, but steps aside allowing the entrance of another. Tall, but thin, her hair short-cropped and looking unsuited to the leathers that she wears. Late teens, early twenties, if you had to guess, with a sword on her hip and carrying herself with the awkward over-awareness of someone who has yet to grow into the instincts of combat. You glimpse fear and doubt in her eyes, but kept at bay by a will of iron. "I," she announces, "am Roswita van Hal. The Elector Countess of Stirland." Anton is the first to introduce himself, bowing to her and almost stuttering over the ritual greeting of nobility, but she returns his bow with an inclination of her head. Gustav is next, and you can see from his expression that he's weighed her up just as you have and found her wanting, but he too knows the rituals and speaks them flawlessly. Schultz is next, and presents himself as the skilled craftsman he is, with deference but not obsequiousness. Then you step forward, dredging up the ritual from Anton's lessons to you so long ago; Mathilde Weber of Stirland, at your service, and a bow. Wizards and knights alike bow, rather than curtsy. She follows through on the courtesies, her eyes on you the entire way through, reconciling you with the character from her father's letters, perhaps. [Among a great many rolls to generate her attributes and attitudes:] [Her attitude towards magic-users: Roll, 9.] Then she steps outside the formality of the greetings. "My father spoke well of the service you provided him," she says, her voice stilted and formal. "I thank you for this, and will provide you with a glowing letter of recommendation. It may be that the curse of magic you labour under is undeserved. Nevertheless, I will not take the chance, and release you from your service to Stirland." Your eyes narrow as you stare back at her wordlessly, and she leans away from you as the silence stretches, nervousness growing in her eyes. But then you incline your head. "As you wish," you murmur. --- The report you had written weighs heavily in a pocket inside your robes as you walk from Eagle Castle, perhaps for the last time, as your mind ticks over, swinging between duty and vengeance. You've got the report, you've got the intelligence network, you've got the Liber Mortis, you've got the sodding Runefang. You've the entire contents of Abelhelm's study gathering dust in your spare room. Any sensible candidate would have waited, but no, she's got a headful of Sigmarite rubbish and thinks that every second in a magic user's presence is a danger to her very soul. You realize through your warring thoughts that someone's calling out to you, and find Anton running up behind you. For an instant you think that the girl's changed her mind and sent him as a runner, but Anton catches his breath after a moment. "I resigned," he says, outrage warring with exhaustion in his voice - it's barely a minute from the castle, he needs to work on his fitness - "I'll not be having with that." You smile at him, remembering what you found so long ago while rifling through his things: the letters written in secret to his aunt in the Jade College, long since slain in the service of the Empire. "Thank you," you say simply, and the two of you walk down the road from Eagle Castle into the town of Wurtbad. [TITLE LOST: Spymistress of Stirland] --- Report on the past eight years -[ ] Keep -[ ] Give The Runefang of Stirland -[ ] Keep -[ ] Give Abelhelm's repeater rifle -[ ] Keep -[ ] Give Liber Mortis. -[ ] Keep -[ ] Give Miscellaneous contents of Abelhelm's Study -[ ] Keep -[ ] Give Information Network -[ ] Keep -[ ] Give Gong Farmers and Niter Factory -[ ] Keep -[ ] Give Discretionary Funds -[ ] Keep -[ ] Give Where will you call home now? [ ] You're quite comfortable where you are, thank you very much. Wurtbad is your position of power; Spymistress was just one arrow in your quiver. [ ] Good riddance to Wurtbad; you've got a nice bit of land up in the hills and a commitment to invest in it, and some solitude will do you good. Lock up the Sunken Palace in case you ever need a safehouse in the future. [ ] There's another way to secure Abelhelm's legacy. Travel to the town of Drakenhof and sink your claws into it. [ ] Anton's as unemployed as you are. He'll be happy to let you crash at his place, and 'his place' is his father's castle so there's plenty of room. [ ] Put Stirland behind you. The rest of the world is waiting to be seen, and your land and investments will keep. And what will you be doing? Staying in Stirland: [ ] Enjoy a well-deserved holiday catching up with personal projects and living off your accumulated embezzlement. [ ] Managing your institutions - the EIC, your land, and the Information Network and Gong Farmers if retained. [ ] Other (write in) Leaving Stirland: [ ] That blasted girl will likely follow through on that letter of recommendation. Send words to the Elector Counts, see if anyone's got a spot in their council for a Grey Wizard. [ ] Hang about. Why bother with that lot? Send word to the Dwarfholds instead. Maybe one of them could use a councillor. [ ] Belegar Ironhammer's call to arms is open to all. It's not the most traditional vacation choice, but you're not the most traditional vacationer. [ ] Traditionally, a Journeywoman journeys, flexing their arcane might and seeing the world. Find Asarnil and seek instruction in the fine art of being a mercenary - one that only serves the Empire and its allies, of course. [ ] Other (write in) Either: [ ] Return to Altdorf to face the Magister's tests, and determine what to do with your life later. --- - It's almost as if there's inherent flaws with the concept of inherited power. The heir hates and distrusts magic and there's no way they'll have a magic-user on their council at all, and that's that. I know this will upset some people, but this was a possibility inside the universe that Mathilde lives in, and dice are the medium to determine whether it occurred. - Leaving Wurtbad means that Ranald's Blessing will linger for about a year before fading; you'll have that much time to create a new holy place to him. - If the Information Network is retained, you have enough personal funds to keep it paid for about half a year, then you'll have to find a new source of income. The Watch cannot be extricated from the grip of Stirland, not with how little loyalty the rank and file hold towards you, but you can pull the gong farmers and the niter factory from it. - Voting will be in plan format, due to how interconnected things are.

Turn 15: To Rise From Ash And Blood

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[X] Plan Let's Get This Done!
[X] Supplementary: Now that the Mechanicus has begun to land its own forces in extreme concentrations, led by things such as Fellblades and their more advanced weaponry and troops, they are leading their own expeditions out into Aerus to attack the daemonforges, strike down newly spawned quasi-titans, and generally other such things. In point of fact, they are practically leading the charge with both potency and quantity of forces. You should not allow yourself to be left behind, of course. Why not dedicate your own forces to fighting alongside their own as they go about their work?
-[X] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes ,Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun
-[X] Chapter Master's Honor Guard
-[X] 1st Company
-[X] 5th Company
-[X] Land Raider Phobos Litany of Purgation, Land Raider Crusader Tarantulus Ultima, Vindicator, 2 Whirlwind, 2 Razorback (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons), 1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Plasma Guns) [+Lascannon], 2 Predator, Predator (Twin-Linked Lascannons), 4 Rhinos, 3 Razorbacks (Twin-Linked Heavy Bolter), 3 Landspeeders, 2 Landspeeders (Tempest)
-[X] All Tarantula Sentry Guns
-[X] Permanently Assign Iron Halo'es to Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Marcus Crixus, Tarkus Varianus.

[X] Gabriel Angelos – Chapter Master
-[X] A thought as struck you to negotiate with the Adeptus Mechanicus for use of their manufactorums in some small part of production value much like what you possess in deals with the masters of Angel Forge. Have you not greately contributed to the reclamation of this very world? Are not your brothers, even now, somewhere with one of their Explorator Fleets? (BP/Turn Value Possible To Be Gained Unknown)
-[X] Now that you know that Aralakh's commanders are at the least somewhat willing to accept the aid of the Blood Ravens due to the sheer casualties they are taking from the Hrud Infestation, you might contribute some measure of your forces to them if you should wish to - Hadrian's rather imaginative application of your orders aside.
--[X] Have Librarians (and Codicier Nero if he available) search for where Hadrian can do the most good with the Fleet, without too much risk. If the results are inconclusive, Hadrian should use his best judgement

-[X] Hunting Down Vandis - Governor Derosa has been delivered information from the Telepathica, surprisingly enough. Signals bearing his name have echoed out from the Cairos System, which at the moment is a total unknown to you. Perhaps it would be best to send those who can scout properly, in stealth and secret, or maybe he has a bastion there demanding unrelenting force? It is unknown, but as a thief of your own relics, he must be found...and interrogated.
--[X] Captain Cyrus Octavius, Brother Kaius Jacobus, Codicier Nero Achillian
---[X] Use Nero's farsight to assist
----[X] Assign Gift of the Seraphim to Kaius Jacobus
--[X] Tenth Company
-[X] Assign:
--[X] The Howling Hatred to Tenth Company Fleet
--[X] Brother Hamul to First Company (Company Champion)
---[X] Give Hamul the Flesh Tearer's Pride and the Pistol of Baal
--[X] Chaplain Uther to Honor Guard (Chaplain)
--[X] 4 First Company Veterans to Honor Guard

[X]Training With Apollo
-[X] Weapon Skill
[X] Train Your Chapter
-[X] Main: Ballistic Skill
--[X] Macharius Sicarius
-[X] Secondary: Weapon Skill
--[X] Apollo Diomedes
-[X] Secondary: Agility
--[X] Kaius Jacobus

-[X] Probalis – Chief Librarian
--[X] Scry for optimal position of Chapter and Mechanicus forces

[X] Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary
-[X] Implant second stage Neophytes and Psyker Neophytes with gene-seed (17 gene-seed)

[X] Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge
-[X] 5 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Hyperion AA)(50BP)
-[X] 5 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons) (50BP)
-[X] Improve the Forges Of
--[X] The Litany Of Fury [50/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn (150BP)

[X] Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits
-[X] Lead the Tenth in the search for Gregor Vandis

To Rise From Ash And Blood
+010.M42+ To +015.M42+
+Our War Is Eternal+

“And that,” Theodosia booms, “IS THAT!”

Atop the Last Scream Of Aerus, as the now shattered Imperator-sized mass of warp touched scrap metal and machinery had been named, the vaguely dreadnought shaped Magos Prime cuts an admittedly imposing figure. Or perhaps it is the multiple tons of hyper advanced weaponry that bedecks her frame that is what could be more intimidating to the foes of mankind. To be sure, the fact that multiple missile launchers, assault cannons, plasma calivers, heavy flamers, and a greater number of weapons that you know not the names for is also likely to do the same. She whirls, somewhat slowly, to face you with the great bulk of her metallic figure, pneumatics hissing under the weight of her weaponry and armor, and though you cannot actually see any part of her that resembles a face anymore amidst all the weaponry she sounds cheerful.

“CHAPTER MASTER!” she greets, “A GLORIOUS BATTLE IN THE NAME OF THE OMNISSIAH!!!”

“Indeed,” you answer with a comparatively much quieter response. “With this, the last of Aerus has finally been pacified.”

Five years. Five years of grueling battle. You had fought alongside the Mechanicum throughout them all, space marines shedding blood alongside the servants of the Omnissiah, and witnessing such things as you have never before. A greater abundance of advanced weaponry you have rarely seen, only to be matched by the necron and eldar. Conversion weaponry, grav guns and plasma fusils and plasma blasters, and far more. You witnessed the Baneblade of Zerann brought onto the field to join it’s Fellblade cousin, both of which dwarfed the two land raiders that fought alongside them all the same. If anything, it was almost humbling to be but aid in a war against a maddened world while the Mechanicus led the way.

And yet, even then, not all had been successful. Blood Ravens had fallen, not just injured but brought to a point beyond the ability of a dreadnought to preserve. Dozens and dozens of tanks have been irreparably lost, melted to slag. The 1st Meridian Consolidated, at the end of five years, has been reduced to a mere ¼ of its original strength. Those that remain are hard-bitten veterans of a fight wherein combat was daily, who have scoured themselves of traitors and mutating brethren time and again with the aid of your own brothers, that of your Chaplains and their priests. But from that core of veterans shall come, in time, a greater whole than there was before. It is something to perhaps take some heart in. Unlike Isador, without hope for mankind, you know that it would have fallen long ago.

“AS TO YOUR REQUEST,” Theodosia stomps from side to side, the sheer size of her form making even simple pacing a rather thunderous affair, “…I ACCEPT YOUR REASONING! IT IS LOGICAL!”

Then a great scattering of binary booms out from her various speakers, and a servitor that would be wholly clerical based on its onboard equipment save for the multiple gun-limbs sticking out of it to accompany its pen and parchment trundles forth on treads. With a vague amount of ceremony, it jerkily bows to both you and Theodosia before scrawling out a rather lengthy amount of text upon its sheaf in what appears to be alternatively be black oil, blood, or both. After a few moments, the rest of your Chapter assembling in the background to observe as you stand atop the corpse of the titan alongside the leader of the Mechanicus on this world, it finishes.

“FOR YOUR AID, BOTH IN FORCES CONTRIBUTED,” and here she lowers her voice to a mere shout, “As well as consistent near-personal sacrifice of your greatest of champion and yourself,” and then she scales back up to bone-rattling volume, “SO SWEAR I, ARCHIMANDRITE OF ZERANN 52X1 AND ARCHMAGOS PRIME AND NOW DECLARANT RULER FABRICATOR GENERAL OF AERUS, THAT A PACT IS FORGED IN OIL AND BLOOD AND BROTHERHOOD BETWEEN FELLOW SEEKERS OF KNOWLEDGE AND DESTROYERS OF TECHNO-HERESY!”

Then, to your utter bemusement, the tiniest and most delicate of handling appendages comes from a slot just beneath one of her still smoking assault cannons to take up the quill and sign upon the last portion of the newly written treaty before offering it to you. In turn, you do the same, and once complete the entire sheaf is rolled up and presented to you with another jerky bow of the servitor that then retreats. With that completed and done with, the now apparently Fabricator-General of Aerus turns back to you, some of her weapons now slowly receding into the depths of her behemoth body.

“You shall taste of my forges until time such as our pact is broken, or our world destroyed,” she says with such suddenly calm and quiet words that your still ringing ears need a moment to register them. “How can I do anything less for ones who have aided us so well? Just LOOK AT THIS GRAVITON CANNON,” she suddenly booms, and then said weapon abruptly emerges from her chassis, and she wriggles it slightly.

“I thank you, Fabricator-General Theodosia, for your benevolence in this matter.”

“YOU ARE WELCOME!”

As she turns to leave, she then suddenly swings about once more.

“Ah,” she murmurs, which for her equates to somewhere between a shout and a raised voice, “You are aware that my world, long ago, once supplied weapons to the Legions of the Great Crusade?”

“…yes?”

“Your Master of Forges, Martellus, I have heard his charming devotion to the machine whenever he descends to maintain or take with him his for turrets for repair,” she stomps a bit closer almost conspiratorially, “I would grant him something, if he desires it.”

“Oh?” you lean back slightly so that she does not brain you with her various weapon emplacements.

“We have discovered for ourselves two small caches of the noble Rapier mobile weapons platform, amidst the ruins as we went about our repairs. They were,” she growls, “Nearly destroyed when we reached them, and already we have found signs of more advanced things being lost as we advanced together across Aerus, but no matter!”

She looms over you.

“For your service, your aid, and in respect of the one who shows such devotion and care to the machine, I would grant you access to one of them.”

You have honestly never heard of the things, which is certainly a rare occurrence for you. Even so.

“I thank you once more, Fabricator-General,” you bow your head.

“I HAVE BEEN GRANTED MY OWN FORGEWORLD, Chapter Master,” she chortles which sounds extremely disquieting as it emanates from her speakers, “A WAR TO KEEP IT, LIKELY A WAR TO KEEP IT PURE. WHAT MORE COULD A MAGOS PRIME WANT FOR?”

=================================
[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 142+39+Apollo(29)=210/800]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill From 4 to 5: 341+99+Macharius(25)=465/500]
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill From 4 to 5: 26+42+Apollo(29)=97/500]
[Chapter Training – Agility From 4 to 5: 94+49+Kaius(25)=168/500]

The return to the Omnia Arcanum is a joyful one, to be sure. For five years your brothers have been on Aerus, and now may return to their quarters outside of the aesthetic of Aerus. They may return to consecrated shrines in your ships, receive and confess to the Chaplains in the proper places, and allow their arms and armors to be truly cleaned of the filth and grime put onto them by the constant battling of warp-corrupted machinery and its cybernetic monstrosities. Yet there is no rest for the Angels of Death in any long-term sense, as you sit in your own quarters and slowly go through the information that has been collected for you by your leadership. Training will continue regardless, and does so as the newfound experience upon Aerus is further refined within the minds and hearts of the Blood Ravens.

The Hrud Infestation has been defeated, and the worlds now reclaimed. Many a Magos Biologis and members of the Eccelsiarchy have been called to bless the soil and cleanse it of whatever it is that the Hrud leave behind them as well as lead and assist in reconstruction efforts of the colonies. A moderate amount of that success is due to the sophisticated weaponry that your ships possess in terms of orbital support which certainly outweighed the less accurate and less powerful weaponry possessed by the Imperial Navy which allowed the Guard to advance further and further against the Hrud. That is not to say that things were not fierce in their fighting, of course,

That stalwart man, consistent ally of the Imperium and the Blood Ravens, Colonel Merrick, was aged into almost right into retirement by the vagaries of the Hrud’s monstrous entropic field before finally disappearing on a particularly violent battlefield. Indeed, much of if not all of the 85th Vendoland has been rendered dead or useless, all aged to a point of combat ineffectiveness. Many of them have died of now age related causes, such as heart failure or dementia or simply in their sleep, and those that remain are now most certainly retired on the worlds they fought and died to save. Colonel Merrick himself on the other hand, has not been seen since his disappearance as he plunged into the heart of a hrud formation at the biological age of 107 years old while carrying an entire heavy bolter by himself against them.

He will be remembered. For all that he was no space marine, he fought with skill and strength against forces that would have destroyed lesser men and indeed slew many a space marine besides. Against Chaos, against the Tyranids, against Orks and Eldar as well, he fought and lived. There are still stories told by Tarkus and Cyrus of the brave Imperials who braved the heart of the tyranid-held territories of Tython Primaris alongside them. That they were brought down by the Hrud, so many to but age and time rather than battle itself is enough to bring a rage even to you, for such an ignoble end to so many noble men and women. It is that, surely, the threat of dying in a bed with the skin sagging off of him, which drove Merrick to lead that charge despite the effects upon him it would surely cause. That his final charge broke the Hrud and sent them into retreat is but one more accolade to surely be heaped upon him. As a gift from the last of the 'Crazy Riders' who were still in possession of their senses and not so old as to be entrapped within abodes for those of their advanced age, did they in what is perhaps an almost insane amount of fatalistic devil-may-care secrecy gift unto your Chapter some of their secretly looted weaponry of the Hrud, a handful of the mysterious and highly prized Hrud Fusils, which would have if sold to those who slaver over them such as the Officio Assassinorum and the Inquisition surely provided an extremely wealthy retirement for the entire now retired regiment.

As for Vandis, that treacherous blight upon your Chapter, thief of your relics, and likely secret aid to Kyras in his time of corrupting the Chapter, Cyrus sets out with an almost feral eagerness to slay him. The 10th Company, accompanied by a small number of others, slipped into the Subsector Carios where the latest signs of his presence had been found. A largely unexplored area of space, your brothers act not only as hunters but almost as cartographers of all three of the star systems within the Subsector. Within the Pharos system, they find a series of mostly dead worlds, where no life ever evolved. Yet cautious is Cyrus, that he endeavored to investigate them to ensure that they are not heralds of, say, necrons hiding beneath. To his credit, he scoured the system, and while he found the faintest of trails of ships that had passed through, none were of human design. Rather that of orks, in truth, as well as others that were not readily identifiable. Already, though, squabbling has begun over who gets the rights to the mineral wealth present on those worlds, or at least prospecting, between the Mechanicus and the various Imperial powers within Sector Korianis.

It was in the Faiyuum system that near-disaster struck. The 10th Company was flying through the quiet star system, noting a Feral World with a reasonable human populace for others as well as a gas giant and other such things, when they were attacked from nowhere. Eldar corsairs, bearing the black edges and unique weaponry used by those known to you as the Dark Eldar, the 10th Company lost two of its escort ships before Cyrus was able to locate the actual location of the attacking enemy vessel and boarded it with the whole of the 10th Company. Some were lost, others were not, as they fought in the shadows and holo-fields natural to the infuriating xenos. In the end, however, he was successful, if only after another frigate was brought down with all hands lost. The 10th Company refused to cease their search, however, though they then played a deadly game of cat and mouse with other such vessels throughout the star system. Apparently, they have been using the unnamed Feral World below as their own personal playground of terror and pain to feed off of while holding an anchorage in a system that the Imperium has let be for far too long. But the recently repaired strike cruiser The Howling Hatred managed to win the fight, scattering the other ships before it and allowing Cyrus to make a tactical retreat for then.

Leaving those battles for later, and they will come, he then found himself within the Thuum System where he finally found more concrete signs of Vandis. The man himself is nowhere to be seen, but Cyrus scouted out a large mansion and fortress in one upon one of the habitable moons orbiting the single planet - a gas giant - within the system. Upon raiding it, he found much corrupted personnel who had been apparently left abandoned by their master years before, with Chaos symbols liberally covering the place. Brutal yet informative interrogations have revealed even more information. Vandis fled to this secret ‘home away from home’ where he slowly built up his forces to return to retake Aurelia, only to be beaten back once again. From here, in Thuum, he assembled his ships, and fled fearing reprisal almost immediately afterwards, fleeing not into Segmentum Obscurus, as you might have suspected of such a tainted wretch but instead towards the greater untamed wilderness of Segmentum Ultima. Cyrus elected, considering the years that had passed, not to pursue further without further speaking discussion with the rest of the chapter.

On a somewhat brighter note regarding the heresy of his claiming Blood Raven relics for his own, is that some were even recovered by Cyrus from his compound within the Thuum System. Just as last time, and perhaps even more disturbingly, is that they were Terminator armor suits and weapons with them. That he possessed such equipment, so rare and honored, is deeply concerning to you. For more was yet taken from his vaults as he fled, this you know. Was he determined to lord over these things, or was he daring to sell them unto others? Ever suit is a treasure, and the thought of him using them in such a manner is enraging to you in the extreme. Regardless, Cyrus returns, the 10th Company with him. In an interesting display of his own authority, he has seen fit to speak with Tarkus and have Kaius Jacobus declared a sergeant, his own prowess elevating him despite not possessing decades more experience. Such is his abilities thus far, they say.

But now Cyrus has returned, as has Hadrian, and the Chapter stands united…and victorious! You shall allow the younger members to celebrate, as they should, before you once more plunge into the fires of war. For you have heard the scattered messages from around the Imperium. Armageddon fallen, or perhaps only just about to. Deliverance itself under siege. The increasing amount of daemons and ships which flow from the Eye of Terror battling the forces of Celestine’s Crusade. Orks and Necron and more rising in greater number, all the while the Third Tyrannic War continues to rage across the galaxy, in Tempestus and the southern reaches of Ultima. The Mechanicus reporting to you that they believe they have finally located Kaptin Bluddflag in the depths of the Judgement of Carrion with the last of his followers. You are but one Chapter amidst all of this, but you know your duty. You will slay the enemies of the Imperium and protect its peoples until your last breath. That is your duty, given unto you by the Emperor.

And He shall not find you wanting.

010.M42 To 015.M42
- The Howling Hatred assigned to 10th Company Fleet.
- Test-Slave Gene-Seed Harvests Complete. Largely successful harvest, some failed to mutation during gestation. +75 Gene-Seed from both Harvests combined.
- 4 1st Company Veterans assigned to Honor Guard, Chaplain Uther assigned to Honor Guard, Hamul assigned as 1st Company Champion.
- 5 5th Company Battle Brothers died in the course of the fighting. +10 Gene-Seed
- 20 5th Company Battle Brothers recognized as true Veterans of the Chapter.
- 4 1st Company Veterans died in the course of the fighting. +8 Gene-Seed
- Forgeworld Aerus and Fabricator-General Theodosia added to relations/contacts.
- Forgeworld Aerus has granted a full +100 BP/Turn of their forges for the usage of the Chapter so long as a ship of the Chapter is in the same sector to receive such materials.
- Fabricator-General Theodosia, out of gratitude and appreciation for Martellus’ open devotion and care for the machine, has given you access to some of the Rapiers discovered on Aerus. NOTE: Forgeworld Aerus at this time cannot actually produce these, the designs and STC are lost, as such they are currently irreplaceable if lost. +4 Rapiers (Quad-Heavy Bolters), +2 Rapiers (Laser-Destroyer Array)
- 2 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 2 to Lexicani
- 15 Neophytes [2nd Stage: Advance: 13 to Scout Marines [1st Stage], Remaining 2 Manifest Psyker mutation post-Gene-Seed implantation, advance 2 to Lexicani instead of Scout Marines. -17 Gene-Seed.
- 4 Lexicani Advance: 3 To Codicier. 1 Executed For Mutation And Corruption.
- 100 Aspirants Advance: 85 To Neophytes [1st Stage], Remainder Expired
- 85 Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 60 To Neophytes [2nd Stage], Remainder Expired. Gene-Seed Implantation Required Immediately.
- 46 Scouts [1st Stage] Advance: 40 To Scouts [2nd Stage]
- 25 Scouts [2nd Stage] Advance: 25 To Full Battle Brothers Ready For Assignment.
- Kaius Jacobus [5th Company] is advanced to Sergeant of the 5th Company.
- Chapter Aid Against Hrud Infestation Of The Caeserion System Has Resulted In Slight Improvements In Relations With Multiple Groups, Check Front Page.
- 1 Major Favored Owed - Reclamation of Aerus, Fulfilled!
- 1 Major Favor Held Shared Scars (85th Vendoland 'Crazy Riders') Lost Due To Effective Destruction of 85th Vendoland Regiment
- Gifts Of The Lost: The now defunct 85th Vendoland saw fit to honor your Chapter for saving Subsector Aurelia over and over, fighting alongside them, and treating them with a respect rarely seen by Astartes towards Guard regiments. +5 Rare Hrud Fusils, Extremely Valuable Xenos Weaponry Prized By Inquisition and Assasinorum Alike.
- NEW CRISIS POINTS IDENTIFIED: Dark Eldar Anchorage, The Search For Vandis
- 10th Company Fleet Loses x2 Gladius Frigates, x1 Nova Frigate to Dark Eldar Corsairs of Faiyuum System.
- Advanced Tartaros Pattern Tactical Dreadnought Armour suits of the Blood Ravens recovered! +5 Tartaros Dreadnought Armors Recovered
- Vandis Vault 9B8.2 Looted! +5 Heavy Flamers, +10 Storm Bolters, +5 Cyclone Missile Launchers, +3 Assault Cannons

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Recall Brothers In The Deathwatch
- (Specify In Write-In)
[] Hunting Down Vandis - Vandis has fled further into the Segmentum Ultima. He is a cultist, a heretic, and a purveyor of that which is yours. Each of these is an individual death sentence, but all three at once demands the most violent of retributions towards him. Yet, to leave the Sector behind is a major decision for your forces, who have up until now remained within Sector Korianis as you rebuild your strength. (Write-In Forces Sent Out)
[] Masters Of Pain And Terror - Cyrus, in his search for Vandis, discovered a small Dark Eldar Anchorage located in the previously unexplored Faiyuum System. One of the most advanced and deadly of foes for the Imperium, your 10th Company Captain lost three of its frigates. They must be dealt with, before they can either hide their Anchorage beyond your ability to locate or relocate entirely. As much force as possible must be used on such agile and deadly foes. First, you will have to find them, then, you must lay siege to their void-fortress wherever it is hiding. (Write-In Forces Sent To Faiyuum System)
[] Burning Bluddflag - The infamous Kaptin Bluddflag was a terror throughout all of Sector Korianis, and yet now the rampaging Freebooter must be put to the flame. The Mechanicus has invited your chapter once more to the Judgement of Carrion if you should so desire to participate in his killing if you wish. (Write-In Forces)
[] Bargaining With The Hrud Fusils - Perhaps sensing their own impending deaths would make the wealth of selling the devices meaningless, as well as perhaps being executed for looting them in the first place, you have been given the 85th Vendoland's Hrud Fusil cache. It is highly likely that there are those in the Imperium who would bargain much for such things. Though it would preclude your ability to study or use them for your own purposes.
- [] Inquisition Minor Favor (Write-In Ordos/Individual Inquisitor)
- [] Assassinorum Minor Favor (Write-In Temple)
- [] Mechanicus Minor Favor from Zerann 52X1
[] Something Else (Write-In)
[] As your chapter grows once more, it may be time to dedicate those of the 1st Company into becoming the honored Scout Sergeants of the 10th Company, at least one or two to aid the burden of Cyrus as his company's numbers increase.
[] Assign your newest 25 Battle Brothers to a Company, either the 5th...or perhaps it is time to re-establish another Company? You would have to designate another leader for it. Perhaps Captain Thule would be willing to lead once more? It is not wholly out of the realm of possibility, not something that has never been done before. (Write-In Assignment/Establish A New Company With Captain Thule)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Implant current generation of [2nd Stage] Neophytes with Gene-Seed. Write-In Gene-Seed Implanted.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- Gracchus is currently studying the gene-seed of the Blood Ravens, to perhaps improve survival rates for implantation.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (350 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [200/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Rapier For Potential Learning Of Design To Allow Replication (WARNING: May end up losing some Rapiers as a result of the study) [0/???]
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [0/????]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- I could use a few more peers in the forges. Or at least subordinates.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- THE RAPIER! Praise be to the Omnissiah! It is as if a Tarantula Turret which can move and maneuver, greatly increasing its chances of survival! Please, Chapter Master, allow me to study it, to learn its secrets, so that the design is not lost should they be destroyed!
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon Two Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds
- [] Calderis
- [] Trontiux III
- [] Meridian
- [] Junius

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.

Turn 16 Results - 2477.5

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] Plan Much to Do Before Magistery -[*] Free action: Bring in prospectors to search for minable metals (100+50 gc). -[*] Free action: Investigate the farming possibilities of the land (50+25 gc for test crops). -[*] Free action: Gun Shopping: You're currently using a pistol that was a spare for the pistoliers. Visit Nuln or Zhufbar to upgrade. (does not take an action; will trigger a subvote next turn for what type and how many; will cost 100-300 gc, don't take this just to window shop - this is committing to the purchase) --[*] Zhufbar -[*] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. --[*] Wilhelmina -[*] Internalized Lessons: If you've been using a particular trait a fair bit in the last year, you can spend some time on it to internalize what you've learned and increase the trait (Stewardship). -[*] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. --[*] Doppelganger --[*] Shadowcloak -[*] Enchantment: You're naturally talented at enchantment; so far, this just amounts to being able to make your desk meow for about an hour. See if you can improve on that, or at least figure out a way to make that useful. -[*] Diggy Diggy Hole, Remixed: You're getting sick of having workmen tramping in and out of your abode. Recruit an entire team and personally oversee them to clear out all of the reachable portions of the Palace-Shrine and be done with it. (-100 gc) --[*] Ranald's Blessing -[*] The New Boss: Keep an ear to the ground, learning what you can of Roswita's actions and plans. There's a great deal of work to be done, and luckily for you, money translates to work very simply. Money flows out to miners, to prospectors, to farmers, to natural philosophers, and closest to home, to a dozen men willing to live and work underground and surrender their memories of you in the end in exchange for thrice what they'd earn anywhere else. You pay careful attention to the workers, making sure they don't stray into any of the rooms in use and remain in their work areas, and they're sufficiently cowed by money and your close attention that they obey. They clear out enough of the hallway to show you what you're working with: six former rooms, filled almost entirely with long-hardened mud, too soft for picks but too hard for shovels. Mounds of broken clay are carried up and out to be piled in the alleyway, to the equal amusement and annoyment of the cats that call it home. One of the rooms is written off when it's found that the ceiling has collapsed, and is filled back in with scree from the other rooms and bricked shut. To empty it of the dirt filling it would be to remove the foundations for whatever is built above, and having a house fall into your Sunken Palace would instantly ruin all the work you've put into keeping it secret. Weeks pass of digging during the day and hauling scree to rented wagons at night as the rooms empty of the debris filling them, and eventually the long-hidden contents of some of those rooms are revealed. [Rolls: 89, 11, 22, 94+20(Ranald's Blessing)=114, 70, 24. Five usable rooms; three loot rolls.] [70: Rolling...] Two of the rooms are empty, but three are interesting. One is, from all appearances, a former stable, which confirms that the Palace once stood at street level. The wooden carriages are long since rotted away to nothing and the skeleton of a horse that was uncovered is just depressing, but adjoining the stable is the long-lost workshop of a blacksmith, anvil and forge and a wall covered in hundreds of useful tools, implements and devices. [89: Rolling...] The second room is far less prosaic. Uncovering silver candles and fragments of stained glass gave you the hint that the room was once a chapel, but when the workers finally uncovered the altar the shocked oaths and murmured prayers drew you over immediately. The open jaws of a great silver shark greets your gaze, and you lift the idol free from the debris that encased it and almost stagger under the weight. Scrutiny of the scratches it already bears reveals it to be silver-coated iron rather than pure silver. Still valuable... at least, if you're willing to risk the wrath of Stromfels, the outlawed Shark God of Shipwrecks and Drowning, by further profaning what must have once been a shrine to him. [114: Rolling...] The last room is even more striking. The door, now that you pay more attention, was once reinforced with iron before time and moisture turned it to a few scraps of rust; that helps explains why a skeleton was found chained to one wall of the buried room. Once, this was a dungeon. The skeleton yields scarce few clues as to its identity. What clothes it once wore are long since rotted away to nothing. There is one item that appears untouched by time, despite the raw iron it appears to be wrought from, and the Aqshy running through it is as much proof of its identity as the starburst of rubies mounted on the ring. Forged by the first of the Bright Wizards under Teclis for use in the Great War Against Chaos, capable of emitting great fireballs in the hands of the untrained and doing even more in the capable hands of a Bright Wizard; this is a Doomfire Ring. --- The work is done soon after, the men more than happy to exchange their memories for a few gold coins apiece. You're left alone once more with four new rooms and one unwanted shrine to a forbidden God. Meanwhile, work continues elsewhere, urged on by your outlay of coin. It is a fact of life that precious metal can buy just about anything, but it's a fact that takes a great deal of scrutiny to actually understand. Gold, unless one is a Gold Wizard, is mostly useless. It's shiny, sure, so it makes for nice jewellery and ornaments, but why does that mean that everything revolves around it? Steel, now steel is useful, and steel ingots would be a much more sensible medium of exchange... but also hideously unwieldy. Is that it? Is gold the medium for exchange just because it's rare enough that a single unit of it is light? You observe the actions of the workers you hired, you observe the inner mechanisms of the EIC, you see over and over useful items and valuable labour exchanged for shiny metal. And then you look once more at a piece of that shiny metal, seeing not just the composition of it but the markings stamped upon it: a year, the familiar skeleton of Stirland's banner, and causing a clench of sadness in you, Abelhelm's name and his head in profile. Not just any gold, but gold issued and guaranteed by the Empire... [Studying Stewardship: Roll, Req 60, 76. +2 Stewardship] --- You've always had a talent for enchantment. The first spell you cast was not the magical lights or telekinesis common to those that develop magic young, or the self-defensive magical backlash sadly common to those that develop it older; it was making your toy horse neigh. But with one thing or another, you've never had the time to refine your ability beyond that. There was always fires to put out and dire secrets to uncover and wars to be fought, no time for academia that wasn't of immediate benefit. The circumstances are less than ideal, but now you have time. Enchantment, you learned long after you had accidentally achieved it, is one of the more difficult of magical feats. Casting magic is simple - humans are naturally able to channel magic through their bodies, each wind of magic is naturally inclined to affect reality in a certain way, so all that's left to cast a magical spell is channelling the correct wind and in such a way that acting according to its nature has the desired effect. Outside, perhaps, of Chamon and the associated Lore of Metal, no type of magic naturally 'wants' to be bound into an object. The natural state of the winds of magic is either flowing freely through the air, gathering in certain places according to its nature, or flowing through those attuned to it. So enchantment requires one to overpower the very nature of the magic one wields and cramming it into an object it doesn't want to go into. One can make it easier for an object to hold magic - runes, appropriate components, preparatory rituals, and so on - but it's never easy. To say nothing of Ulgu, the ephemeral wind of confusion and shadows, which by its nature is even more reluctant to be trapped in a static and unchanging form... You begin with stones, taken from the cobbles on the streets above, worn smooth by the passage of ten thousand feet. Inherently shaped and tamed by human artifice, but constantly overlooked, you carve the rune of the Grey Wind into them and hope that they will serve as a vessel for Ulgu. And then, over painstaking hours, you begin to focus your will and channel wind into stone. Days pass in mind-numbing concentration, and progress is gained an inch at a time as Ulgu lies trapped within the stone a little longer before breaking free once more and dissipating in a puff of smoke. As tedious as the work is, you refuse to let your concentration falter, even as days turn to weeks. Each day the Ulgu bends a little easier to your will. Each day the gap between you releasing your mental grasp on the stone and the Ulgu wriggling free lengthens. And finally, at long, long last, the day comes when it doesn't escape at all, so thoroughly cowed by your will it remains where it is placed, the nature of the wind leaking into the rock itself and turning it ever so slightly translucent when held up to a light. It is the least of victories. But it is a step forward on a very valuable road. [Studying Enchantment: Req 70, Learning, 42+18+10(workshop)+10(Enchanter)=80] --- Other magical pursuits draw your attention. One of them is Shadowcloak, the deceptively subtle spell of enveloping oneself in shadows and making oneself significantly harder to see. The other is Doppelganger, to shroud oneself instead in illusion and imitate the appearance of another. Both among the most basic of the spells of Ulgu, both potentially incredibly useful. Your personal envisioning of Ulgu is not of shadow, but of fog. Neither is more correct than the other; most spells deal with shadow, but elemental Ulgu is more commonly drawn to fog. So, after weeks of study and practice, when you finally perform Shadowcloak, it isn't so much the drawing of shadows to you but the summoning of mist to envelop you, rendering you slightly translucent rather than blending you into the shadows around you. In practice the difference is negligible, but you find it an interesting demonstration of the nature of magic. Sadly, Doppelganger proves frustratingly elusive. It is easy enough to wrap your form in Ulgu - you did as much for Shadowcloak, and before that with Aethyric Armour - but to shape said magical energy until it changes your appearance is a leap you're unable to make, no matter how many times you carefully read through the scroll of instruction. You try and try until you become frustrated enough that trying any further would be dangerous, and then, sensibly, you put the scroll aside. You can come back to it later, with a fresh mind and outlook, and hopefully without the risk of miscasting due to being emotionally compromised. On another note, with the scrolls came a note from your Master, hinting that soon you should either pursue advancement or find another way to serve the Empire. It's not quite a command, but it is a reminder that he has the ability to give that command, at least until you graduate from Journeywomanship, and that you are expected to at least metaphorically journey. But you still have some time before those nudges turn into shoves. [Learning Shadowcloak: Req 60, 55+18=73] [Learning Doppelganger: Req 60, 30+18=48] --- "I've given notice," Wilhelmina says, over the extended working lunch that your Shareholder's meetings tend to turn into. "The Council had enough holes kicked in it, would have been bad if I had quit on the spot." "Her own doing," you note, trying to keep bitterness out of your voice. She nods. "That as may be, but I've long experience with putting up with unruly children who know a great deal less than they think they do. Might have been satisfying, but it would be Stirland that suffered for it." You nod, conceding the point. "Schultz? Kasmir?" [Rolling... 95] [Rolling... 97] "Schultz is staying on - the girl has some plan for reinforcing the bridge across the Drak, turning it into a memorial to her father. And Kasmir briefly reappeared. He apparently spent most of a year tending to the people of the town of Drakenhof, filling the spiritual void left by the necromancers and vampires. Searching for meaning, he said. Seems to have found it." You swallow a hundred bitter comments. If Kasmir's made peace with Sigmar having failed Abelhelm, that's his business. Instead, you move on to an equally bitter topic. "And my... former position?" [Rolling... 14] "The Witch Hunter that was travelling with her has taken the job. Abelhelm kept that lot on a leash, but I worry that they've got her on one." You say nothing directly, but your stomach twists at the ugly possibilities that that could lead to. You knew that Julia hadn't managed to claim your former job, but says she fancies her chances of staying on under the new regime. "What's her approach to the EIC?" "She'll leave well enough alone as long as it keeps dropping money in her coffers. The campaign did real damage to the treasury, and refilling the ranks of the army will do even more." You nod and look down at the paperwork scattered across the table. That's something, at least. With a free hand for this half of the year, Wilhelmina has been focusing on making sure her supply contracts with the Army of Stirland are iron-clad. You note that much of the EIC profits come from the treasury of Stirland in the first place, and smile a nasty little smile. Then you see the logo of the EIC atop each piece of paper, and your smile fades. Three swords, it represented. And you're the only wielder of those swords still alive. --- Through Wilhelmina, Julia, and word on the street, you piece together the rest of what Roswita has been up to. Despite dearly wanting to, you're unable to fault her priority: the securing of the gains her father paid for with his life. The Witch Hunters are moving in force into the secured portion of Sylvania to ensure that no necromancers remain. The Chancellor's position remains as yet unfilled; on a related note, Anton, after a tearful farewell to you and extracting a promise that you'd stay in touch, has returned to Blutdorf to prepare to take up his ageing father's position as Baron. [Minable minerals: 21] [Farming Possibilities: 5] Word comes back to you from those investigating your land for mineral wealth and farming possibilities; one figuratively barren and fruitless, the other literally. There appears to be no mineral wealth at all lurking under the thin topsoil of your land, and no plant can be persuaded to take root in it save for the hardy grass and scraggly bushes that the sheep and goats thrive upon. You had been watching them on and off through the months as part of your study into the mystery of gold's command over people, and you know they actually performed the work, so you're forced to accept their conclusion and thank them for their time. Finally, as the year comes to a close, you make your way at last to Zhufbar. Your reputation gets you in the door, and that you're here to buy a gun garners approving nods, and you're shown through the workshops of a number of different dwarves, each at least five times your age and each eager to have crafted the firearm that ends up on your hip. You single out a number of designs for further consideration: Marksdwarf's Pistol: This pistol is based on the tried and true single-shot design that still reigns supreme in the Empire, but both the firearm itself and the odd self-contained capsules of powder and ball are so finely built that the only restriction on accuracy is the wielder. It is currently missing the handle, for the simple reason that one will be built to match the wielder's hand when it is purchased. Spoiler Hand Blunderbuss: The brilliance of this design is not in the firing itself, but in the system of tubes and piping that absorbs the blast of the massive blackpowder charge, making recoil manageable with one hand. It fires anything that can be crammed down the barrel and does so without breaking the wielder's wrist. Spoiler Dwarven Revolver: Similar to the Repeater Pistols of Nuln, except instead of having eight separate barrels it has only one, and the chamber holding the balls revolves to line up with the one barrel instead. Spoiler Dwarven Pistol: A cutting-edge single-shot Dwarven design, this fires a massive, spiralling bullet with extreme velocity and decent accuracy. Spoiler Blacksmithing Tools: [ ] Keep [ ] Sell (+75 gc} Shrine to Stromfels: [ ] Sell the idol for its silver, tear down the altar and use the room for something else. (+150 gc, +1 room, ???) [ ] Melt down the idol, cast it into a new one to Ranald, call in your priest friends to re-sanctify the room. (bonus to rolls and reduced cost to creating a second shrine to Ranald, either in your Estate or elsewhere, +1 room, ???) [ ] Leave the idol on the altar and brick the room up. No sense taking risks. Doomfire Ring: [ ] Keep it. [ ] Sell it (+??? gc). [ ] Return it to the Bright College (???). Pistol: [ ] Marksdwarf's Pistol, 75 gc. [ ] Hand Blunderbuss, 50 gc. [ ] Dwarven Revolver, 125 gc. [ ] Dwarven Pistol: 100 gc. - To vote to purchase multiple guns, include them in one vote like so: [*] Dwarven Pistol and Dwarven Revolver or [*] 2x Dwarven Pistol. - Ask any questions you have about what Roswita's up to, if it's the sort of information Mathilde can get I'll add it below. Any big motivation speeches where she states her goal for the years to come? She isn't the bombastic type, and keeps everything compartmentalized. If there's a bigger picture she's keeping it to herself. Her stance on Dwarves and Halflings? Neutral on the former. Somehow she got her hands on the amount of extra tax that would be coming in if the Moot was part of Stirland, so she's miffed at the latter. How's new boss treating Julia? Fairly well, actually; he seems delighted to have a ready-made intelligence network dropped into his lap. Current orders are to expand into Nachthafen and Drakenhof. Any changes to the watch? No major changes yet, but information on identifying illicit magic-users has been distributed among them. Does Roswita have any idea we're still in the city and if so where we are? You've made no secret of the fact that you're still in Wurtbad, but absolutely nobody knows your address. I take it she hasn't taken us up on our offer of correspondence? Her silence is a pretty clear answer. Any news on what's she's planning on doing to the newly liberated lands of Drakenhof and the Haunted Hills? Count's demesne or new/expanded vassals? She's desperate for money to refill the treasury, and seems likely to create new counties or baronies to sell off. Have we heard of any tidings from Gabriella? (That vampire noble lady) Her name was on the list you gave your Master, and as such you were unsurprised that she up and disappeared. Succession is for Roswita to decide.. Is Haunted Hills land for sale? Can we invite the dwarfs to prospect it and how much would it cost? The goal is to buy out the best mineral spots for EIC. It's not currently on the market, but likely will be soon, one way or another. You could spend four favours to do a surface survey of the entire Hills, though it'd only catch the very obvious stuff - it's a massive amount of land to cover and a proper survey of it all would take lifetimes. Do we know anything about how/what Gustav is doing? Trying to refill the ranks of the army as best he can with the treasury as pitifully low as it is. Any significant shifts in military deployments? No, they're remaining mostly concentrated on the frontier. Any action been taken to replace the greatswords? If no, what bodyguards does she use when in public? A new cohort is being raised in Altdorf for her. Has Abelhelm had a funeral yet? Based upon a previous vote option ("attend the long-delayed funeral of Abelhelm") it was implied that one would be held after his successor's arrival. If there was a funeral, and you assume there was, it was kept private. Has she had any events/meetings with the various prominent nobles of Stirland, as we know? No. Any significant public efforts to restore Stirland's coffers as yet, either as reducing expenses or moneymaking initiatives? Not yet, but it does look like she's going to be liquidating the Haunted Hills in one way or another. Has she brought in friends, forces, or visible assets of any kind other than that one witch hunter? And what is his name, anyway? Either she brought a lot of Witch Hunters or they've become a lot more visible without Abelhelm keeping them in check. The new Spymaster's name is Lucas von Salkalten. Anything we've learned about her personal traits/habits? Reserved, bookish and private. What do we know about the Witch Hunter who replaced us? Like general attitude, province of origin, Hat sizes and the weapons he carries around. By name and accent, a northern Ostlander; combined with Abelhelm's taste in brandy you suspect that's where his children were holed up. He's equally suspicious of damn near everyone and seems to be really jumpy to suddenly find himself on the front line of the whole Sylvania business. He favours a falchion.

Turn 17 - 2478 - Growing Concerns

Spoiler: Winning Vote [x] Melt down the idol, cast it into a new one to Ranald, call in your priest friends to re-sanctify the room. (bonus to rolls and reduced cost to creating a second shrine to Ranald, either in your Estate or elsewhere, +1 room, ???) [X] Keep Blacksmiths Tools [X] Dwarven Revolver, 125 gc. [X] Return to the Bright College (???) All of the options appealed to you to some extent, and the temptation was there to purchase more than one of the examples of fine art arrayed before you. But in the end, it was the revolver that won out over the others. It may lack for accuracy or raw stopping power, but it could be fired eight times without reloading and was compatible with the powder and shot that could be found in any town in the Empire instead of requiring some exotic Dwarven 'bullet'. You are given a short lesson on the firing, reloading and maintenance of your new weapon, as well as directions to the Leatherworker's Guild for a complimentary holster. When you leave Zhufbar and head back to Wurtbad, it's significantly more heavily armed than before, with the revolver tucked into a holster beneath your robes. --- It's been quite some time since you spent much time with Wolf and Heideck, but they answer your summons without hesitation. After you explain the fact that your hidden underground palace is, well, a hidden underground palace, they agree to being blindfolded and led through the streets as well, either trusting you not to pull anything or in Ranald to protect them, their arms full of various tools and props for the task ahead of them. Wolf lets out an impressed whistle as you led him into the alley. "Don't know what you've done, but I'm liking the energies here." Getting them down the ladder is trickier, but you manage. And then, finally, you release them from their blindfolds in the hallway outside the Shrine, and they blink and peer around them into the darkness, lit by a glowing orb of light you summoned. Heideck steps through the doorway, takes a look inside, and steps out again. "Found your problem." You roll your eyes. "I know what the problem is, I want you to solve it." Heideck glances after Wolf, who has stepped through the doorway and is complaining loudly about river pirates. "We'll see what we can do." "Glad to hear it. What do I owe you?" He shakes his head. "Stromfels is no friend to Ranald, so should this work it will grant us favour with our mutual friend. No payment necessary." You nod and leave them to it, occasionally looking in to see how it goes. Incense is lit, chants are chanted, games of chance played and outrageously cheated at. The clatter of rolling dice and the soft sounds of shuffled cards echo unnaturally in the air. [Re-sanctifying the Shrine: Roll, 50] Energies gather, energies simultaneously akin and completely different to the magical energies you're so used to manipulating. The now-familiar presence of Ranald is in the air, as well as one completely alien to you: violent, brooding, and eternally hungry. You make sure that raw iron runs from everything sensitive down to the floor to allow stray magical energies to earth themselves harmlessly. In the shrine, the two priests ceremoniously smash apart the shackles they brought with them. [The Grappling of Gods: 52] The presences grow in strength as energy crackles through the air. The two priests are kneeling before the Altar, chanting in incomprehensible Thieves Cant with their arms crossed in front of them as they reinforce Ranald's presence. It seems like it's working, that Ranald is growing slightly faster than the terrible hungry God that called this place home... [Forces brought to bear: 8] And in a single bloody instant, Wolf disappears from the waist up and gore sprays across the room, snatched up by the jaws of a hungry God. You're unable to keep from flinching away in horror, but Heideck's prayers redouble in strength as the terrible God is occupied with Wolf's mortal remains. [A momentary distraction: 69] That distraction is all that is needed, as Ranald's familiar presence waxes once more. The idol on the altar glows, and for a moment you think it's with magical light but it's heat, you can see drops of molten silver pattering onto the altar below, and in a single incomprehensible instant it's done - the duel you couldn't begin to understand is over and the presence of the terrible God is banished. You enter the room on unsteady feet as Heideck gets to his own. As he turns to you, you open your mouth to say something, thanks or an apology or something, and he holds up a hand to interrupt. There's tears in his eyes but a smile on his face. "Many die in debt to Ranald, but very few die with Ranald in debt to them. His new home in the afterlife will be grand indeed." Right. A priest to an unorthodox God, but a priest nonetheless. You murmur your thanks anyway, and he claps you on the shoulder and sets to work gathering up his implements and the remains of poor Wolf. As he does so, you inspect the idol, its glow fading back into the sheen of silver. The shape of it has changed, and while you know that it's just from the nose of the shark having melted and run downwards into the open jaws and then cooled into strange, blocky shapes, it looks like the shark's open maw has been crammed with dice of all things. Unnoticed, Heideck has come up behind you and you jump as he begins talking. "There's a blacksmith just inside the southern gate, next to the Cheesemonger's Guild. He can be trusted to remain silent. Have him reforge this into an idol worthy of Wolf's sacrifice." He leaves, a basket of priestly implements in one arm and the remains of his former partner tucked under the other. Matters of blindfolds and secrecy didn't occur to you until long after he was gone. --- The Bright College itself is set within an area of Altdorf that was burnt to the ground in some long-forgotten incident. Rumours of hauntings and inexplicable reignitions keep it from being rebuilt as much as the laws saying it should be left as is, as a reminder of... of something. Evidently, it failed. Ignoring the glimpses of movement from the corners of your eyes and refusing to investigate the occasionally smouldering remnants that make it seem as the fire burned hours instead of centuries ago, you push through the empty streets until you reach your destination - a collection of towers collapsed atop each other in an otherwise empty plaza. You stare in thought at the illusion, seeing the familiar flow of Ulgu through it, and wonder at what long-past agreement or deal led to its creation. Then you step through it, and flinch back from a wave of heat as you penetrate the illusion and instead find yourself at the brass gates of the college, glowing red with heat. Far above you, twenty-one identical towers stretch into the sky, each of them burning brightly. No illusion, this; such is the place that Pyromancers call home. As impressive as the gate is, even the Bright Order must surrender to practicalities, and to one side is the modest stone gatehouse and, visible through a window, the Gatekeeper, an old man in shabby robes who seems to be currently enjoying a cup of tea. He catches sight of you, rises, and ventures out from the small building, teacup still in hand. "Yes?" he asks, his burning eyes the only hint to his nature. "Dame Weber, of the Grey College." "Ah, yes." He totters back inside, consults a massive tome standing open on the table, then totters back out. "Magister Victor is expecting you. Would you like to come in, or are you happy to wait out here?" The heat is already oppressive, you've no desire to find what sort of temperatures the Bright Wizards consider homey. "I'll wait here." "Very well," he says with a smile, walks up to and opens the gate with no care for the sizzle or the smell of burnt flesh that filled the air, and into the depths of the College he goes, leaving you alone with your thoughts. You mull over your checking in at the Grey College (indirectly, because as a Journeywoman you're banned from the premises proper) and checking the reception to your Matrix. The Grey Order is impressed, and have been nudging the other orders to take notice of what was, you reluctantly admit, a rather dry paper. So far the Jade Order have started picking up on it, and have started experiments to form a Jade equivalent to the Matrix. While thinking, your eyes were drawn up to the burning towers, far above. It is rather a staple of being a wizard, you think to yourself. Maybe you should build one of your own. Or perhaps it just wouldn't be practical... "Dame Weber, I presume?" asks a cultured voice, and you lower your gaze to the man who has emerged. Heavy lines mark his face as that of an old man, but the fiery red of his hair disagrees. You nod. "Magister Victor?" "I have that honour." He holds out his hand expectantly, and you produce the iron ring from a pocket and place it there. He examines it closely, and a smile stretches across his features. "Wonderful," he says. "So many of these have been lost over the years, but some still find their way back. Where was it?" You'd prepared a half-truth. "In the freshly-excavated ruins of a manor in Stirland, still worn by its former owner." "You buried them appropriately?" You nod. "Good. Almost certainly it was not one of ours, but still." He inspects the ring again, this time in admiration. "The puissance of these artifacts is, perhaps, less than one might expect from something crafted by those under Teclis," he observes, the rubies shimmering in the firelight. "But they were never meant to turn the tide of wars single-handedly. What they represent is protection for our most vulnerable members as they venture out into the world, and handed down to another as each reaches Magisterial rank. If it means that just one more wizard reaches the prime of their career instead of dying to the trials of their journeying... well, what more potent effect could you ask of an enchantment?" You nod in agreement. "You've returned a prized relic to us, and the Bright Order repays its debts." [Rolling...] He reaches into his robes and produces an unadorned steel semi-circle - a torc, similar to that worn by the men of Sigmar's time. "I understand you have been knighted," he says. "A position of a leader and a warrior both. As such, I would grant to you this torc. It contains the essence of the spell known to us as Crown of Fire, which will make you inspiring to your allies and intimidating to your foes." He smiles. "More so than you are already, I mean." You take the torc from him, and find that the metal is comfortably warm instead of the coolness of metal you were expecting, and slip it around your neck. You feel the magic in it reaching out, surrounding your form, the Aqshy of the enchantment dancing above your skin a safe distance from the natural Ulgu in your body. "Once the spell has run its course over about five minutes, place it in a fire to recharge it. An hour in a typical campfire should do the trick, or half a day suspended above a candleflame, or a minute in a proper forge." "A worthy gift," you say, and mean it. "Thank you." "Thank you," he replies, "for the apprentices that now stand a greater chance of surviving their journeys." You exchange bows, and then you turn and make your way back out of the devastated quarter. --- PLAN FOR THIS TURN As you are no longer employed, there is no longer a distinction between 'personal' and 'organizational' actions. Pick six of the below; you can take up to two extra actions as Overwork - if you do, mark them accordingly. All of your Organizations can be safely 'ignored' if you desire - they will continue operating as they have been. The Weber Estate Earmarked Funds: 1,066 gc Estate Profits: 10 gc / turn You can spend money instead of turns here to have someone else oversee the work; this will increase the cost by half again, and double any dwarf rep cost. For instance, an option costing 100 gc will cost 150 gc. It also means that your personal stats will not apply to whatever is being done. [ ] Build a modest home for yourself, equal in size to the rooms you're using in the Sunken Palace (3 rooms, 50 gc). [ ] Build a large home for yourself, with plenty of spare rooms to expand into (6 rooms, 150 gc). [ ] Why muck about? Build a proper manor (10 rooms, 300 gc). [ ] Build a tower, either into an above structure or on its own (1 room, 100 gc, bonus to room's purpose). [ ] Build fortifications into your home, turning it into a hillfort, or motte (50 gc for wood, 200 gc for stone, optional dwarf help for -1 dwarf rep). [ ] Erect a shrine to Ranald in honour of his victory over Stromfels, and of Wolf's sacrifice that made it possible. (NEW) [ ] Use your newly-acquired blacksmithing gear to lure in a skilled but poor blacksmith to begin servicing the area. (no action required) (NEW) [ ] Build a communal granary to store food for lean times (50 gc). [ ] Build a well (50 gc). [ ] Build a bailey for your subjects to shelter in and to encompass other structures (100 gc for wood, 400 gc for stone, optional dwarf help for -1 dwarf rep). [ ] Have the dwarves build you a fortress. (1000 gc, -2 dwarf rep. Protects but does not build living area. No, there is no cheaper option. If you want cheap, get manlings to build it.) [ ] Bring in dwarvern prospectors to search for minable metals (-1 Dwarf Rep) [ ] Bring in dwarvern farmers to investigate the farming possibilities of the land. (-1 Dwarf Rep) [ ] Improve the road between the Estate and Sonningwiese (50 gc) [o] Establish upkeep of the roads between the estate and the individual households. (requires a local smith) [ ] Purchase a loom, erect a building for it, and invite weavers to start calling your estate home. (100 gc) [ ] Set up a dairy and recruit skilled cheesemakers from among the locals to work in it. (100 gc) The Eastern Imperial Company Outstanding Debt: 1,400 gc Your share of EIC Profits: 50 gc / turn Wilhelmina's Current Focus: Expanding into Southern Stirland. [ ] Use your reputation to build trade ties with Zhufbar. [ ] Use your reputation to build trade ties with Karak Kadrin. [ ] Use your friendship with Anton to build trade ties along the Nuln Road. [ ] Expand the EIC into Sonningwiese; this is unlikely to increase profits, but would indirectly improve the lot of your subjects. [ ] Have the EIC print and sell a second edition of Asarnil's memoirs. [ ] Investigate whether Ostermark is building a Talabec-Stir canal near Karak Kadrin. [ ] Spend some time getting to know Wilhelmina's sons. Gong Farmers Currently Revenue Neutral due to supporting the Niter Factory [ ] Fold them into the EIC; no need for you to have personal control of them. (no action needed) [ ] Formalize and organize the payments people make for the Gong Farmers to perform their service. [ ] Expand the Gong Farmers into the rest of Western Stirland. [ ] Create market gardens outside the walls of Wurtbad, fertilized with the solid waste collected by the Gong Farmers. [ ] No longer linked to the Watch, the Gong Farmers might be vulnerable. Arm and train them so they can defend themselves in the sewers. Niter Factory Goods currently unsold; costs covered by Gong Farmers. [ ] Fold it into the EIC. (no action needed) [ ] Sell the factory itself. [ ] Sell the produced niter crystals to Nuln. [ ] Sell the produced niter crystals to Zhufbar. [ ] Sell the produced niter crystals as fertiliser in Stirland. [ ] Sell the produced niter crystals as fertiliser to the Moot. [ ] Investigate the rest of the process for making gunpowder. [ ] Bring in dwarven experts to expand the factory to produce gunpowder (-5 Dwarf Favour). Personal Actions Personal Wealth: 357 gc Living expenses: 10 gc / turn Magister: [ ] Go to Altdorf and submit yourself to the Magisterial examination. (takes three actions, will take place after other actions in the turn) Self-Improvement: [ ] Internalized Lessons: If you've been using a particular trait a fair bit in the last year, you can spend some time on it to internalize what you've learned and increase the trait (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective the more you've used the trait lately). [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: If you haven't been using a particular trait lately, you can try to practice it anyway. [ ] Combat Training In The Free Market: The war cost you your combatant friends, but training is always for sale. Go out and buy some. (-20 gc) Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential, and no longer with mud. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got four rooms cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put in one of them and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Expand your library to cover a new subject or go deeper into an existing one (choose which; -50 gc). [ ] Volatility: Examine how to move your various fragile and magically sensitive bits and pieces without endangering them. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got several gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. [ ] Your experience with the so-called Fog of War has given you a lot of ideas for new applications of Ulgu. Investigate them to see what might be possible. [ ] Read the Liber Mortis. Enchantment: [ ] Imbue an item with a petty or lesser magic. (specify item and spell) (NEW) [ ] Attempt to imbue an item with a Relatively Simple spell. (specify item and spell) (NEW) [o] Advance your understanding of enchantment even further. (cannot be taken until you practice enchantment at your current level) (NEW) Influence: [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool - especially considering you no longer have official power. Relations: [ ] The New Boss: Keep an ear to the ground, learning what you can of Roswita's actions and plans. [ ] The New Spymaster: Witch Hunter Lucas von Salkalten currently fills your position. As per the Articles of Imperial Magic, wizards owe assistance to the Templars of Sigmar if they can prove they need it. Drop by to offer it freely instead. (NEW) [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with someone, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one) (can be taken multiple times). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: Trust, but verify. Spend some of your time seeing what a certain person spends their time doing (choose one) (can be taken multiple times). [ ] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (does not take an action) Familiar: You've grown much in power; it might be time for you to seek a familiar. Animals that are suitable to be familiars are incredibly rare. You can hunt for them and spent a great deal of time doing so, or you can buy one for an agonizing price. Or you could make one. [ ] You'll have a cat, damn it. Spend time with the alley cats of Wurtbad and see what you can find. (low chance) [ ] Wander the streets of Wurtbad and see if any animal jumps out at you. (moderate chance, could be any tame or feral animal) [ ] Spend some alone in the woods. What could go wrong? (high chance, but no telling what animal would be. chance of dangers in the woods) [ ] Travel to Altdorf and see what suitable animals are for sale. (will cost 300-600 gc; can decide not to purchase if you don't like the type or look of the animal. Options for loans or dipping into EIC/earmarked funds will be available if you can't afford it) [ ] Why trust in nature or the free market? You'll damn well make your own familiar. (50 gc, resulting familiar is unpredictable in appearance and will be visibly unnatural). - Voting will be in Plan format. - Don't forget Ranald's Blessing! - Yes, you can spend spare time with Anton if you want. Such is the power of Shadowsteed.

Turn 16: Bringing Fire To Darkness (Part One)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[X] Plan: Get Of My Lawn!!!

[X] Masters Of Pain And Terror - Cyrus, in his search for Vandis, discovered a small Dark Eldar Anchorage located in the previously unexplored Faiyuum System. One of the most advanced and deadly of foes for the Imperium, your 10th Company Captain lost three of its frigates. They must be dealt with, before they can either hide their Anchorage beyond your ability to locate or relocate entirely. As much force as possible must be used on such agile and deadly foes. First, you will have to find them, then, you must lay siege to their void-fortress wherever it is hiding. (Write-In Forces Sent To Faiyuum System)
-[X] All of our forces not sent to after Bluddflag.
-[X] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes , Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun
--[X] Chief Librarian Probalis and other members of the Librarium will concentrate their efforts to scry and find the Dark Eldar
-[X] Ask Governor Derosa if she has any Rogue Trader contacts that could be useful
[X] Burning Bluddflag - The infamous Kaptin Bluddflag was a terror throughout all of Sector Korianis, and yet now the rampaging Freebooter must be put to the flame. The Mechanicus has invited your chapter once more to the Judgement of Carrion if you should so desire to participate in his killing if you wish. (Write-In Forces)
-[X] The Chapter Honor Guard and 17 Veterans, led by Hamul
--[X] 10x Tartaros Pattern Dreadnought armor with 8x Thunder Hammers, 8x Storm Shields and 2 Ligthning Claws (Hamul and Uther are armed with Tartaros armor), the rest are armed with Indominatus Patter armor and 7x Assault cannons, 4x Heavy Flamers, 2x Thunder Hammers, 2x Storm Shields, 11x Power fists and 10 Cyclone Missile Launchers.
-[X] Send them off with one Gladius-class frigate from the 5th Company fleet

[X] Gabriel Angelos – Chapter Master
-[X] As your chapter grows once more, it may be time to dedicate those of the 1st Company into becoming the honored Scout Sergeants of the 10th Company, at least one or two to aid the burden of Cyrus as his company's numbers increase.
--[X] Search sergeants from the veterans of 5th Company as well
-[X] Assign your newest 25 Battle Brothers to a Company, either the 5th...or perhaps it is time to re-establish another Company? You would have to designate another leader for it. Perhaps Captain Thule would be willing to lead once more? It is not wholly out of the realm of possibility, not something that has never been done before. (Write-In Assignment/Establish A New Company With Captain Thule)
--[X] 5th Company
[X] Bargaining With The Hrud Fusils - Perhaps sensing their own impending deaths would make the wealth of selling the devices meaningless, as well as perhaps being executed for looting them in the first place, you have been given the 85th Vendoland's Hrud Fusil cache. It is highly likely that there are those in the Imperium who would bargain much for such things. Though it would preclude your ability to study or use them for your own purposes.
-[X] Inquisition Minor Favor (Inquisitor Adrastia).
-[X] Keep one of the Fusils to yourself for future study. Make sure that Martellus keeps it safe and hidden.
[X] Transfer 2 Gladius Frigates from 1st Company Fleet to 10th Company Fleet
[X] Search amongst the neophytes and scouts for any with the potential to become an Apothecary, Techmarine or Chaplain

[X]Training With Apollo
-[X] Weapon Skill
[X] Train Your Chapter
-[X] Main: Ballistic Skill
--[X] Macharius Sicarius
-[X] Secondary: Weapon Skill
--[X] Apollo Diomedes
-[X] Secondary: Agility
--[X] Kaius Jacobus

[X] Probalis – Chief Librarian
-[X] Scry for the Dark Eldar with rest of the Librarium

[X] Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary
-[X] Implant second stage Neophytes and Psyker Neophytes with gene-seed (60 gene-seed)
-[X] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. (30 Geneseed)

[X] Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge
-[X] 2x Gladius-class Frigate (4 Minor Favors)
-[X] Improve the Forges Of
--[X] The Litany Of Fury [200/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn (300 BP)
-[X] Study The Rapier For Potential Learning Of Design To Allow Replication (50 BP)

[X] Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits
-[X] Enact Blood Trials Upon Two Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds
--[X] Calderis
--[X] Trontiux III

Bringing Fire To Darkness
+015.M42+ To +020.M42+
+Distrust The Xeno, Hate The Xeno, Kill The Xeno+

“There is…one,” Derosa sighs, rubbing at her temples as she sits behind her monolithic desk, a dozen servo-skulls darting around carrying parchment and pens for her to look at and sign. “Though he is a boorish individual.”

“Is that so, Governor?” you ask politely, standing of course as none of her furniture could possibly handle an armored space marine.

“He was convinced that we were to be married, once upon a time. Then his father died, he became the head of his House and I…well,” she smiles slightly, “I’ve become a Governor over an entire world.”

The name of the Rogue Trader who, as of yet, only rarely comes around Subsector Aurelia since Derosa snubbed his advances so long ago, is Claudius Alexandre Jullien Tarquindil. Of the House Tarquindil. Segmentum Ultima, as the least-settled of all the Segmentum by the Imperium, is rife with opportunity for one such as he who needs not follow many an Imperial law as he goes about his business. His business is largely, it seems, both rediscovering old human settlements to bring them the light of the Imperium, selling them technology at massively unfair prices for their ignorance, as well as perhaps dangerously diving into the grey market of xenos trading, both flesh and technology. Only the most exotic of things interest him, and yet he is more than a little mercurial. A perceived insult from a planetary governor a decade ago saw him abandon the entire Sector that the planet lied in forever from his trading routes.

It is, of course, wholly up to you as to whether or not you wish to speak with him in the first place.

==========================================

“Gabriel,” Adrastia hums as she looks you over. “I think that Subsector Aurelia has seen more Inquisitorial attention in a single century that some Sectors see in generations.”

“At the least this should be a more positive interaction,” you reply, though there is little humor in your voice.

“I should hope so. It would be a terrible shame for the Imperium if you’d called me here to report yet more issues amongst the Blood Ravens,” she drawls.

Even now, upon the Omnia Arcanum, she looks wholly unconcerned about making conversation involving the potential utter destruction of the Chapter. Then again, you had seen her match even Chaos Space Marines blow for blow with a power sword despite her exterior appearance. It was incredibly likely that she had many an enhancement that only an Inquisitor could afford to possess.

“It is, in fact, a gift for you,” you gesture behind you where Martellus slowly unfurls the cloth covering the Fusils.

Adrastia is on her feet and moving faster than you could catch before she is halfway towards the weapons, her ever present inferno pistol still flickering at her side.

“Hrud Fusils,” she hisses, and there is unmistakable interest and want in her voice as she runs her fingers over the weapons. “I had wondered if it might be possible to procure such in the aftermath of where I suspect you got these, but the Mechanicus got there first,” she pouts slightly before stepping back, eyes flicking to you. “They destroyed them all for being techno-heresy, or so they say. And yet you possess them.”

“Indeed. I have heard well that those of the Inquisition find them useful, while we of the Blood Ravens…,”

“Would do well to avoid open usage of such things considering the eyes upon the Chapter,” she flicks her hands away in casual dismissal, “Yes, yes I am aware. I am also aware that such a gift would not be given freely, would it.”

You consider it, and shake your head.

“Indeed.”

“Well,” she hums, tapping her finger alongside one, and then juts her chin out at her phalanx of black-armored troopers with the Inquisition’s symbol stamped in silver on their shoulders and helmets. “I wonder.”

One of them steps forward, silent as the rest of his brethren, and is promptly handed one of the weapons.

“Do you think you could use it, Merrick?” she tilts her head even as Martellus jerks slightly.

The stormtrooper takes off their helmet, to reveal the grizzled face of the alive Colonel Merrick, who lifts his chin at you in silent greetings before putting the weapon’s stock against his shoulder.

“Feels funny, but I figure I could use it, yeah.”

“Excellent,” Adrastia murmurs before looking at you, then at Martellus. “The identity of my retinue is, of course, classified in the extreme, yes?”

“She stole me off the battlefield, middle of a heart attack and kidney failure at the same time, and uh,” Merrick interjects, shrugging at his own remarkably youthful appearance, “Made me young again.”

“How could I not desire a soldier who has stared hive tyrants in the face without faltering, who defended against his own sworn brothers in blood when Vandis and Chaos came calling?”

In the end, of course, despite your surprise, Adrastia accepts your gifts without further questions though no doubt she has her suspicions. It is not the most incredible of things you could have given her, but she acknowledges your aid and the weapons well enough. She exits to a ship that could have been just a jet black strike cruiser, given the profile, except for the fact that it was missing a bombardment cannon, drop pod exits, and more that had instead been replaced with lance weaponry, torpedo bays, and likely much more weaponry and technologies that you could not even precisely see. The ink black vessel, only the massive silver symbol of its allegiance marking it, soon after disappears in the warp leaving you with only more questions and paranoia than you had before.

So, in the end, the usual for an encounter with an Inquisitor such as Adrastia.

============================================

The combat servitor blurted out a death oath to the Omnissiah in binary cant before it exploded, unfortunately ineffectually. Which, in this case, amounted to merely exploding a few orks rather than its main target. Shattered metal and sparking circuitry joined with the many, many piles of the rest of its kin, while the orks present toasted themselves with fungus rum, one even going so far as to light up a cigar as the congratulated themselves on another successful fight. The fact that every day their numbers dwindled more and more was happily ignored for the moment.

Of course, this changed when they heard the telltale noises of others coming through the single passage that remained into the former loading bay. Once it had looked out into the void, before collected rock and metal of a dozen ships and more had been crushed together in the physics-defying nature of the Warp for centuries and centuries on end.

“Aw, c’mon,” Bluddflag moaned, dragging himself to his feet once more, adjusting his hat. “More of you mekbo- oh ho! Space marines!” his voice lightened as he spoke, and the ork grunted as he raised his kutlass into a welcoming salute as the stomping and unmistakable suits of the beakies arrived before him.

“Bluddflag,” the leader amongst them called out, “The Blood Ravens have come for you.”

The Kaptin shrugged, and brushed off his shoulders with one hand before picking up his mega-shoota.

“You can give it a go, if you want. I’ll warn ya though, space marine,” he pointed at them with the kutlass, “I’ze killed yer kind before, spikey and un-spikey types.”

“Unfortunately for you, ork,” their leader said, before raising a hand and twitching its fingers, “I have learned more than enough from my time in the Deathwatch of one of the best ways to deal with your kind when in situations like this.”

“Oh yeah? How?”

“Like this,” Hamul grunted, and clenched his fist.

At which point, orks simply disappeared as seven assault cannons and ten cyclone missile launchers fired at once. Cover simply ceased to be, ancient metal deck plates torn up for defensive cover, scrap metal of long rusted and ruined aircraft and vehicles, and general detritus and debris alike all were obliterated completely and utterly. Terminators strode forward and slammed down storm shields, forming an impromptu shield wall, while their brothers continued to fire near endlessly. Only when the ammo for the assault cannons and missile launchers actually ran dry in an exorbitant display of firepower did they cease.

“Hurr,” Bluddflag staggered out of the inferno and to his knees, before weakly gesturing with his kutlass as he bled from over a hundred new holes in his chest, one leg gone entirely and his shoota-arm similarly torn apart. His hat was entirely non-existent save for a few scraps of black leather and cloth. “G-get ‘em boyz….show ‘em…what for…,” the Kaptain gurgled, one assault round having ripped through his throat and out the other side, exposing meat and spine to the open air.

Out of the still lifting smoke charged those few nobs that had survived by virtue of being the furthest back and the sheer weight of bodies in front of them. In turn, the assault terminators lifted their shields and engaged with their hammers, Hamul striding forth ahead of all of them straight towards Bluddflag. Uther’s own cries to the Emperor boomed out through the lonely halls of the Judgement of Carrion, where they would echo forever more long after the Chaplain had departed. More orks arrived, out of the ducts and having heard the signs of battle, only to be targeted by now reloaded cannons and launchers, while those who got close enough tasted fiery death.

“Dat…wasn’t…very sporting of you…beakie,” Bluddflag gasped up at Hamul, even managing to swing with some considerable force with his weapon only for the Champion to take a step back so that the power-field insured that it stabbed itself deep into the metal floor and stuck itself there.

“Orks have no honor. I will show them none. A lesson of the Deathwatch, ork,” the space marine noted calmly before rising up with his boot and then bringing it down onto the skull of the Kaptin at a resolute and steady pace, until there was nothing but wet meat and bone chips remaining.

“Why could the Mechanicus not deal with him themselves?” one of his brother spoke, one he knew not but who was of the Honor Guard, “That was no great battle.”

“They were busy with the madness of this place, and the vast amounts of tyranids and daemons that remain in it even now,” Uther answered for Hamul who himself had been curious. “They kept him contained fine enough, and would have gotten to him eventually.”

“I see. In any case, our task is done, let us-,” Hamul twisted at astonishing speed for one clad in Terminator-armor and grabbed a leaping lictor out of mid-air and slammed it down, lighting claws flashing as he tore it in half.

“Let us leave here, and return to the Chapter.”

====================================

“You are, all of you, now my Scout Marines,” Cyrus barked as he stalked back and forth across the deck.

It was not quite a stage, but rather a raised platform intended for just such a purpose as a near parade ground was constructed just so that the 10th Company could be taught and drilled as needed. Behind Cyrus stood the silent frames of the 10th Company, their armor recolored and heraldries changed to reflect their new positions. Some had been sergeants, others had not been, all were now here, silent and imposing behind him as he glared down at all fifty of his new recruits.

“You will fight. You will kill. Some of you,” he glanced at them, finding weakpoints already, those who were still struggling to make the full mental transition into a space marine, “Will die. But know this, even in death, you will serve the Emperor with your actions.”

He then stabbed a finger straight down, towards the planet below.

“Your first test, shall be to once more be reacquainted with what you once were, and so that they can see what they may someday be.”

All across the Chapter, some together, some ships far apart, did the Blood Ravens drill and train. Some for what was coming soon, in a battle with the vilest of xenos, and others simply so that they had the chance to become Blood Ravens in the first place.

[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 210+90+Apollo(29)=329/800]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill From 4 to 5: 465+50+Macharius(25)=540/500]
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill From 4 to 5: 97+30+Apollo(29)=156/500]
[Chapter Training – Agility From 4 to 5: 168+46+Kaius(25)=239/500]

========================

“Damn it.”

Martellus glared at the ruined piece of once-beautiful machinery. How hard could it possibly be, he had thought? Well, now he had learned. At the least, he had learned.

“I will not let your sacrifice be in vain, my friend,” he patted the heap of dissembled technology, and sighed before fiddling with another piece that squawked at him once before falling silent.

Saddened, he turned back to the forge itself surrounding him. Perhaps if he had just had better tools, a better facility? At the last it would help him from lamenting over the loss of a rapier once more, for surely if he simply did better its secrets would be fully revealed to him. One day, he would fix what he had inadvertently broken in his research, overeager as it had been.

Of course, first he needed to peruse the missives that the Mechanicus had sent. A list of things that could be done in exchange for the ships that the Chapter needed to rebuild…

=========================

“I can’t do it, I’m sorry,” Nero growls, blood pouring from his empty eye sockets. “They are eldar, if not of the Craftworlds. They are more adept at concealing themselves from sight through the materium and immaterium alike than orks or most cultists.”

“The whole of the Librarius has turned towards this,” Justinius turns towards you, blood trickling from one of his own eyes as well. “And we are finding ourselves stymied. One of the Lexicani was devoured from within after he peered too deeply into the warp, trying to find them.”

It is more than a little frustrating, to find even the psychic might of the Blood Ravens incapable of finding the foe in this instance. It is not as if it is impossible, for the warp is utterly unpredictable and cannot be trusted more often than not. It would have to be the eldar, regardless of the designation, that would be such an annoyance to what is still otherwise a long refined and trustworthy talent of your Librarius.

“There is another option,” Apollo suddenly speaks from beside you, drawing the attention of all who stand before the blazing beacon at the heart of the Litany of Fury.

“Apollo?”

“They are predators. We know, at the least, that they have at least four of their cruisers at the anchorage, though nothing about what remains inside. But they are eager for pain and torture, hunting,” he grunts before running a hand over his scalp. “They could be baited.”

It is a dangerous gamble.

One strike cruiser, deliberately made to appear as wounded, to draw out the Eldar. Then, once the Dark Eldar arrived, could you arrive in force and attack them. Those that fled, you would chase after instead of being forced to flee as Cyrus did before, and let them bring you to their Anchorage. It is either that, or once more attempt to have the Librarians pierce through their own anti-psychic defenses once more.

Results Of Part One
- Critical Success On Burning Bluddflag! Gladius Frigate and Honor Guard rejoins the fleet as it prepares to assault Dark Eldar Anchorage!
- New Potential Contact: Rogue Trader Claudius Alexandre Jullien Tarquindil (Xeno Artifact Specialist/Frontiersman Exploiter)
- 1 Minor Favor HELD - Adrastia's Appreciation (Ordos Hereticus Inquisitor Adrastia)

- 60 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 50 To Scout Marines [1st Stage], Remainder Expired. -60 Gene-Seed. +10 Gene-Seed.
- New Test-Slave Gene-Seed Harvest To Occur In 025.M42! -30 Gene-Seed
- Blood Trials Held On Calderis, And Trontiux III: +50 Aspirants, 2 Psyker Aspirants
- 5 Years Of Training/Struggle/Trials = 30 Aspirants Advance, 2 Psyker Aspirants Advance - 20 To Neophytes [1st Stage], 2 to Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage]
- 20 Neophytes [1st Stage]/2 Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 20 To Neophytes [2nd Stage]/1 Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage], Remainder Expired. Gene-Seed Implantation Required.
- 3 Techmarine Potentials Identified Amongst Current Scouts [1st Stage], 1 Apothecary Potential Identified Amongst Current Scouts [2nd Stage], No Chaplains Identified Currently
- 1 Rapier (Quad Heavy Bolters) Lost During Study. Reassembly May Be Later Possible. 50/??? Of Research Complete!
- Chapter Training: Ballistic Skill Cap Reached!
- Lexicani lost to possession and subsequent execution. -1 Lexicani.

Potentials Options (Choose One):
[] Send Off Techmarine Potentials and Apothecary Potential for training, immediately.
[] Hold off until later, you may need them as scouts for the moment.

Mechanicus Vote (Choose Whatever Combination You Wish To Achieve 4 Minor Favor Equivalence....Or More If You Wish):
Note: These forces will, hopefully, be alive to be assigned post-Anchorage Assault, though if not you can assign someone else to still finish the favor. They are not required to leave immediately, obviously.
[] Squad Protection - Zerann has recently come into possession of a brand new STC, brought forth from the reach of the Ghoul Stars. As they study it for potential later replication, they request that you dedicate a squad to its protection on their Forge World. Even with their own defenses, the knowledge that the space marines stand ready would still have benefits. Minor Favor - Dedicate single squad of 10 marines to task for 5 years (1 turn)
[] Veteran Squad Search - Theodosia, despite laying claim to Aerus, still finds many a place and rock left currently unturned. She is wondering if you could dedicate a strong veteran squad to aid her in the retrieval of potential archaeotech as well as generally providing protection to her less-martially inclined adepts. Much of her more militant assets are currently busying themselves with other duties. Minor - Dedicate single squad of 10 veteran marines to task for 5 years (1 turn)
[] Trontiux II Culling - Already have the orks of Trontiux II begun to rise again in number. The Mechanicus will not ever let them become a threat again. While the Knights are already present, Zerann would surely accept aid from the Blood Ravens once more in this matter, though it would more likely than not be a single squad required for the work. Minor Favor - Dedicate single squad of 10 marines to task/Assign 10th Company to task for simultaneous training of scouts for 5 years (1 turn)
[] Return Of Judgement [Crew Quarters] - The Judgement of Carrion is a deadly, deadly place. That Hamul escaped unscathed is astonishing in its own right. Yet the Mechanicus would ask of you, should you wish it, to assist them in further clearing of the hulk of the remaining orks and many tyranids and other things still within it. Minor Favor - Dedicate 2 squads of 10 marines to task, or 1 Squad of 10 Terminators for 5 years (1 turn)
[] Return Of Judgement [Gellar Field Installments] - The Judgement of Carrion is a deadly, deadly place. The Mechanicus is determined not to let it slip back into the Warp again. As such, they could use aid in setting up Gellar Fields across the ship to further separate it from the Warp which it is so very much attuned to. It will not be the first Space Hulk that they have reclaimed and turned to their usage, but they would prefer it if they did not have to continually lose so very, very many skitarii and servitors doing it. Apparently daemons do not like it when one attempts to remove their influence on things. Major Favor - May assign whatever forces deemed necessary. TERMINATORS RECOMMENDED! Warning! Daemons Are Likely Opponents For This for 10 years (2 turns)

Dark Eldar Anchorage Decisions (Choose One):
Note: The only forces of the Chapter not currently involved in this is the 10th Company.
[] Wounded Gambit: One strike cruiser, filled to technical over-capacity amounts of marines, pushed out as a wounded animal seeking refuge. Martellus believes he could make it somewhat believable, with the Librarius coating the serfs and ship itself in the psychic appearance in false terror and pain to draw the Dark Eldar in. Once they attack, you can attack them and let them flee to their precious Anchorage to be brought down fully.
[] Piercing Further: Let the Librarius continue their efforts, even if it may cost more time than you might need. For all you know, in the meantime the Dark Eldar might receive further reinforcements, retreat fully, or something else entirely. Thus far they have proven at least somewhat a bulwark against psychic abilities, but that does not mean they are inviolable.
[] Call In The Navy: Long ago, it was decided that the vast majority of Space Marine Chapters were to be kept from possessing the greater of void warfare ships and technologies, though some subverted this in their own ways. This is a void engagement, summon the navy. It may take them a while to come, but they likely will. Battlefleet Korianis is unlikely to want to allow a xeno Anchorage to be present, even in a previously unexplored area. Of course, what they might actually do is not precisely known either.
[] Write-In

Turn 17.5 - 2478 - Collegiate Interlude

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] Four Months [*] Intrigue and Tradecraft. (locked in) [*] The Nature of Ulgu [*] Spells of Grey Magic [*] Enchantment Once, you were a peasant girl who had known only the crude huts of her village; once, you were an apprentice that had a very small cell to herself with a hard bed and a tiny stove and a pet cat called Morr. But since then you have known both castles and tents, manors and barracks. You've experienced the best taverns of Wurtbad and the Moot and passed out in dingy roadside inns after a day of hard riding. The cell you're given as a graduating journeyman fails to appear on either extreme of your jaded palate. The bed is small but comfortable, there's a well-ventilated hearth, and there's a rope that can be pulled to summon one of the College staff, though it is a privilege very easily revoked if abused. Once more, you sink back into the hidden ecosystem of Collegiate life. A bustling staff of people whose job titles could be found nowhere but in a college exists everywhere you look; bedels and bursars and proctors and porters and provosts and dozens of other highly-specialized roles. The Wizards, too, shrug off the ranks of the outer world; nobody is introduced as Magister or Lord Magister here, but instead by the role they play in The Faculty. Professors and Readers and Lecturers and Docents and Tutors, and parallel to them, the librarians and curators. All of this exists primarily to impart knowledge to those such as you. It would be humbling, if you had time to think about it. But you don't. Four months, you've decided on - two to both practical and theoretical Ulgu, one to adding to your grasp of enchantment, and one dedicated to one-on-one tutoring with your Master as you go over the sudden and almost universally fatal disassembly of the organisation that once pulled your strings. --- The College operates on an apprentice system, but you never before realized how restricted that was to those below the rank of Magister. Once one reaches that rank, learning opportunities cease to come at the whim of your Master or the harried and hollow-eyed Substitutes that stand in when said Master is off doing gods only know what; they lie thick as autumn leaves and every time you stop to scoop one up three more have fluttered away. You cram your schedule; a lecture here, a dissertation there, an experiment on the nature of Ulgu when transmitted through various gases on the side and always plenty of library time as you try to use books to cement the gaps between the knowledge snatched from this dizzying array. It's not until several days in that you realize you can talk to those giving the presentations - not during them, of course, but you can ambush them in the hallway or track down their office and nine times in ten they're delighted to have someone to talk the ear off about their latest pet project. What you quickly learn is though you don't quite have the proper vocabulary of jargon, you do have a grasp of the nature of Ulgu that matches many and exceeds some that are giving these lectures; the conversations you have are interesting but often not educational, as those giving the talks spend several hours to get to a point that you grasp on an instinctive level. Still, it does help to better understand the underpinnings of the conclusions you reach without thought, which leads you to be better able to apply your magical insight. And you turn this newly strengthened insight on possibly the most important lessons of all: learning new spells. It's one-on-one, of course, and in a specially warded and reinforced room to hopefully minimize disaster, but you absorb knowledge at an impressive rate and shape the illusions as fast as they are taught to you. Mutable Visage is the instant makeover of a more materialistic girl's dreams, and Eye of the Beholder is focused around the mental manipulations you've used so well with Mindhole. With those absorbed in a few days apiece, your Master decides you might have earned something a bit more difficult, and the much more complicated structure of Mockery of Death is revealed to you. It takes twice as long, but as before, your intuitive grasp of Ulgu makes learning the spells straightforward, so your Master decides to push you further than ever before. Substance of Shadow, a spell with frankly astounding possibilities, is laid down before you, and your Master sits back to watch if you'll rise once more to the occassion. It's an observation you've made before: either because of your country background or some personal quirk, to you, Ulgu is more fog than shadow. Mastering a spell explicitly based around the shadow aspects of Ulgu presents some difficulty because of this; it just doesn't instinctively mesh in the way that's so familiar to you. Days turn to weeks as you try to visualize the strange warping of reality that the spell causes, until you finally reach a breakthrough that changes everything: shadow is the gate through which fog travels and changes states. A person or object passes through the ensorcelled shadow, and becomes not just invisible but also intangible until the spell runs its course or the person or object is illuminated. They are converted to an energy pattern not unlike fog which travels through the medium of shadow until ejected. From there, it's still most of a fortnight until you finally manage the spell, but it's with a glowing sense of accomplishment that you watch your Master confirm that the test crate has been converted to an ephemeral state. [Theoretical Ulgu: Learning, 39+18=47] [Windreader trait gains an additional +1 Learning] [Practical Ulgu: Learning, 84+19=102] [Rolling...] [Eye of the Beholder learned!] [Mutable Visage learned!] [Mockery of Death learned!] [Substance of Shadow learned!] [Sufficient spells learned - magic level has increased!] --- At first, you thought that there'd been some mistake and one of the College staff was cleaning the room, but before you can embarass yourself you realize that the man in front of you is your teacher, and he has eschewed the robes of office as unnecessary forewarning to those he hunts. He introduces himself as Mr Grey, which is possibly the worst alias you've ever encountered, and he explains his purpose here today: to break you of your reliance on the trappings of enchantment paraphernalia. You think he's going to teach you new enchanting techniques, and you smile in anticipation. Except what he actually teaches you is a suite of very specialized spells to do all the things your tools normally would. Ways of concentrating Ulgu to bend, reflect, or refract light, ways to craft very small and immobile illusions that act as lenses, a variant on the shadowknife he called a 'shadowchisel' to carve runes, a way of creating an illusory box that will allow sunlight in but not out, and a wide lens to concentrate a large area of sunlight into it, to build a tiny solar forge. All things that could be done significantly easier with your current workshop, and you do somewhat resent that he's presenting this to you after the time and effort you spent getting your hands on the items of your workshop. That said, you do pick up a lot of general knowledge about the art of enchantment along the way, and feel you're that much closer to reaching new heights of possibilities. [Enchantment Training: Learning, 96+19=115 [Rolling...] [Trait Gained: Tool-Free Enchanting! (Possibility 4 of 6)] --- The final quarter of your study is entirely between you and your Master: the postmortem of the organization that you helped your Master to take apart. You sit together by a fire, waiting for him to begin. And waiting. You clear your throat. "My student," he says, apparently apropos of nothing, "tell me what you know of the highest level of secrecy ratings." The sudden swerve in topic comes as a surprise, but you're used to thinking on your feet."Not much," you say. "It's when something is considered so secret that you're not even allowed to reveal that-" you pause, realising, and then continue the sentence "-that there is anything to be classified." "Correct," he says. The fire crackles as your Master stares into it, perhaps weighing how much could be communicated versus the danger in doing so. Then, he sighs. "Your progress is satisfactory. Return to your studies." There are no studies to return to; you earmarked this time for your lessons with your Master. But now there's nothing to discuss. Now, even filling that time gap could disturb the layer of secrecy that has apparently been put into place. It's immensely frustrating, but there's little you can do about it. When this level of secrecy is invoked, a month of learning is but the tiniest of sacrifices that can and will be made to it. You burn with curiosity as to what could have caused this, and it's likely you'll never know. Unless, of course, it blows up in everyone's face. [Internalizing Intrigue: 1] --- It is the beginning of what promises to be a long and exhausting process, and it begins, apparently, with you sitting at a desk and table in the center of an otherwise unadorned room, watched intently by a Proctor. You stare down at the sheet of paper; you scan the questions on it, you double-check the name at the top to make sure that you've got the right page, and yes, you're being asked to report on your own loyalties. That strikes you as somehow deeply unfair, and it's just the start. --- To the best of your knowledge, assess Journeywoman Mathilde Weber's level of dedication to a) the Grey College; b) the Empire; and c) humanity, factoring in her beliefs and motivations as well as any ties that bind her to the well-being of the above. [ ] (write in; can either be Mathilde's words verbatim or an outline of what she says) In the space below, describe your plans for the next five years (should you reach Magisterial rank). [ ] Seeking employ as an advisor to an Elector of the Empire. [ ] Seeking employ as an advisor in one of the Dwarfholds. [ ] Seeking adventure in the Zhufbar expeditions into Karak Varn. [ ] Seeking adventure in Belegar Ironhammer's reconquest of Karak Eight Peaks. [ ] Seeking adventure as a mercenary, ideally with Asarnil the Dragonlord, and possibly build a Mercenary Company of your own. [ ] Seeking adventure as the second coming of Nagash, searching for ways to overcome the final enemy of life. (you won't actually write this on the paper, but choose it if this is what you want Mathilde to do) [ ] Seeking knowledge by building a branch campus of the Grey College in Stirland, possibly on your estate. [ ] Seeking knowledge by investigating the phenomena and manifestations of Sylvania. And, finally, Should you reach Magisterial rank, you are expected to contribute to the wellbeing of the Grey College in the manner/s of your choosing. Select all of the below Collegiate Responsibilities that you are willing and able to perform. (omitting those you're unable to do or are ill-suited to any of your future plans) [ ] Enchantment Commissions (payment in cash) [ ] Enchantment Services (payment in College rep) [ ] Lectures and Demonstrations [ ] Tutoring [ ] Taking on Apprentices [ ] Interrogation [ ] Research and Development (thaumaturgical) (ie. stuff derived from Shyish-Kebabs and Qhaysh juice) [ ] Research and Cataloguing (biological) [ ] Being available to investigate reports of unsanctioned magic-users. [ ] Being available to intervene in matters of great import as needed - This is your eviction notice from limbo. It's time to choose what the future will hold for this quest. If your plans take you out of Stirland, you'll have a turn to wrap everything up so that it can continue and survive in your absence. - Keep in mind that while 'stay in one place and do nothing but research for the next half decade' might be a valid career option for Mathilde Weber, it would be really boring for both you, the reader and quester, and I, the writer and QM. - There isn't a 'wrong' choice for your career from the perspective of the Grey College. Each serves the Empire's purposes. - This was written as a whopper of a sleep debt started catching up with me so I apologize for any weirdly purple prose or grammar oddities. - If you've got a different idea for a direction for Mathilde's adventure to go in, chime in. - Nothing is in plans, just check whatever boxes you like. Sorry for the five or six times I changed my mind on how to do this; if there's anything left in the old formats when it comes time to tally I'll add them to the tallies manually.

Turn 18 - 2478.5 - Promotion

Spoiler: Winning Vote To the best of your knowledge, assess Journeywoman Mathilde Weber's level of dedication to a) the Grey College; b) the Empire; and c) humanity, factoring in her beliefs and motivations as well as any ties that bind her to the well-being of the above. [*] Plan Collegiate Loyalties -[*] Grey College - High --[*] Debt of gratitude for retaining sanity and health through being born with magic. --[*] Familial loyalty to Master --[*] Academic interest in the preservation and perpetuation of discoveries --[*] Self preservation in maintaining Wizard status within Empire for safety reasons. --[*] Ambition in maintaining access to College resources and knowledge for the purpose of self improvement in the field of magic. It is very unlikely to obtain knowledge of similar depth in any one area, and impossible to do so for broader areas. -[*] Empire - High --[*] Belief in the ideal of Mankind United under the Empire for the betterment of all. --[*] Obedience to the Laws of the Empire as the premier force for Order in the world. --[*] Oath to the Articles of Magic, to act in the interests of the Empire. --[*] Duty as a Wizard of the Grey College to obey the Grey College, transferred from duty of the Grey College to follow the lead of the collective Colleges, transferred from the collective Colleges loyalty to the Empire. --[*] Duty as a Knight of Stirland to the Elector Count of Stirland, transferred from the duty of the duty of the Elector Count to the Empire --[*] Self preservation from the Enemies of Man, Undead, Orc and Chaos would be free to wreak havoc without the intact Empire to protect its people from those. --[*] Practical utility in acquiring assets, equipment and common services requires the continuance of civilization. -[*] Humanity - Modest --[*] Religious beliefs mandate the protection and furtherance of humanity. --[*] Personal ethics seeks to minimize unnecessary harm to humanity in general. In the space below, describe your plans for the next five years (should you reach Magisterial rank). [*] Seeking adventure in Belegar Ironhammer's reconquest of Karak Eight Peaks. [*] Seeking adventure in the Zhufbar expeditions into Karak Varn. (due to how close these two were, there will be a vote to decide between these two) Should you reach Magisterial rank, you are expected to contribute to the wellbeing of the Grey College in the manner/s of your choosing. Select all of the below Collegiate Responsibilities that you are willing and able to perform. [*] Being available to intervene in matters of great import as needed [*] Research and Development (thaumaturgical) (ie. stuff derived from Shyish-Kebabs and Qhaysh juice) [*] Interrogation [*] Being available to investigate reports of unsanctioned magic-users. It's a product of a great deal of thought and you have to start over a few times after crossing out too much of the paper to remain legible, but eventually you're left with a finished report on your own loyalties: Grey College - High - Debt of gratitude for retaining sanity and health through being born with magic. - Familial loyalty to Master - Academic interest in the preservation and perpetuation of discoveries - Self preservation in maintaining Wizard status within Empire for safety reasons. - Ambition in maintaining access to College resources and knowledge for the purpose of self improvement in the field of magic. It is very unlikely to obtain knowledge of similar depth in any one area, and impossible to do so for broader areas. Empire - High - Belief in the ideal of Mankind United under the Empire for the betterment of all. - Obedience to the Laws of the Empire as the premier force for Order in the world. - Oath to the Articles of Magic, to act in the interests of the Empire. - Duty as a Wizard of the Grey College to obey the Grey College, transferred from duty of the Grey College to follow the lead of the collective Colleges, transferred from the collective Colleges' loyalty to the Empire. - Duty as a Knight of Stirland to the Elector Count of Stirland, transferred from the duty of the Elector Count to the Empire - Self preservation from the Enemies of Man, Undead, Orc and Chaos would be free to wreak havoc without the intact Empire to protect its people from those. - Practical utility in acquiring assets, equipment and common services requires the continuance of civilization. Humanity - Modest - Religious beliefs mandate the protection and furtherance of humanity. - Personal ethics seeks to minimize unnecessary harm to humanity in general. You'd almost listed your loyalty to the Grey College as higher than your loyalty to the Empire before you'd remembered the first line of the Articles of Imperial Magic that dictates it should be the other way around. The Proctor watches you serenely the entire time, supplying new pieces of paper when requested. The other questions prove almost as tricky. You've got an urge to adventure with the dwarves, who've proven more pleasant company than most humans you've encountered, but you're split between the literal call to adventure that Belegar Ironhammer has given with the crusade to retake Karak Eight Peaks, and the more modest but also more nearby recurring raids into the mines of Karak Varn, so you keep it vague and say you'll be working with dwarves with a view to retaking lost holds or at least the treasures within them. Finally, for your Collegiate Duties: you put yourself down for thaumaturgical research and development (though part of you flinches at the thought of going through what you did with the Matrix paper again), investigating reports of unsanctioned magic use, and offer your services as needed for interrogation or for matters of great import. When you finally finish your response to the questions, the Proctor takes them without comment and they're taken away into the depths of the College for, you're sure, careful examination. Meanwhile, you're taken to the carefully warded and reinforced room usually reserved for apprentices to fumble with magic and told to demonstrate every spell at your disposal, with the help of a volunteer from the menial staff. [Magical demonstration: Magic, 72+15=87] [Endurance: Magic, 37+15=52] You run through them without difficulty, even those you learned only within the last few months, and you only start to flag as you feel the depletion of the local Winds right at the end. The door opens and you're thanked for your cooperation by one of the observers who were watching through the grille on the door, while the rest remain occupied with the notes they were jotting down. The utterly befuddled volunteer who was the target of your spells is taken off to have a lie-down. It's not nearly the end of your spellcasting testing, as you're called upon to use the spells under every conceivable circumstance, and then given various scenarios and told to use whatever magic you wish to get through them. 'Guards' are snuck past, incapacitated, and otherwise tormented in a hundred different ways as you demonstrate your grasp of the spells you're capable of. You're given a letter and told to deliver it to a man waiting just inside the gates of Nuln; you're back before lunch and given a great many suspicious looks until a raven familiar delivers word that your letter has reached the recipient. You demonstrate your ability to channel Ulgu through weapons without any visible spellcraft, and more notes are taken. You're placed in an empty room with nothing but a candle, a torch and a fireplace, and the flickering of each is carefully observed and even more notes are made. You're told to watch as the Proctors cast spells, and then determine what is cast. They start off with the familiar rote spells, then move on to more esoteric ones, and finally wizards from other Colleges are brought in and you're left doing your best to calculate results based on the movement and reaction of the Winds around the caster. The tests move away from magical ability and senses and into more esoteric parts of being a Grey Wizard. You're made to debate a number of different topics, some of them topical and some of them nonsensical; some days you're talking about geopolitical relations with Bretonnia and the situation with Marienburg, and others you're championing the argument that Hochland doesn't actually exist. Your lack of finesse with wordplay is made up for by your ability to grasp the salient details of whatever the situation at hand is, and you feel you manage to conceal the fact that diplomacy is among the least of your strengths. You're also called upon to recite the Articles of Imperial Magic, as well as to explain your understanding of them at length. Then they give you assignments based on more underhanded approaches, and you can't conceal a grin. A volunteer among the nobility is told to conceal three tokens somewhere in his house and instruct his guards to yell 'seen' instead of drawing steel if they spot an intruder, and you turn the place over without disturbing even the dog napping in front of the smouldering fire and find all three tokens as well as evidence that said noble is being a little bit cheeky regarding his tax obligations. You're given a five minute head start and told to hide before three of the Proctors start hunting you; four days later the town criers start broadcasting a request that you report to the College, and you say goodbye to the grocer you had been working for as Alys Schmidt and report smugly back. In what is apparently a tradition dating back to the founding of the Colleges, you sneak into the University of Altdorf and steal a full-size anatomical skeleton model while an exam is being taken in that very room. Judging by the guards they placed, you're not the first, and judging by how easily you bypassed them, you won't be the last. The annual drill for the Imperial Palace is underway, and you're told to try your best to get into position to threaten the life of the man representing the Emperor and given three attempts. The first ends in the Great Hall with you fighting off three of the Reiksguard (all of you armed with wooden swords, of course, and laying down upon receiving 'fatal' wounds) before five more turn up and force your surrender. The second ends in a rooftop chase where your flight from guards is interrupted by a wax bullet that gives you a nasty bruise along your ribs, but you had managed to reach a window that overlooked where the ersatz Emperor was taking his lunch, though you only caught a glimpse as he was hurried out a door by alarmed guards. On the third, you enter via one of the towers and find your way to one of the Palace's many kitchens and spread little green tokens to represent poison through much of the food, and then almost manage to charge your way past the guard on the door to the Emperor's bedroom, and there's a great deal of discussion and business with measuring tapes as those overseeing the exercise try to decide whether you had made it into a theoretical bomb's blast radius range of where the target had been lying. The Reiksguard are picking green tokens out of their meals for weeks to come, and the Palace sends a grudging thankyou to the Grey Order that is passed on to you as a souvenir. [Spell flexibility: Learning, 80+19=99] [Magical senses: Magic, 58+15=73] [Debates - diplomatic skill: Diplomacy, 21+10=31] [Debates - grasp of material: Learning, 99+19=118] [Intrigue test: 93+19=112] Finally, the day comes when you are to meet one of the examiners in a duel. The arena is a sunken pit thirty yards across, dimly lit by two low-burning lamps. Your opponent is a man in his forties, who is rather put out when the duel begins with a wax bullet to the chest knocking him sprawling. There's some discussion amongst the Proctors, and it's determined that while your quickdraw was very impressive and your victory has been noted, it didn't give them a very good idea of the breadth of your abilities, so another duel shall be performed. The second begins, predictably enough, with your opponent vanishing from sight; you check your senses, determine there's no foreign influence on your mind, and watch the Winds carefully, for the movements of him disturbing them or the drawing in of him casting a spell. The moment Ulgu begins concentrating, you unleash bullet and spell and a cry signals that one of them has connected, but that he doesn't declare the duel over indicates it must have been non-vital. You use the distraction to mask yourself in Ulgu, covering yourself in spells to make you hard to see and hard to notice, and the two of you circle the arena warily, moving close to keep from emitting sound or disturbing the Winds. The room is so quiet you can hear the scratch of quill on paper from the observers above, and you breathe as shallowly as you can. What finally gives you away, you determine after, is the lamp on the wall flickering as you approach; a fan of black knives emerges from Ulgu and is sent to you, and one of them - blunted, of course, in a minor modification of the normal spell - bounces off your ribs, and though the enchantment of your robes prevents any damage it does give away your position and you duck as an invisible wooden sword is jabbed through the space where your chest was. You scramble away, each time the sword passing so close to you you can hear it, and he remains hot on your heels as he pursues you through the room. You're moving too quickly to be silent and you can't slow down or his sword will catch you, and you can't even see it to parry. It has to end eventually, and it does painfully as you duck into the sword and catch it across the throat. You collapse on the floor, gasping for breath as the spells you were holding shatter, and you wave off your suddenly-visible opponent as he tries to assist you. You're fine, but if that sword was live steel you'd be dead. It's a sobering reminder that as good as you've become, there are still people better than you. You held out well, you force yourself to admit. Even without the first duel, you did inflict a minor wound, remained unseen through the mutual stalking, and when he found you it took him a while to make it stick. [Initial moments: 97 vs 27+10=37] [Take two: 34 vs 7+10=17] [Cat and mouse: 64 vs 51+10=61] [Someone has to blink: 73 vs 79+10=89] [Scramble: 88 vs 82+10] [Try to recover: 1 vs 60] And the Proctors evidently agree. When next you're led into one of the countless small rooms you've been tested in, you find yourself before a man you've laid eyes only a few times previously: the legendary Algard, Magister Patriarch of the Grey Order and one of the foremost magical researchers in the history of the Colleges. His surprisingly young-looking face peers out at you between his grey hood and his pale blue scarf, and he leans on his skull-topped staff to support himself. "Ah, Weber. Dame Weber, no less." "A pleasure to meet you, Lord Algard," you greet him, trying to ignore your nerves. He smiles, swirling grey eyes twinkling from under stormcloud-grey hair. "Likewise. This is not the first time you've come to my attention; first the matter with the Knighthood, then there's that wonderful Matrix of yours. The Jade Order are close to adapting it for themselves, and the Amber are working on it. Where did you get the idea for it?" You consider lying for half a second, then spend several more considering how terrible an idea it would be. "The magical framework was created by trial and error, but the idea itself was based on a Dhar construct inside the minions of the necromancer claiming to be the heir of the von Carsteins." "Interesting," he says, showing no sign of judgement. "Any differences between the two?" "The Dhar construct would corrode and unleash the spell it held if not maintained every few days, but the Ulgu Matrix appears to last indefinitely - I had a test subject hold the Matrix within it for over a year with no sign of weakening. I theorise that it leeches a tiny amount of ambient magic to sustain itself." "More proof, if more is needed, of the inherent flaws of Dhar," he says, half to himself. "I look forward to what further discoveries you may make. Third, you came to my attention during the Sieges of the Drakenhofs. Did you ever discover what it was that the late Hexensohn was looking for?" You shake your head. "I had other priorities." He nods. "Of course. Needs must. I'll bring it up with his successor at some point." He gazes into the distance, his eyebrows furrowed. "What were we... oh, yes. It is my pleasant duty to inform you that the Grey College has seen fit to bestow upon you the rank of Magister, along with all responsibilities and privileges thereof." He nods to his staff. "We used to give a staff to commemorate, but the previous Turner passed away and none have shown the ability and inclination to take it up. So I'm afraid all I can offer you to commemorate the occasion is my congratulations." You stand there silent for a moment, taken aback by the abruptness. "I was expecting something more," you admit. He nods. "The other Orders, no doubt, fill this moment with pomp and ceremony. But we are the Grey Order. Our work is rarely seen and even rarer appreciated. Temper your expectations accordingly. A job performed well needs to be its own reward, for we so rarely see any other." "I see," you say. He smiles. "Look on the bright side. We get to slit open reality's underside and meddle with the steaming guts that spill forth, and we're no longer burned at the stake for it. There's been precious few throughout the history of humanity that can claim the same." He pats your shoulder and hobbles out of the room, leaning on his staff for support. You stand there and digest the words, before turning and following and being met by your exuberant Master. Well. Former Master. It will take some time to get used to calling him Regimand. --- A night of celebratory excess later, you're making your fragile and hungover way back to Stirland, slumped over the neck of your shadowhorse. There's much to be done before you venture off, as well as the final decision to be made of which dwarven adventure you'll set off on. +1 College Favour - Mathilde's Mystical Matrix +1 College Favour - Matrix adopted by Jade Order! +1 College Favour - Matrix adopted by Amber Order! +1 College Favour - Graduated to Magisterial Rank +2 College Favours - Proctors Impressed +2 College Favours - Won Duel [ ] Zhufbar regularly sends salvaging parties into Karak Varn and mining parties into the tunnels below. It will be close enough to Stirland to keep in touch, and you have a good reputation in Zhufbar especially. [ ] Belegar Ironhammer has sent word that any that wish to seek their fortune are welcome to join him in retaking Karak Eight Peaks. While it is far from the civilized lands of the Empire, the treasure, the glory, and the adventure will be all the greater. What will you be doing with these items? Shyish swords: [ ] Donate them to the Amethyst Order (+2 College Favours) [ ] Return them to the barrow you originally got them from. [ ] Leave them stored in your spare room. Mirrorcatch Box: [ ] Leave it behind; have Heideck come in and replace the containers as they fill. [ ] Bring it with you, doing what you can with padding and cushions to protect it. Liber Mortis: [ ] Leave it safely in your Sunken Palace. [ ] Bring it with you, safely locked within the enchanted box Abelhelm kept it in. Pick FIVE of the below; you can take up to two extra actions as Overwork - if you do, mark them accordingly. All of your Organizations can be safely 'ignored' if you desire - they will continue operating as they have been. Spoiler: Organizational Actions The Weber Estate Earmarked Funds: 916 gc Estate Profits: 20 gc / turn You can spend money instead of turns here to have someone else oversee the work; this will increase the cost by half again, and double any dwarf rep cost. For instance, an option costing 100 gc will cost 150 gc. It also means that your personal stats will not apply to whatever is being done. [ ] Seek and hire a steward to manage and improve the fief in your absence. (100 gold to pay them for the projected duration of your absence) [ ] Build a relation with the local community leader so that either he or someone else from the community can perform the duties of a steward. (cannot be outsourced) [ ] Build a modest home for yourself, equal in size to the rooms you're using in the Sunken Palace (3 rooms, 50 gc). [ ] Build a large home for yourself, with plenty of spare rooms to expand into (6 rooms, 150 gc). [ ] Why muck about? Build a proper manor (10 rooms, 300 gc). [ ] Build a tower, either into an above structure or on its own (1 room, 100 gc, bonus to room's purpose). [ ] Build fortifications into your home, turning it into a hillfort, or motte (50 gc for wood, 200 gc for stone, optional dwarf help for -1 dwarf rep). [ ] Build a bailey for your subjects to shelter in and to encompass other structures (100 gc for wood, 400 gc for stone, optional dwarf help for -1 dwarf favours). [ ] Have the dwarves build you a fortress. (1000 gc, -2 dwarf rep. Protects but does not build living area. No, there is no cheaper option. If you want cheap, get manlings to build it.) [ ] Bring in dwarvern prospectors to search for minable metals (-1 dwarf favours) [ ] Bring in dwarvern farmers to investigate the farming possibilities of the land. (-1 dwarf favours) [ ] Improve the road between the Estate and Sonningwiese (50 gc) [ ] Establish upkeep of the roads between the estate and the individual households. (cannot be outsourced) [ ] Purchase a loom, erect a building for it, and invite weavers to start calling your estate home. (100 gc) [ ] Set up a dairy and recruit skilled cheesemakers from among the locals to work in it. (100 gc) The Eastern Imperial Company Outstanding Debt: 1,340 gc Your share of EIC Profits: 60 gc / turn Wilhelmina's Current Focus: Expanding into Southern Stirland. [ ] Use your reputation to build trade ties with Zhufbar. [ ] Use your reputation to build trade ties with Karak Kadrin. [ ] Use your friendship with Anton to build trade ties along the Nuln Road. [ ] Expand the EIC into Sonningwiese; this is unlikely to increase profits, but would indirectly improve the lot of your subjects. [ ] Have the EIC print and sell a second edition of Asarnil's memoirs. [ ] Investigate whether Ostermark is building a Talabec-Stir canal near Karak Kadrin. [ ] Have dwarves do a surface survey of the Haunted Hills in anticipation of a land sale (-4 dwarf favours; will be mostly pointless if the land is given over to a Count or Baron instead of sold individually) (does not take an action) [ ] Survey the Haunted Hills for sites rich in Ulgu for the EIC to buy on your behalf if the land goes on the market. [ ] Spend some time getting to know Wilhelmina's sons. Gong Farmers Currently Revenue Neutral due to supporting the Niter Factory. They can and will continue their operations in your absence. [ ] Fold them into the EIC; no need for you to have personal control of them. (no action needed) [ ] Formalize and organize the payments people make for the Gong Farmers to perform their service. [ ] Expand the Gong Farmers into the rest of Western Stirland. [ ] Create market gardens outside the walls of Wurtbad, fertilized with the solid waste collected by the Gong Farmers. [ ] No longer linked to the Watch, the Gong Farmers might be vulnerable. Arm and train them so they can defend themselves in the sewers. Niter Factory Goods currently unsold; costs covered by Gong Farmers. It would be a very good idea to organize a buyer for the produced crystals before you leave, or to unburden yourself of control of the factory. [ ] Fold it into the EIC. (no action needed) [ ] Sell the factory itself. [ ] Sell the produced niter crystals to Nuln. [ ] Sell the produced niter crystals to Zhufbar. [ ] Sell the produced niter crystals as fertiliser in Stirland. [ ] Sell the produced niter crystals as fertiliser to the Moot. [o] Investigate the rest of the process for making gunpowder. (not enough time to follow through before you leave) [o] Bring in dwarven experts to expand the factory to produce gunpowder. (-5 Dwarf Favour) (not enough time to follow through before you leave) Spoiler: Personal Actions Personal Actions Personal Wealth: 356 gc Living expenses: 10 gc / turn Self-Improvement: [ ] Internalized Lessons: If you've been using a particular trait a fair bit in the last year, you can spend some time on it to internalize what you've learned and increase the trait (choose which trait; can be taken multiple times; will be more effective the more you've used the trait lately). [ ] Practice, Practice, Practice: If you haven't been using a particular trait lately, you can try to practice it anyway. [ ] Combat Training In The Free Market: The war cost you your combatant friends, but training is always for sale. Go out and buy some. (-20 gc) Home Comforts: Your Palace-Shrine is bursting with potential, and no longer with mud. [ ] Filled with Potential: You've got four rooms cleared out and ready to be put to use. Decide what you're going to put in one of them and get started on equipping it. (write in the purpose of the room) Research: [ ] Expand your library to cover a new subject or go deeper into an existing one (choose which; -50 gc). [ ] Condense the information collected during the Purge of the Haunted Hills into a single tome to be added to the collected knowledge of the College. [ ] Volatility: Examine how to move your various fragile and magically sensitive bits and pieces without endangering them. [ ] Shyish-kebabs: The Shyish swords are hideously dangerous as weapons, but fascinating as a subject of study. Try to reverse-engineer the lost enchantments woven into them. [ ] Qhaysh Juice: Whatever it is, it's dripping out of the box at a steady rate. You've got several gallons of the stuff and it's still coming out. It's got to be good for something. [ ] There's always room for more shadow spells in your repertoire. Send off to the Grey College for the basics on one of the others and get started on trying to learn it. [ ] Your experience with the so-called Fog of War has given you a lot of ideas for new applications of Ulgu. Investigate them to see what might be possible. [ ] Read the Liber Mortis. Enchantment: [ ] Imbue an item with a petty or lesser magic. (specify item and spell) [ ] Attempt to imbue an item with a Relatively Simple spell. (specify item and spell) [ ] Advance your understanding of enchantment even further. (unlocked by College study) Influence: [ ] Thieves Guild: It's currently little more than a church group, albeit of a very unconventional god. If it could be expanded under your aegis, it could be a powerful tool - especially considering you no longer have official power. Relations: [ ] The New Boss: Keep an ear to the ground, learning what you can of Roswita's actions and plans. [ ] The New Spymaster: Witch Hunter Lucas von Salkalten currently fills your position. As per the Articles of Imperial Magic, wizards owe assistance to the Templars of Sigmar if they can prove they need it. Drop by to offer it freely instead. [ ] Getting To Know You: Spend time with someone, offering your help in their tasks and generally getting a feel for them (choose one) (can be taken multiple times). [ ] Getting To Know You Whether You Like It Or Not: Trust, but verify. Spend some of your time seeing what a certain person spends their time doing (choose one) (can be taken multiple times). [ ] Free Time: Now well-established in Wurtbad, you can spend some time in your scant off hours getting to know someone better. Pick one character. (does not take an action) [ ] Farewell: Visit everyone you've gotten to know during your time in Stirland, let them know where you're off to, and say auf wiedersehen. (does not take an action, incompatible with Free Time) Familiar: You've grown much in power; it might be time for you to seek a familiar. Animals that are suitable to be familiars are incredibly rare. You can hunt for them and spent a great deal of time doing so, or you can buy one for an agonizing price. Or you could make one. [ ] You'll have a cat, damn it. Spend time with the alley cats of Wurtbad and see what you can find. (low chance) [ ] Wander the streets of Wurtbad and see if any animal jumps out at you. (moderate chance, could be any tame or feral animal) [ ] Spend some alone in the woods. What could go wrong? (high chance, but no telling what animal would be. chance of dangers in the woods) [ ] Travel to Altdorf and see what suitable animals are for sale. (will cost 300-600 gc; can decide not to purchase if you don't like the type or look of the animal. Options for loans or dipping into EIC/earmarked funds will be available if you can't afford it) [ ] Why trust in nature or the free market? You'll damn well make your own familiar. (50 gc, resulting familiar is unpredictable in appearance and will be visibly unnatural). Spoiler: College Actions Study: As a Magister, you're no longer barred from returning to the Grey College. If you've been pulling your weight for the Order, you can return to it to further your studies. Each costs 1 College Favour. Practical [ ] Intrigue and Tradecraft. [ ] The Use and Creation of Poison [ ] Spells of Grey Magic (teachers' choice; multiple spells) [ ] Spells of Grey Magic (your choice; one spell) [ ] Swords and Swordplay [ ] Ritual Magic [ ] Psychology [ ] Imperial Law [ ] Practical Diplomacy Theory [ ] The Nature of Ulgu [ ] The Nature of Magic [ ] The Enemies of Man [ ] The Allies of Man [ ] Religion and the Empire [ ] The Empire and its Provinces [ ] Human Nations of the Old World [ ] Chaos and Chaos Gods Extracurricular [ ] Enchantment [ ] Potions and Alchemy [ ] Power Stones and their Creation [ ] Runes and Runecraft [ ] Wyrdstone Containment [ ] On the Education of Apprentices [ ] Searching for and Identifying Animal Familiars [ ] The Creation of Artificial Familiars Commissioning an Enchantment (does not take actions) [ ] Relatively Simple enchantment (two favours) [ ] Moderately Complicated enchantment (three favours) [ ] Fiendishly Complex enchantment (five favours) Apologies, but there's no easy way to do this: The difficulty of a spell is based on the casting number in Realm of Sorcery; if the casting number is a single digit, it's Relatively Simple. If it's between 10 and 19, it's Moderately Complicated. If it's 20+, it's Fiendishly Complex. I ask those with access to the book to highlight interesting possibilities for those that do not. If you want something more complex than spell in item, outline what you're looking for and I'll give it a pricetag. - Due to taking an extra month of study before your exams, you have five instead of six actions this turn. - College favours is also the currency for making requests from other Orders; if there's any you have in mind, let me know. For reference, it would cost 2 favours for a simple enchanted item. - I'll make a new thread or change the title or something to something more suited once the adventure begins. - The Steward is not a clever way to bypass the 50% surcharge on tasks you don't oversee personally. They'll be hiring the same Managers you would be to perform the task. The point of them is to invest any leftover funds when you leave and the income in the meantime.

Turn 16: Bringing Fire To Darkness (Part Two)

Spoiler: Plan Space Hulk 2: Terminator Boogaloo

[X] Plan Space Hulk 2: Terminator Boogaloo
-[X] Send Off Techmarine Potentials and Apothecary Potential for training, immediately.

Spoiler: Post-Anchorage Conflict Decisions

-[X] Squad Protection
--[X] 5th Company Tactical Squad
-[X] Veteran Squad Search
--[X] 9 5th Company Veterans, Codicer Nero to search for uncorrupted tech
-[X] Trontiux II Culling
--[X] 10th Company
-[X] Return Of Judgement [Crew Quarters]
--[X] Marcus Crixus (Stormbolter), Uriel Hamul (Thunder Hammer/Storm Shield), Ares Actus (Crozius/Stormbolter), Marcharius Sicarius (Power Fist), Amicus Antal (Powerfist/Stormbolter), 5 1st Company Veterans
---[X] 5 Tartaros-Pattern for named characters, 5 Indominatus-Pattern for others, applicable relics
----[X] 2 Heavy Flamers, 1 Assault Cannons, 1 Pair of Lightning Claws, Thunder Hammer, 1 Power Axe, 2 Power Fists, 3 Cyclone Missle Launchers
------[X] Marcus's terminator group and 1st Company to join Gabriel Angelos on Gellar Field assingment after completion of purging the Crew Quarters
-----[X] 1st Company Squad plus apothecary to wait in support
-[X] Return Of Judgement [Gellar Field Installments]
--[X] Gabriel Angleos, Apollo Diomedes, Hannibal Palrun, Uther, Tarkus Varianus, Justinius Probalis, Damion Tyrin, Doukas Laskaris, 20 1st Company Terminators
---[X] 5 Tartaros-Pattern armors for Apollo, Tarkus, Justinius, Hannibal, and Doukas. 22 Indominatus-Pattern to everyone else. Applicable relics
----[X] All other Flamers, Assault Cannons, Plasma Cannons, and melee weapons. Stormbolters to those without a specialist weapon. 5 Cyclone Missle Launchers
-----[X] Honor Guard and 1 5th Company squad plus apothecary to wait in support

-[X] Call In The Navy: Long ago, it was decided that the vast majority of Space Marine Chapters were to be kept from possessing the greater of void warfare ships and technologies, though some subverted this in their own ways. This is a void engagement, summon the navy. It may take them a while to come, but they likely will. Battlefleet Korianis is unlikely to want to allow a xeno Anchorage to be present, even in a previously unexplored area. Of course, what they might actually do is not precisely known either.

Bringing Fire To Darkness
+015.M42+ To +020.M42+
+Distrust The Xeno, Hate The Xeno, Kill The Xeno+

“In all my years, I never thought to see the mighty space marines beg for help,” sneers the mustachioed Admiral as he glares down at you.

It is not that he is, in fact, somehow taller than the Angels of Death in armor, rather that upon the communicator system his holo-image is projected as to be massive in comparison. Indeed, all you can see of him is from the waist up, which happens to be liberally coated in enough medals and ribbons to likely count as their own armors. Also potentially just his preference, for based on even some small amount of time speaking to one of the Admirals of Battlefleet Korianis you suspect that he is, in fact, much smaller than even an average human being based on the serfs all around you. In either case, Admiral Whitmore came rapidly after the initial astropath communications, meaning that he only took a few months rather than years and years thanks to the nearness of his ships and as he has stated more than once, ‘his magnanimousness and lack of otherwise pressing concerns’.

You do not believe that you like this man.

“Yes, you have repeated this more than once, Admiral Whitmore.”

He sneers again, before leaning forward, his jowls jiggling as he does what is likely meant to be intimidating.

“I do not trust you, Chapter Master Angelos. I trusted Chapter Master Kyras, the whole Sector trusted Kyras,” he sniffs, even as you feel Hadrian, Apollo, and the rest of the Honor Guard present on the bridge tense. “And here you come now, asking me to send my ships into unexplored space, to fight eldar who might not even be there? Why should I ever commit my cruisers to this, I ask of you?”

The sheer audacity before you is almost stunning, were you not perfectly aware of how tremendously weak your political position is not just in the Imperium but even in Korianis itself. Kyras himself fostered the extremely political nature of the Chapter’s leadership, Apollo personally partook in it, ensuring that it was not simply martial strength and true deed, but politics which decided who ascended. In truth, perhaps that is why you spent so much time taking your Company in the farther ranges of the Imperium to get away from it all. Yet perhaps if you had remained, you would have seen the deep corruption that was allowed to sink into the chapter. It is that dabbling, that focus on politics, which entrenched Kyras’ touch and name deep into the Sector Command, even all the way into Krasus itself.

You will be dealing with the repercussions of his machinations for a long, long time. This is only more evidence of it.

“Because the Inquisition has declared us pure,” you respond, your tone even as a not small part of you desires to wrap your hands around his throat for his insults. “I can refer you to either Inquisitor Mordecia Toth…or Inquisitor Adrastia,” you tilt your head slightly at her name, “I believe she recently departed the Sector Capital.”

He stiffens at the word of her organization, and further at her name. It is useful indeed that Merrick mentioned offhand their next destination as he was exchanging honored greetings with Martellus and Cyrus before donning his faceless helmet and departing into the unknown behind her. Truly an interesting man. You do believe that he would have made quite the space marine if he had not gone into the Imperial Guard.

“Be-be that as it may,” he blusters, “What, precisely, are you expecting us to do, hmm? Simply charge in for you while you step back and watch us die?”

One of the nearby serfs, a failed Scout Marine whose body was simply unable to withstand the implantation of the latter organs and was thus rejected for gene-seed implantation, visibly makes choking motions at his console, as if to strangle some specter in front of him. He also apparently did not become a space marine due to his odd quirks, but you suppose on some level you can understand his offense at Admiral Whitmore’s very presence.

“We would aid you, obviously,” you reply with a steady slowness. “But as determined in ages long past, it is the Imperial Navy which shall be the truest masters of void combat, whilst the space marines…are not.”

“And yet,” he raises a coiffed eyebrow, “There are Nova-class frigates within your Chapter Fleet. A bit of a contradiction, wouldn’t you say?”

“Only if we were not a Chapter who is based not upon a world but in the void itself.”

The back and forth continues for a few minutes more, but invoking the name of the Inquisition for the Chapter’s good name, an odd thing but one possible now due to the fact that it is simply factual and to deny the judgements of the Inquisition as sound and correct is heretical in the extreme for many…he agrees. His fleet is rallied, and prepares itself to plunge into battle once more, not simply to slay the xeno but to protect mankind. A noble mission in both descriptor and reality itself. Behind him comes the Chapter Fleet, unified together once more. While the 10th Company would be leaving after this for Trontiux II, they come with you as well. Two more strike cruisers, while again not nearly meant for prolonged void engagements as the Imperial Navy’s vessels are still a reasonably powerful boon.

=========================

The arrival of so many Imperial vessels into Faiyuum had sent shockwaves through the warp, and with that done the ripples managed to for lack of a better word bounce off of a void in space where the warp broke around. It amounted to a lack of sheer tonnage, which even had the entire Chapter gone as one would not have been possible but was tipped over by the arrival of so many Imperial vessels with the addition of Whitmore’s fleet. His various cruisers had burst forth out of the warp, their attendant escorts following, and apparently sensing that the time for simple ambushes were past, the Dark Eldar turned to fight like the arrogant aliens they were.

With your own Librarium, Nero and Justinius especially, working alongside the collated auspex scans of both fleets, as well as the astropaths and sanctioned psykers on Whitmore’s fleets a more comprehensive plan of attack is devised. Which, in truth, amounts largely to Whitmore driving his vessels forth into the system, right at where the otherwise still invisible Anchorage is present. He is not happy exactly with it, but when it comes to the eldar to play games when you otherwise have the sheer striking force to crush them it is the latter that is the better course. Something Apollo acknowledges as he muses upon it, as his previous suggestion was built around the idea that you would be going it alone.

After all, it is not entirely often that space marines ask for aid, and rather the other way around that you are far more familiar with.

=============================

Within the heart of the Split Heart Kabal’s home, the Archon Khannaer Izensar seethed before throwing aside a bone-goblet of agony ridden blood.

“They have found us,” he snarled, pale lips peeling back as he rose from his throne, slapping aside the vapid and certainly rendered mindless pet which had pawed at him with mewling coos as he strode forward.

“Archon, what are we to do? Our preparations are not yet complete…and Vect’s calls for all to return to Commorragh are making some question whether,” one of his sniveling corsair captains began only to find himself stuttering to a halt at the furious glare directed at him.

“Vect,” he hissed, “Is doomed. Khaine’s Gate is fallen, the forces of the Warp are swarming through the lower reaches. We will never return to that fallen place. It is here that we will regrow our strength and power. It is the entire point of establishing ourselves out here!”

A century, and yet too many had denied the Split Heart’s call. To join them beneath his magnificence and brilliant leadership. Only now, as Khaine’s Gate collapsed inward, had they been joined by others desperate for succor. To be truthful, perhaps Vect would win, he had the power, the technology, and the sheer unbridled cruel strength to maybe even push the daemons back and close the gate that had been broken down. It didn’t matter. What mattered was the that the Split Hearts had grown much in the past decade, a drop in the bucket for ones such as they. What mattered was that the cattle had grown scared, and his now executed Captains who had failed to slay the Blood Raven strike cruiser’s failure had grown compounded.

“We will fight, we will destroy them, and if necessary,” he growled as he loomed above them all, eldritch lightning sparking along his klaives, “Relocate. We have not yet the strength to truly display our dominion over this place.”

His Sslyth bodyguards slithered behind him as he strode towards one of his slaves who whimpered at its console.

“Contact our fleet. Tell them the time for battle is now!”

The Imperial vessels were already in the system, and charging right towards the Anchorage. He had known it would happen the moment the warp ripples caused by their massive arrival had caused even the most temporary of momentary breakdown in the stealth systems as the crystals cracked and had to be replaced. That did not mean that now was a very inconvenient time for it! In any case, faces flickered into being through the projector, and he almost snarled again at the looks on some of their faces.

“Izensar, what is it?” came the languid and insultingly casual voice of Iyesdreos, as she reclined in her vessel.

“The Anchorage is about to come under attack. Your raid is cancelled, you must-,”

“Hmmm….no,” she interrupted – she interrupted! – and leaned forward with delight dancing in her eyes. “I think not. Besides which, I am too far away to return.”

“Iyesdreos,” he growled, “You swore to me…,”

“And I lied,” she shrugged before smiling again, plucking an eye from one of her nearby slaves to pop it in her mouth as the human screamed in pain and fell to the floor. “Vect has promised me much of I return my ships to the Dark City, and he promises….more than you.”

“WHAT?!” he roared, grasping at the edges of the crystalline screen, “You treacherous-,”

“You tore my Kabal in half for their ships and their slaves, and you expected me to be grateful for your ‘rescue’?!” she screamed back, eyes blazing with their own fury, the sleepy air around her disappearing. “Die! Die in fire, Izensar!”

Then the screen winked out, and with it, three more of his captains who followed their apparent bitch of a mistress. The remainder appeared conflicted before they looked at him and nodded.

“Archon? Your orders?”

He seethed silently for a long breath before his gaze lifted again.

“Let them strike at the Anchorage, focus upon it entirely, and then attack their flanks and rear. KILL THEM ALL!”

==============================

The Anchorage was a twisted thing of wraithbone and black metal spikes, chains freely floating for whatever reason. It shimmered back into existence as apparently the Dark Eldar gave up the pretense of stealth, halfway between the sole inhabited world of the system and the asteroid belt. You had no particular care as for why they did this, only that they had done so and allowed a clear target for all ships to advance. Even so, it was more than a little suspicious that they would allow themselves to be seen as this without a greater fight. That was, of course, until a great many weapons batteries upon the vast thing, which matched and even exceeded the basic size of a Ramilies-class star fort, began to fire upon your ships.

“Wait,” Justinius says, his hand on your shoulder just as you were about to give the order to begin sending out boarding parties onto the anchorage, witch-light blooming from his frame.

“Justinius?”

“Hold,” he shuts his eyes tightly before opening them wide. “They come from behind!”

Indeed they do, as three eldar vessels shimmer out of their stealth fields and begin to fire at the vulnerable rear of the Navy ships, breaking apart two escorts and nearly killing another in their opening salvo. The vox system screeches as two more of the torture cruisers appear, on each side of your combined fleets and begin firing as well. The Litany of Fury weathers the strike without void shield collapse, but that does not mean that it will continue to do so depending on how long this conflict may last.

“ANGELOS!” Whitmore’s voice booms onto the bridge, fraught with panic and pain, “Break down the doors of that Anchorage, and stop those defense batteries!”

“You do not wish us to aid you against their ships?”

Before you, upon the tac-screen, his grand cruiser executes a surprisingly tight turn as it turns its broadsides against one of the flanking torture cruisers.

“I’ll handle them, you handle getting that Anchorage’s defenses down so I don’t lose any more of my bloody ships against them!”

Anchorage Assault Troop Deployment Decisions [Stage 1]:
Note: You do not have to assault every position, it may be better to concentrate your forces on some targets now and then attack others later.
Note: Precise determination of enemy troops present on Anchorage impossible at this time due to psychic baffles, sensor-ghosts, etc. Librarius efforts at such things in turn is similarly stymied, as well as additional warp fluctuations present in system.
[] Defensive Lance Battery 1: One of the three defensive lance batteries present on the Dark Eldar Anchorage you face in battle now, if it is let to function for too long it will likely tear apart all of your ships given the fact that you are fighting both the Anchorage itself as well as its fleet. It is likely heavily defended for just that same reason by whatever monstrous creatures that the Dark Eldar possess as well as those twisted xenos themselves. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Defensive Lance Battery 2: One of the three defensive lance batteries present on the Dark Eldar Anchorage you face in battle now, if it is let to function for too long it will likely tear apart all of your ships given the fact that you are fighting both the Anchorage itself as well as its fleet. It is likely heavily defended for just that same reason by whatever monstrous creatures that the Dark Eldar possess as well as those twisted xenos themselves. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Enemy Hangers 1: From this wraithbone pit are spewed dozens of Dark Eldar fighters and bombers that if given enough time can likely damage and further even destroy escort vessels and damage systems of larger ships. Of increased concern is their potential to take down drop pods as they are deployed onto the Anchorage, killing your brothers before they can even meet the enemy in combat. Not to mention they could provide an easier passage for your troops to move in without the risk of being struck by other point defenses through thunderhawks. Said thunderhawks will obviously also have to fight through here in order to take said hangars. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Shield Battery 1: Currently stopping you from truly unleashing the devastating power behind your bombardment cannons and other weaponry from being truly effective is this. Protecting a large portion of the anchorage with what shielding that the eldar can possess, as well as projecting whatever techno-sorcery they are capable of that ruin traditional targeting methods to make even hitting them difficult in the first place despite the size. Likely heavily guarded for just that purpose. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. This Shield Battery Protects Lance Battery 1, 2, and Hangar 1 from concentrated bombardment assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Enemy Hangers 2: From this wraithbone pit are spewed dozens of Dark Eldar fighters and bombers that if given enough time can likely damage and further even destroy escort vessels and damage systems of larger ships. Of increased concern is their potential to take down drop pods as they are deployed onto the Anchorage, killing your brothers before they can even meet the enemy in combat. Not to mention they could provide an easier passage for your troops to move in without the risk of being struck by other point defenses through thunderhawks. Said thunderhawks will obviously also have to fight through here in order to take said hangars. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Defensive Lance Battery 3: One of the three defensive lance batteries present on the Dark Eldar Anchorage you face in battle now, if it is let to function for too long it will likely tear apart all of your ships given the fact that you are fighting both the Anchorage itself as well as its fleet. It is likely heavily defended for just that same reason by whatever monstrous creatures that the Dark Eldar possess as well as those twisted xenos themselves. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Shield Battery 2: Currently stopping you from truly unleashing the devastating power behind your bombardment cannons and other weaponry from being truly effective is this. Protecting a large portion of the anchorage with what shielding that the eldar can possess, as well as projecting whatever techno-sorcery they are capable of that ruin traditional targeting methods to make even hitting them difficult in the first place despite the size. Likely heavily guarded for just that purpose. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. This Shield Battery Protects Lance Battery 3 and Hangar 2 from concentrated bombardment assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Enemy Command Center: Deep within the Anchorage, likely at its center where it would be best protected, is no doubt where the enemy commander currently resides. If you were to manage a strike here, either by Deep Striking, fighting your way through, or sending forth someone like Cyrus to attempt an assassination and begin sabotaging the entire location with explosives, is up to you. Either way, a xeno in command of a station such as this is likely quite powerful and will possess bodyguards. But if he is defeated here, and the command center taken, you could potentially attempt turning the anchorage against itself. Too deep within Anchorage for bombardment to be effective at this time. Deep Strike Teleportation assault possible. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)

Anchorage Assault Ship Deployment Decisions [Stage 1]:
Whitmore Fleet Present: 4 Lunar-class Cruisers, 2 Gothic-class cruisers, 15 Frigates
Dark Eldar Fleet Present: 7 Torture Cruisers, 25 Corsair Escorts
Blood Raven Fleet Present: Entire Chapter Fleet
[] Bombarding: Lay siege to the station as best as possible, despite the difficulty in breaking through its advanced shielding and targeting-baffling abilities. With the Emperor’s blessing, you might be able to break through regardless and be able to destroy parts of the Anchorage’s defensive hard points without being forced to land troops there! Not to mention the fact that you generally are just trying to destroy the entire Anchorage. (Write-In Ships Dedicated, Write-In Targets)
[] Aiding The Navy: Despite Whitmore’s words, the enemy ships are quickly dancing in and out of range, and adding the power of your own weaponry will likely aid his ships in long-term survivability throughout the battle. It is not as if at the moment that you can fully unleash your vessels weapons and bombardment weaponry against the well-shielded and protected Anchorage. (Write-In Ships Dedicated)

015.M42 Through 020.M42 Interlude: Silence and Infinity

015.M42 Through 020.M42 Interlude: Silence and Infinity

The C’tan…still lived. Those that remained at the least. If accepting the ruination of their bodies, minds, and souls was regarded by some as the absolute worst mistake that had ever been made by his people in return for what was more than just a flawed immortality, those that granted it being put in the position to do so was what he regarded as a mistake even higher in grade of horror. One that he had once fought against, had struggled against, but in truth knew in the end that it was at his hands that the pact had been made. Only when he had truly seen what he had wrought in bitterness and foolish hope had he truly understood. It was that understanding that had led him first to his wanderings, it was that understanding that had made him abandon his peoples. By necessity, and in truth because he knew that he did not deserve to rule over them.

But then…he had discovered it.

The Devourer. The Endless Hunger. By many names and more, though the most well-known by virtue of those who said it being one of the most numerous in a galaxy that they had once ruled, was the tyranids. He had seen them for what they truly were, in a greater scope than none in the galaxy but he had seen, even the so-vaunted powers of the eldar. He had seen the vast sun-thick cables of organic matter that could eclipse worlds and worlds and worlds. Watched as a rogue planet that had spent thousands of years flying freely in the void be eaten not in the course of several months after a failed desperate battle as he had observed throughout the time since his return, but in mere moments. His single vessel could not have stopped it, surely not.

So he returned, and found a galaxy entranced with ever more conflict and chaos. Anarchy breaking down across a dozen alien empires that he passed by in silence as their citizens went mad, souls bending and breaking underneath the forces that were being unleashed upon what some would term the immaterium, others the warp. In those times he deeply regretted the severing of the control protocols…but in the end still felt it was the right decision to make. Besides which, he had already seen that some were leading in a way that he could not, not any longer. That was not to say that he had none who would follow him, of course.

Never again would he command the legions and dynasties as he had once in the past, but he did not need to. Not at the moment. Perhaps that would change later. Perhaps he would not need it to.

But in this, on this day, he did not come to battle that menace before his people could rise to true prominence once more. He had come here today, with those that would still follow him, not stripped of free will but of their own as befitting what his people should possess and not what he had forced upon them. It was a mighty force nonetheless, and supplemented further by one who had come to him not out of an enslaved mind but merely because he agreed with what his own purpose had become. Where once there had been the Silent King, now there was but he, and the Traveler.

“There is lies,” he lifted one achingly metallic finger, so bereft of flesh, and pointed out the target before them.

“Then we shall do what we must,” the Traveler bowed his own head.

All protocols. Not that of the machines, but of honor, of blood, and yes, of flesh. That some still held to them would have been heartening if he had a heart anymore. In truth, by circuitry and code could he have communicated, but he still elected to speak. Silent too long, he refused to be silent any longer when the very existence of his people was at risk. So here, now, had they come.

“We have been detected,” Anrakyr murmured, for it was in fact his very vessel and fleet that had provided transport for what forces that Szarekh had been able to marshal beneath him. “They cannot stand against us.”

It was just as well, that even in this short amount of time that had been filled with so much destruction of the Tomb Worlds that the true strength of the necrons had not been unleashed fully excepting a few small instances. This, now, as they plunged their necrodermis ships through a great cloud of primitively constructed metal and weaponry that was both touched by the warp and not, worked to their favor. Dozens of vessels that if they had concentrated fire would have been able to stop them had they properly utilized the firepower available to them did not do so. Surprisingly it was the forces of the ‘Imperium’ that recognized them better, yet they were too busy being put into retreat for them to be worth bothering.

They were not the enemy this day. Neither was the ‘Chaos’ warlord who called himself the Despoiler.

The true enemy, was the eldest foe of all his people. Not the Old Ones, no, he was too old and too wizened and too soulless to feel any true anger towards those lost beings. Nor the eldar. No, it was the true foe of his people, those that he had once bargained with…and lost. When he had learned of the release of some of their shards, he had despaired. Machines and tesseracts failing despite redundancy after redundancy. No doubt they even now had begun searching each other out. There were others, those few that he had failed to rend to pieces, and he could not abide his people not possessing the correct weapons to face them.

The C’tan.

In truth, was little that his husk could feel, in these dark and cold days, but his shame and rage for all things involving them was still there. As ghosts in the back of his mind, but they were there. Reminders of what had been lost, what still might not ever be regained. The tyranids had to be defeated before they stripped the galaxy of flesh for the necron to re-inhabit once more, but the C’tan needed to be prepared for should his people fail. No doubt they could once more rip what little free will that his people possessed. Those who had been rendered utterly mindless surely, other Lords and Overlords…he could not risk it.

He had heard the names of what they called the weapons, and he did not care. It was useful only for them. Weapons they were, and weapons he needed. The other had been tainted, corrupted, the ancient taste and feel of what had filled it long-recognizable on the vastly superior technologies that even the strained vessels that Anrakyr possessed. Which was why he had not pursued it, only giving the thought of it to one who would surely desire it beyond imagining. Hence why, as they dived towards their prize, he could feel through his connection to the ship of the much vaster vessels plunging through the forces of ‘Chaos’ and ‘Imperium’ alike.

“Oh my goodness,” he felt the lilting voice of his erstwhile ‘ally’ burst into his mind.

If he had the ability to feel irritation, then that man would be one capable of inflicting it.

“It is just as you said, oh King,” he heard him speak again, “So powerful, yes, and unique besides!”

It didn’t matter, what mattered was the one that was less tainted and more useful to his purposes.

“Phasing now.”

He wished he could feel the transition, but instead all he got was the flash of green and the odd not-sensations of his systems realigning as he dipped out of reality and back into it again. He wished that the hot rush of combat would return to him, but even as he listened to the surprised screams of the humans before him before they were cut down by immortals and warriors alike, he felt nothing. Forever to be reminded of his mistake, to be locked in it as a prison of mind and body. But perhaps his state was also a blessing, in that he could not fall upon such things as a crutch as organics could. Instead he forged forward.

Studded craters appeared in his chest, but the necrodermis was already flowing to heal it. In the meantime, from his staff blasted out green lightning, and it flensed the armor of the horned ‘marine’ before him to send the supposedly ancient warrior’s body flying in two directions. For all that he had seen the Blood Angels fight, they at least could display honor. The slavering creature with its odd little axe? Less deserving of his attention, much less his contempt.

All throughout the station, forces teleported in. Forces bearing the sigils of a dozen and more dynasties were present, many belonging to Anrakyr and yet more belonging to him. For all that they had come, the bargain was that many of those who had arrived would not be leaving with him and would instead joint the traveler in his own crusade. Which, to be fair, he could respect.

“BLOOD FOR THE BL-HURK!” he reached out and punched his fist through the chest of one of the charging mongrels, ripping out not just its hearts but much of its internal organs. Then he stomped his foot down onto the head and pulped it entirely.

For a brief moment, he stilled, and felt as some warriors fell but many more poured through, both on this place and the other in the distance. It was…something, at the least. On the outside, the dancing ships of his people tore through and destroyed the ships of any and all who dared to approach. That many of them belonged to those who declared themselves against the monstrous creatures of the warp, he did not particularly care too much. If anything, he would prefer that they be spending more of their strength stopping the tyranids…but then that was likely because he knew that the necron were more than capable of bringing an end to Chaos if required – as it likely would be.

His people’s pylons on ‘Cadia’ more than proved that point.

“Silent King,” Anrakyr spoke, joining him and now covered from head to metal toe in the blood of his enemies, “We have taken control of the station.”

“The controlling artifacts?”

“Their connection has been severed, for now. If we wish to maintain that situation, then we must move them. Now.”

“Oh what fun this will be,” the third of their makeshift triarchy spoke up again, “I shall give it a prized place in my collection! Though I’ll have to remove these pylons of course. It looks a bit…studded with them, at the moment.”

Without a single communication to any force whatsoever, the necrons turned, and began to depart. Massive cairn-class vessels blocked the way of any who attempted to stop them, while darting shrouds and scythes danced in and out to strike out faster and smaller targets. The pylon system, ‘Of the lamented and lost Dynasties of the past’ which had been brought forth after much convincing from deep within the vaults of the one who called himself Infinite, prevented any and all present from teleporting through the warp, and did its own part in reducing the power of their otherwise powerful psychic rituals and powers from working as well.

Yet some warriors had been lost permanently, to his faintly felt regret. One or two ships as well had fallen under the sheer infuriated firepower of the one who they had reclaimed the weapons from. Stolen would imply that the mongrel primitive had been deserving of ownership in the first place.

“Trayzn, your pylon cordon…,” he suddenly said, watching through the scanning systems of the Traveler’s flagship.

“Oh, do not worry, oh King, I see it. Why, it reminds me of an exquisite tesseract labyrinth I possess, captured in stasis at the perfect moment of failure…but I shall not allow it to occur here.”

It was one thing for one of the shards of the C’tan to tear apart the machinery built to contain them. It was wholly another for creatures or powers of the warp to tear through what his people had built. Even so, he watched with what might have been concern as yet more pylons were released from the underbelly of Trayzn’s flagship that joined the masterfully crafted pylon system present, more than enough for containment, he realized. For all that he blustered, and wandered, and sounded absentminded, when it came to truly unique prizes, the Infinite would go to great lengths to keep them secure.

But now they had them. Now they would learn to use them beyond simple propulsion and dragging them along behind and alongside their ships. They would learn them, and use them, for he knew well that the C’tan were not done with his people if they had their way. He had heard the tales of some escaping, shards disappearing into the unknown. They still did not know for certain the location of some of those who had not been rent to pieces. Yet these weapons…built for striking out at things such as they, and his own people to boot. Did it abhor him to use technologies that were built for such a purpose as eradicating his people? No. Not when they could be turned to his own usage. The C’tan…were not done with his people, he knew. He could feel it, to use a human phrase, in his bones.

Mag'ladroth, who had been unsundered.

Mephet'ran, who he knew had yet many shards unbound and free to work their foul deeds.

Yggra’nya, released by those who knew not what they did.

Aza'Gorod, of whom he had already heard many a tale of shards rending those around them to pieces and disappearing.

There were others.

But he was the Silent King, yet silent no longer.

And he would be ready for them.

Turn 16: Bringing Fire To Darkness (Part Three)

Spoiler: Plan: Little Eldar, Little Eldar, Let Us In, Let Us In!

[X] Plan: Little Eldar, Little Eldar, Let Us In, Let Us In!
[X] Shield Battery 1
-[X] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chaplain Ravias, Chaplain Antonius, Apothecary Falkor Ryll, Chapter Honor Guard, 5th Company
--[X] Bolters, meltaguns, 5x multi-meltas, flamers, some plasmaguns and 2/3rd of our power weapons.
[X] Enemy Hangers 2
-[X] 1st Company, 10th Company, Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus, Chaplain Uther Volkoss, Chaplain Ateren, 2x Techmarines
--[X] 10x Tartaros Pattern Terminator armor, 10x Thunder Hammer, 10x Storm Shields, 10x Cyclone Missile Launchers. The rest take a loadout meant to deal with nimble opponents: bolters, regular meltaguns, flamers, some plasmaguns and 1/3rd of our power weapons,
--[X] 1 Rapier (Quad-Heavy Bolters), 1 Rapier (Laser-Destroyer Array), as many non-AA Tarantulas as we can get there (priority on heavy bolter and assault cannon ones) as soon as it is safe for our Thunderhawks to travel there.
---[X] All of our Thunderhawk gunships and as many Thunderhawk transports as necessary
[X] Bombarding:
-[X] Lance Battery 1
--[X] 5th Company fleet and 10th Company's Nova-Frigate
-[X] Lance Battery 2
--[X] 1st Company fleet
[X] Aiding The Navy
-[X] 10th Company fleet sans the Nova-frigate

Bringing Fire To Darkness
+015.M42+ To +020.M42+
+Distrust The Xeno, Hate The Xeno, Kill The Xeno+

“Initiating drop!”

The familiar thump of the drop pods being released from the ships grows into a steady rumble as they are launched at speeds that would crush the bones of an unmodified human. Within the drop pod, you close your eyes, and listen as Hannibal unleashes a sermon of hatred and resilience throughout the vox channels. He speaks of the unrelenting need to slay the xeno in all its aspects for their treachery upon humanity in ages past, present, and those that may come in the future. The tales of the Age of Strife are granted even further fire as he bellows his words, into not just the ears of your brothers but openly to whatever aliens that dare to be listening to their impending deaths. Conflicts against the eldar are spoken of as well, with specificity. When he reaches the finale of his sermon, with a resounding wordless scream of the eternal hatred of humanity for the alien, does your drop pod impact into the hull of the anchorage.

In your helmet’s systems, you spy one of the lights indicating nominal status of the drop pods flicker into an infernal red as metal, blackened steel, and scattered chunks of psycho-reactive wraithbone are shattered beneath the drop pods in their descent. There is a brief shuddering span of five seconds as more of the hull is torn away, the oscillating shielding batteries of this place not quite so impenetrable a barrier as void shields in that they trade more of such potential utter durability for bouncing shadowfields. Even so, that they possess more ‘traditional’ shielding than you are most accustomed to is more than a little worrisome. At the least, the Librarium and the blessed machine spirits have ensured that only one squad’s drop pod suffered the worst.

The five seconds pass, and then there is a steady impact, the drop pods exploding open to release not only you, but the whole of the 5th Company and your command squad as well. Even as you emerge, kabalite warriors fire with splinter rifles, impacting against your terminator armor as you exist only for you bull forward and smash one of the comparatively fragile eldar against a wall, the corridor you landed in tight enough that the drop pod has completely separated one end from the other. Luckily it opens such that you can proceed through it if needed. But at that moment, the whole of your attentions are focused on the eldar first, slaying those you can reach before more of them arrive. All around you is carnage, your mind barely deigning to take in the disgusting spiked and purposefully twisted architecture of the foe, instead focusing on one of the 5th Company marines being hacked apart by cackling incubi as he attempted to engage them in melee combat, another being shot through the skull by a massive crystalline sliver which rocks the marine backwards to the ground.

“For the Emperor!”

“NONE SHALL FIND US WANTING!”

==============================

“Hangar guns are proving a bit annoying,” the techmarine noted casually as Cyrus stood beside him, hand on the seat. “Those shadowfields make retaliatory shots difficult…”

Cyrus did not have all of the integrated technologies and sensors at hand that the techmarine did, but he found little to dispute the statement. A great flurry of spikes thrown up by the half dozen or so turrets secreted around the hangar shot forward at speeds that would surely be impossible for one who was not so literally connected with the machines and trained with thunderhawks to avoid. Behind him, those within the thunderhawk held tight to their restraints, as twin litanies of hatred and fury were recited from the chaplains that had been elected to join the assault.

“Will we make it?”

“Of course. So long as you have your helmet in place, and the doors to the troop compartment are sealed and locked.”

Cyrus barely began to ask ‘why’ when a massive splinter from the point defense guns speared through the incredibly thick and protective materials that made up the cockpits covering, slamming directly between the techmarine and his serf pilot, on the opposite side of the techmarine’s shoulders that Cyrus himself stood on. Void immediately began its hungry work upon them, the shattered glass-like materials sucking away into the darkness while the magnetic workings of their own armors and that of the serf activated in turn. The stars beckoned, and yet all that was accomplished was a massive hissing noise before the breach was sealed, additional panels sliding down from somewhere to cover the holes around the spike which even now remained.

“Well, there we go,” the techmarine spoke as the thunderhawk finished entering the hangar, surrounded by the others which began to circle slightly.

One of the thunderhawk transporters sped forward above them all, spinning wildly as it slammed itself onto the ground so that its bulk smashed and smeared dozens of eldar, shattered three weapon emplacements, and then finally opened its doors containing much of the 1st Company directly into a corridor leading to the hangar bay in front of a group of stunned and dazed dark eldar. The remainder of the vessels span up their own weaponry, and from within began to let loose, shredding jetfighters and bombers alike at close range. Some had already begun to lift off, their pilots inside them frantically trying to escape, but the speed and fury that the thunderhawks had entered with negated much of their shadowfields abilities to compensate for sheer volume of firepower. Their job done, the gunships began to deposit their troops before turning towards the hangar guns themselves and ruining them from outside of their ability to turn.

“Look at that,” Cyrus heard the techmarine say, the 10th Captain turning slightly to gaze at his own pilot who was gesturing towards the transporter which had performed the more violent maneuver upon the vile things which inhabited the hangar, “What a reckless maneuver. Daedal!” Cyrus heard the vox crackle as the techmarine opened communications. “What in the Emperor’s name was that!”

A returning voice, growing increasingly hard to hear as the weapons fire exchanged with charging kabalite warriors and incubi and that of the space marines grew more intense, responded.

“Calus, I don’t want to hear that from someone who has a massive spike in the front of his gunship,” was the sardonic reply.

“The gunship is built intentionally tough such that-,”

“The transporter is meant to be able to-,”

Cyrus leapt from the gunship which still hovered about so that its guns could be put to good use, and set to work himself, planting explosives and firing alongside the rest of his company. The addition of the 1st Company veterans who had been seconded to his chapter proved a great boon, he found if a bit reluctantly. But his pride was worthless compared to the needs of the chapter. Across the bay, he watched while sniping down a grotesque that looked like it might once have been an ork before the Haemonculi got to it as one of the newer scout sergeants reached forward and dragged back an intrepid scout who had charged into the open to prevent them from being torn apart by a splinter cannon blast which vaporized the crates behind the scout. An action he himself could not have performed, and yet now only needed to worry less about. Excellent, especially as he planted another shot into the eye of a charging incubus before it could tear apart the Chaplain Ateren who had been brought to the ground by a gaggle of them.

Then he whirled, his cloak flaring as a third of it was cut apart by a silently appearing mandrake, its blade dripping with what almost appeared to be acidic poisons. The blade sliced deep into the deck, but slid out just as quickly, straight towards his throat. The relic sniper rifle in his hands began to fall, yet before it had completed half of its descent he was lifting his own combat knife to deflect. Not to block, he knew, the monomolecular nature of many dark eldar weaponry would more likely than not slice straight through his knife, and so it was deflection instead. It’s shadowskin rippled back and forth, obscuring much of its body in differing amounts in the blink of one eye to the next as Cyrus retreated out from beneath the shadows dropped by the empty voidraven that lay above with its dead pilot still slumped in the seat.

Mandrake met marine in combat that was near silent save for the faint swirl of cloak and blades meeting one another again and again. Cyrus did not grit his teeth as part of the poison struck his check, though h mentally acknowledged the fact that it was not the usual assortment of skin-contact poisons he had suffered from dark eldar before. Rather it was more of a tyranid variety. As his combat knife skittered along the mandrake’s own weapon, he glanced at it more carefully before rising up an arm to slam against the inside of the eldar’s wrist as its other arm attempted to stab down with a barbed hook, knocking the weapon away. It was as he suspected, a blade which looked to be more of some tyranid’s body rather than more traditional weaponry. Which, now that he focused upon it, did not possess nearly as many blade-guards that were a weapon and protection in and of themselves. The fight had gone on so blindingly fast he had not yet even perceived that until this very instant.

Well then.

He adjusted his tactics accordingly, and twisted his knife down, into the hand holding the shaped claw and past the hilt. The mandrake did not hiss in pain, its thin lips only splitting open slightly as a sign of the pain. A rapid exchange of strikes was exchanged then, until he finally managed to wrap his own arm about that of the remaining weapon, and with a grunt and slamming of his legs broke the knee of the mandrake backwards and granted himself enough leverage to shove the barbed hook upwards into the lower jaw and out the forehead of his opponent. The mandrake sighed slightly as it died, its eyes drifting upwards to watch as the first rivulets of its own blood traveled down its forehead.

Cyrus released the thing, slumping to the ground, and breathed deeply as he absorbed the fifteen seconds that had passed before turning back to the greater fight, a hand coming up to his ear as he activated the vox.

“Chapter Master, the hangar is nearly secured, the 1st Company is already fortifying the entrances here, our gunships have destroyed the hangar guns so that more forces can be brought in. We can advance to new targets if required.”

A series of heavy explosions erupted into his ear from the channel, heavy breathing turning into a roar that ended with a heavy squelch and the telltale sound of a daemonhammer crushing a xeno ribcage coming next.

“Very well Cyrus,” Gabriel grunted, “We have taken the shield battery, and are planting our explosives now. We will be gone from this area soon, and bombardments can soon take place.”

“Chapter Master,” Hadrian’s voice entered into the channel, his voice tight with concentration, “Merely give the word, and the ships will be ready.”

Cyrus let them speak as he checked over his recruits, standing grimly over the body of one slain scout who had almost been ready to advance further into the chapter as the solemn duty of the apothecaries was carried out.

“How goes the battle, Captain?”

“We have lost two of our gladius frigates, but we have taken many more down with them,” he growled, “As for the bombardment of the anchorage…we are dealing damage, to be sure, but their shadowfields and actual shielding is making it difficult to tell how much damage is actually being done.”

“One of their batteries is about to go down, and we shall see what we shall see then.”

==========================================

“Chapter Master,” Apollo says as he marches along with you away from the blast zone, “The missing drop pod has been identified.”

“Yes?” you turn to him, even as behind you the explosives begin to go off.

Almost immediately you can feel far more accurate bombardment occurring on a suddenly unguarded and revealed section of the anchorage.

“It is Sergeant Laskaris’ squad,” he murmurs.

Damnation. Just to return from the Ghoul Stars to die here?

“Can we recover their Gene-Seed?” is you weary response.

He hesitates before speaking, the winding hallways of the anchorage watched and set alight with flamer and bolter fire the moment the dark eldar come pouring out of them. All around you, the 5th Company continues to battle. In one bright flash a squad of kabalite warriors simply vanish at the wave of a hand from your Chief Librarian, in another a pair of incubi who nearly gutted a 5th company marine to death are battered apart by Hannibal. The mandrakes fled after realizing that your own librarians found their attempts to slide through the air invisibly pointless, leaving only a few of the most vicious of their direct fighters left before you, now.

“Their signals are still transmitting,” he finally says, drawing you to a halt. “Their drop pod did not hit off course, it was not destroyed, Chapter Master.”

Apollo raises his eyes to you, and the set of his face is grim.

“Their drop pod pierced through several more layers than expected, breaking through newer constructions of the Anchorage and spearing through structural weakpoints that their own anti-psychic defenses prevented the Librarians from sighting. They are deep within the structure, but we are still receiving vox signals even if we cannot precisely reach them.”

The Anchorage shudders as one of the defensive lance batteries it possessed is destroyed, the earlier bombardment combined with the loss of its protective shields ending it entirely, as you stare at Apollo.

“Chapter Master, your orders?”

Stage 1 Complete:
- 7 5th Company Marines Dead. +11 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 6 Scouts [2nd Stage] Dead. +12 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 7 Scouts [1st Stage] Dead. +10 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 4 1st Company Marines Dead. +8 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 1 5th Company Squad, commanded by Sergeant Doukas Laskaris, is deep within the anchorage, and is in unknown condition!
- Hangar 1 Successfully captured! 2 Thunderhawks (Gunship, Transporter) in need of minor repairs but still flight capable!
- 2 Gladius-class frigates of 5th Company Fleet destroyed in battle! Chapter Fleet remains strong, Imperial Navy Fleet taking majority of damage!

Anchorage Assault Troop Deployment Decisions [Stage 2]:
Note: You do not have to assault every position, it may be better to concentrate your forces on some targets now and then attack others later.
Note: Precise determination of enemy troops present on Anchorage impossible at this time due to psychic baffles, sensor-ghosts, etc. Librarius efforts at such things in turn is similarly stymied, as well as additional warp fluctuations present in system.
[] Defensive Lance Battery 1: One of the three defensive lance batteries present on the Dark Eldar Anchorage you face in battle now, if it is let to function for too long it will likely tear apart all of your ships given the fact that you are fighting both the Anchorage itself as well as its fleet. It is likely heavily defended for just that same reason by whatever monstrous creatures that the Dark Eldar possess as well as those twisted xenos themselves. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here) This location has sustained heavy bombardment damage, and can likely be finished off by a single strike cruiser - Hadrian, Master of Fleets.
[] Enemy Hangers 1: From this wraithbone pit are spewed dozens of Dark Eldar fighters and bombers that if given enough time can likely damage and further even destroy escort vessels and damage systems of larger ships. Of increased concern is their potential to take down drop pods as they are deployed onto the Anchorage, killing your brothers before they can even meet the enemy in combat. Not to mention they could provide an easier passage for your troops to move in without the risk of being struck by other point defenses through thunderhawks. Said thunderhawks will obviously also have to fight through here in order to take said hangars. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here) Unprotected by the shield battery, a single battle barge's bombardment cannon could easily destroy this target utterly - Hadrian, Master of Fleets.
[] Defensive Lance Battery 2: One of the three defensive lance batteries present on the Dark Eldar Anchorage you face in battle now, if it is let to function for too long it will likely tear apart all of your ships given the fact that you are fighting both the Anchorage itself as well as its fleet. It is likely heavily defended for just that same reason by whatever monstrous creatures that the Dark Eldar possess as well as those twisted xenos themselves. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Shield Battery 1: Currently stopping you from truly unleashing the devastating power behind your bombardment cannons and other weaponry from being truly effective is this. Protecting a large portion of the anchorage with what shielding that the eldar can possess, as well as projecting whatever techno-sorcery they are capable of that ruin traditional targeting methods to make even hitting them difficult in the first place despite the size. Likely heavily guarded for just that purpose. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. This Shield Battery Protects Lance Battery 1, 2, and Hangar 1 from concentrated bombardment assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Captured Hangers 2: This location has been captured successfully, a great amount of enemy weaponry and ships destroyed before they could exit and be used against the forces of the Imperium. While your troops head elsewhere, it would be wise to dedicate some to holding this location so that thunderhawks can ferry troops, honored dead, etc. out of the anchorage as you go about destroying it. No doubt the eldar know this and will do their best to stop you in the meantime. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Defensive Lance Battery 3: One of the three defensive lance batteries present on the Dark Eldar Anchorage you face in battle now, if it is let to function for too long it will likely tear apart all of your ships given the fact that you are fighting both the Anchorage itself as well as its fleet. It is likely heavily defended for just that same reason by whatever monstrous creatures that the Dark Eldar possess as well as those twisted xenos themselves. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Shield Battery 2: Currently stopping you from truly unleashing the devastating power behind your bombardment cannons and other weaponry from being truly effective is this. Protecting a large portion of the anchorage with what shielding that the eldar can possess, as well as projecting whatever techno-sorcery they are capable of that ruin traditional targeting methods to make even hitting them difficult in the first place despite the size. Likely heavily guarded for just that purpose. Forces which are deployed here will have to go by way of Drop Pod assaults. This Shield Battery Protects Lance Battery 3 and Hangar 2 from concentrated bombardment assaults. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Squad Retrieval: Veteran Sergeant Doukas Laskaris, recently returned from the Ghoul Stars, has suffered great misfortune as his squad's drop pod pierced far deeper into the enemy structure than any other drop pod thus far. Recreating the exact conditions to allow others to reinforce by drop pod is impossible, and while their beacons are transmitting there is not enough stability in the signals to retrieve them alive or dead by teleport. You could attempt to teleport to their location instead, or send troops already present in the anchorage to attempt to reach them. And yet, for all of this, they may already be dead. On the other hand, even if that is so, dare you forgo attempting to retrieve their precious Gene-Seed? Must specify whether teleporting troops or not for this action if selected. (Write-In Options)
[] Enemy Command Center: Deep within the Anchorage, likely at its center where it would be best protected, is no doubt where the enemy commander currently resides. If you were to manage a strike here, either by Deep Striking, fighting your way through, or sending forth someone like Cyrus to attempt an assassination and begin sabotaging the entire location with explosives, is up to you. Either way, a xeno in command of a station such as this is likely quite powerful and will possess bodyguards. But if he is defeated here, and the command center taken, you could potentially attempt turning the anchorage against itself. Too deep within Anchorage for bombardment to be effective at this time. Deep Strike Teleportation assault possible. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)

Anchorage Assault Ship Deployment Decisions [Stage 1]:
Whitmore Fleet Present: 3 Lunar-class Cruisers, 2 Gothic-class cruisers, 6 Frigates
Dark Eldar Fleet Present: 3 Torture Cruisers, 14 Corsair Escorts
Blood Raven Fleet Present: Entire Chapter Fleet
[] Bombarding: Lay siege to the station as best as possible, despite the difficulty in breaking through its advanced shielding and targeting-baffling abilities. With the Emperor’s blessing, you might be able to break through regardless and be able to destroy parts of the Anchorage’s defensive hard points without being forced to land troops there! Not to mention the fact that you generally are just trying to destroy the entire Anchorage. (Write-In Ships Dedicated, Write-In Targets)
[] Aiding The Navy: Despite Whitmore’s words, the enemy ships are quickly dancing in and out of range, and adding the power of your own weaponry will likely aid his ships in long-term survivability throughout the battle. It is not as if at the moment that you can fully unleash your vessels weapons and bombardment weaponry against the well-shielded and protected Anchorage. (Write-In Ships Dedicated)

015.M42 Through 020.M42 Interlude: Blood And Ash Rising

GM NOTE: Active five years, or active muse? Eh?

015.M42 Through 020.M42 Interlude: Blood And Ash Rising

It had once been an important manufactorum for the Hive World. Or at least important in the sense that the incredibly mundane items and tools that it had produced in vast numbers were of quiet utility to the population across the planet that had once stood in the billions but had quickly been reduced to millions over the course of the Black Crusade. As it was, however, now, so many years later of constant fighting, it stood as simply one of the few remaining structure that had not fallen apart entirely, had been blasted to pieces, or had not been ground beneath the endless boots of Chaos and Imperium marching back and forth as they ground against another. Back and forth, back and forth had the fight begun. Here, then, they had come, for while it was not a truly significant manufactorum, not an area of vast importance for war material, for the greater battle.

But it’s people had needed help. The Imperial Guard had fallen back, too far back, retreating to parts of the city they could defend. Too many had been left behind. Tens of thousands, huddling in fear and terror as the endless waves of mutants, of cultists, of chaos space marines, of daemons, all that could be spawned from the warp had come to the world, to crush yet one more world within the Agripinaa Sector. The world had not yet fallen at the time, and while it was true that they might have fought against the enemy in a more direct manner, they had elected instead to provide their own forces as defenses against the enemy so that those who could finally evacuate were protected as they did so.

“Into the fires of battle, unto the anvil of war!”

It was a battle cry carried out by all of their surviving brethren, all of them fellow sons of Nocturne, as they fought their desperate last stand. The shattered remains of the 7th Company fought on, many of them forming up in a tight core around the body of their slain captain. Or at least the parts of him that had been left behind after the daemon had cut him into pieces. It had been slain, to be sure, but that did not make his death any easier. Where once the entire company had stretched out its lines to defend against the millions of plagued zombies left by the Plague of Unbelief as cursed vanguard, now they had ever more slowly pulled further inwards, methodically burning and shooting all they could the entire way. They bellowed their war cries, and they died. They killed the enemy, and were overrun by sheer numbers. They saved the lives of tens of thousands who were allowed into the protective gates of the spires surrounding this one fallen city, at the stern behest of their own forces.

But millions more zombies came on. Upon them, here and there, chortling and rot-filled Death Guard could be sighted. Cavorting plaguebearers dragged their diseased blades along the ground leaving unnatural life and disease springing up behind them. Thousands yet more of mutated and plagued men and women who had sworn to Nurgle shuffled forward, their skin sallow and torn open in many places while they carried weapons which ought to have ceased functioning long ago such was their own conditions. But for all that they came on, in a line that stretched unto the horizon, they were fought. For all that the world had begun to collapse, forces retreating elsewhere again and again until there was nothing else left to defend, save here, they had fought on.

There was nowhere else left to retreat to.

“Calidus?” N’mul called out over the sound of his melta gun firing again and again.

The Librarian grunted a thick sheet of flame erupting into air that incinerated dozens of oncoming plague zombies which continued to push forward regardless before turning to him and shaking his head in silence.

“Damn. Cendium?”

“Nothing, Sergeant,” the techmarine slowly shook his head. “It might have been a response to our distress signal, it might not have been.”

“Wait,” Calidus spoke up, his voice echoing with the same waves of psychic power that burst forth from him. “I can feel him once again!”

It was a fools hope, but trapped as they were like this, almost sure to die like this, the last living Sergeant of the 7th Company had seized upon it. With their own strike cruiser gone, torn apart by daemons and a horrifically unlucky nova cannon shot striking it across the bow, they were all that was left. But the idea of a psychic response, of someone hearing them, after so many weeks left to die, it had almost seemed impossible. Before the Librarian could say anything more, the others of their motely survivors of the ruination that had been brought to the Imperium’s forces upon the world arrived from the shadows.

“Sergeant,” the Raptor marine nodded, before hoisting over and depositing another heavy bolter from somewhere or another. “Put it with the others,” the marine directed at one of the other of the Raptors, who dragged it onto the barricades and began to sight down it. “Is something happening?”

“We may be getting rescued,” N’mul told him, pausing only to fire another melta blast at what might have been a plague marine amidst the endless ocean of zombies outside.

The previously destroyed vox, repaired thrice, crackled in Cendium’s hands, who raised it up for all those present to see.

“-repeat, confirm your position, brothers! Orbital window for retrieval is closing fast, multiple enemy ships inbound!”

“Confirmed!” N’mul cried out, his hand thumbing the response rune on the device, “This is Sergeant N’Mul, Salamanders 7th Company, we are in need of assistance! Our position is completely surrounded by the enemy!”

There was silence on the other line, before the steady response came.

“Understood. Epistolary Kogal has confirmed the presence of at least one of your number is a Librarian. Confirm his identity?”

“I am Calidus, Epistolary of the 7th Company. I know of the ironbound fire that is your brother, I feel his presence even now.”

“Confirmed! Stand by for thunderhawk and drop pod deployment!!”

They did not wait long. More and more daemons were marshaling behind the endless waves of moaning plague zombies, an endless shield of meat preventing any of their number from truly destroying the foe before them. They had slain beyond counting, but there were always more. The greatest singular value of a Hive World given over as a weapon to the enemy – its population. Yet then came the gloriously familiar whistling of drop pods flying down through the atmosphere right in front of their own defensive line. Likely aided by psychic communication between one Librarian to another, N’mul later realized. That, and the fact that it was the very tactics and nature of his rescuers that they would only proceed with precise strategies and hopefully planned for contingencies for any battle they leapt into. It had kept his saviors alive, and would keep him alive in battles to come, he would contemplate months later.

From the drop pod erupted a dreadnought, who slammed down one mighty spinning fist to release an unrelenting and progressive curtain of cerulean and emerald flame which even he found impressive, while the rest of their rescuers began to fire. It was only then that he realized how few of them there were, and of what weapons they fired and possessed. Well that, and the fact that also exiting one of the drop pods was a full squad of Sororitas, who fired with their own bolters and flamers towards the enemy while calling out to the Emperor for salvation and fury. From another drop pod, which had clearly been modified slightly, was an honest to goodness Leman Russ tank, which had already begun to fire from within the drop pod without moving an inch. But truly, it was the fact that he saw an apothecary firing a missile launcher towards a tight grouping of plague zombies which truly shook him out of it, while the rest of his brothers and his allies in the raptors began to take advantage of the shock done to the enemy to do what they could.

Soon after came the thunderhawks, and yet for all of it the steady pace of the nurglites remained the same. They cavorted and laughed up at them, to N’mul’s shame, calling them cowards, telling them that they would find his forces once more, and bring them their God’s touch. He was but a newly promoted sergeant, and yet in one of the first truly great battles of his career, the majority of the company had died. Died to save so many, but died all the same. It was not the same for the Raptors, he knew, for they had purposefully vastly divided their chapter up across the entire Black Crusade, small single squads doing what the Guard could not, stealth assaults, providing morale boosts all over. But for his Company…he did not know what he could do for it.

“You are N’mul?” one of the hulking terminators who had arrived spoke, coming closer, a crackling power fist on one arm, a still lit heavy flamer slung in the grip of the other.

“I am.”

There was a pop and a hiss, to reveal the scarred face of the one within the armor, cybernetics curling upwards along his throat to just under his chin. A steady hand was offered.

“I am Force Commander Aramus, of the Blood Ravens. My brother, Tarkus, spoke highly of the Salamanders and of Nocturne which he once visited upon his pilgrimage.”

N’mul stared at him, and realized he had in fact heard of Aramus and his Blood Ravens before. A single strike cruiser, taking utterly insane risks as it dove into the worst of the fighting across the Sectors and Subsectors under assault, endlessly retrieving and rescuing those who had been certain to die, lost resources, personnel, artifacts of churches and the Eccelsiarchy, and more. Performing missions with a small strike force, but one that had been remarkably successful in the past. Yet even so…there were other things said of the Blood Ravens. That they were traitors and heretics, often spoken by the Iron Hands and their successors. But on the other hand, they had already fought alongside the Salamanders in this Black Crusade…

“I have not heard of this Tarkus before,” N’mul said, and honestly so for he was only but a century old yet had been tapped to join the newly formed 7th Company.

Aramus shrugged, a remarkable feat in his terminator armor, and stepped back so that he could flip up the heavy flamer. N’mul stared at it, and as he ran his hands over it he knew it to be surely Salamander work before he even reached the etched sigils of his Chapter in its workings. Behind him, Cendium approached as they all huddled together within the troop compartment of the thunderhawk which even now sped up towards the ship above, and grabbed it with his servo-arm.

“I remember Tarkus of the Blood Ravens. I recall that this was meant to be given to him upon the day he received his terminator honors.”

“And it was,” Aramus bowed his head, “It has merely fallen to me at the moment, and with his blessing.”

“For your Penitent Crusade,” one of the Raptors spoke.

The Blood Raven’s lips did not tighten, his eyes did not narrow. Instead, he merely nodded.

“Yes. I made my mistakes. Arrogance, and pride, and foolishness. Now I suffer for it, but I do not suffer without purpose. What of your gene-seed, do you need us to return you to the lines? We cannot leave for Nocturne, it is beyond our oaths to leave the fight here.”

“Fer’vel?” N’mul looked towards the company apothecary who was heavily weighted down with the precious cargo he carried all about his person.

“The Mechanicus should have some vessels capable of it, and they will honor our previous agreements and dealings,” the apothecary grunted.

“Very well.”

===========================================

“You are not leaving?” Aramus blinked at the sight of the Salamanders returning into the thunderhawk.

N’mul looked at him, and then back at the rapidly departing ship and its incredibly valuable cargo, before turning back to him and shaking his head.

“No. The Salamanders cannot simply abandon the fight either. The 7th Company still exists, in part, and we will not leave when there is yet more to be done. And while I know that you do not partake in the ‘grander’ battles, you fight to preserve what others have been forced to leave behind.”

“It is all we can do,” Aramus murmured. “We have not the forces to do anything else.”

“I did not say that they were worthless acts. Which is why we shall join you. We cannot act as a company, but we can act as a squad, a task force, which,” N’mul glanced at the nearby raving Canoness as she yelled at her own sisters for failing to slay as many in the latest fight as the space marines, “You appear to need.”

“You do not know what you ask, what you will be committing yourself to,” Aramus frowned, “Why?”

“Your honor has been spoken of, you and of Captain Tarkus. You have been judged pure by the Inquisition. I do believe, Aramus,” N’mul clasped him on the shoulder once before heading for the thunderhawk as well, “That you at least deserve a chance.”

Aramus was stilled in shock for a long moment, before one of the Raptors, done with their own preparations, walked past as well.

“You as well, Celeritan?”

The Raptor Sergeant looked at him and slowly shook his head.

“We are all going to die anyway. I simply find that dying on one of the missions that you pursue to be…agreeable rather than dragged underneath an ocean of plagued flesh or bronze chainaxes.”

Then the fatalistic Raptor walked on.

Aramus stared upwards at the stars, and then lifted one hand up so that he could examine it. He ran it slowly along his front, though he could not see the bionics that had been placed within where his innards had been carved through in multiple places by the ork that had nearly killed him. He did not pretend to know what would happen next. It was not as if Kogal had the ability to perform the Emperor’s Tarot anymore given his state, though he could sometimes attempt to pierce the veil of the future. Even then, he was not Justinius. Kogal had become an Epistolary on his more immediately effective powers. Fire, geomancy, things such as that. He…did not want more to die because of him. Too many already had, and for an instant the memory of the slaughtered forces at Angel Forge because of his shattering the gate returned. Deaths unneeded, but his fault in turn.

“My duty is death,” he whispered, “None shall find me wanting.”

Then he banished his idle musings and doubt, and headed back towards his thunderhawk. He did not have time for such things, not when there yet remained more to be done. It was not about surviving this Crusade he was on. It was about doing his duty to the Emperor, in as great a magnitude as he could manage. To save what he could, save who he could, destroy what he could, and kill who he could. Already, one of his two progenoid glands had been destroyed by what nearly killed him, leaving but one left in his body. It was, he felt, a sign of what was going to come to him eventually. But he would not simply let it happen, no. He would fight, and yes, die, but he would not wait for it to happen. He was an Angel of Death, a space marine, and he would find that death in service to Mankind, as the Emperor intended. Not for glory. Or honor. But because it was right, and it was good, and it needed to be done.

=====================

The years stretched on, caked in the blood of heroes and monsters alike. Tales of the Retribution would spread as well, as a hundred, hundred more stories would across the 13th Black Crusade and beyond. But such on occasion, of Blood Ravens and Salamanders and Raptors, was one of the somewhat more notable than average. A dozen more daring rescues here, another lighting insertion and assassination against a commander there. At other times they would come as much needed defenders, only to depart once the battle was complete even if only temporarily. Other times...they came too late, and could only pay their respects to a blasted landscape, a slain regiment, a broken fortress. It is impossible to know which occurred more. In the end, it did not matter.

The 13th Black Crusade ground on.

Turn 16: Bringing Fire To Darkness (Part Four)

Spoiler: Plan Fast Rescue

[X] Plan Fast rescue
-[X] Captured Hangers 2
--[X] 10th Company, 1 non-Terminator Squad of 1st Company+2 1st Company Dreadnoughts (ranged equipped preferably), Chaplain Uther Volkoss, 2 Techmarines dig in and entrench. Reorient the turrets if necessary, effect what repairs possible to the Thunderhawks, stabilize the wounded.
-[X] Defensive Lance Battery 3
--[X] All 1st Company not defending Hangers 2 or going to find Doukas, Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus, Chaplain Ateren cut a path internally through the Anchorage
-[X] Squad Retrieval
--[X] 10 Terminators from 1st Company Teleport to Doukas's position & reinforce them. Attempt to meet up with Gabriel's force afterwards.
--[X] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chaplain Ravias, Chaplain Antonius, Apothecary Falkor Ryll, Chapter Honor Guard, 5th Company head deeper into the Anchorage, destroying targets of opportunity along the way. After resolving the fate of Sergeant Doukas's squad, assist with Lance Battery 3 if they're still fighting.
-[X] Bombarding Defensive Lance Battery 1
--[X] 5th Company Strike Cruiser Rage of Erudition, 1 Hunter Destroyer, 1 Nova Frigate. Secondary target Shield Battery 2.
-[X] Bombarding Enemy Hanger 1
--[X] 5th Company Battle Barge Litany of Fury, 1 Hunter Destroyer (1st Company). Secondary target Shield Battery 2.
-[X] Aiding The Navy
--[X] All other ships (10th Company Fleet, 1st Company Fleet)

Bringing Fire To Darkness
+015.M42+ To +020.M42+
+Distrust The Xeno, Hate The Xeno, Kill The Xeno+

“For the Emperor!” Doukas grunted out as he tore his power sword from the chest of the eldar so that he could block an incoming sword blow directed as his neck.

Around him, the bodies had slowly piled high, the speed and trickery that the xenos possessed amounting to less and less as the amount of available space for them to make use of it decreased. More than one of the grotesques he had faced, those mad designs of the eldar haemonculi, had possessed the strength of an astartes and more, but thus far he had yet won out. Some of his brothers…had not. Some of them, he knew not, for they had all be broken up so that their greater knowledge might benefit other squads, some he did. All that their deaths did was inflame his fury further, to allow him to slay more of the enemy. He knew, of course, that eventually he would be overwhelmed. His drop pod had performed far in excess of its purpose, for which it might be commended by a techpriest, but thus far it had seemed to only doom him.

It was then that a blast of light and the tingling remnants of the warp crawling into real-space ever so slightly such that a faint chill heralded their arrival, did a squad of fully armored terminators appear in the corridor. A split second afterwards their storm bolters were triggered, tearing dozens of surprised abominations and xenos to pieces. One of the trueborn, marked by his more elaborate armor, barely had time to open his mouth before a backhanded strike from a power fist exploded everything from the waist up. Doukas grimly nodded but once in their direction before returning to the fight, power sword flashing and bolter booming.

The carnage only grew, as ever more of the mad creations of the dark eldar spewed forth from their tunnels, walls, and even the ceiling itself as they fought their desperate battle. Even so, Doukas noted with clinical detachment as more of the xenos themselves seemed to be retreating from the fight in favor of letting the abominations fight for them. Far more of his focus was on the enemy, of killing one more, of preserving the sanctity of the bodies of those of his brothers who had already fallen in the initial moments of the conflict. Time blurred away, the ground piled up with shell casings as stormbolters fired endlessly, heavy bolters spitting out death into the ranks of cackling creatures. One, he thought, might once have been an ork given its skin coloration or perhaps it was the viscous acidic poisons within its veins that had lent it the color.

It was only as he heard the crackle and boom of power weaponry and smashing of bodies that he realized why they had turned away from the fight against he and his brothers. From behind the morass of bodies, their own dexterity left useless against sheer weight of fire, did come the Chapter Master himself. With each swing of his daemonhammer, did another eldar die. Beside him came Apollo Diomedes, once one of the greatest heroes the Chapter had once ever possessed, his face set and grim without a hint of the boastful cries he once let fly in battle. Lighting and fire spewed from the hands of the Chief Librarian to set the xenos to wonderfully sounding screaming. Better than all, however, was the heartening shouts of the Chaplains, led by Master Palrun, for it was those voices which provided the greatest of succor after so many long decades surrounded by the endless worshipful cant of the Mechanicus towards the Omnissiah. Hearing sermons of the Emperor invigorated him more than anything else ever possibly could have.

He would admit, however, that when he was brought to his knees by an eldar grenade that warped gravity terribly so that even a terminator was nearly crushed to death, it was the Chapter Master who bid him rise.

“Sergeant Doukas. Report,” Angelos grunted even as he turned to smash another grotesque, while behind him Justinius let loose another blast of lighting which shot down a cackling hellion from the air to smash into the ground as a charnel pile of flesh.

“Five dead, the rest are combat-fit.”

“May they find the Emperor’s side,” Angelos nodded once, before turning away.

Nothing more needed to be said. The apothecary emerged from the bloodletting, his white armor soaked in a disturbing rainbow of modified life-required fluids, acids, and more, to perform his holy work. Upon the vox channels the signals strengthened as the interference from the various subsystems of the Anchorage itself began to fail, and he heard once more the venerated voices of the captains of the fleet as they continued to bombard their targets. That, coupled with the cries of victory from those who had apparently been sent to another lance battery, made for a more than triumphant return as they cut their way free. Steadily, more and more of the eldar seemed to disappear, either to return to their cursed home or to fleet through other methods.

=============================================

“Chapter Master,” Hadrian’s voice cuts through the noises of battle as you and the rest of your battle brothers repelled seemingly endless waves of twisted and malformed flesh. “The Litany of Fury’s target has been destroyed, the second shield battery is near to collapse.”

“Good news indeed, Hadrian,” you grunt out as you shoulder charge a bulging mass of muscle from which a dozen swirling monomolecular blades spun wildly as three feet crunched their way forth. “The other bombardment targets?”

“Destroyed. I will remain upon the Litany of Fury, but shall turn the rest of the fleet against the enemy ships. The Navy has lost many men this day, and I can still direct our ships from here. They fight like cornered rats.”

“They will die like them,” you intone before switching over to Cyrus’ channels. “Captain? Report.”

“We’ve repelled several attacks, though I could do without the chatter. Clearly these two techmarines have forgotten some of the lessons they were taught before going to Mars.”

In truth, you can hear them bickering even now.

“- laser battery meant for anti-armor purposes you can’t just turn it on a charge of slaves just because-,”

“-it tore through them regardless! Just because you couldn’t turn the quad bolter around in time doesn’t mean that my rapier-,”

“-YOUR rapier?! It’s not yours, its the Chapter’s!”

“- I am wielding it in the name of the Chapter! Thus, for this moment, it is – look, ownership is nebulous considering-,”

At that point Cyrus cuts back in, thankfully so.

“We have repelled various assaults, though as time has gone on fewer and fewer eldar can be seen. I suspect that they are up to something, though they could simply be retreating through internal webway portals.”

Hmm. It is something to consider. As such, you turn to your Chief Librarian.

“Justinius?”

A massive explosion ripples throughout the entire Anchorage, then, and then from Justinius erupts a wild blaze of unrestrained light and power. He turns to you, eyes now practically miniature blue-lit stars within his sockets, and with a slight tilt to his head.

“The last shield battery has shattered, and with it, their anti-psyker defenses,” he explains before lifting a hand to summon a ball of ethereal flame to his hand which then quickly evaporates into nothingness. “I…can see them…HADRIAN!” he suddenly yells, “Prepare your defenses, they make to board you and escape upon the Litany of Fury! The last of their webway portals have failed!”

“Understood,” is the Master of Fleet’s terse reply.

A dire moment passes, during which the enemy finally slackens in their pressure upon your forces as they apparently have finished exhausting themselves to keep you back, and another series of shudders erupts from the Anchorage itself. You do not even need to hear Hadrian’s noting of enemy boarding slivers shooting out in a great shower filled no doubt not with the cannon fodder you’ve faced thus far but with actual eldar warriors. At the least, Hadrian had some time for preparation which few others forces in the galaxy would have possessed.

Even so.

The Anchorage will not survive the solar day. It is obvious in the damage dealt to it by the many bombardment cannons which have been unleashed against it. It was inevitable from the moment that you ordered weapons that could batter planets into submission be used against but a single station. Despite its size, it has clearly sustained heavy damage. More and more foreign warning alarms blare wildly, lights blinking on and off through the fire and smoke that are the evidence of the Emperor’s fury unleashed upon this vile place.

“They failed to pierce the shields protecting the bridge, but have struck center mass within the ship and are attempting to head here now,” Hadrian reports tersely, “I am marshalling the serfs and combat servitors upon the ship to defend it! The Litany shall not fall on this day!

“Chapter Master,” Apollo murmurs from your side as ever, “Your orders?”

Stage 2 Complete:
- 3 5th Company Dead. +6 Gene-Seed
- 2 1st Company Dead. +4 Gene-Seed
- 5th Company Squad Recovered! Casualties Taken, 5 Marines Dead! +10 Gene-Seed
- Litany of Fury boarded! Enemy Archon and Personal Guard present!
- Dark Eldar Anchorage is on the inevitable path of destruction, and is collapsing! Forces must either achieve their objectives upon it quickly, or retreat very, very soon!

Anchorage Assault Troop Deployment Decisions [Stage 3]:
Note: You do not have to assault every position, it may be better to concentrate your forces on some targets now and then attack others later.
Note: Precise determination of enemy troops present on Anchorage impossible at this time due to psychic baffles, sensor-ghosts, etc. Librarius efforts at such things in turn is similarly stymied, as well as additional warp fluctuations present in system.
[] From The Hangers: This location has been captured successfully, a great amount of enemy weaponry and ships destroyed before they could exit and be used against the forces of the Imperium. Thus far they have proven mighty bulwarks against the charges of the enemy, with enemy assaults weaning off even now. You could order that they take their thunderhawks and begin flying up to aid the Litany of Fury, or they can hold it for those forces who may be arriving soon enough. (Write-In Forces Dedicated To This Objective)
[] Heading To The Hangars: Not all of your forces can be teleported out, but instead must march their way back to the Hangar or elsewhere potentially. Those that head for the Hangars will surely not face nearly as much resistance as you have up until now, due to many of the xenos fleeing into the Webway or joining their Archon in their attempt to claim the Litany of Fury to escape upon. (Write-In Forces Dedicated To This Objective)
[] Loot Enemy Command Center: Deep within the Anchorage lies the Command Center of the entire Anchorage. With the great holes now blasted into the station, deep striking and thunderhawk deployments are possible. While the Archon is now upon the Litany of Fury, information gleaned from here might give better information about the Dark Eldar and their potential movements throughout the entire Sector, technologies, insights, and more. And, of course, for while None Shall Find You Wanting...Knowledge Is Power. Deep Strike Teleportation and thunderhawk assault possible. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here)
[] Teleport To The Litany Of Fury: The Archon of this entire Kabal, along with several of his guards, have boarded the Litany of Fury where Hadrian is currently based. It will take time not only to fight back to the Hangars, board the thundrhawks, and return much less fight. On the other hand, you could order that those amongst you bearing Terminator Armor as well as your Librarians to partake in an emergency return teleportation. You cannot take with you those who do not bear the teleportation beacons, not in the general chaos left behind by the steadily collapsing Anchorage. On the one hand, teleportation is a finicky technology on the best of days, but on the other, with the aid of the Librarius they should be able to assist in reducing the chances of some of those who would teleport from being lost forever in the warp or meet with some other misfortune. (Write-In Forces Deployed Here) May Only Take Terminator-suit bearing troops, including Chapter Master and Apollo, others bearing TH sigils on Chapter Designator. Librarians, due to their psyker natures, can guide the process as well and thus can come along.

- Characters Present On Litany of Fury: Master of Fleets Hadrian, 3 Codiciers (1 is Nero Achillian), 2 Apothecary Trainees!

Anchorage Ship Information, Hadrian Indesposed!
Whitmore Fleet Present: 1 Lunar-class Cruisers, 2 Gothic-class cruisers
Dark Eldar Fleet Present: 3 Torture Cruisers
Blood Raven Fleet Present: Entire Chapter Fleet, Litany of Fury remains above Anchorage and has been boarded!

Turn 16: Bringing Fire To Darkness (Part Five)

Spoiler: Orderly Movements

[X] Plan Orderly Movements
-[X] Teleport To The Litany Of Fury
--[X] From the Squad Retrieval Group: 10 Terminators from 1st Squad, Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chapter Honor Guard will teleport onboard and take the fight to the enemy boarders before they can enact any schemes to sabotage or takeover the ship or corrupt gene seed or any other Eldar plots
-[X] Loot Enemy Command Center
--[X] All forces in the Squad Retrieval Group (5th Company, non-TH named characters) who didn't teleport out. Ensure these forces have working locator beacons with clean signals in case they need to be teleported out in a hurry. Once at the Command Center, high priority should be to secure their egress route to link up with incoming Thunderhawks.
-[X] Heading To The Hangars
--[X] Forces assigned to destroy Defensive Lance Battery 3 (All 1st Company not defending Hangers 2 or going to find Doukas, Chief Apothecary Nero Gracchus, Chaplain Ateren) return from there backtracking along their previously cleared route for speed and ease of travel
-[X] From The Hangers
--[X] Defensive forces stay on station until the Lance Battery 3 forces return, then pack up and mount the Thunderhawks for egress.
---[X] Send enough Thunderhawks to the Enemy Command Center to pick up the forces transiting there after they finish (undermanned as necessary to fit everyone on the return trip), along with any items they are bringing back (recovered artifacts, intelligence that needs more time to decipher, etc).
---[X] All others travel back to the Litany of Fury as late reinforcements

Bringing Fire To Darkness
+015.M42+ To +020.M42+
+Distrust The Xeno, Hate The Xeno, Kill The Xeno+

Teleportation is a dangerous technology, but one that must be used regardless. It is far too useful to give up, it is as simple as that. That does not mean that you do not need to steel yourself for the oncoming rush through the warp. You hear the words of the initiation rites, the swelling of otherworldly power that surrounds Justinius, and the righteous fury of Hannibal as he bellows against the very warp itself should it dare to make you tarry in your journey. Then, with the depression of the activation runes, the world lifts, twists, and turns inside out. For an instant, nothing more, you are pulled wildly through the immaterium and hear the endless cackling of daemons and its denizens. You are a space marine, and know no fear, and yet it is simply unavoidable that something frozen tears its way up and down your spine as before your open eyes the incomprehensible insanity of the warp blazes its way before you.

Then it is over, and you are upon your former flagship and home. Before you have even taken your first lungful of smoke-clogged air nor have your ears begun to process the sound of weaponry both Imperial and xeno firing are you swinging Godsplitter upwards so that its head strikes a leaping incubi in the ground and causing everything upwards of that point to explode in viscera and metal. All around you battle commences within a split second of arrival, over the bodies of slain chapter serfs and dead eldar. For once, there are none of their disgusting grotesques or wracks, but only the xenos themselves left alive after you slew all they could muster.

Good. You tire of killing slaves when you would kill their masters. Especially when you know where they are.

“To the bridge!” you bellow as you lead the charge, attacking the xenos from behind as they slaughter serfs and battle combat servitors through the heavily damaged corridors. For once, it is you who hold surprise against them, and it is a feeling you relish as you end their monstrous existences.

“Let none find us wanting!”

Some of your party splits off, instead heading either to protect the apothecarium where distress signals from those there have been received or for the engines, but the majority of those who teleported charge alongside you along the corridors. The signs of battle are rampant, but even without an actual 4th Company to man the ships defensively Hadrian has performed remarkably well given the sheer number of corpses found. Many even located just outside of their damn boarding slivers which jut into the hull here and there. But it is to the bridge where you go, and the bridge you find yourself at, or at least just before it.

Hacking apart a dying serf who was once almost a space marine before the implants failed to properly integrate, stands an utterly hulking creature which bears only the faintest resemblance to the eldar it might once have been. Surrounded by other incubi, the eldar turns, and yet behind it you can see the doors to the bridge have been carved and blasted open by their destructive alien technologies. Whatever the creature is, whatever might have given rise to it, you simply do not find it within yourself to care. What matters truly at this point is killing it, and Justinius provides. As its guards and handlers leap forward without hesitation to face you, Hannibal, and the others, your Chief Librarian seems to blur reality itself to surprise the creature as he simply appears in front of it. The details of the fight are largely lost to you as you busy yourself with the frustratingly agile incubi which face you in turn, spitting poisoned slivers and pulse pistols at you while they dance around the strikes of Godsplitter, but by the time you manage to shoulder check one into a wall and plant a fist into the ribcage and through it, and twist your daemonhammer in your grip so that it trips up the other and sends it crashing to the floor where Apollo kills it with a stomp while he kills his own opponents despite their attempts to cut through his armor, there is a blast of psychic energies.

By the time you return your gaze to Justinius, he stands atop a charred pile of meat and armor that has at least half of its original mass simply missing from existence entirely, lighting and fire crackling off of his frame. Perhaps he found the anti-psychic defenses of the dark eldar to be particularly frustrating and wished to take out said frustration upon them once it was stripped away. What matters, of course, is the bridge, and you are moving rather than saying anything else, followed by the others in turn. Only Hannibal speaks, a low constant litany of fury – appropriate, some grim humorous fraction of you notes – about the desecration done here and the retribution that shall be dealt out to it.

When you enter onto the bridge of the Litany, where you yourself stood for over a century, you leapt immediately into battle once more. Yet more Incubi were present, but they faced no fresh battle brothers promoted out of the 10th Company or even those more veterans of the 5th. They fought the Honor Guard, and the leading members of the Chapter itself as a whole. Hannibal simply bulls over another wrack that outmassed him with his sheer strength, while Apollo deftly assaults some of the bulkier incubi who have obviously cut their way through far too much Imperial blood given the splatters across them. As for the Archon himelf…you sight him, just as he reaches the Command Throne where Hadrian sits.

But as you charge forward, you find yourself confronted by not by another eldar, but in fact a Sslyth, one of the vile alien mercenaries often found in the employ of such creatures as the dark eldar. Godsplitter rises and falls against one of its held klaives, shattering the alien blade, but there are yet three more which whirl towards you fast enough to tear into your armor as a visible field of power glows upon them. Hadrian’s yell up ahead galvanizes you, but the simple fact of the matter is that the damndable sslyth is like the rest of its kind in that it is all but inured to physical pain and thus does not seem to take into effect the fact that you slam your hammer into it with enough force to certainly kill a normal space marine. At least, at first. Immunity to pain does not mean that the damage itself is not sustained. Amidst the broken consoles and shattered bodies of your serfs, you batter it again and again until it simply cannot move any more after you have reduced its innards to useless paste.

“DIE YOU INSUFFURABLE HUMAN!!”

Your eyes rise, to find Hadrian held up by the throat of the Archon, easily denoted by a banner of screaming faces sewn into a single layer of glossy human flesh which is wrapped upon three stiffened spines connected the back of its armor. Around you the rest of the battle is winding down simply by the utter destruction of your foes and all those that the rest of your battle brothers faced, yet as you rush forward, Godsplitter at the ready, the Archon falls back, honest surprise on his face, with a single massive gaping hole marking where flesh and armor were vaporized instantly. Hadrian, an entire klaive slammed through his chest and out the back, falls to a knee, yet spits defiantly at the corpse of his foe as the twin plasma guns he holds in his hands screech wildly as the heat cooks off of them.

“And stay…off….my…ship!” he snarls before tipping over, blood spurting wildly out around the blade of the klaive.

==============================================

Twelve hours later, and the battle is over. The Anchorage’s broken remains as the last of its internal systems failed utterly float freely within the void, while your own brothers have returned once more to the fleet itself. The knowledge garnered by those who raided the abandoned command center will likely be of use given enough study, which the Librarium can perform in accordance with the rest of the vast amounts of knowledge remaining in the chapter records. Hadrian himself will live, though it will take a small amount of time for him to heal from his impaling. He was coherent enough, at least once given the proper stimulants from the apothecaries, to give you what information he could.

The foe, slain by his hand, had proclaimed himself as the Archon of the Split Hearts Kabal, as well as a sundry pile of threats to violate every single living individual on the Litany of Fury in the most terrible of ways for daring to destroy his sanctuary. Where the Archon planned on taking the ship is unknown to you, but Codicier Nero spoke of dark spaces and darker places when he shredded the dark eldar who attempted to raid or destroy the Librarius itself. Martellus, still on the Litany had personally seen to the defense of the reactors and engines, and noted with no small amount of apprehension that the haemonculus who he slew rather thoroughly possessed a disturbing amount of ability with Imperial technology. To the point of even overwriting numerous servitors and servo skulls on the ship to his purposes in the very middle of the fight. Had Martellus managed to drive a rapier into the incredibly tight corridors and used it successfully you might have had to deal with the actual ship itself turning against you even if you held the bridge.

Regardless.

“Admiral Whitmore,” you greet the mustachioed fat man as he glares at you with undisguised contempt from the holo-screen, both of his eyes aggressively bloodshot from the sheer exertion of the furious battle that had occurred within the void.

“Chapter Master,” he grunts back, before running a hand down his face. “Are you aware of the fact that I have lost tens of thousands of lives in crewmen, and several good captains in that fight?”

“I am, yes. I am sorry for their loss.”

“Bah,” he huffs, waving your condolences to the side with the same gruffness as he has ever displayed thus far. “They knew the stakes. Do you know how rarely we’ve actually been able to confront eldar in their bloody ships without them skittering away?”

Given their normal cowardly nature, it is likely that it is indeed more than a little rare.

“This is what the Navy is for, to strike down all those who would threaten the Imperium from its God-Emperor given right to mastery over the void itself,” he sneers before spitting to the side. “But it does not mean that this has greatly reduced our available manpower.”

Then his expression brightens slightly, though it is hard to tell through the folds of flesh upon him for sure.

“But now, a world of humanity has been returned to the Imperium and freed from the depredations of the xenos. Our own little piece of the Age of Strife, returned to the present. I hear the Order of the Lost Rosetta is already gearing up to enlighten the savages below.”

Ah. Part of you had thought perhaps about the world’s potential use for the Chapter…

“I’m heading back to Sector Command,” Whitmore speaks up again, and again he seems to lord his larger holographic appearance above you, “But know this, Blood Raven. One battle, one deed, does not excuse or excise what your predecessor was.”

Part of you knows, and seethes ever so slightly, at the disrespect. At the suspicion. At the open contempt. But the larger, wiser remainder of your soul knows for truth that the centuries of heresy which lay within the heart of the Chapter will have results such as this likely beyond your own death. It is inevitable, but that does not mean that it does not wear upon you.

“I understand that more than enough, Admiral. Safe travels.”

“Hmph.”

He does not thank you for the fact that your own Chapter Fleet threw itself headlong into the fight, and by Hadrian’s reckoning the Navy would have lost the fight without your aid, but at the same time it is, again, not exactly unexpected. He does not ask after your own lost ships. Nor does he speak further on the Anchorage itself who you note he has his ships bombard to further pieces in the meantime before his ships begin to leave. There is no exchange of favors, or condolences, or anything of the sort. The Navy faced their duty, and were grievously wounded for it. The Blood Ravens did their duty, and suffered losses as well. Then Whitmore leaves, and the Blood Ravens collect their own losses. More of your forces recovered from the Anchorage return to the Litany and help scour it from the rest of the Archons last desperate gambit to flee.

And that is the end of it.

Yet at the same time, it is not. For almost immediately afterwards after minor repairs have begun, with Hadrian’s efforts at preventing the dark eldar from bringing ruination to any truly particularly vital systems successful, the Blood Ravens move out further. With the destruction of the Anchorage, there yet remains plenty more to be done. Cyrus and the 10th Company move out to cull Trontiux II, while others are seconded to other Mechanicus interests. It might frustrate some due to the fact that your Chapter seems too focused on aiding the Mechanicus but you know for a fact that you need to rebuild your Chapter Fleet to its former glory. Without such relations or contracts such as the Iron Hands or Salamanders might possess, you will do as you must for the betterment of the Chapter.

As the next four years and some odd months pass, you find yourself on the Judgement of Carrion, battling its long-standing inhabitants and safeguarding the work of the techpriests as they go about their work in wresting the vast space hulk from the grip of the warp. They are not glorious fights, but instead a dozen or more desperate struggles that you barely win out again and again. Casualties are high, but remarkably they remain only as such. No new dreadnought needs awakening from half-death, no brothers are forced into such a state. That does not mean the fight is not grueling, yet from the constant passes by Aramus in the past and the Mechanicus up until this point you do not at least have to deal with the constant outflow of tyranids or orks as you might have in the past. Instead, the daemons come, and for while they are of the most vicious and horrific of opponents to face, you can at the least prepare for them. Set up kill-zones, and the like. The fight continues, both here, and across the rest of the Imperium, but you shall not falter. None shall find you wanting.

Stage 3 Complete:
- 2 5th Company Dead. +4 Gene-Seed
- Dark Eldar Anchorage Destroyed! All Enemy Ships Destroyed! Command Center Looted! Victory!
- Zero improvement in Navy relations due to battle casualties taken!

Spoiler: Mechanicus Detachments

-[X] Squad Protection
--[X] 5th Company Tactical Squad
-[X] Veteran Squad Search
--[X] 9 5th Company Veterans, Codicer Nero to search for uncorrupted tech
-[X] Trontiux II Culling
--[X] 10th Company
-[X] Return Of Judgement [Crew Quarters]
--[X] Marcus Crixus (Stormbolter), Uriel Hamul (Thunder Hammer/Storm Shield), Ares Actus (Crozius/Stormbolter), Marcharius Sicarius (Power Fist), Amicus Antal (Powerfist/Stormbolter), 5 1st Company Veterans
---[X] 5 Tartaros-Pattern for named characters, 5 Indominatus-Pattern for others, applicable relics
----[X] 2 Heavy Flamers, 1 Assault Cannons, 1 Pair of Lightning Claws, Thunder Hammer, 1 Power Axe, 2 Power Fists, 3 Cyclone Missle Launchers
------[X] Marcus's terminator group and 1st Company to join Gabriel Angelos on Gellar Field assingment after completion of purging the Crew Quarters
-----[X] 1st Company Squad plus apothecary to wait in support
-[X] Return Of Judgement [Gellar Field Installments]
--[X] Gabriel Angleos, Apollo Diomedes, Hannibal Palrun, Uther, Tarkus Varianus, Justinius Probalis, Damion Tyrin, Doukas Laskaris, 20 1st Company Terminators
---[X] 5 Tartaros-Pattern armors for Apollo, Tarkus, Justinius, Hannibal, and Doukas. 22 Indominatus-Pattern to everyone else. Applicable relics
----[X] All other Flamers, Assault Cannons, Plasma Cannons, and melee weapons. Stormbolters to those without a specialist weapon. 5 Cyclone Missle Launchers
-----[X] Honor Guard and 1 5th Company squad plus apothecary to wait in support

- 4 Minor Favors Of Mechanicus Garnered In Exchange For 2 Gladius Frigates! To Be Delivered By Beginning of 020.M42.

The March to Karak Eight Peaks - Week 5 - Barak Varr

Spoiler [*] Yes -[*] Talisman -[*] 15 Favors -[*] Protection [*] Have them help you teach your fast-growing familiar simple commands. [*] Barak Varr is a trading hub; go shopping with her and employ your good name among dwarves to see if there's seeds of anything useful to be found. [*] Many mercenaries look for work at Barak Varr among trades looking to make the long and dangerous trip to the east. See if any can be convinced to join the Expedition instead. [*] Barak Varr is one of the greatest centers of trade in the world. Spend some time browsing to see if you find anything interesting. Favours as currency is an art that the Grey College excels at, since the Vow of Poverty rather limits using currency as currency. To cash in said favours is not as simple as handing coin over to a shopkeeper and having them at your service. It takes care, tact, and dropping a great deal of hints. You spend time with various dwarves high up enough in circles to have the ear of those that matter, sharing a drink or two and speaking of the Sylvanian campaign; how it might be nice to have some sort of ornament to wear as a memento of those times, and of the great work you did with (and for) the dwarven Throng. There's no explicit acknowledgement, just a few deep, thoughtful nods, and just like that a nugget of information enters the collective knowledge of the assembled dwarves: the means to settle an outstanding debt. Somewhere, someone is having a quiet word with Kragg the Grim; he's ranking his level of disapproval and finding that he disapproves of the Dwarven Empire being in your debt more than he does crafting an item for a manling. Various dwarves are plucked from the gathered Throng, both of adventurers from Zhufbar and from the assembled dwarves from Karak Kadrin, and the events of the Sieges of the Drakenhofs nearly two years ago now are recounted in exhausting detail. Somewhere, a stammering and overawed Barak Varr Runepriest surrenders his forge to a living legend, and Kragg the Grim sets to work settling a debt. --- If one could even say there's such a thing as a 'conventional' dwarfhold, Barak Varr would be the opposite of it. Far from being isolated, conservative and dour, Barak Varr is full of life and activity and visitors from across the world. The vast harbours are full of ships, sleek Tilean galleys, vast Estalian galleons, proud Bretonnian corsairs, nimble Arabyan dhows and mighty Empire Wolfships, but outnumbering them is the mighty navy of the Dwarves. Driven by closely-guarded secrets of steam and smoke, they have no need of the sails or oars that feature on every human ship present, and they fill the space that is saved with armour and guns. The nimble monitors capable of patrolling the many rivers of the Border Princes region, the mighty ironclads that bristle with guns, and here and there, the dreadnoughts, so massive and costly that barely one is built a generation. If those were not wonders enough, the markets of Barak Varr rival the harbour in grandeur and are greater even than those of Altdorf or Marienburg. You see barrels and mounds of spices that you've previously seen only in measures of pinches and pouches, entire bolts of precious silk stacked as haphazardly as if they were the most inferior wool, and under the careful watch of guards of a dozen nationalities or more, handfuls of precious stones glimmering brilliantly in the torchlight. Everywhere you look there are wonders, drawn in from every corner of the world, whether from long, gruelling oversea voyages that round entire continents, or from overland trips through territory held by greenskin and undead and other, even fouler threats. Hawkers not only sell their wares but actively recruit for the next voyage, and the crowds are made up as much of mercenaries looking for their fortunes as they are merchants looking to spend theirs. Dwarven moneychangers operate gadgets of intricate clockwork as they exchange one currency for another. Vast notice boards display the prices of goods in distant centers of trade, as well as how current the prices are; judging by how recent most of them are, they must have arrived by gyrocopter or some other, even more outlandish means. It is into this swirling melee that you will throw yourself thrice over: once for Panoramia, once for yourself, and once for the Expedition. --- If anything, Panoramia is more awestruck by the markets than you are; you have to guide her by the arm through the crowds as she gawks to keep her from being trampled underfoot by some vast cargo-beast you don't even have a name for. You steer her into the spice section of the markets, and then through it to a smaller, much less prestigious one: that dedicated to other, non-edible plants. Here is the realm of those with big dreams that are so often disappointed, and you find yourself surrounded by flagging merchants trying desperately to convince anyone that will listen that this or that is the food crop that will revolutionize farming in the Old World. It's all so many poor, wilting examples of greenery to you, but Panoramia comes to life, and you're shown an entirely new side to her as she tears through the hopeful merchants like a buzzsaw. Some plants are dismissed at a glance, others are closely examined before being moved past, and a very few cause her to actually speak to the merchants trying to sell them. You've brought your purse and you doubt that a few seeds will set you back too much, but even that proves unnecessary as she negotiates a deal: the plant in question is magically revitalized and the merchant can start trying to sell their plant with actual documented evidence from the Jade College as to the positive effects of it, all for a few seeds that wouldn't have sprouted without her intervention anyway. The first plant chosen for further examination is a sort of grass from distant Ind. The merchant calls it koo-sha grass, and claims that the natives of that place use it in religious rituals to achieve enlightenment; more of interest to you and Panoramia is that they apparently also use it to treat dysentery and influenza, and failing that it's also a rather hardy plant and quite edible for livestock. A neat piece of spellcraft later, a thriving example of the plant is sprouting out of a barrel half-filled with dirt and Panoramia has a small handful of seeds tucked into one of her glass phials. The second is from slightly closer to home; the cone of a type of Estalian pine that, according to Panoramia, produces a sap that can be distilled into a sort of oil good for treating wounds and discouraging parasites. The merchant had been advertising the cone for its use in predicting the weather, claiming it would open when it will be dry and close when it will rain, so accepted a few silver coins for it before moving onto the next customer, unaware that he'd just practically given away a curative for an entire army. No further wonders are to be found, and while it's slightly disappointing to not have found any rare and exotic wonders and instead come away with grass and a type of pine tree, Panoramia is quite happy to have some new plants to work with, and says that she might be able to unlock further effects with a little help from magic. And even if she doesn't, she says, dysentery and infection are terrible enemies of armies on the march, and having the tools to fight them both are not to be sneezed at. [Plants and Seeds in the Markets of Barak Varr: 66, 52, 31.] [First plant: Rolling for Origin: Ind] [Second plant: Rolling for Origin: Old World] --- The next day you brave the crowds alone, looking for nothing in particular. There are shiny and pretty and aromatic wonders everywhere you look; more difficult to find is something useful, or at least something especially distracting. You succeed. The first strange wonder you find is a merchant selling a clutch of five eggs, each the size of a man's head. He claims they have been brought from distant Lustria, and that they contain terrible, wondrous beasts that will serve whoever hatches them. You doubt this, but the eggs are larger than any you've laid eyes upon and you do find curiosity burning inside of you at the sight of them. Even if the eggs were dead, whatever strange creature lay within would be worth dissecting for novelty value alone. The second is allegedly from the terrible Land of Chill, Naggaroth, homeland of the Dark Elves - a small pile of pitted scales that are allegedly from a Helldrake that attacked a tradeship bound for Barak Varr and was driven off only at great cost in blood and cannonfire, leaving behind death, destruction, and a few fractured scales that fell from its body. Looking at the scales, each the size of a dinner plate, you can feel the truth of what he says - this came from a terrible creature indeed, and are still attuned to the magical energies that allows such enormous creatures to exist. Though you don't currently have the skills to match these materials, these could one day be part of a powerful and terrible enchantment. The third is from very close to home: the dented and tarnished crown of a Border Prince, along with a deed on ancient parchment bequeathing a section of land somewhere in the anarchic region to the holder. Accompanying that is a short note from Barak Varr acknowledging the legitimacy of the claim, and another note acknowledging the legitimacy of the acknowledged legitimacy. Standing next to the merchant is an incredibly surly dwarf who says, before you even ask, that the scroll is genuine; since he's wearing the livery of Barak Varr in full sight of the market's guards without being put to some very serious questions, you're inclined to believe him. From what little you know of the region, the kingdom in question is likely to be the incredibly small, utterly poor, claimed by a dozen other Princes and hosting a greenskin infestation for good measure; but then, Princess would be such a nice title to add to your growing list, and it might unlock certain geopolitical options for you... [Searching for whatever you might find: [HIDDEN], 56, 47.] [First item: Rolling for Origin: Lustria] [Second item: Rolling for Origin: Naggaroth] [Third item: Rolling for Origin: Old World] --- On the third day, it is the part of the market filled with recruiters and mercenaries that calls to you; you find an unclaimed section next to a thoroughfare and add your voice to the din. By mid-morning, you've accomplished nothing, being utterly untrained in the art of 'yelling very loudly at crowds' and apparently there's more to it than just doing exactly that. You lurk in the crowds, watching which of the criers attract the attention of the passers-by, and attempt to emulate them, but to no success; there's just too much noise and not enough of you. You consider magically amplifying your voice, but you've never had the need to achieve fine volume control with the Sound spell and now's probably not a good time to trial-and-error it. By mid-afternoon, you've had more than enough of trying, and you slink off in a huff. [Recruitment attempt: Diplomacy, 14+10=24, 22+10=32] --- You've had your fill of the sights, sounds and smells of the market. You make your way out of Barak Varr and round the bulk of the mountain it is built onto until it evens into a steady slope, and you climb it. An hour later, you've reached a point giving a breathtaking view of the Black Gulf, with Barak Varr far below you, where a single tent is raised. And you stop mid-tread as an unmistakable set of sounds reach your ears, and turn and walk away with your cheeks burning. You'd heard rumours of that sort of thing among the more... earthy Colleges, and you suppose you are an uninvited guest in the piece of land they've claimed as camp, but honestly, it's the middle of the day! A half hour of admiring the view about five minutes walk down the mountain, you make your way back up and find Esbern and Seija working on a fire, which thankfully isn't a euphemism - they've carved a piece of wood into shavings and are banging a flint and tinder together to shower sparks upon it. They greet you as you approach and you very firmly put the events of a half hour ago out of your mind as you unsling your pack, letting your passenger hop out and stretch his legs. The two of them coo over your puppy, and ask you his name; you've been calling it Wolf for sentimental reasons, and they accept that as perfectly suitable. They examine him carefully as they feed him scraps of dried meat, and guess his age at about three months. About the age where he'd start joining his parents' hunts; in two weeks or so, he'll enter a stage of rapid growth, gaining over a pound of weight every week until about seven months of age, at which point he should be about seventy pounds in weight. After that, he'll enter the period of slow growth and gain about half a pound of weight per week, until reaching his full size of up to a hundred pounds at a year old. He's likely to be ravenously hungry the entire time, so it's just as well the army will have plenty of meat on hand to feed the even larger predators of the Knightly Orders. They seem more than happy to help you with the training of your familiar; they say that eventually the bond between the two of you will grow to the point where training isn't needed for him to know what you want, but that point could be months or even years away and in the meantime it's a sensible precaution. It's agreed that once the march resumes, they'll be joining you every night after dinner to help teach your familiar basic commands. --- As the week draws to a close, news filters through the crowds of the agreement struck between the two Kings. After much consulting of ancient maps, the location of a subterranean highway linking Death Pass and Blood River was rediscovered. The Barak Varr navy would secure Blood River up to where it met this highway, and the Expedition would secure the Highway itself from whatever menace currently calls it home. In this way, supply lines would be established that would not be threatened by the greenskin occupation of Black Crag or the innumerable tribes of the Badlands, and all the Expedition had to do to remain in contact with the world is to keep a stretch of Death Pass secure. And, perhaps more importantly, the greenskin stronghold of Black Crag that dominates the mouth of Death Pass - which, incidentally, was once the dwarfhold of Karak Drazh - could be bypassed entirely. All the Expedition had to do was march along the southern bank of the Blood River under the protective guns of Barak Varr's riverine navy, bridge a couple of tributaries, and build a dock in the shadow of Thunder Mountain. It is as this news spreads and the Expedition regathers that you feel the unmistakable feeling of Ulgu sobbing quietly to itself, and you turn to see Kragg the Grim approaching you. "Hand," he barks, and you hold yours out and he drops what looks like a rope of chainmail into it. He nods the satisfied nod of someone who is finally done with a distasteful task, and turns and leaves without another word to you. You examine the item, and find it to be a belt made of chainmail links of blackened steel, with a large buckle etched with a simple mountain; extremely common in Dwarven fashion, but you recognize it as the mountain that Castle Drakenhof was once built upon. And on the reverse, etched deep into the steel and filled back in with what could only be pure gromril, are three runes, and you can feel the power radiating off them. When you look up again, a harried and awed looking dwarf with a pure-white beard that brushes the ground is standing there. "He didn't wish to linger to explain," he says numbly. "But nor did he want his work unappreciated. But though he allowed me to watch the entire way through, I barely understood a fraction of it." He points to the first rune. "This, as I understand it, is a variation on the Spelleater Rune. When a hostile spell is targeted against you, it will not only counter it but also burn - literally burn - the knowledge of it from the mind of the caster. It will be dormant for twelve hours after each use." He points to the second. "This appears to be based on the Master Rune of Spite, but somehow combined with the Rune of Fortitude. It will grant you the strength to withstand wounds, while returning twofold any strike against whoever dealt it to you." And the third, the largest and most intricate of the three. "This one incorporates elements of both the Rune of the Furnace and the Rune that Valaya gave to us that allowed us to weather the coming of Chaos. It will grant you such resistance to flame that you could wade through lava, and burn off any taint of chaos before it could even touch you." He stares at it in awe. "Thank you. Had you not performed a task worthy of such a gift, I would not have been able to witness its creation." He takes a deep breath and tears his eyes from it, and stumbles off back into the depths of Barak Varr. You remove the simple cloth belt that has kept your robes fastened, and replace it with the metal of this belt. You feel the power in it thrum as you fasten it, flooding your body with a power unlike that you're so familiar with; this is power that has been brought to heel, tamed by the dwarven runes; its only character now is that which it has been given. You cautiously reach into the flames of a nearby torch, feeling the warmth of it but no more no matter how close your fingers dance to it; you decide that your Seed can heal you if this goes terribly and grasp the flaming torch by the end you normally shouldn't. The flames sputter around your hand, but you still feel no more than a pleasant warmth, and your skin remains unharmed. --- The course of the Expedition has shifted; instead of going south along the Old Silk Road, you will be travelling south-east along the bank of the Blood River, named for how red it runs every time a greenskin Waagh emerges from the Badlands to crash against the realms of men. That path will take the Expedition through the territory of the Ironclaw Orcs - made famous by the terrible and cunning warboss Gorbad Ironclaw some eight hundred years ago, whose Waaagh utterly destroyed the province of Solland, burned Nuln to the ground, and besieged Altdorf, during which a wyvern smashed its way into the Palace and ate the reigning Emperor. Today they are merely a local threat rather than an existential one, but one that has never been entirely stamped out. From the former dwarfhold of Iron Rock, an aptly-named mountain made almost entirely of iron, they are all but immune from the retribution of man or dwarf. Choose as many as you wish from the below; the THREE with the most votes will be Mathilde's actions for the coming week. Any purchases you make will not take actions. Contributing to the Campaign: [ ] Forces have been sent ahead to bridge the first inconvenient tributary of the Blood River; join them and aid in standing guard against any that may try to stop you. [ ] Ulthar's Rangers and Petrescu's marksmen are ranging far to ensure that any greenskin that claps eyes on the Expedition don't live to tell the tale. Assist them. [ ] If any resistance does start to gather, they will be smashed apart by the very heavy cavalry of the Knightly Orders. Stand ready with them. [ ] Have Ulthar handpick his best sharpshooters to be equipped with envenomed bolts. Spend time with the Council of War: [ ] Thane Skaroki Grimbrow [ ] Master Engineer Durin Wutokri [ ] Grand Master Sigwald Kriegersen [ ] Grand Master Ruprecht Wulfhart [ ] Marksman Codrin Petrescu [ ] Marshal Titus Muggins Other Preparations: [ ] You've heard that greatswords and greataxes are near identical in the way they're used, and you happen to be surrounded by experts in the art of the axe. Learn how to use one. Spend time with your Journeymanlings: Esbern and Seija of the Amber Order [ ] Test their skills in battle. [ ] Help Esbern teach Seija to Dispel. Maximilian de Gaynesford of the Gold Order [ ] Ask him to reforge your sword into a superior one. [ ] Introduce him to the dwarven smiths so he can try to convince them to teach him. [ ] Ask the smiths to teach him as a favour to you (-2 favours) [ ] Ask him to teach Johann to Dispel. Johann of the Gold Order [ ] Help him find a place with the dwarf artillery crews so that he can supplement their abilities in combat. [ ] Keep tabs on his interactions with the dwarves, making sure he's not fishing for information that the dwarves want to keep for themselves. --- Purchases from Barak Varr You currently have 556 gold coins. [ ] Purchase the strange Lustrian eggs (200 gc). [ ] Do not purchase the strange Lustrian eggs. [ ] Purchase the Helldrake scales (100 gc). [ ] Do not purchase the Helldrake scales. [ ] Purchase the title of a Border Princess (300 gc). [ ] Do not purchase the title of a Border Princess.

020.M42 Through 025.M42 Interlude: Curse And Blessing

020.M42 Through 025.M42 Interlude: Curse And Blessing

Celestine screamed as Abbadon slammed down his boot upon her back, crushing her to the blood-soaked soil face first hard enough to leave a crater. Before the horrified cries and disbelieving screams of all those who watched, launching endlessly fusillades which bounced off uselessly against the shield of blackened sorcerous flames which surrounded him. Many more were so frozen by their viewing of the spectacle that bloodletters and plaguebearers who leapt through the holes in the walls began to slaughter many before they shook off their foolish stupor. Beneath him, the ‘Saint’ as she was called writhed, growling in pain as she attempted to rise before he stomped down once more, cracking her marble-esque white armor.

“Fight on, scions of the Emperor,” she finally called out, her voice echoing across the battlefield despite the fact that he ground her face into the dirt, “Do not despair, but instead fight!”

“Be silent, pathetic wretch!” he bellowed before grasping her disgustingly ‘pure’ wings with one mighty hand each, and then exulted in its pained scream as he tore both of the white feathered things from her in great spurts of blood which hissed and sizzled as they touched him.

“Lady Celestine!” one of the warp-touched sisters howled, and with a mere look in her direction, the chaos space marine that had been holding her down on her knees placed the head of his meltagun against her skull and fired.

“No!”

“Yes,” Abbadon growled down to her, grinding the tips of the Talon of Horus along her back, drawing channels in her flesh to release her blood. “Kill the other one too.”

The other champion of the Imperium of the pair that had accompanied this curious creature before him died thereafter, and yet he paused momentarily to puzzle over the strange wisp of her soul as he fled before his witch-sight before the true powers of the warp could consume it. Beneath him, the greatest concentration of such strangeness and who had confounded him across the surface of Cadia screamed again as he drove the Talon of Horus into her back fully so that it excited the front, shredding what looked like they were meant to be human organs if inlaid in gold and white somehow. With a grunt, he turned his lightning claw around so that she was facing him, and then ripped the Talon of Horus through to shear her in half.

“LADY CELESTINE!” some of the sisters of battle still alive screamed in fury, abandoning their defensive positions to charge forward firing their bolters and flamers.

Abbadon turned to them, and fired upon them in turn. From the Talon of Horus’ combi-bolter spewed a hundred rounds, each possessed by a daemon, and shredded the fanatics to pieces before they could even truly finish exiting their foxholes. The fortress, such as it was, was suffering a similar fate. One of those forward positions that had fallen to his forces and had then been reclaimed as their precious ‘Celestianian Crusade’ pushed back his weaker and more feckless commanders across Cadia. But now it was his once more, and he would personally oversee the rituals done with the disemboweled remains of the creature beneath his boot.

Then he felt the corpse shifting beneath his boots.

“For…,” the dead thing gurgled, and his eyes widened in shock as he looked down, only to see that its blade was once more engulfed in bright flames as the shorn torso impossibly managed the strength swing at him. “The Emperor!”

He was Abbadon, and so even its defiant last gasp was nothing to him. Drach'nyen rose up, the fell intelligence within speeding itself towards the clash before Abbadon could, and he was forced to blink his eyes clear of the white flash that erupted when the two blades struck one another. Only then did he truly see what had occurred, and thus did the Despoiler let loose a wild scream to the stars as all evidence of the meant-to-be-dead creature that was almost as if a daemon but not had disappeared entirely. Not only that, but her two precious servants had disappeared as well, despite the warp-touched melta blasts evaporating much of their torsos along with their heads. He roared again, and then teleported further into the falling fortresses.

There yet remained hundreds of sisters and guardsmen left within, fighting with pathetically inspired hearts and desperate hope in their souls. He would slay each and every one of them, and feed their souls to Chaos!

==================================

“In the name of the God-Emperor, death to his enemies!” Celestine cried as she flew from the heavens upon the open battlefield, sword blazing with light and a visible halo of gold and white surrounding her as she descended.

Abbadon did not waste his time with shouts of ‘impossible’ or any other myriad denial as he heard from other lesser minds. Instead he fired upon with a storm of warp-touched bolter rounds from the Talon of Horus, which fell upon her shining aura with no visible effect. Yet at the same time as she cut through two of the obliterators before him, when he struck with Drach’nyen she was forced to duck. Not even her own protections could deny his blade, and thus he struck again and again, driving her back all the while her feet remained above his world by a foot or more. Her increased agility and flight would not avail her in the end. Yet she dueled him all the same, until finally she failed. Abbadon exulted in slicing through her arm, sending her pathetic ‘Ardent Blade’ clattering onto the earth where its fires burned at the visible black corruption which seeped from the bodies of the Death Guard on the battlefield, and laughed as he tasted her blood on his tongue as he grasped her around the midsection with the Talon, the claws tearing into her deeply as he did so.

“Scream, you wretch!” he snarled, and yet as she opened her mouth as he squeezed hard enough to crush and slice her internal organs apart, dropping her as pulped organs were forced up out of her throat.

Celestine arched slightly before falling flat, and yet as he readied to plunge Drach’nyen into her skull which cackled in his mind in joy at the carnage, he was forced back by the explosion of light which erupted from her corpse, his very eyes melting in the sockets slightly before he raised his arm to block it. When he lowered his arm, the body of the abomination in the shape of a mortal was gone once more, along with her two precious helpers. Abbadon roared, and yet found that in the time it had taken for him to kill her, transports secreted away many of the troops of the Imperium so that they could reset and reinforce their lines. Growling, he marched on, stomping heavily into the soil where her blood had been spilled as he moved on.

=====================================

Nine massive sets of chains wrapped around the Saint’s body, choking her throat, binding her limbs, crushing her wings. Each of them was of transmuted warpflesh and blackened steel forged in the blood of the damned, runes carved in each link by the sorcerers of the Black Legion. While many of his own sorcerers had disappeared some time ago, returning to the side of their erstwhile Primarch who as of yet still refused his summons, many remained besides. Abbadon chuckled as he stepped up the altar, where the sorcerers stood, their staffs held high as the warp twisted and moaned beneath their touch. Here, at the broken epicenter of one of the destroyed pylons of Cadia, one of the frustratingly few he had thus far been able to obliterate, he had finally captured it. His army stretched out in all directions from this one point, and yet he focused his attentions here.

“You are no mortal creature, Celestine,” he rumbled as he stood above her, the powers of the warp thrumming through him as he glared down at her bound body. “And yet, you are no daemon. Not quite.”

She would have likely said some other insipid statement about the glory of the Corpse but thankfully a thick looping of chain cut off her airflow and wound its way across her mouth as well as a gag.

“I do not know what you are, or how your False God has granted you this…but it doesn’t matter. You are close enough,” he let Drach’nyen sate a modicum of its thirst as he slowly sliced her open from stomach up towards her chest in a single thin line, “For a ritual such as this to bind you.”

“It will be done soon, my lord,” the feathered and hunched sorcerer closest to him spoke.

It was an inferior creature, not an astartes, but the power and pacts it had made as an Inquisitor in its past life was more than enough to grant it a position here. Abbadon inclined his head slightly as he stepped back, taking care not to harm even a mote of the warpdust ground from daemon bones which made up the ritual circle surrounding the entire altar. The Despoiler turned, for a moment, to gaze upon the horizon, to where another fortress fell to his forces, another stood defiant, and yet a third was being built anew. The war, this glorious war, was not even close to over, but he would win it without the continual interference of the one who would now be bound.

“Like the rest of your kind, you are weak,” he called out to her as she struggled.

A hundred of his veteran space marines had fallen to her, and yet this…this was more than worth it. The many wounds which covered her only made her oncoming doom all the sweeter.

“You have slipped away, your essence like the Corpse-Emperor fleeing as a coward would, again and again. This time…no longer!”

The warp heaved, and billowed as the ritual grew in power and potency. Blood and bone began to rise in the air, forming into unreadable sigils of binding blazing with unholy light.

“This time,” he snarled, “You cannot flee, you cannot escape, you cannot win!”

His instincts and a dozen other infernal intelligences besides bound to his service screamed, and Abbadon twisted to let a bolter round shimmering in ghostly black and red fire miss him. Instead, it struck one of the sorcerers, and upon impact erupted in an explosion which vaporized the thousands year old astartes of the Black Legion from the waist up. Abbadon turned, his ire already raised, his combi-bolter firing, and yet his own rounds struck none of the dozens of flame-wreathed and black armored astartes which had appeared all around him. They came, he realized then, from the very coils and rips in the warp that the sorcerers had made such that they could finally bind Celestine in one place to enable him to utterly end her existence!

“No! I will not allow this!” he roared as he leapt, armor grinding with the movement, and swung Drach’nyen down towards her.

She was bound enough, and as Drach’nyen drank down the very essence of the immaterium, it would have to be able to kill her! But the chains had snapped, fired upon by the very marines who had appeared from nowhere and were even now cutting down his cabal and around at the thousands of marines and daemons surrounding the ritual site who fought back with all their own horrific fury. Celestine rose, her wounds healing before his very eyes, but instead of clashing blades with him once more as he knew she would fail in battle against him, she flew directly into the air, her sycophantic servants rising with her as their own bindings were ruined.

“RRRAAAAAGH!”

He threw Drach’nyen, then, and laughed aloud as it pierced the back of one of them, and the many-lived sister screamed as it drank of her deeply. The glowing light which surrounded her faded, and she fell to the earth with the distressed screams of Celestine and her remaining slave-creature. Her body crumpled and wasted away even as he strode over to reclaim his weapon which rose into the air and flew into his grip, the body still impaled upon it. The sister struggled once, twice, and then finally fell still, her features wasting away until there was little more than a desiccated pile of flesh and bone and broken armor on his blade.

Turning back, he growled at the sight of the ghostly marines who had appeared being replaced instead with carnage from within his own camp. Of the marines themselves, there was no sign but the destruction they had left behind. Abbadon gnashed his teeth, before raising up the corpse still impaled on his blade and examining it, turning the head left and right. He had not yet succeeded at killing Celestine…but at the least he knew that the next time she appeared she would bereft of at least one of her servants. His mind then turned to churning about the possibilities of strong enough usage of the warp providing a passage for those…things. He knew them not, they held no heraldry he knew, and yet he knew of them. They came and went without warning, save that when the warp grew strong, and the barrier between it and the materium grew weaker, they could arrive.

It didn’t matter. He did not rest on shock or laurels. He yet had a war to win, and more blood to spill! If it took him a hundred years, or a hundred more…he would end her. She had interfered too many times to allow any other course of action, even as some spoke of trying to twist the being towards the Chaos Gods. She would certainly be a powerful boon then, but he cared little for such talk. Let Erebus do his best, let the Word Bearers speak as they willed. So long as they completed their own objectives, he did not care. So long as this…Celestine lived, she would inspire, and lead, and buoy the meek hearts of the Imperium’s lickspittles. If that meant he had to dedicate more of his forces to hunt her down rather than elsewhere…then so be it!

020.M42 Through 025.M42 Interlude: The Fate Of Beasts Is To Be Hunted

020.M42 Through 025.M42 Interlude: The Fate Of Beasts Is To Be Hunted

In the void, a space marine screamed.

“There…is…,” the Chaplain Guelph gurgled out from where he lay, chained upon the top of the sarcophagus and unable to move a muscle. “Still time to stop this…Ciacco.”

A lie.

Over a dozen of their eldest, some captains, others sergeants, snuffled and gnawed at his gaping wounds, tearing bits and pieces out at random from his still living body. Blood and meat caked their haphazardly sharpened teeth, cut into sharp triangles with their own combat knives as their minds descended into the murky depths of animals. Throughout it all, the Guelph’s pained gasps could be heard through his grit teeth while he gazed at the Chapter Master who stood above them all, slowly crunching through a human leg with a maw that had twisted and bulged with mutation. The sigil of the Chapter had been carved into his chest as the body of the formerly pure astartes had swollen larger than even terminator armor could cover, one of his arms grown so massive forward to rest on the knuckles while the other remained smaller.

“No…Chaplain,” Ciacco growled, a foot-long tongue licking across the hundreds of small sharpened teeth which poked out through his own cheeks and chin and bleeding itself in turn. “It is too late. It was always too late.”

“In the name of the Emperor, please,” Guelph hissed in pain as one of his most beloved brothers, Captain Ghibelli, howled to the air before ripping off a massive chunk of flesh from one of his thighs and swallowing it whole and then latching his mouth to the wound to suck down the blood which wept from it.

“Nnnno!” Ciacco roared, slamming his oversized arm’s fist into the wall plating, crumpling it with his mutant strength. “No Emperor. Hhheee died for Him….and nnnooow,” his words slurred as he shambled closer, “We wiiiillll live.”

“As monsters,” Guelph whispered, “As beasts.”

“We are nnnoooot monters!” Ciacco growled, barreling forward and sending his former brothers scattering in a host of growls and whimpers as they were either knocked to the side of crawled away on all fours. “Weee….are…asstarteeeees.”

With a grunt, he pointed towards his own face with his un-mutated arm, and thrust it towards Guelph.

“I…doooon’t drink or eat of you,” he struggled to speak, a long tooth suddenly growing and spearing through his lower jaw to let blackening blood drip to the floor. “AND LOOK WHAT I HAVE BECOME!”

What had once been the 2nd Company Captain leapt forward, mewling as it lapped at the pool, boney growths spilling out of its back to punch through the broken remains of its ceramite armor.

“We…needed…sacred…flesh!” Ciacco grunted, tongue running again along his hundreds of outer teeth, hungrily staring down at the dozens of gnawed wounds on the 1st Company Chaplain’s body. “Neeeeed….pure….blood!”

“You murdered a convent of Imperial citizens and sororitas,” Guelph snarled back, struggling to rise despite the consuming of too many tendons to allow his body to shift much more than an inch, “You have eaten a third of the chapter within yourself!”

The Chapter Master screamed, then, and reached down to rip and twist off Guelph’s left leg in one movement, before stabbing the entire limb into his gullet without pause.

“They….turned….to CHAOS!!” Ciacco boomed, his slurring gone for that one instant, the hungry fog in his eyes clearing ever so slightly. “We need to purge them...”

“And then you ate their flesh!”

“We were already turning!”

By now, the scattered remains of the chapter leadership had begun to creep closer, their endless hunger for flesh and blood sublimating even the primitive remembrance of animals for the presence of their leader. Ciacco turned and growled, picking up what had once been an apothecary and throwing him bodily out of the entire chamber, thumping the giant fist against his chest for emphasis. The rest of the mutated things squealed and ran, fear and power once more enforcing themselves upon their broken psyches.

“We…,” Ciacco groaned, falling to one knee as a massive spike of red bone tore its way out of the shoulder of his mutated arm, dripping blood the color of obsidian. “We were already turning, chaplain. The gene-seed, mutating more and more with each generation of our neophytes…,” his voice came on steady now, calm, as the flesh of Guelph was digested more fully. “And with half of the Chapter falling to the Black Rage and to Chaos…,”

“You let the Red Thirst take control of you all,” Guelph coughed. “We are doomed. We are fallen. Our forefathers grow strong once more. So many of our brothers do…but not so…not for the Flesh Eaters.”

“No…no!” Ciacco hissed, rising once more to his feet, “We can. We can! As…as long as we can keep our minds, continue to consume purity and restore ourselves, we can fight for the Emperor still!”

Guelph turned his head to look his Chapter Master in the eye that remained un-mutated and slit as a beast’s.

“Sanguinius would be ashamed of you.”

For some, the Black Rage can come over course of hours. It can be fought for days, or even months. In some rare cases, the Black Rage consumes one over the course of entire decades. But often, it is as simple as one blink to the next, where once stood a proud son of Sanguinius and the Emperor is a hate-fueled monster that has become forever subsumed by the psychic echoes of their Primarch’s murder. All that is, all that will be, is become Horus, and they are filled with the immortal hatred which blazed in the heart of their gene-father before his murder. Yet for all that it was so utterly destructive, and had driven so many to death, destruction, and damnation, the Red Thirst was its own challenge to conquer. The desire to consume the flesh, to drink the blood of the foe, could so easily grow stronger and stronger until it could overwhelm the will of the astartes who suffered from it. A natural and even deadly weapon of utility for the arsenal of a space marine could become an all-consuming drive which overwhelmed all else.

In some cases, both could affect a marine totally, completely, and unstoppably in one single crystallized instant.

Chapter Master Ciaccio would never wake from his twinned monstrous flaws, one that had been surrendered to and the other barely fought off for weeks as the battered Chapter Fleet of the Flesh Eaters floated through the void endlessly. Deemed Excommunicate Traitoris as the flaws of their line had grown stronger and stronger with their forces growing visibly more mutated as the fighting went on before it culminated in their attacking their own allies in madness, they had fled away from the reaches of the Imperium. Some, surrendered to despair, chose to fall into the embrace of Chaos that promised some form of survival beyond the mindless existence of the Death Company. Others did not, believing that they could still serve the Emperor despite their constantly worsening state. None would know of the civil war which occurred amongst the chapter’s leadership. It did not matter.

For they had become prey in and of themselves, hunted by those who were willingly watching for just such opportunities for themselves. For in truth, the sons of Sanguinius grew stronger and weaker in equal measure, the Blood Angels and Flesh Tearers growing in number once more, others such as the Flesh Eaters and Knights of Blood fell to ever more mutations and flaws in their gene-seed. It was these that had become prey, become targets, for where they would fail, others would make use of their fall. It was a grim thing, to be certain, but one that occurred nonetheless. Where blazing hatred and fury destroyed a chapter, wintery pragmatism and a cold anger drove another to make use of it.

When the Space Wolves arrived, just beyond the reach of the Astronomicon where the Flesh Eaters had fled after the declarations of the Inquisition and the High Lords, they said nothing. There were no broadcasts for surrender, nor of announcing their assault. It was not as if there were servitors or serfs remaining alive and uneaten for them to have communicated with in the first place. Within the gore-soaked hallways of the Flesh Eaters’ fleet, the animals they had become were hunted down, including the hulking monstrosity that had been their Chapter Master, hewn in half and then quarters by the axe morkai as he ate the last scraps of flesh and pure gene-seed of the last chaplain left alive in the chapter.

The Rune Priests came, old and new, and they cleansed what they could and destroyed what they could not. Blood claws were set to cleansing the ships, menial work in action but the message undeniable – for weeks they were forced to observe the truth of becoming but beasts and animals, of what desire for blood and what uncontrolled savagery had wrought. Weapon systems were checked, new serfs and blood claws installed in newly repaired bridges and ship stations, and Iron Priests and their own new apprentices grown of the Wolf Wombs strode forth to examine, study, and repair what they could.

As he stood upon the bridge of one of the two battle barges that the Flesh Eaters had possessed – the other too slaked in Chaotic taint to be usable – he barely moved as one of the last old Wolf Lords approached. There were no feasts, now, no grand drinking contests, no songs to be sung. All that had once run hot and fresh and freely in their hearts had become as the lost glaciers of Fenris, now, their minds and wishes colder still.

“Great Wolf.”

“Krakendoom.”

The last great son of the oceans of Fenris silently handed Logan a dataslate, which he scanned briefly.

“The ‘Relictors’?”

“Formerly known as the Fire Claws. They became obsessed with possessing artifacts and weapons of Chaos, believing they could turn them against the forces of the warp.”

“Foolish,” Logan murmured, watching as the rest of the fleet slowly assembled around their newly captured vessels.

“Yes. Their Chapter Master was consumed from within, releasing a Bloodthirster unto the Cadian System’s defenders and obliterating a critically important defensive structure at one of newly reclaimed fortress-cities. The rest refused to hand over the rest of their misbegotten relics, and fled.”

Logan hummed, leaning forwards slightly to rest his hands upon the console before him.

“Towards the Eye?”

“Initially, yes. They diverted their course upon the arrival of a great fleet of necron vessels.”

At that, the Great Wolf turned.

“Those which stole the Blackstone Fortresses under Abbadon’s yoke?”

“Indeed. Now they were last sighted fleeing into the Ultima Segmentum…near our position, in fact. The Inquisition’s latest attempt to destroy them has left them with but one battle barge and a handful of strike cruisers left.”

It was more than enough to convince him.

“We make ready. They have been declared Excommunicate Traitoris…and we are yet still the sons of the Emperor’s Executioner.”

That what ships they might possess that could be claimed which were not tainted was, by now, a given. That they had done so now and would again, hunting and searching as the wolves they were before killing and claiming what they could, whilst guided by the Rune Priests was a given. It was, in fact, one of the reasons that Engir remained Logan’s most stalwart supporter, for it was in these dark days that the raiding and naval hunting prowess of his people that had proven most valuable and most oft-used. Skills that needed much honing, Engir insisted, for when they inevitably came to hunt their ultimate foe. Only a few wondered if that was in truth the Planet of Sorcerers…or the Rock of the Dark Angels, and none could say for sure.

“Yes, Great Wolf.”

And the Rout hunted on.

Turn 18 (Part One): Writ In Blood

Spoiler: Voted Plan: May None Find Us Wanting

[X] Plan: May None Find Us Wanting

-[X] Gabriel Angelos
--[X] Hunting Down Vandis
---[X] Contact Rogue Trader Claudius Alexandre Jullien Tarquindil. Ask him to find the location of traitorous governor and possibly what he is up to, so that you can crush him yourself.
-[X] Promote 5th Chapter Veterans To 1st Company (20)
-[X] Assign your newest 45 Battle Brothers to:
--[X] The 5th Company (15)
--[X] The 4th Company (30)
-[X] Assign the 2 new Gladius-class Frigates within the Chapter Fleet
--[X] 4th Company Fleet
-[X] Assign the Battle Barge Scientia Est Potentia within the Chapter Fleet
--[X] 4th Company Fleet
-[X] Assign the 2 Strike Cruisers, The Great Father's Fist and Burning Seeker within the Chapter Fleet
--[X] Burning Seeker to 4th Company Fleet
--[X] The Great Father's Fist to 5th Company Fleet
-[X] Derosa's Debt
--[X] 3 transports, 13 gunships
-[X] Inquire as to aid that can be given to Derosa
-[X] Bring more forces in for the latter portion of Return Of Judgement [Gellar Field Installments]
--[X] Marcus Crixus (Stormbolter), Uriel Hamul (Thunder Hammer/Storm Shield), Ares Actus (Crozius/Stormbolter), Marcharius Sicarius (Power Fist), Amicus Antal (Powerfist/Stormbolter), 5 1st Company Veterans
---[X] 5 Tartaros-Pattern for named characters, 5 Indominatus-Pattern for others, 2 Heavy Flamers, 1 Assault Cannons, 1 Pair of Lightning Claws, Thunder Hammer, 1 Power Axe, 2 Power Fists, 5 Cyclone Missle Launchers
--[X] All of our Dreadnoughts
-[X] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (20)
-[X] Investigate further sector threats for potential Chapter intervention/aid.
-[X] The Honor Guard
--[X] Search for suitable members to the Honor Guard from the 1st Company
--[X] Assign Apothecary Falkor Ryll as the Honor Guard Apothecary
--[X] Assign Veteran Sergeant Doukas Laskaris as the Honor Guard Captain
-[X] The 4th Company
--[X] Assign Apothecary Caesar as the Company Apothecary
--[X] Assign Chaplain Ateren as the Company Chaplain
-[X] The 5th Company
--[X] Assign Sergeant Kaius Jacobus as the Company Champion
-[X] Attempt to establish communications with Canoness Preceptor Margaret Tenenbaum. The Order of Lost Rosetta was once one of the greatest friends of your Chapter. You wish that to be so again.

-[X] Training With Apollo
--[X] Weapon Skill

-[X] Train Your Chapter
--[X] Main: Agility
---[X] Kaius Jacobus
--[X] Secondary: Weapon Skill
---[X] Apollo Diomedes
--[X] Secondary: Strength
---[X] Macharius Sicarius

-[X] Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary
--[X] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years (40)
--[X] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage]/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] with Gene-Seed. (21 Total)

-[X] Probalis – Chief Librarian
--[X] Study what was retrieved from the Dark Eldar Anchorage Command Center for anything useful, and to log it within the Librarius for later perusal if necessary.

-[X] Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (525 BP)
--[X] 12x Force weapons (180 BP)
--[X] 1x Crozius Arcanum (15 BP)
--[X] Cybernetics for Nero Achillian (50 BP)
--[X] Improve the Forges Of
---[X] The Burning Seeker [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn (80 BP)
--[X] Study The Rapier For Potential Learning Of Design To Allow Replication (WARNING: May end up losing some Rapiers as a result of the study) [50/???] (200 BP)

-[X] Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits
--[X] Enact Blood Trials Upon The Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive

Writ In Blood
+025.M42+ To +030.M42+
+If You Will Not Fight, Then You Will Not Live+

Spoiler: 025.M42 To 030.M42

025.M42 To 030.M42:
- Test-Slaves Implanted with 40 Gene-Seed. Harvest In 030.M42
- 250 Aspirants Recruited! - 250 Aspirants Advance: 135 To Neophytes [1st Stage], Remainder Expired
- 10 Psyker Aspirants Advance: 10 To Neophytes [1st Stage]
- 135 Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 112 To Neophytes [2nd Stage], Remainder Expired. Gene-Seed Implantation Required Immediately.
- 20 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 10 To Scouts[1st Stage], Remainder Expired. +10 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 1 Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] Advances To Lexicani
- 0 Scouts [1st Stage] Advance: 0 To Scouts [2nd Stage]1
- 10 Psyker Aspirants Recruited! -> 10 Psyker Aspirants Advance: 10 To Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage], 7 Advance To Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage], 3 Expired.\
- x12 Force Weapons Constructed, x1 Crozius Arcanum constructed, Cybernetics for Nero Achillian Constructed.
- Sector Threats Collating, To Be Available Post Rogue-Trader Discussion
- Dark Eldar Anchorage Study Complete! Anti-Anti-Psyker Study Now Available.

“A good duel, Chapter Master,” Apollo gasps out, falling out of his stance in exhaustion as he finally is forced to yield against you.

You stand across from him, victorious, the crackling energy field around the training hammer disappearing as you flick the deactivation rune upon it. All around you, the makeshift training chapel bears the marks of your fight, the whirlwind exchange of hammer smashing into the walls and ground when the target managed to dodge or deflect. Already you can imagine the many days it would take the servo skulls and servitors to fix the damage were it a true chapel, but your mind is busy moreso with analyzing the fight that had just taken place over several hours.

“Indeed, Apollo,” you finally say as your heart rate returns to normal, bionic lungs pushed into overdrive finally wheezing their way back into a more nominal rate. “A good duel indeed. It is somewhat lucky that the Mechanicus will be utterly stripping the entire hulk, a little more damage such as this will not cause untoward disfavor”

The galaxy is darkening around you, but you can take some small solace and satisfaction in the simple act of smashing things. In the purity of martial confrontation. You cannot rightly say that strength is returning to you, more that you are simply learning to better make use of what is now almost the whole of your body. Perhaps if you were an Iron Hand, such a transition would be easier for you. But you are not, and instead have had to quite literally fight against your body and mind to re-integrate both into the single formerly sublime whole devised by the Emperor. At the least, with a nod to Apollo, you turn and exit the thoroughly ruined cargo bay turned temporary training area, and begin to gather up your true weapons and armor. Your work in the Judgement is not yet done, after all.

“What of the rest of the Chapter?” you say after a moment, watching as a cloud of servo skulls float right past you.

“Training proceeds apace as best it can, Chapter Master,” Apollo hums, passing you a dataslate to peruse. “I’ll be working with more of our assault marines by the end of the week, but Brother Kaius has demonstrated a surprising amount of leadership in his own works.”

“And Sicarius?”

“I think he managed to get a few of his battle brothers to pass out from exertion,” is his bemused reply.

For a split second your mind stalls at the incredulous thought before you flick your remaining biological eye in Apollo’s direction.

“Is that a good thing, for him?”

“I don’t know,” he manages to shrug in his armor, before his face screws up slightly in thought. “I think it’s a good thing, anyway.

“And the 4th Company?”

“Well, as much as they can be all things considered."

"And Probalis? Has he found anything?"

Apollo passes you another dataslate to scrutinize carrying your Chief Librarian's notes. The baffling amount of anti-psyker weaponry and technologies and rituals used to disguise the Dark Eldar station were certainly concerning - and it seems that Justinius has been studying what he can on them. He believes that, with careful study, he could perhaps increase the effectiveness of the Blood Ravens against similar effects in the future. Against things that would ordinarily stifle the powers of the Librarians, it could prove an advantage in the future if properly studied and disseminated. A valuable thing considering how many times the Chapter has lately come into conflict with the Eldar of both varieties. Still, it is something for the Librarius to study as a group, or for him to take on as a personal project. Either way, it is something to consider. The whole of it is by now fully cataloged, ensuring that the Blood Ravens will have more knowledge to study in the future. Knowledge is Power.

"Is Kaius adjusting to his new position?"

"Somewhat," Apollo shrugs again, "He was more accustomed to being in the dark, working in the shadows. But as Company Champion he will need new arms, new armor, and prepare himself for meeting the Company's greatest foes in single combat."

"Let none find him wanting."

Neither of you speak of the cold silence that was your response from the Canoness of the Order of the Lost Rosetta. Once, they happily fought alongside you, and many a battle and glory were won at their side. Even now you bear relics from that burnt and scalded friendship, may Kyras burn forever. Your attempts to reconcile with them, to even speak with them, have been met with the same chill as their deathly homeworld, where the glaciers are the mountains, on a planet cold enough that their own home is carved into the ice itself. They never fear it melting despite the vast amounts of promethium their doctrine demands, which only emphasizes the cold of that world further. A cold, then, that extends to your open hand. Very well. So be it, for now at least.

[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 329+98+Apollo(29)= 456/800]
[Chapter Training – Agility: 239+61+Kaius(25)=325/500]
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill 4 To 5: 156+16+Apollo(29)=201/500]
[Chapter Training – Strength 4 To 5: 0+18+Macharius(25)=43/600]
[Attempt To Reconcile With Lost Rosetta: 23. Failure!]

=====================================================

It is a good thing that you brought what forces you did onto the Judgement of Carrion, you decide as the years press on. Despite the fact that more and more Gellar Field Dispersal Units – special devices crafted with the aid of Angel Forge itself – the daemons seem ever more eager to propagate themselves into reality within its corridors. The fighting grows ever harder, and it is not aided by the fact that orks and tyranids still exist within the labyrinthine superstructure. The orks desire the ‘shiny bitz’ to the point of ludicrous suicidal assaults on flanks, while the tyranids only see the influx of both Mechanicus and Imperial flesh as the chance to gain more biomass. Attacks from both must be fought off at the same time as daemons appearing from the ether, possessing random piles of scrap into bodies, exploding out of the walls themselves, and in one memorable case possessing a psyker-turned-servitor which became extremely troublesome.

The creature managed to break three of your holy dreadnought brethren’s shells, only just missing the living contents within, and tore through a number of the skitarii sent to apprehend it. In the end, it was Kaius working alongside Probalis who hunted the thing down finally, setting it aflame with both promethium and cerulean flames pulled from the warp. Even then it was a hard fight, one that saw Brother Kaius nearly losing every limb he had, and in return gaining a series of scars for his troubles. Thankfully, however, the Adeptus Mechanicus, the Priesthood of Mars, was…extremely persistent in their attempts to wrest control of the space hulk away from the unyielding hand of the warp which had choked it for all this time. By the end of it all, they have installed their fields across the ship, and after a few worrying titanic shakes which for a moment made you thumb the comm for emergency teleportation retrieval…the Judgement of Carrion falls silent.

Truly silent. It’s cogitators hum, still, but now in a quiet slumber free of nightmares for the first time in centuries. The ghosts of the place are not quite yet expelled, as far as you know, but they are certainly being far more repressed than ever. Even as you shake hands with the Magos in charge of its return to Zerann where it can be properly transformed into a servant of the Omnissiah, you can see thousands of servitors, servo skulls, and techpriests beginning to carve away at the worthless and input ritualistic engravings into its very bones. It is a vast prize indeed, and they intend to be very exacting with it. Jury-rigged engines fire in time with others on its rear which have been re-activated to send it careening towards Zerann itself. It will be a long journey, each exposure to the warp kept as minimal as possible as it makes its jumps, but for now…your task here is done.

A good thing too, in time for you to both return to Meridian to speak to Derosa…and her Rogue Trader.

===============================================

“Our deal is done, then,” Derosa favors you with a smile as you acknowledge the usage of your favor with her. “It took some convincing of the techpriests and the Administratum, but more and more I am finding that Vandis’ propensity for disallowing the production schedule to be modified even in emergencies was either incompetence or deliberate sabotage of the God-Emperor’s gifts,” she rubs her temples for a moment before straightening.

“I thank you for your gift, Governor,” you give her the barest of bows, for still there are some in the Chapter who muse over the tale of the put-upon assistant gunning her way into the former Governors palace to aid the subsector in its time of need.

“It is no trouble, Chapter Master Angelos. Anything I can do to strengthen the Blood Ravens – within reason – I will. If it weren’t for them Meridian would be dead three times over. But we can speak on that another time. I have spoken with…,” she shudders slightly, “Claudius. Though I will note, in your speaking with him, refer to him with his full name.”

“That ‘legendary temper’ you spoke of?” you raise your remaining biological eyebrow at her.

She sighs, again, and nods as she gazes out the window at a healing Meridian. Shuttles fly back and forth, smoke billows up from the smokestacks as industry returns, and there are at the least no riots within immediate earshot. A vast improvement from how it was left by Vandis and the servants of Black Legion only a comparative short time ago. For all the aid you have given her, much of this work including bulling through the Administratum was entirely all her. A respectable woman, is Derosa, it seems.

“Indeed. He is mercurial in the extreme, but he keeps out of Imperial Space most of the time so it’s not too much trouble. Be wary, Angelos,” she turns to keep speaking only to huff as another bevy of servo skulls carrying more messages for her surround her. “He is not to be trifled with, despite how foolish he might seem.”

This you know. Any truly powerful Rogue Trader has likely entire fleets beneath them, vast household armies…perhaps xeno mercenaries and more. Regardless, the meeting has been set, somewhat just beyond the borders of the Sector itself, but easily reachable with your own forces. It will be up to you as to what and who you bring with you, of course. And you must, indeed, go to meet him. Simply shooting off a message to a Rogue Trader and expecting him to do your bidding would be foolish. No, it will be an exchange, more likely than not. Of favors, of materials, he may even demand space marines to accompany his ships as a matter of protection and prestige.

Select Forces To Be Brought To Meeting With Rogue Trader Claudius Alexandre Jullien Tarquindil:
[] Write In Forces To Accompany Gabriel (Ships, Troops, Etc.)

Turn 18 (Part Two): Writ In Blood

Spoiler: Escort For Meeting

Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Justinus Probalis, 1x Techmarine, Honour Guard, 5th Company and 5th fleet.

Writ In Blood
+025.M42+ To +030.M42+
+If You Will Not Fight, Then You Will Not Live+

“That…is the most garish ship I’ve ever seen,” you hear Justinius murmur as he stares at the pict-screen displaying the vessel in question.

You happen to agree.

Claudius Alexandre Jullien Tarquindil’s flagship, sitting at the center of a fleet which out-masses the whole of every space asset available to the Blood Ravens entirely, is one of the grandest and most open displays of wealth you’ve ever seen. It is also clearly one of the most powerful vessels in the fleet. Careful probing scans reveal that the hulking ship is in fact of the mysteriously rare Victory-class Battleships, and how a Rogue Trader managed to access a full battleship rather than the heavily modified cruisers they are more known for is something to carefully contemplate indeed. The lance-heavy craft floats in the void, visible to all for quite a distance around. Then again, that is not hard when one has plated the entire ship’s outer hull in at least a solid meter of gold. Vast statues of the Emperor, Imperial Saints, and the Primarchs are placed all across the outer hull, sternly facing the stars themselves, while trawling swarms of attack craft float about the ship as attendants.

“Yet he is here, and we can speak with him.”

“A fleet like that? He could definitely prove a boon to hunting for Vandis. If…we are able to convince him to aid us,” Justinius nods, rubbing at his chin slightly before his eyes widen. “Hmm.”

“Justinius?”

“He has sanctioned psykers on that ship. I can feel them,” he hums.

“Chapter Master, we are receiving a communication from the Rogue Trader’s flagship!” a serf cries out.

“And?”

The serf pokes a bit more at the runes on his console before nodding.

“They have given us access codes and directions to one of the bays on their flagship, the Spear of Radiance, Chapter Master.”

A look is exchanged between you and Apollo, and he nods.

“Prepare the thunderhawks then.”

==============================

When you finally do depart the transport, the Honor Guard around you, Apollo on one side and Justinius on the other, you are forced to a halt again as a full orchestral band begins to play some song or another within the loading bay. The various strike craft that would normally fill it are outside the ship, expending fuel in somewhat pointless displays of agility to no-one as a defensive measure against no one, leaving the cargo-bay to be instead filled with the welcoming committee. And what a committee it is.

Twin formations, each one possessing hundreds of soldiers, stand at parade rest on both sides of you leaving a single channel forward. While their armor may somewhat appear to be similar aesthetically to the Imperial Guard the coloration is a gaudy gold and purple, with likely more unknown modifications performed unto them. Their weapons are cataloged immediately in your mind as a split-second threat assessment takes place in your thoughts, and you are surprised to find them…respectable. A heavy allotment of plasma weaponry marks them, though the lasgun remains the most common amongst them all. There are even a few heavier weapon teams though such devices are not yet set up fully for usage, though if they were this would likely be an ambush rather than a mere meeting. Though they might turn out being one in the same, for all you know. Especially for a Rogue Trader described as mercurial by Derosa.

On the far side of the divide between the two formations lies what has to be the Rogue Trader himself.

Claudius Alexandre Jullien Tarquindil’s smile can be seen from the exit ramp of the thunderhawk, yet for all of that he is remarkably…small. In truth, he is dwarfed by his retinue, amongst which you can indeed see two psykers standing directly behind him, their staffs even now faintly crackling with energy. They could be clones of each other, or twins, yet they remain silent as you approach, their eyes locked onto Justinius and for the faintest of moments you can feel the ozone taste in the air as one psychic presence sidles against another. But they are not the only ones that make up the Rogue Trader’s companions. One, a techpriest with a frankly overbearing amount of mechadendrites sprouting from all over their body, rocks back and forth slightly. Another, what appears to be an Imperial Priest who alternates from looking at you to glaring at the psykers, his collar a horribly hooked thing, small metal barbs digging into his own neck at all moments. Standing directly at the man’s shoulder, however, as an equal like none of the others, is a woman dressed in night-black power armor, and not of the like that the sisters of battle wear. Indeed it is clearly a custom creation, and unlike Claudius she bears a flat frown, her bald head covered in tattoos common to those of the higher ranks of the Ecclesiarchy.

As for the Rogue Trader himself, he wears a burnished set of power armor, itself also colored the same golden and purple that everyone else is. A curling golden serpent on the purple appears to be his heraldry, given how it is emblazoned on the pauldrons and across his chest plate. An inferno pistol flickers at his hip on one side, while a plasma pistol hangs on the other. Along his shoulders is the hide of some xeno furred creature or another which bears a superficial similarity to the animals of Fenris, only it possesses three eyes in a vague triangle shape. And yes, as the Blood Ravens approach him, his smile only grows wider, and he opens his hands wide, spayed out to the point of almost knocking into his twin psykers who have to lean backwards slightly.

“THE BLOOD RAVENS!” he booms, the band continuing to play though quieter now, “Welcome, my friends, welcome,” he then bows deeply before shooting up again at somewhat unsafe speeds.

“Claudius Alexandre Jullien Tarquindil,” you nod to him, coming to a stop before him.

His too-wide smile flickers at your use of his full name, which happens to concern you for the fact that Derosa informed you that he preferred its full usage, but returns to normalcy immediately after.

“Oh, pish posh,” he waves his hand wildly, “No need for such formality…besides! You are among friends here, tell me, how is Derosa? She probably told you to use my name like that – I only require that from the gauche people of the Administratum. Is she well? I hear she’s become Planetary Governor now! Huzzah!” he cheers with his hands in the air, spinning about on his heel before coming to a stop while facing you again.

“She is…adapting well to her duties,” you finally say after waiting a moment for him to confirm that he is actually done speaking.

“Hmm,” he narrows his eye at you before shrugging slightly, “I suppose that’s the best I’ll get out of you. Bit humorless, aren’t you? Welcome, again, to the Spear! My ancestors rode this thing all the way from Terra, you know, with the writ handed to them by the Emperor himself! And here you are, the Blood Ravens! So close to Our Sectors, and yet we’ve never met? How stupendous! Personally, I blame that Kyras fellow, what a naughty man I hear he was! I knew there was something up with him, never taking my calls like that,” he sighs breathily and comes to a dramatic stop with the back of his hand upon his forehead, before whirling back to you.

Apollo’s teeth grinding is barely audible from where you stand, even with his helmet on. As ever, the shame of his service to Kyras burns at his very soul, the deception lasting for the vast majority of his career and his failure to see it screaming at his sensibilities every time he is reminded of it.

“Ah.”

“Ah, indeed, Chapter Master Angelos,” he taps the side of his nose at you, before putting his hands on his hips. “But we are not here to discuss that traitor, we are here to discuss what I can do for you…or so that is what I hear, hmm?”

“Oh shut up, Claudius,” the woman next to him finally says, her voice clearly exasperated, as she slams a heavy fist into his shoulder hard enough to send him stumbling slightly. “Get to the point.”

Claudius rights himself, chuckling and brushing off imaginary dust, and gives her the most childish of pouts.

“Oh Christina, my beautiful wife of mine, why must you be so cruel to your love?” he whines.

“I don’t love you,” is the woman’s answer, her gaze not leaving your own.

“Ah, my heart!” he clutches at it, scrabbling against the armor with his fingers, before sighing again. “Oh fine. Come! We have a room ready and waiting for you.”

With that, he twists about, armor squealing on the bay floor panels, and gestures towards a door leading out of the place. The rest of his retinue turn about as well, but you yourself are offered a position next to him as he walks, and an uneasy melding between your own escort and his occurs soon after. Claudius dances ahead – literally so for a moment – and begins pointing out various points of interest about the corridors, as well as talking about each room you pass. While he speaks, however, his voice quickly transforming into a droning nothing, his apparent wife matches your stride.

“I would apologize for my husband’s idiocy,” she says casually.

“So long as his behavior does not stop us from properly negotiating, then I do not care,” is your honest answer.

“It won’t. You won’t be negotiating with him in the first place. It will be me,” she says curtly, only to continue when she turns slightly to see your raised eyebrow. “He is ‘The Great Explorer’ or so he says. He spends more time heading out of the bounds of the Imperium, usually with his escort fleet trying to keep him alive. It is my responsibility to ensure the Dominion runs properly. Which means any major allocation of our resources to any course goes through me.”

Ah, now you see. For a moment, you had in fact worried that trying to deal with Claudius would be an exercise in futility, too flighty for you to make any concerted request. At the same time, you have seen what is only likely a part of his dynasty’s power, and it is likely that they would be able to greatly assist in the search for Vandis at the same time. But now you see it, the way that the retinue follows behind her, not Claudius himself. At the sweep of a few hand signals from her, one of the psyker twins heads off behind Claudius as he loses himself down a different corridor, the imperial priest following behind him, while his wife heads down another with the techpriest and remaining psyker with her. A mere moment later and you realize that there are no other armsmen present at all in this suddenly isolated section.

“We are here,” she presses an activation rune against one large door, enough for you to pass through to reveal a conference room large enough to accommodate even you.

Your eyes immediately note the disappearance of ostentatious decoration, only a few skulls in the pillars of the room. The table is without decoration as well, a single massive slab of black stone, and yet there are chairs present for the woman and her fellows. None have been provided for your own sake, and it is just as well. Very few seating constructions can accommodate the bulk of a fully armored space marine. Or even an unarmored one. As you assemble on one side of the table, and her on the other, another inhabitant of the room makes themselves known, to the sudden crackling of Justinius’s energies around his fingers, and more than one hand flickers to weapons…before you see the heraldry on their black armor.

“Chapter Master,” the Blood Raven greets you, his head bowed slightly, a fist coming up against his chest. “I greet you in the name of the Deathwatch.”

“Epistolary Vaikos?” You stare at the former 1st Company Librarian, who was not slated to return from the Deathwatch until some decades from now.

“Aye,” he raises his head, eyes visibly glimmering with power, his psychic hood glowing. “I apologize for the deception of my presence here, Chapter Master. I take full responsibility.”

“What is this,” you glare at Christina, hand falling against Godsplitter.

“Calm yourself, Angelos,” she says quietly, “He is here at my request.”

Glances are shared amongst your brothers, and more than one do not give up their weapons as they prepare themselves for what might be an ambush by unknown elements. Justinius seems personally incensed, audible crackling as he glares at his technical subordinate if Vaikos was back within the arms of the Chapter.

“You willingly committed yourself to obscuring my sight,” Justinius growls.

“Again, at my request,” she notes.

Then she places a very well-known icon onto the table’s surface, and your accusations die down somewhat in your throat. On the other hand, it further forces your forces into a defensive posture, Apollo going so far as to fully draw his weapons though he doesn’t point them at anyone in particular.

“Allow me to introduce myself, because Claudius failed to do so,” she bares her teeth for a moment before her lips close again.

The icon glimmers slightly as it is lifted up with a faint measure of telekinetic force so that it stands fully.

“I am Lord Inquisitor Christina Brutus Alba Tarquindil of the Ordo Xenos.”

“Lady Inquisitor,” you began to say before she raises a hand to forestall you.

“I am not part of the Ordo that would be able to aid you normally against Vandis, I know. I’m honestly surprised you didn’t ask for Adrastia’s aid in this. It is not as if it is outside of her purview, far from it, but,” again she raises a hand to stop your rebuttal, “I am not one to criticize it. Regardless of how we got here, here we are,” she gestures at the room vaguely before laying her hand on the table, palm down. “And yes, I know you wanted aid against Vandis. He was a vile little creature when I first met him, and that hasn’t changed. I can easily shift some of the dynasty’s resources to searching for him, however. Far more easily and with more subtly than Claudius could.”

“And in return, you expect some of us,” you grit out.

“Indeed,” she nods before her lips tighten. “Tell me, how aware are you of the current challenges facing the Deathwatch?”

Your eyes cut to Vaikos who remains head bowed, and back to her.

“Evidently less than we thought.”

“Mmm,” she purses her lips. “That is a fair response. But I will dispense with subtlety, in this instance, because I simply have no time for it,” and then she stands, hands slamming down on the table.

“We are being overrun.”

The silence that emanates after that sentence is strong enough to choke the life from some beings.

“What?” is finally the only word that comes out of your mouth.

She shakes her head, staring down at the table before sighing.

“We. Are. Being. Overrun. With the Imperium’s resources so heavily dedicated to already apocalyptic threats, such as the 13th Black Crusade, Armageddon, the latest Tyranid Hive Fleets, Huron’s Black Crusade, a thousand alien civilizations from without and within the Imperium’s borders have been rising up,” she stabs a finger in the general direction of the void waiting outside the ship. “And I am done cajoling and promising and ‘convincing’. Now I am telling.”

You can hear the rising heartbeats of your brothers, even while your own continue on their methodic mechanical pace, as she speaks without passion, her very voice dead and resigned.

“We need aid, and we need it now. As of last year, Epistolary Vaikos is being remanded to the Deathwatch without return indefinitely. The same is happening across every Watch Fortress still standing. Every marine remaining is going to remain there until we can push back the enemy – and we haven’t even begun to do so,” she grunts, fingers clenching together into fists as she stares you in the eye.

“Why have we heard nothing of this, Inquisitor?”

“Because the greater Imperium is focused elsewhere, Angelos,” she tosses her head to the side, snorting. “On average, a single one of these races could barely hope to defeat a single system, much less a Subsector or full Sector, of the Imperium. But with the Imperium in the state it is in now? We are bleeding out a thousand, thousand miniscule cuts,” she raises a thumb and forefinger, closing them almost completely together. “We don’t have enough Kill-teams to deal with all of what we face.”

“What of other Chapters, or the Guard, or the Navy?” you grunt back, but even now your mind is awhirl with this new knowledge and what it could mean for the future.

“Don’t insult yourself or me, you are not the only ones we are contacting in this manner,” she sniffs. “But, to the point. I know well enough not to go about wielding my authority as a cudgel, especially with a Chapter such as yours – I don’t have the time to deal with Toth and Adrastia both right now. So, instead, I propose an exchange.”

Then she raises her finger, and points it at Vaikos.

“The Deathwatch is, to put it simply, desperate. We need every single body we can get, and then some. We need space marines. I require them, the Imperium requires them. In return, however, I will throw the resources of the Tarquindil Dynasty to finding Vandis – that is ships which go beyond the Imperium’s borders where he might hide, black market contacts, Chartist Captain scoutings, and more. Would we have an accord in this?”

They must be truly desperate to lay her cards upon the table in such an open manner.

Minimum Request of Lord Inquisitor Christina of the Ordo Xenos In Exchange For Finding Vandis:
- 15 Veteran Space Marines
OR
- 30 Space Marines
OR
- Apollo Diomedes, 5 Veteran Space Marines
OR
- Some combination of the above or more. (Write-In) [1 Veteran Marine counts for 2 Marines in this instance.]
OR
- Refuse, likely enraging the Ordo Xenos, the Deathwatch, doom one to many more worlds to loss by the xeno, infuriating a Lord Inquisitor, etc. etc. etc.

Turn 18 (Part Three): Writ In Blood

Spoiler: Voted Deathwatch Contribution

10 Veterans and 10 Space Marines from the 5th Company

Writ In Blood
+025.M42+ To +030.M42+
+If You Will Not Fight, Then You Will Not Live+

“We have an accord,” she grunts, offering a hand for you to shake on it. It is a small gesture, and considering the fact that you are going to be soon bereft of twenty good battle brothers stings, but you take heart in the fact that your duty will at least be done in this measure just as well.

And that is that, it turns out. You do not see Claudius himself again, further impressing on you how much control Christina has over not just his own person, but his resources as well. It is not particularly what you wanted to find when you came to this meeting, but the potential for finding Vandis that much faster deeply appeals to you in a visceral sense. On the one hand, perhaps it does make a dark sense that the Ordo Xenos would want to keep an eye on a Rogue Trader Dynasty which has made great riches off of the trafficking of alien technologies and artifacts. On the other, the amount of times you have encountered any member of the Inquisition that have left you or your chapter well can be counted on one hand – and still have most digits left over.

Soon enough you are returning to Subsector Aurelia, and discussing your surprise meeting with the Lord Inquisitor. Cyrus seems ready to burst at the seams at the news, furtive energy coloring his every movement as he drills the recruits that much harder. For a man who spent two centuries within the Deathwatch, to hear that the organization has been reduced to such straits is likely more than a little infuriating for him. The knowledge that the Imperium teeters on a thousand knife edges anew does not particularly please anyone else either. As it seems to be one of the few consistent things about interactions with the Inquisition, few are happy by the end of it at all. In this case, none.

Tarkus is especially aggrieved.

“I respect the Deathwatch, and what they do, but even this alone will set us back badly,” he tells you privately after your meeting with the Chapter Leadership has concluded.

“I am more than aware, Tarkus. But could we do no less?”

“I am not disagreeing with your decision, Angelos,” he shakes his head as you walk through the Omnia Arcanum, “Merely noting that this will cause difficulties. Not least of which that we would be throwing newer battle brothers in the most vicious of battles without nearly enough experience.”

“And yet, dark times call for dark measures,” you respond, finally coming to a halt in front of your own quarters, where much remains yet to be done for the organization and command of the Chapter.

“Aye,” he stares at the ground, his gaze hard, before sighing again. “But I understand. If the Emperor willed it, then the whole of the Chapter would plunge into the fire, unto death…but that does not mean I have to like it.”

“I do not like it either, Tarkus,” you clamp a hand to his shoulder, “The Blood Ravens march upon the brink, constantly, since our failure to discover Kyras’ treachery. The universe is cruel, and unforgiving. And yet…?”

“None shall find us wanting,” you both intone in unison, a small smile quirking its way past Tarkus’ perpetual flat lips, and he leaves you alone in the corridor.

Indeed. You may be hamstrung and bled again and again, but the Blood Ravens yet live.

It is time to go to work. At the least, returning home after a long, long time, comes one of the first marines you ever saw off upon becoming Chapter Master. Quarius Zergan has come back from Mars, and he bears the marks of his trials well. Martellus is highly impressed with the young marine, and puts him to work in the forges almost immediately after his return arrival and the minor celebration it caused.

Results:
Lord Inquisitor Christina lends her resources and that of the Tarquindil Dynasty to the Hunt for Vandis. Hunt For Vandis Underway. Time To Completion/Success Results: UNKNOWN
5th Company contributes 10 Veterans and 10 further battle brothers to the Deathwatch in its time of need.
Claudius had two bottles of amasec to drink and passed out.

Note: Quarius Zergan has returned from Mars as a fully fledged Techmarine!

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Look for specialist candidates amongst aspirants/neophytes/scouts.
[] Assign Unassigned x16 Thunderhawks (x3 Transporters, x13 Gunships) Within Chapter Fleet (Write-In)
[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (Write-In Amount) [Note: Those selected will be unusable for any other purpose during the turn this option is selected i.e. 5 years.]
[] Polonius Liberation Crusade Aid: The orks of the Polonius Subsector have been a plague on the sector for generations. Sometimes they unify and emerge as a full blown WAAAAGH!! which must be beaten back, other times they are chased back to their homes but never fully dislodged. It is a pattern repeated across the galaxy, for it is rare for the Imperium to be able to marshal the forces to fully exterminate such hovels when surrounded by other more immediate threats. However, over the past few years Sector Command has apparently come to the conclusion that System A4XX is due for cleansing and colonization by the forces of Man. Too many times have the orks there unified, and caused unspeakable damage. More recently, after a successful assassination of the current Warboss of the system who had already begun unifying it in its totality, the Imperial Navy and Imperial Guard are invading with assisting elements from the Order of the Lost Rosetta. The Blood Ravens were pointedly not invited, but it is not as if you need to be invited to a fight against orks, after all. Whether your arrival would be welcomed or not, you cannot say for sure. Even if it is not, you could surely still aid them regardless. [Write-In Forces Sent]
[] Beneath Blood Raven Wings: Derosa has acknowledged your request for information, and has responded in kind with a...remarkable request. She made extremely attentive note to how valuable Cyrus was when he was on Meridian, cleansing it thoroughly of xenos, mutants, etc. For that matter, now, she knows that more could be done. It is a somewhat selfish request, but one that makes some sense as well. Specifically, one fully dedicated squad on the planet at all times to assist her in keeping Meridian stable, safe, and productive for the Imperium. Considering how the Subsector has come under such nearly apocalyptic circumstances so rapidly in such a short amount of time, having a permanent presence on Meridian would be somewhat prudent, is her argument. That her prestige with having a squad of Blood Ravens at her call would skyrocket is unspoken, of course. On the other hand, Derosa is one of those most rare of things, a dedicated and principled servant of the Imperium. There are deathly few like her compared to the more corrupt Imperial officials ruling worlds, this you know for truth. [Select a full Squad of 10 Marines to be permanently posted on Meridian, immediately gain 1 Major Favor from Derosa. Chance to gain Minor favors randomly for Meridian Squad taking out threats, solving problems, etc. across Meridian for Derosa as long as Squad is there.]
[] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien: The Deathwatch is being strained to the breaking point, by their own secretive messages to all Chapters in the galaxy who can hear them. Watch Fortresses and Stations are under assault, alien civilizations are rising in ever higher number, deadly threats are growing in severity and breadth. Normally only the best of the best marines would be given over to the Deathwatch, but out of sheer desperation the Ordos Xenos is loosening their standards in an uncharacteristic display of acceptance. That is, apparently, how bad the problem has gotten across every single Segmentum. Ordo Xenos Inquisitors are calling in favors, the Deathwatch is calling upon nearly every Chapter possible to send someone, anyone, as many space marines as possible. With such threats as the Black Crusade, the War for Armageddon, the Hive Fleets, all of the Deathwatch cannot hope to fight back against the apparent thousands of full-scale alien invasions of the Imperium going on across the galaxy without help. How could you possibly stand by and do nothing, in the face of this? (Write-In Additional Forces Sent To The Deathwatch)
[] Recruitment World Preservation: Trontiux III is one of your more consistent recruitment worlds, but Cyrus has noted a worrying pattern over the past few visits for Blood Trials. Specifically, the exceedingly high population of orks there has been growing further and further lately, and despite their feral natures they have been breeding beasts that act practically as tanks and are nearly as deadly. He believes that they are reaching a dangerous critical mass, and that the Blood Ravens should take immediate steps to cull their population considerably. By sheer numbers they are quite deadly indeed, while they possess numerous strange alien beasts up to and including sightings of the especially dangerous 'Squiggoth'. The issue at hand is not killing a specific leader, for no great unifying ork has truly emerged yet from amongst the belligerent green masses, but rather a great culling. Something that requires extreme, continual, and violent force. While they seem ruled by the cultural mores of the ork 'klan' type known as the Snakebites, according to the Librarius, they should not be underestimated. [Write-In Forces Sent]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (112 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (7 Total) with Gene-Seed.
-[] Due to the fact that there is not enough Gene-Seed, if Neophytes end up rejecting their Gene-Seed, ensure that implantation of excess Neophytes is attempted.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- The Potentia has returned? Good. The Arcanum may have had the largest of our Apothecarium, but it was the Potentia that possessed the most advanced, as befitting its name. This should aid in the works of the Apothecarium for its purposes in the future.

Justinius Probalis - Chief Librarian (Choose 1):
[] Request to recruit and train potential psyker aspirants from the Adeptus Astra Telepathica. High likelihood of successful training and implantation for recruits made in this manner.
[] Begin in-depth studies of the remains of the various eldar Avatars of Khaine possessed by the Chapter [Note: This will mean that all non-Chapter Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.]
[] Anti-Anti-Psyker Study: The Split Heart Kabal made strange xeno advances in the baffling, diffusing, and blocking of psyker powers and abilities. By making a study of such things, the Librarius of the Blood Ravens would be able to train its forces against such things, improving their ability to defeat such things in the future while providing an additional aid of likely effectiveness against the vile Eldar specifically. [Note: This will mean that all non-Chapter Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.]

Things To Consider - Justinius Probalis
- The latest combat against the daemons of the Judgement of Carrion has made me think on the daemonhammer that the Chapter Master wields. We could, perhaps, use more of such weapons. It was created using a shard of the weapon of an Avatar. Perhaps we could make some ourselves, if we studied it enough?
- The Chapter's greatest advantage was its Librarians. I know that they were used for...ill purpose in the past by Kyras, but I will not allow such a political character to be assigned to them ever again. We were meant for more than that. For the betterment of the Chapter, for its coming battles, and the maintenance of the Sanctorium Arcanum, we must rebuild our ranks, and soon.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (525 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/750] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Burning Seeker [80/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Construct Forge Facilities On Company Flagships (Current/Former)
- [] The Faith's Horizon [0/500] to recieve an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Howling Hatred [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Rapier For Potential Learning Of Design To Allow Replication (WARNING: May end up losing some Rapiers as a result of the study) [250/???]
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [0/????]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- I could use a few more peers in the forges. Or at least subordinates.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- Thank goodness the Potentia has returned to service. Amongst the rest of the ships within the Chapter Fleet, it possesses the most advanced forge facilities, as befitting its name. This will surely aid me in construction of more advanced technologies in the future, as well as their study!
- THE RAPIER! Praise be to the Omnissiah! It is as if a Tarantula Turret which can move and maneuver, greatly increasing its chances of survival! Please, Chapter Master, allow me to study it, to learn its secrets, so that the design is not lost should they be destroyed!
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon The Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive
[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- With the arrival of many experienced 1st Company Sergeants, more Blood Trials can be enacted without Cyrus' direct observation.

Turn 19 (Part One): By Duty, Bring Death

Spoiler: Plan Consolidation

[X] Plan consilidation
-[X] Gabriel Angelos
--[X] Look for specialist candidates amongst aspirants/neophytes/scouts.
--[X] Assign Unassigned x16 Thunderhawks (x3 Transporters, x13 Gunships) Within Chapter Fleet
---[X] New Fleet
--[X] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage
---[X] 21
--[X] Polonius Liberation Crusade Aid:
---[X] 1st Company & Fleet, 4th Company & Fleet
---[X] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun
---[X] Chapter Master's Honor Guard
--[X] Beneath Blood Raven Wings:
---[X] 10 Astartes from 1st Company as selected by Marcus
--[X] Recruitment World Preservation:
---[X] 5th Company & Fleet, 10th Company & Fleet
-[X] Training With Apollo
--[X] Weapon Skill
-[X] Train Your Chapter
--[X] Main: Ballistic Skill
---[X] Tarkus
--[X] Secondary: Weapon Skill
---[X] Apollo Diomedes
--[X] Secondary: Agility
---[X] Cyrus Octavius
-[X] Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary
--[X] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (112 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (7 Total) with Gene-Seed.
-[X] Probalis – Chief Librarian
[X] Begin in-depth studies of the remains of the various eldar Avatars of Khaine possessed by the Chapter [Note: This will mean that all non-Chapter Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.]
-[X] Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (525 BP)
[X] Improve The Forges Of
---[X] The Burning Seeker [80/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn (420 BP)
--[X] Study The Rapier For Potential Learning Of Design To Allow Replication (WARNING: May end up losing some Rapiers as a result of the study) [250/???] (105 BP)
-[X] Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits
--[X] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
---[X] Trontiux III

Spoiler: 030.M42 To 035.M42

030.M42 To 035.M42:
- Test-Slaves Harvested: +80 Gene-Seed
- 30 Aspirants Recruited From Trontiux III -> 30 Aspirants Advance: 25 To Neophytes [1st Stage], Remainder Expired
- 4 Psyker Aspirants Recruited From Trontiux III -> 4 Psyker Aspirants Advance: 4 to Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage]
- 4 Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 3 to Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage], Remainder Expired.
- 25 Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 15 To Neophytes [2nd Stage], Remainder Expired. Gene-Seed Implantation Required Immediately.
- 102 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 80 To Scouts[1st Stage], Remainder Expired/Become Serfs. +22 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 7 Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] Advances: 6 To Lexicani, Remainder Expired. +1 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 10 Remaining Neophytes [2nd Stage] Attempt Advance With Recovered Gene-Seed: 5 to Scouts [1st Stage], Remainder Become Serfs. +5 Gene-Seed Re-Recovered.
- 6 Techmarine Candidates/2 Apothecary Candidates/3 Chaplain Candidates Located amongst Scouts [1st Stage], Remanded Into Appropriate Brotherhoods For Training.
- Avatar of Khaine Studies Begun: Justinius Probalis and all non-Epistolaries Unusable For 2 Turns. (Aka this, and the next)
- Burning Seeker Forge Improvement Progress (500/500), Additional +50 BP/Turn For Burning Seeker And Chapter.
- Rapier Study (355/???). No Rapiers Destroyed. Formerly Dissembled Quad-Bolter Rapier Re-Assembled Successfully.
[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 456+54+Apollo(29)=539/800]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill 5 to 6: 40+76+Tarkus(25)=141/600]
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill 4 To 5: 201+44+Apollo(29)=274/500]
[Chapter Training – Agility 4 To 5: 325+38+Cyrus(29)=392/500]
.

By Duty, Bring Death
+030.M42+ To +035.M42+
+Pain Now! Reward In The Afterlife!+

“Chapter Master we’ve arrived – SHIFT TO PORT!” Hadrian bellows, suddenly turning the chapter’s ships in shuddering acceleration as they almost run into a large pile of floating scrap before the last of the vestigial warp energies have drifted into non-existence.

“What has happened Hadrian,” you call out, even as warning klaxons blare.

“We almost ran right into a series of wrecks, and fresh too,” he responds from the command throne, while serfs run back and forth and babble to one another across the entire bridge. “Hold on…there are some Imperial beacons present.”

“They are Imperial wrecks? What happened, what has happened to the Liberation Crusade forces?!”

There are several intense moments of silence from Hadrian as he absorbs the information flowing into his skull by his implants and subordinates, before he finally grunts and stands from it to come stand by you.

“We were a bit later than expected. The Crusade’s commanders moved forward without us. The fighting has expanded across the entire system.”

It is not as if you would demand that they all have waited for you, it would be pointless for one and foolishly petulant for another. Regardless, as you roll your shoulders out to release some of the odd kinks in the bionics resulting from the training that was performed in the warp on your way here, you cannot help but think that it is perhaps a little foreboding that the orks were capable of delivering such a blow to humanity like this. For too long had the Korianis Sector been satisfied with simply pushing the orks of this system back, never fully contributing the forces to completely crush and exterminate the greenskins. It is not entirely without reason, of course. More immediate threats demanding strength be turned elsewhere is one of the banes of the Imperium’s existence after all. Still, the knowledge that broken and ruined Imperial ships are even now floating past your Chapter Fleet through the void is not particularly welcome.

But regardless. The Blood Ravens have come to the Polonius Subsector, and it is time that the orks here finally be fully dislodged.

Polonius Review said:

Polonius Overview

The principal threat has been identified. Warboss Bonebreaka is a powerfully built example of his kind, but it is his tactical sense that is worrying. Disturbingly capable at beating the various orks of the system in order, willing to liberally make use of what measure of ‘subterfuge’ an ork is capable of, and brutal enough to not even need it most of the time, Bonebreaka has unified the system beneath himself in recent years. Ork population build-up has been registered as a nascent WAAAAGH!!! and efforts were undertaken to prevent it from reaching that critical point. The presence of all major ‘klan’ subtypes of ork society as noted in the Librarium records are present in the system, while Warboss Bonebreaka himself appears to be of the Deathskull’s clan – which explains where and why he possesses such powerful weaponry including known Imperial vessels that were looted for him. Preliminary investigations have learned that Bonebreaka arrived in-system already at the head of a powerful fleet, intending to conquer the system and turn it into his personal dominion. The resources he arrived with allowed him to crush the other orks present in time, and he has now bent the whole system to his purpose.

Unfortunately, many battles have already occurred in the time it has taken the Blood Ravens to arrive from Subsector Aurelia to aid the already begun Liberation Crusade.

The Imperial Navy attempted for a rapid conclusion which would break the full might of the orkish fleet by baiting them into one massive battle. The bait was taken, but unfortunately the orkish space assets were greater than initially estimated, with several orkish ships managing to flank and attack the rear of the Navy’s ships. While the Navy eventually managed to break the haphazard encirclement of their formation, and dealt a considerable amount of damage to the enemy fleet, the end result was more than mutual dissatisfaction. Currently the main ork fleet has retreated to the planet Spinesnap while the Imperial Navy has moved on the other three worlds in system, attempting to deliver their cargos so that more of the system might be taken now that the fast solution has failed. Three frigates were hijacked in this engagement and returned into orbit over the world Spinesnap where they are currently undergoing orkish ‘retrofitting’ for lack of a better word.

Of considerable concern to the Administratum is how much damage is dealt to the planets themselves. They are, after all, being evaluated for liberation from the boot of the alien and future colonization by humanity. The more damage that is dealt to the worlds within the now named Zemel System, the longer this will take, and the more annoyed the Administratum will be. This is something that not even the zealous sisters of battle present are entirely willing to test. Precision is key, and wanton destruction of the planets will not be tolerated for anyone who wishes for the Administratum to not hold them in dis-favor, which can often spell a death sentence for many.

Communications between the Blood Ravens and the rest of the Imperium’s forces is sparse, save for an acknowledgement of your presence and an extremely threadbare thanks for your potential aid. Notably, however, the Order of the Lost Rosetta said nothing at all, though they surely are aware of your presence. Currently the relative disorganization of the system’s theater due to the disastrous initial battle which required falling on back-up plans not properly prepared for has meant that the current overall Imperial commanders present have yet to specify specific targets that they would desire to be struck by the Blood Ravens.

'Greenkrump'
A jungle world based upon a single great continent, Greenkrump is inhabited by orks of the ‘Snakebite’ and ‘Goff’ varieties. They are currently boiling over with small amounts of inter-warfare as the Goffs beat in the Snakebite’s heads in order to force them to produce many squiggoths for the upcoming WAAAAGH!!! that is set to tear across the entire sector. Various ships hang in orbit over this world, keeping a close eye on the growing population of warbeasts that the Warboss seems to desire for his forces. Over a billion orks and creatures infest the jungles of the planet. The orks on this planet are under the dual leadership of Boss Slitherjaw of the Snakebites and Boss Fistkicka of the Goffs. It is suspected that after from Spinesnap, that this planet possesses the highest amount of orks in the system.

Imperial Navy forces are currently struggling to achieve some measure of orbital supremacy so that they can properly support the troops that have already landed – having ferried the Order of the Lost Rosetta forth so that they may cleanse the planet. The current Canoness of the Order of the Lost Rosetta has been sighted on-planet, personally leading the fighting.

'Dustboom'
Massive deserts and wide wastelands cover this entire planet over, with what little vegetation and water existing on the planet being highly coveted resources for the more powerful orks on the planet. Also highly coveted are the minerals beneath the surface which have been relegated to the sacrilegious usage of the orks as they create various vehicles that rampage about the whole of the planet – the ork variety present here being of the ‘Deathskulls’ and ‘Evil Sunz’ sort. Rival meks have battled here for centuries, leaving behind the shattered remains of hundreds of tanks both hand-made and crafted, custom battlewagons, war trukks, and more. Under Warboss Bonebreaka, however, this usual rivalry has stopped and the constant boom of guns and cannons upon this world are now all pointing in the same vague direction i.e. towards humanity. There are multiple Big Meks leading the orks present, all under the currently hidden Mekboss Killdakka.

The Imperial Navy has achieved orbital superiority here, but are still forced to remain cautious as massive ork mek guns are capable of producing firepower capable of reaching ships at the altitude where orbital fire might be launched. Anti-air vehicles trundle across the landscape, firing indiscriminately in the sky though they focus quickly whenever an actual target appears. The Imperial Guard has launched out here in force, challenging the metal might of the meks here with the concentrated mailed fist of their own. There are currently several running battles going on between tank battalions and orkish creations. [Note: Presence of looted Predator Tanks has been confirmed based on Imperial Guard reports. ]

Spinesnap
As close to a ‘capital world’ as this system might possess within the bloody grasp of Warboss Bonebreaka, this jungle world possesses numerous mountain chains which are completely slathered with haphazard weaponry pointed in every conceivable direction. In some cases right at each other. Here is where the majority of the orkish fleet remains, held in a close defensive posture despite the otherwise normal aggressiveness of their species. The clearly stolen and looted Imperial vessels which sit at the heart of the formation are the most significant threat due to their advanced weaponry, though whether or not they are capable of being recovered after the battle is unknown. After the mutually disastrous void engagement at the beginning of the Liberation Crusade of the system, the orks have retreated here to lick their wounds. The orks present on this planet are a somewhat ‘equal’ mix of the various major ork klans, though nothing is for certain given the difficulty in approaching the planet for more thorough intelligence gathering. It is assumed that Warboss Bonebreaka is present, as he did not die in the initial battle and openly howled insults on his retreat to Spinesnap into the ears of the Imperial Navy…and anyone else who was listening to him broadcast on all channels.

The Imperial Navy is currently attempting to marshal strength near Spinesnap to attempt to break the xenos fleet present, or at least prevent them from reinforcing the three other worlds in the system. No forces are present on the surface of the planet. [Note: It has been rumored that there is a Space Marine Strike Cruiser present somewhere in the thick of the orkish formation – albeit obscured by whatever desecrations the orks have layered upon it.]

Shinehole
Previously believed to be uninhabitable entirely, this was instead the result of a weakened ozone layer for the planet closest to the system’s sun. Powerful radiation blasts the surface of the planet, keeping all life beneath its surface. Here, the orks have apparently been breeding in secret for quite some time, but that is not the planet’s true purpose amongst the orks. Instead, the planet’s impressive tunnel system, carved out by the orks and whatever its previous inhabitants were over thousands of years, acts as a planet-sized storehouse. Looted weaponry, guns, tanks, creations, bodies, scalps, sticks, particularly impressive piles of dung, and more all fill the tunnels of this place. This also means that the orks defend this place extremely aggressively. Now that the ruse is up, the Imperium finally managing to exert some effort on the system beyond the most cursory of scans, the orks are fighting that much harder to keep everyone else away from their slowly collected piles of treasure from various sources over an unknowable amount of time and sources. The orks of the cultural inclinations of the Blood Axes and Bad Moons reign supreme here, unleashing a bevy of looted weaponry and some of the best possible weapons that orks can create to your knowledge. It is unknown what ork leaders reign here, or if it is just a bevy of extremely belligerent orks trying to defend their pile of ill-gotten gains.

The Imperial Navy is struggling to hold orbital superiority here against orkish ships, while the Imperial Guard is being slaughtered in droves as they attempt to drive into the tunnels, barely holding what beachheads they have been able to make within the tunnel mouths. The depth of the tunnels makes orbital support iffy and air support pointless. The ground troops suffer brief exposure to near-lethal radiation each time they exit their transports and run for the tunnels. [Note: Shinehole’s orks have been noted wielding plenty of Imperial Weaponry, up to and including looted Leman Russ tanks, lascannons, and more. It is unknown what else they might possess.]

Ork ‘Killa Team’ Flotillas
While Warboss Bonebreaka is of the Deathskulls, he possesses an ally in a Blood Axe ork. ‘Supa-Kaptin’ Krarg appears to be a long-time second in command to Bonebreaka and seems to be acting as an orkish equivalent to an Admiral. Multiple small packs of ork kill kroozers flit about the system, nipping at the heels of the Imperial Navy and Imperial Guard transports. They strike and then retreat, something that likely requires quite the forceful personality or offered rewards to ensure that such retreating is done, before the ships reappear out of the warp elsewhere in the system. While not yet a major threat, they continue to be an issue in terms of attrition upon the already beleaguered Imperials present. Any attempts to chase one pack down results in the arrival of others, meaning that without a strong concentrated force baiting and then crushing them, the pursuers are inevitably surrounded and destroyed – or have to risk flight into the warp.

No force in the system is currently dealing with this, the Imperial Navy’s forces fully engaged across all of Zemel.

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Estimated Naval Presences Across System said:

Greenkrump
- 1 Hammer Battlekroozer
- 20 Kill Kroozers
- 8 Onslaught Attack Ships
vs.
- 1 Emperor-class Battleship
- 2 Mars-class Battlecruisers
- 5 Dictator-class Cruisers
- 3 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 25 Escorts (x14 Cobra, x5 Sword, x6 Firestorm)
- 2 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Dustboom
- 3 Overlord-class Battlecruisers
- 10 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 13 Escorts (x10 Firestorm, x3 Cobra)
- 4 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Spinesnap
- 5 Looted Battleships (x2 Retribution-class, x2 Oberon-class, x1 Apocalypse-class [Flagship Vessel])
- 4 Looted Battlecruisers (x3 Overlord-class, x1 Mars-class)
- 10 Kill Kroozers [Strike Cruiser Hull Suspected In Usage For A Kill Kroozer Present]
- 10 Onslaught Attack Ships, 5 Terror Ships

Shinehole
- 1 Ork 'Battleship'
- 9 Ork Kill Kroozers
- 12 Onslaught Attack Ships, 8 Terror Ships
vs.
- 1 Overlord-class Battlecruiser
- 3 Dictator-class Cruisers
- 7 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 5 Escorts
- 3 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Current Plans For Stage One Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One/Do Not Need To Head To Every Theater At Once]:
Greenkrump
[] Deploy On The Ground: While the Order of the Lost Rosetta has not shown any particular favor for the Blood Ravens recently, in fact the opposite, they might welcome some aid in battle. Or take it as an insult that you thought they couldn’t do it on their own. It is impossible to know what Canonness Margaret might think. Regardless, it is time for the orks of Greenkrump to suffer the hand of the Blood Ravens. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Take The Sky: The Imperial Navy is struggling to maintain itself over Greenkrump, especially with the occasional ork ‘killa team’ flotilla showing up and attacking them from the side before disappearing before proper reprisal can be proffered. Once this is done, proper orbital fire and air support can be directed onto the planet below. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: Write-In

Dustboom
[] Starting Out Of Range: Land troops on Dustboom in areas already claimed by the Imperial Guard, and thus out of the range of orkish anti-orbitals and anti-air, that can then fight alongside the Imperial Guard with their own fury. The large amount of armor in the enemy’s ranks demand just about the same.
-[] Crush Enemy Tanks: There is nothing for it, the enemy must be destroyed. They infest Dustboom, and must be shot to pieces and destroyed wherever they are found. Fighting alongside the Guard in this should make for…an interesting fight. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
-[] Destroy Defenses: The Imperial Guard knows what it is doing when it comes to such massive battles. Space Marines could, instead, try to make for surgical strikes against the massive orkish guns which prevent proper orbital support. They would be on their own, and if caught likely to be torn apart by the thickets of enemy armor, but success would bring an overall victory that much sooner. [Write-In Forces Deployed]

Spinesnap
[] Attempted Infiltration: You do not possess nearly the firepower required to break the ork fleet which hangs over Spinesnap, but you could attempt to at least temporarily draw their ire so that some troops might be inserted onto the planet itself to begin fighting against the orks on the planet itself. This would open them to the risk of orkish orbital bombardment, however. On the other hand, the information they could learn about Bonebreaka could be valuable for the rest of the fight.
OR
[] Wait: You are not yet strong enough to face this foe in open battle, but if you were able to aid the Imperials across the rest of the system they might gather their own strength enough to take the fight to the enemy here instead.
OR
[] Something Else: Write-In

Shinehole
[] Into The Dark: The orks here are some of the best equipped in the entire nascent WAAAGH!!!, and are in their home territory. The Guard are only just holding onto what few beachheads they possess, and must be reinforced. It will be rough tunnel fighting, but necessary to fully expunge the orks from this place. This will surely be the most difficult of fights possible to reach at this moment in the Crusade. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] The Sky Is Ours: The Imperial Navy is struggling to hold off the orks they just dislodged from the stars in this area, and could be aided. They are split between chasing down the orks which once hung above Shinehole uncontested and ferrying troops to the surface and wounded back into their berths. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: (Write-In)

=============================================

"This will be no simple thing, Tarkus," Cyrus growled as he glared at the tactical map which mirrored the situation on the planet below them.

"There is little that is easy when it comes to the duty of our kind, Cyrus," the Captain of the 5th shook his head slightly, though he too was somewhat troubled by what he saw. "But my brothers are ready, and I know your forces are as well."

The 5th and 10th Companies of the Blood Ravens floated in silence above Trontiux III, their deadly cargo eager to be deployed. For this was a Recruiting World of the Chapter, and they had already lost far too many. That they would be threatened again, and by feral orks of all things? No, it was a situation that could not be allowed to continue. Even without speaking the two who had fought together across all three Aurelian Crusades knew well enough what each other were thinking. The orks of this world had not ever been truly beaten into the grave by the Blood Ravens, their very nature providing a whetstone upon which to sharpen the populations of the planet to improve the stock of their recruits. But they had overstepped themselves, gone beyond their means, and now, the Blood Ravens would punish them for it. With extreme prejudice.

"Let us begin," Cyrus slowly tapped his fingers in staccato along the edge of the tactical map, scrutinizing the information brought from the Librariums, the auspex scans, and even from that of the Epistolary.

Trontiux III Overview said:

Multiple human citadel-cities are located on various plateaus across Trontiux III surface. Trontiux III possesses two main continents with a small scattering of islands connecting them. One, named Petramis, is mainly inhabited by humanity connected between the massive plateaus by enormous bridges and heavily guarded roads carved through the jungle. The other, Pacemen, is wholly inhabited by orks. Occasionally the feudal lords of Trontiux III make an effort to cleanse first Petramis, and then Pacemen by boat and by hopping across the Black Archipelago which is the closest thing to a land-bridge between them. None of these efforts have ever truly succeeded in the long-run, with the orks eventually forcing mankind back onto Petramis and back up into their heavily defended and somewhat self-sustaining cities. At some points the citadel-cities fall, but are later reclaimed, and so the bloody existence on Trontiux III goes on. The orks rampage in the jungles around the plateaus and boil over from Pacemen with unpredictable yet acknowledged regularity. There are two acknowledged ‘seasons’ on Trontiux III. The Season of Blood, when the lords of the world march out from their citadels and down from the plateaus and make another attempt to remove the orks forever, and the Season of Pain, when they are pushed back to those same citadels and forced to bunker down for up to an entire generation to pass as the orks bloody themselves against the walls and each other and break down.

This latest Season of Pain, on the other hand, has been going on for three generations, the longest in recent memory. The orks have not fallen out amongst themselves, and they are only growing in number. Some of the citadels have fallen, their citizenry slaughtered and their lords brought low. Squigs run rampant through the jungle, and the orks seem to possess a strange purpose to themselves as they march. The presence of a Warboss is suspected, but has not made any major sign of their presence at all.

Petramis, Cradle Of Humanity On Trontiux III

Dominated by dozens of large citadel-cities of humanity, with massive walls and heavily defended tunnel systems. Each resembles the concept of ancient Terra’s castles of old, writ large enough to possess farms and a considerable population each. For the most part, they remain viable and strong against the enemy, but three have fallen entirely, the orks picking across the remains, stealing the stone and metal in vast quantities in salvaging rarely seen by the orks of this planet. Each citadel-city is built upon massive plateaus, with the vast jungles of the world growing all around them on all sides. The jungles are currently utterly infested with orks in extreme numbers. Purgation recommended, but continual orbital bombardment is not due to the danger of geological damage dealt to the surrounding areas causing potential collapse of the citadel-plateaus themselves. Ironically, if the orks of this world were of a more technological bent, the typical firepower and ramshackle construction they use would have long ago seen to the tectonic destruction of humanities place on the planet entirely. [Note: Orbital Bombardment restricted on Petramis due to dangers of causing chain reaction resulting in destruction of citadel-cities of Trontiux III.]

Points of Note:

Citadel A = Closest to the Black Archipelago, and the first to fall to the resent resurgence of the orks on the planet. It has been almost completely stripped of its former signs of habitation, and instead is undergoing transformation into a massive ork hold to replace it. At the moment, however, it is yet unfinished. Many gaps remain in its defenses – which at the moment are represented by swathes of orks and their horrible pets, as well as squig monstrosities.
Citadel B = Further from the Black Archipelago, and more recently fallen, it remains somewhat still recognizable as a human settlement. This location has been chosen for apparent penning of the several squiggoths of the variety known to stand at about the same height as Leman Russ tanks of the Imperial Guard. They are apparently undergoing feeding, healing, and insane surgeries to ‘improve’ them before the next push onto another citadel. The care of the alien for their monstrous pets is extreme, and defenses here are in fact more strongly complete and thorough than at Citadel A, though bereft of higher technologies. It should be noted, however, that the divergent creations of orks have been noted to be able to detect stealth by technology with their own mutated and specially bred senses.
Citadel C = Equidistant from Citadel A as Citadel B is, this location seems to be simply filled with orks. The rest have filed into the jungles to surround the citadel-cities themselves, or killed each other, or whatever else they may have felt inclined to do. It has yet to serve some specific strategic purpose compared to Citadel A or B other than a large barracks, without any major defenses to speak of. Other than the thousands of orks there, of course.
Jungles of Petramis = The jungles of Petramis are swarming with orks in vast numbers, enough to easily overwhelm even a squad of space marines if caught unawares. The jungle cover and their many centuries on the planet have ensured that they are consummately successful jungle fighters, skilled at remaining in stealth within the jungle…to the instruments of the lords of Trontiux III, whose weaponry does not yet include guns beyond basic blackpowder rifles which explode more often than not. It is here that the greatest amount of greenskins can be found, however, on Petramis itself.

Black Archipelago
A series of islands which have been used as stepstones to go from Petramis to Pacemen and back again by both humanity and orks. It has been so named due to the fact that the amount of blood spilled here has permanently stained the soil black across all of the islands entirely. Currently massive bridges made of dead squigs, living squigs, squiggoths, rock, wood, and rope made from a dozen sources connect the islands and continents. It is ramshackle in the extreme, but the orks use it without care, driving their great war beasts over and towards their foes with glee. It is the main channeling point providing the orks access to Petramis. If this area could be taken, it could provide a temporary relief to Petramis itself from even more orks coming across – for it is likely that the orks of Pacemen would construct aquatic rafts or somesuch to ensure the fighting can continue, but not for some time after.

Pacemen, The Green Tide’s Home On Trontiux III
A massive sprawling continent of intense jungles, occasional rolling hills, and dipped tunnels, Pacemen has long been home to none but the orks of Trontiux III. Dozens of attempts have been made by the feudal lords of this world to exterminate the orks, but no beachheads have ever remained for longer than a generation or two. Here the orks are truly established, with over a hundred ork forts recognizable from orbit – likely due to the fact that the feral orks here do not yet comprehend the sheer damage that aerial combatants can do just yet, much less orbital fire. Massive clearings can be seen from orbit where the jungle has been cut away to make room for various squiggoth creations, including a few notably large Orkeosaurus variants which are currently being trained and equipped for war. Such is their size and strength that should they progress into Petramis that the citadels would surely be cracked open without difficulty. There is no specific sign of the enemy leader who has unified the orks of the planet so, or led them to success thus far over, and initial psyker scannings cannot locate any particularly massive outpourings of the bestial WAAAAGH!!! energies just yet, though some shamans have been located on both Pacemen and Petramis.

Points Of Note:

Orkeosaurus Breeding Grounds: A large squiggoth is the size of a Leman Russ battle tank. A gargantuan squiggoth can match size with an Imperial Knight. An Orkeosaurus is the size of a full Imperial Titan, and nearly as deadly depending on its equipment. Its own natural armors aside, enough armored padding can make them even worse to deal with. At the moment, some are visible from orbit in massive cleared areas clearly meant as breeding and training grounds. None have yet been sighted on Petramis itself, a blessing as just one would likely be able to crack open a citadel-city on its lonesome, let alone the dozen or so present on the planet.
Various Ork Forts: A benefit of facing a foe so culturally anti-technology as an orkish population following the ‘klan’ of the Snakebites – or so the extensive notes of the Librarium describes – is that they have built their defenses with their specific foes in mind. That is, the humans on Trontiux III who march in simple steel armor, wielding primitive blades and shields, with barely a primitive black powder gun among them. Thus, they are open to the skies, either by thunderhawk bombing runs or outright orbital bombardment.

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Current Plans For Stage One Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One]:

Petramis:
[] Ride Out Into The Dawn - The orks have been beating their heads against the citadel-cities for a considerable length of time. If you were to land your forces there, and march out from the gates, you would be able to throttle them down in great numbers as they are gathered in very large numbers outside of the citadel-cities for your own forces to tear them to shreds. At the moment, of course, you do not yet possess the ability to cull the orks entirely from the jungle...but this would be a good start. It would also likely ingratiate you to the feudal lords to see the Angels of Death arrive and protect them in person. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
[] Fury From The Skies - For too long have the orks of this world assumed the sky held no major threat for them. It is time to change that. While orbital bombardments are not recommended lest the plateaus be collapsed or something similar, more concentrated and skillfully delivered bombing runs and targeted airstrikes could tear apart enemy positions across Petramis. This would allow you to obliterate the orks upon the plateaus, possibly creating the opportunity to claim them for yourself in at least some temporary measure as FOBs. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

Black Archipelago:
[] Take And Hold - From the skies, rain down destruction upon the various bridges connecting the islands and continents, and then deliver drop pods amongst the islands to scourge them of the greenskins upon them. In this manner, this vital choke-point between the two continents can be defended, potentially reinforced, and allow the feudal humans a way to strike back in the future. Just as well, fortifications built upon these islands will ensure that the orks will have a visible target to attack, and thus to die against. [Write-In Forces Contributed To This Action]
[] Obliteration - For too long has the Black Archipelago provided a passage point for the orks to arrive in Petramis. It must be dealt with, and here there is no worry of catastrophic geological damage. Initiate continual orbital bombardment and burn these islands out of existence. In the future, it will require that the orks travel to Petramis by sea, and there will be no main central funnel for them to travel across meaning that their arrivals would be more spread out, but in the immediate moment this will greatly aid in the current culling of the orks. The people of the world can adapt to the circumstances later on, with a hopefully much reduced orkish population. Black Archipelago destroyed. Orks will require alternate passage to arrive on Petramis in the future.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

Pacemen
[] Fear The Skies - There are no anti-air weaponry for you to face. Some flying creatures, to be sure, but nothing that can challenge a thunderhawk, and nothing at all that can stop an orbital bombardment. For too long have the orks of this world been allowed free reign, and they have forgotten to fear the void itself. Every settlement visible from the air, every ork hold, ork fort, watch tower, and workshop, every pit and place where they breed their foul creatures from the smallest of squigs to their mighty Orkeosaurus variants must burn. Or be exploded. Or torn apart by heavy bolter fire. What matters is that they face death. There is no fear of geological damage, indeed, it would only provide a boon if earthquakes were to rumble across Pacemen!
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

The March to Karak Eight Peaks - Week 8 - The Valley Grove

Spoiler: Winning Vote [*] Work with Ulthar and Panoramia to equip the best Ranger sharpshooters with envenomed bolts. [*] Help him find a place with the dwarf artillery crews so that he can supplement their abilities in combat. [*] Marksman Codrin Petrescu Your first self-appointed task is the equipping of a band of marksmen with the Black Lotus venom. Logistically, it would be a lot simpler to set up if you weren't on the march, but needs must. Panoramia clings gamely to the back of a shadowhorse you summon for her as the two of you ride ahead to the point where the army will be making camp in a few days, and in the entrance to the wooded valley the two of you set to work digging a small pond and carrying buckets of water from the nearby river. It doesn't have to be big, but it does have to be a suitable environment for the Black Lotus to bloom. With the small pond dug, Panoramia takes one of the seeds she gathered earlier and plants it in the mud and, uncomplainingly, lowers herself to sit cross-legged in the muddy pond. She cups her hands around the seed and focuses, and you can feel the Ghyran of the nearby woods answer the call and flow to her. After ten minutes, you can see a single stalk gamely growing for the surface of the water; after another twenty, large, flat leaves have grown and begun to cover the surface, drinking in sunlight. You dig a book out of your pack while you wait, and you're glad you did because it's not until just over an hour has passed that the first bulb blooms into a deep purple flower, and more don't start sprouting until even more time has passed. Eventually, three hours after she went into her trance, Panoramia finally returns to the here and now, rises to shaky feet, accepts your help in clambering out of the pond, and looks over her work with pride. From there, it's much more mundane work - business with mortars and pestles, with a very hot flame and a retort, and in the end the half-dozen flowers are reduced to a pint of opaque black liquid that swirls sluggishly in the bottle. Panoramia goes off into the nearby woods to gather compost to fuel another round of hyper-accelerated growth, and you mount up to rejoin the bulk of the Expedition. Dwarves in general have little tolerance for unsavoury tactics like poison, but Rangers are very much the exception and Ulthar is more than happy to accept anything that could provide an edge. The contents of the bottle are separated into a score of vials, each with a neck just large enough to allow a bolt to be dipped into it, and they're distributed to what Ulthar has taken to calling his Raiders - the elite of his Rangers who have shown the most aptitude for striking terror into the hearts of the greenskins. They accept the vials and disappear out into the Badlands; a few days later, reports filter back in that the poison is doing an acceptable job, though a glancing blow can do more harm than good as the target becomes even more dangerous as they're swiftly driven mad by the delusions it causes and become extremely unpredictable and violent. They do, however, theorize that when it's not one-on-one, such an effect could cause impressive chaos among enemy lines, especially if they target larger and more dangerous parts of said forces. By the time the army's reached the advance point where Panoramia has been doing her work, there's enough accumulated poison that you have to set the solar forge back up and blow more vials just to distribute it. All in all, it's a good result for a few day's work. --- Your next task is to assist Johann in endearing himself to the dwarven artillery crews so he can find a place amongst them when it comes time for battle. The Master Engineer, Durin Wutokri of Karak Norn, is unusual for a dwarf engineer in that he puts his trust in wood, rope and tension, rather than steel, lead and blackpowder. The hardy mountain oak the dwarves favour may approach the toughness of steel when properly dried and treated, but it's still an entirely different approach than that of Narfi, the Zhufbar engineer you spent time with during the Sieges of the Drakenhofs. Your reputation among dwarves means that he listens doubtfully rather than dismissing you out of hand as you explain your idea, and you re-emphasize several times that the spell he'd be using would not extend to the dwarven crews at all - it would solely work upon him, allowing him to swiftly calculate the consequences of their actions and correct them accordingly. He reluctantly allows for a demonstration, and two bolt throwers are set up by the side of the trail and a distant hillock is designated as the target. One crew has Johann supervising and assisting, the other does not, and may the best team win. [Rolling...] The effects are subtle - Johann simply watches and occasionally comments, pointing out an imbalance of strain here, a slight crookedness in the aim of the massive siege weapon there. But the results speak for themselves - after ten shots, Johann's team has struck the hillock six times while the other manages only four. Durin's eyebrows rise to meet his hairline, and a third bolt thrower is pulled out of storage along with a crew with longer and greyer beards. This bolt thrower has a trio of sullenly glowing runes emblazoned into it, and when a bolt is slid home it bursts into flame of its own accord. Johann watches as they set up, and only comments twice, but each time the crew very carefully examine whatever it is he pointed out, and then reluctantly concede the point and make the adjustment. Instead of simply embedding themselves in the hillock, these bolts punch right through it, sending dirt flying in every direction. Durin nods once, and Johann's place among the artillery crews is secured. --- Codrin Petrescu, you notice, never turns his back to you. His hands remain a safe distance away from his weapons while he does so, careful not to present any kind of threat to you, but it's clear that he is at least cautious, if not concerned, about you - or what you could become. Nevertheless, he does not protest as you join him on the day's march, and cooperates as you engage him in conversation. "There are two kinds of people in Sylvania," he says softly, as you walk side by side through the valley. "Those that would willingly serve the vampires and necromancers, and those that want to be left alone by any would-be masters." "And yet you served the Army of Stirland," you note. "I said people in Sylvania, not Sylvanians," he points out. "The Sylvanians who would prefer a human master, even an Imperial one, over a vampire or a necromancer need only cross a border, and become Stirlanders or Averlanders or Ostermarkers." "Is this common?" you ask curiously. "Oh yes," he says. "Families in Sylvania are large, because so many will die young. There are always those that choose to leave, and those that have managed to survive in Sylvania are usually able to thrive in the Empire." "And did many of them join the Expedition?" you ask, starting to suspect how he became their leader. "Some," he admits. "Perhaps a half of the huntsmen and a third of the crossbowmen are at least partially Sylvanian, by birth or by blood." "Is that how you came to lead them?" "In part," he says. "I lived in Sigfriedhof, patrolled the Hunger Wood and worked with the Black Guards of Morr. That elevated me in the eyes of many. Very few of the crossbowmen were officers, but I was a Major in the militia. That helped with many more. I can put an arrow through the heart of a deer - or a man, for that matter - at a hundred and fifty paces. That, too, impressed some." Having gotten to know him a little, talk turns to the men under his command. "Most of the Stirlanders," he says, "and perhaps a third of the rest, seek nothing more than enough money to purchase a farm of their own. The remainder, however, seek their fortunes - either for ambition, or because they are the type to drink and gamble and whore away any amount of money they get their hands on." He looks at you appraisingly. [Rolling...] And apparently reaches a positive conclusion, because he continues on frankly. "It is my solemn duty to ensure that as many of that remainder die in the attempt as possible." Being a Grey Wizard means you have long since learned to school your expression, so you are able to keep from showing any surprise at that as Petrescu continues. "Should they achieve their ambition of looting the dwarfhold, it will endanger the fair recompense of the rest. My loyalty is to my fellow Sylvanians and Stirlanders, and to those who would willingly join in their humble ambitions, and not to the band of vagabonds and bandits who would happily anger the dwarves for their personal enrichment." "Reasonable enough," you say, though you're not sure if you mean it. --- [Rangers vs Greenskins: 58 vs 9] Ulthar's Raiders keep the Ironclaw Orcs thoroughly terrorized until the army is across the bridge and the bridge is collapsed safely in your wake, and the Expedition is able to avoid that needless battle, to the relief of most and the disappointment of some. The valley is a welcome break from the near-badlands that the Expedition has been marching through since leaving Barak Varr, and it's given the name of Kagazan Thingit, or the Valley Grove. The deer population, left in peace for untold generations, is given a sharp lesson in the food chain as the Amber Mages and the Knightly Orders cut swathes through the woods, ensuring it's as peaceful as it looks. The next week is going to be a change from the past two months of marching, as the Expedition is going to send a force down the Underway to stamp out the snotling interlopers and fill in the site of their 'city'. In the meantime, the docks are going to be repaired, the cranes replaced, barracks and warehouses built, and assuming nothing has gone terribly wrong back at Barak Varr, the first of the resupply ships is going to be steaming its way upriver very soon. Assuming all goes well, the week will close with a fifty mile underground jaunt to Death Pass, neatly bypassing Black Crag. How do you feel about Codrin's plan to have as many of the vagabonds and adventurers under his command die in action as possible? [ ] Dangerous nonsense. This needs to be stopped. [ ] He's got a point. You should help where you can. [ ] His command, his business. Stay out of it. The THREE of the following with the most votes will be performed: Contributing to the Campaign: [ ] The Snotlings need to be wiped out so their 'city' can be filled in. Join in the extermination, possibly with a Journeymanling along to see how they fare in battle. - [ ] Bring Esbern and Seija - [ ] Bring Panoramia - [ ] Bring Maximilian - [ ] Bring nobody [ ] Scout the far side of the Snotling city to ensure there's no other surprises waiting to be found. Spend time with the Council of War: [ ] Thane Skaroki Grimbrow [ ] Master Engineer Durin Wutokri [ ] Grand Master Sigwald Kriegersen [ ] Grand Master Ruprecht Wulfhart [ ] Marshal Titus Muggins Other Preparations: [ ] You've heard that greatswords and greataxes are near identical in the way they're used, and you happen to be surrounded by experts in the art of the axe. Learn how to use one. Spend time with your Journeymanlings: Esbern and Seija of the Amber Order [ ] Test their skills in battle. [ ] They'll be going hunting in the valley. Join them, and bring Wolf along too. Maximilian de Gaynesford of the Gold Order [ ] Ask him to reforge your sword into a superior one. [ ] Introduce him to the dwarven smiths so he can try to convince them to teach him. [ ] Ask the smiths to teach him as a favour to you (-2 favours) - Bringing a Journeymanling to the battle will not take an action; however, you can only take one (or two, if you take the Ambers) since you'll be evaluating their performance and protecting them from any serious harm and you can't do that if your attention is split.

Turn 19 (Part Two): By Duty, Bring Death

Spoiler: Plan Arbit

[X] Starting Out Of Range: Land troops on Dustboom in areas already claimed by the Imperial Guard, and thus out of the range of orkish anti-orbitals and anti-air, that can then fight alongside the Imperial Guard with their own fury. The large amount of armor in the enemy’s ranks demand just about the same.
-[X] Crush Enemy Tanks: There is nothing for it, the enemy must be destroyed. They infest Dustboom, and must be shot to pieces and destroyed wherever they are found. Fighting alongside the Guard in this should make for…an interesting fight. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
--[X] 4th Company
--[X] Land Raider Phobos Litany of Purgation
--[X] 1 Predator (Twin-Linked Lascannons)
--[X] 1 Predator
--[X] 1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Plasma Guns) [+Lascannon]
--[X] 1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons)
--[X] 1 Vindicator
--[X] 4 Assault Bikes (2x Multimelta, 2x Heavy Bolter)

[X] Into The Dark: The orks here are some of the best equipped in the entire nascent WAAAGH!!!, and are in their home territory. The Guard are only just holding onto what few beachheads they possess, and must be reinforced. It will be rough tunnel fighting, but necessary to fully expunge the orks from this place. This will surely be the most difficult of fights possible to reach at this moment in the Crusade. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
-[X] 1st Company, Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chapter Master's Honor Guard
--[X] All deployed as Terminators
--[X] 3x Rapiers (Quad-Heavy Bolters)
--[X] 1x Rapier (Laser-Destroyer Array)

[X] The Sky Is Ours: The Imperial Navy is struggling to hold off the orks they just dislodged from the stars in this area, and could be aided. They are split between chasing down the orks which once hung above Shinehole uncontested and ferrying troops to the surface and wounded back into their berths. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
--[X] 1st Fleet
--[X] 4th Fleet after deploying 4th Company on Dustboom

[X] Ride Out Into The Dawn - The orks have been beating their heads against the citadel-cities for a considerable length of time. If you were to land your forces there, and march out from the gates, you would be able to throttle them down in great numbers as they are gathered in very large numbers outside of the citadel-cities for your own forces to tear them to shreds. At the moment, of course, you do not yet possess the ability to cull the orks entirely from the jungle...but this would be a good start. It would also likely ingratiate you to the feudal lords to see the Angels of Death arrive and protect them in person. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
-[X] 5th Company, 10th Company
--[X] 13 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Twin-Linked Heavy Bolters)
--[X] 13 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Twin-Linked Lascannons)
--[X] 8 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons)
--[X] 5 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Multi-Melta)
--[X] Land Raider Crusader Tarantulus Ultima
--[X] 6 Razorbacks (Standard Twin-Linked Heavy Bolter)
--[X] 1 Razorbacks (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons)
--[X] 2 Whirlwinds
--[X] Predator

[X] Fear The Skies - There are no anti-air weaponry for you to face. Some flying creatures, to be sure, but nothing that can challenge a thunderhawk, and nothing at all that can stop an orbital bombardment. For too long have the orks of this world been allowed free reign, and they have forgotten to fear the void itself. Every settlement visible from the air, every ork hold, ork fort, watch tower, and workshop, every pit and place where they breed their foul creatures from the smallest of squigs to their mighty Orkeosaurus variants must burn. Or be exploded. Or torn apart by heavy bolter fire. What matters is that they face death. There is no fear of geological damage, indeed, it would only provide a boon if earthquakes were to rumble across Pacemen!
-[X] All availabe Thunderhawk Gunships
-[X] 3 Land Speeders (Standard)
-[X] 2 Land Speeders (Tempest)
-[X] Orbital bombardment against Orkeosaurus, Orkeosaurus breeding grounds and large settlements.

By Duty, Bring Death
+030.M42+ To +035.M42+
+Pain Now! Reward In The Afterlife!+

Dustboom Combat (1)
Imperial Guard Vehicles: 55
Ork Vehicles: 2
Blood Raven Vehicles: 89

Twin blasts of eye-searing blasts spat out from the front of the assault bikes as they passed, spearing through not one but two war trukks entirely. The orks within that had somehow survived the blast, their hides charred and melting off, attempted to leap free before over seventy tons of metal and ceramite slammed into the broken wrecks, running the survivors underneath itself as it continued on. Around the first mass came a small phalanx of others, staggered out behind it in a wedge of deadly intent and grave purgation. The heavy bolter placed in the front of the wedge’s point vehicle fired until the barrels grew red and orange with the heat, sponsons whirring as twin-linked lascannons fired in unison at a stalled battlewagon which had ceased all movement.

“OVERRUN THEM!”

Here was a vehicle that responded to his thoughts faster than any other. Or perhaps it would be more correct to say that there was less of it that had to respond. In the void, his mind connected on all levels to the comparatively ungainly berth of the battle barge, where even the most rapid of swerves or twists required painfully lengthy moments for the entire bulk to move. But here, now, surrounded on all sides by an ocean not of darkness illuminated by the light of the stars, but an ocean of roaring metal and swirling dust, he could truly appreciate the difference. Here, his blood pumped harder and faster than it did in the skies above, where his heart and soul beat in slow and steady tandem with the reactor cores.

Well.

There was that and the fact that he was standing on top of the Litany of Purgation holding a missile launcher in his hands, which was certainly more ‘exciting’ in certain senses of the word which might have had something to do with it.

“Come on, come on!” Hadrian snarled as the minor targeting protocols of the machine spirit failed from the dust swirling everywhere and decided to simply fire the weapon at where he could still see. “All units, fire as one upon the enemy!”

“Affirmative, captain!”

Assault bikes swung back around, bolter and more primitive slugs flying through the air as a hailstorm. Predators shifted all weapons as they shattered aside the broken wrecks of old and the still smoldering remains of more recent casualties of the fighting. The razorbacks whirred up with their own weaponry. Behind, marching as a scattered mass and bearing plasma, melta, and missile launchers aplenty, the 4th Company arrived out of the swirling dust as red avengers on the ridge their vehicle pool had just driven over. Behind them all, the Imperial Guard slowed their movements, taking these precious moments to enact emergency repairs on what damage they had taken or simply to watch in awe as the Angels of Death made themselves known.

“NOW DIE GREENSKINS!” Hadrian bellowed, firing again with the missile launcher just as the Purgation rammed into the already coming apart battlewagon which had ruined a dozen Leman Russ tanks not a week before…and broke through to the other side.

A shard of broken metal, superheated by the weaponry unleashed on to its mother corpse, flew free and planted itself in Hadrian’s shoulder, to which he grunted and pulled it free to toss it aside into the dirt. Less than a minute passed before rounding a mountain of broken scrap metal of what had once been all a manner of vehicles came another bevy of the enemy, howling with glee all the while as they charged into battle. Dozens of orks hung off of them, firing guns in all directions, while at the head of a deff dread rode a cackling ork whose brain was exposed to the dust and air.

“Forward, then!” Hadrian cried, and the 4th moved with him.

==========================================

Shinehole Beachhead Tunnel Securing
Imperial Guard Attackers: 68
Orks Of Shinehole Defenders: 9
Blood Ravens: 63

“The Angels of Death are here!”

“Emperor be praised!”

Leave it to the commanders to be angry, to be suspicious, to be leery of accepting aid from the Blood Ravens. The story of the long-time inhabitants of the Korianis Sector was known to many. It was hard to keep that sort of information away from the upper echelons. Especially amongst the Ecclesiarchy, for whom the information had filtered down with rather annoying speed if one were to ask the Inquisition. But in that moment, face covered with the ash and blood of a full hundred men and women he had once ministered but a week before, Antonio Nicatus had nothing but happy tears to see them present. Draped in their holy and blessed armors, the Blood Ravens had arrived within the tunnel mouths which so many had died to take and so many died to hold, and moved into the thickest of the fighting.

There, their leader, wielding a crackling hammer which broke apart entire weapon emplacements and roaring epithets to the enemy. Another, wielding a masterful blade which cut through all who opposed him including a squad of mega nobs who had just the day before cut apart the leading commissar with their terrifying weaponry. All of them pushed forward, save one. Marked by his skull masked helm, his task and his nature was known to those who had a passing familiarity to space marines. Raising a crozius high, he extoled these broken men and women with a fervor that humbled Antonio to his core.

“Fear you not death, my friends, for the Emperor is with you. We! Are with you! See the enemy,” he swung the crozius in the direction of the howling orks as they retreated further than they ever had into the tunnels, “See how they run, see their weakness! You have lost so many to them, do you not desire vengeance!?”

His words inflamed the holy hatreds in the hearts of his flagging flock, and Antonio wept as they stood and roared their defiance against the choking pain and depression that had taken hold in their hearts. But they were tears of joy, and as he lifted up his own chainsword high, screaming to the God-Emperor, charging forward, he felt His eyes turn on them again. To think that he had begun to question his own faith! He would flog himself a dozen times more at the end of all of this for his folly!

==========================================

Shinehole Space Securing
Imperial Navy: 85
Ork Fleet: 36
1st Company Fleet: 66
4th Company Reinforcement: 52
4th Company Fleet: 82

“Boss, boss, dem new ships just killed ol’ Kaptin Brukk and iz turnin’ our way!” screamed the grot before Kaptin Tuskmunch grabbed him up and squeezed until the gretchin’s neck broke.

Adjusting his tri-corn hat, Tuskmunch growled as he wrapped his meaty green fingers around the metal wheel that had been forcibly connected to the entire ship. Rolling his fungus cigar back and forth between his blackened teeth, he chuckled for a moment as he squinted with red eyes at the wildly flickering holographic projection sticking out of the wall which showed the general direction of the enemy.

“Den let’s GO already!” he roared, and slammed down on the big red button with the grot’s corpse before flinging the body away.

He always liked hitting the big red button.

“Come on, you gitz. COME ON! Doesn’t matter if ya got more ships den us, doesn’t matter if dem humie Navy boyz suddenly got demselves a spine! COME GET SOME OF TUSKMUNCH’S GUNS!”

One solar revolution later found the orks over Shinehole completely eradicated in a joint assault by the Imperial Navy and Blood Ravens. The greenskins had plunged directly at their newest targets, their ships comparatively unblemished compared to the battle-worn Imperial Navy, opening up their flanks and rear to several lance barrages into their unarmored backsides. A small measure of acknowledgement was shared between the Rear Admiral in charge – who, as it turned out, happened to know of them specifically, for he was drinking friends with one Rear Admiral Whitmore of Krasus Command.

======================

Dustboom Combat (2)
Imperial Guard Vehicles: 10
Ork Vehicles: 16
Blood Raven Vehicles: 75

“We’re dead, we’re dead! We’re dead!”

“Shut up!” Colonel Zvorsk growled, and when the tertiary loader failed to cease his sniveling, found himself silenced as Zvorsk cracked the back of his hand off of the man’s cheek. “Status!”

“Treads are still down, battle cannon is cut apart, autocannon is broken too, and,” his driver began to rattle off before another great squealing filled all of their ears with literal ear-bleeding volume.

The ork Stompa had been a surprise, a trap laid in waiting within another of the larger scrap piles, before erupting out of the sides of as they had moved forward in a column in an ambush. Ork looted tanks had surrounded them on all sides, with missile firing war trukks too, attacking with reckless abandon. That had been five frantic minutes before they had steadily lost the ability to see outside of the baneblade outside of sticking their heads out – a sure death sentence they had already learned. Then the Stompa had begun trying to cut open the baneblade itself. Or at least that’s what they thought what was happening. Or maybe it wanted to just destroy the baneblade in general.

“Damn it,” he grunted, trying to wipe the stinging sweat out of his eyes, “If the General had listened to the Blood Ravens…,”

“Why would he, when he can throw us into the grinder in a completely opposite direction that they were going?” Triana snorted as she methodically loaded her bolt pistol in her lap, no point in trying to fire weapons from the primary gunner station any longer. “Still,” she glanced up at him, a shaky smile on her lips, “I plan on killing at least one of them after they open the old lady up.”

Zvorsk grunted and let his eyes roam over the innards of Mother Death, and opened his mouth to respond when he felt the entire baneblade rock – and not in the manner it had been before. The echoing booms of weapons fire, lascannons, and melta weaponry was easily recognizable to the elder colonel, and he felt his heart begin to swell ever so slightly with hope. More explosions rocked outside of Mother Death, until finally there was silence. Zvorsk shared a look with Triana before both jumped slightly at a knocking at the hatch. They waited a moment, until the knock came again, and Zvorsk swore before finally going up and dragging the corpse of his secondary gunner aside to crawl up the ladder.

“Ah. I was wondering if there was anyone left alive in the baneblade,” the Blood Raven said to him as Zvorsk stared at them. “What luck. The enemy is dead, and the techpriests are already on their way here. They seem especially aggrieved at the condition of it, which in this case…should probably be good for it,” the space marine said, pointing a finger back out into the dust to where Zvorsk could not see. “Good day, and may your dead find peace.”

Then the Blood Raven leapt off of the baneblade and on top of the land raider which had ridden up to them, and began to move past them all. Of the column itself, only a third of it was still viable and functioning, the rest either destroyed or their crew members expired in one way or another. Zvorsk stared as the Blood Ravens disappeared into the dust, the sounds of combat starting up not a few minutes later with flashes lighting up the distance, and swore again to himself before he found a lho-stick poked up from the depths of the tank, held in Triana’s hands.

“Thanks,” he finally said, and lit the stick up, staring unceasingly in the distance as the sounds of the space marine tanks steadily disappeared.

“I can’t believe they swung back around to save us,” he heard her say as she sat back in her seat, exhausted. “Seriously, look at that. I think they just outright vaporized some of those war trukks, I think. Didn’t totally get a full count before, of course, but I can believe it. God-Emperor help us.”

“I can believe it,” he finally said.

Stage 1 Dustboom Results:
Multiple Dustboom Ork Vehicle Formations Destroyed.
Multiple Stompas and Deff Dreads Destroyed.
Imperial Guard Casualties Middling.
No Blood Raven Casualties Taken.
1 Space Marine Predator Wreck Recovered From Ork Hands. Condition Critical. Repair May Be Possible.

=================================

Shinehole Tunnel Advancing
Imperial Guard Attackers: 17
Orks Of Shinehole Defenders: 6
Blood Ravens: 21

The bodies are not in fact, as some might think, thick enough to reach up to your knees, terminator armor or no. It is the general fungal filth which instead has claimed not just the floors, but the walls and the ceilings as well. Even so, you can see just why they call this place Shinehole, even in the parlance of the alien. From the piles of orkish loot you have found in the first few initial caverns taken after the beachheads were fully secured, you are seeing many an Imperial weapon dragged out to the actually audible screams of the techpriests at the desecration – in one case at least. Everything from lasguns, laspistols, and broken heavier weaponry, to more esoteric things like particularly shiny Imperial insignias. There were at least three shining medals for especially valorous Imperial soldiers found in the muck, which leaves a sour taste at the thought of how they were acquired by orkish hands in the first place.

“Fight on, Blood Ravens, fight on!” you cry, firing your plasma pistol into the depths of the enemy.

And there were depths aplenty. They were packed tightly in these tunnels, firing back with enough brass falling onto the ground from their guns to create a life-sized statue of the Emperor himself a dozen times over within the span of minutes. The volume of fire at this particular tunnel section was enough that even terminator armor was no true aegis against them. On the one hand, the rosarius that Hannibal carried had certainly aided you thus far against similar issues. On the other, it was currently recharging. It was by the grace of the Emperor that you had more than but one tool in your arsenal, however.

“Make way for the rapiers!”

“Make way!”

And then the tunnels were illuminated at rapid-fire by two rapier platforms firing in tandem. Eight heavy bolters fired at once, beating back the orks in volume and accuracy entirely. The noise was…considerable, and did not stop for a full sixty seconds, at which point the tunnel was almost entirely silent save for the groaning noises of a few somehow still barely alive greenskins.

“Living ones on your side, Calus,” he heard one of the techmarines manning the rapiers say to the other.

“That’s your side, Daedal.”

“No, that’s my side, I took the left, you took the right, and then I swept right while you swept left.”

“I started on the left while you took the right before I swept right while you swept left.”

“That makes no sense! Why would we both,”

“Techmarines,” Apollo growls as he strides to stand behind them, his voice just barely level. “Do you intend to stand here forever or to actually advance.”

Immediately the platforms began to move, slightly faster than was necessary, as he stalked after them down the tunnel. Behind, you shared a bemused glance with Doukas as you begin to advance after them. A faint squeal of pain and following crunch marked the death of the few survivors of the rapier barrage, yet even that was obscured by the bickering techmarines as they gesticulated wildly from atop their platforms.

“Look what you did! You made Diomedes-,”

“Me?! How could you-,”

Stage 1 Shinehole Results:
Shinehole Tunnel Beachheads Completely Secured.
Shinehole Space Theater Completely Secured.
Shinehole Tunnels 30% Cleared.
Significant Imperial Presence In ‘Shinehole Loot Piles’ Noted.
Shinehole Ork Leader Remains Unknown.
Notable Imperial Guard Casualties.
No Blood Raven Casualties Taken.

===========================

“BURN YOU VILE XENO SCUM, BUUUUUUUUUUURN!!!”

Atop a pile of burning and charred corpses, Canoness Superior Margaret Tenenbaum howled with rage as she slammed a flamefist into the face of the charging ork, turning to fire out a swirling gout of burning promethium into the face of another as it charged up the pile to get at her. All around, the Seraphim and Celestials fired into the approaching orks, while the sisters repentia screamed their death-curses and fell upon the enemy. The sounds of rockets firing heralded the arrival of yet more stormboyz, and in turn the seraphim ignited their own jump packs to take to the skies and face the greenskin threat where they flew. A raucous cheer coming from the orks dragged Margaret’s attention away from the latest ork be broken by fire and crackling powerfield, and where a massive ork with the darkest green skin she’d ever seen cut his way through a dozen sister repentia and stomp forward out of the trees.

“So youz the burny humies wot been killin’ all me boyz, eh? Well den it’s time ya met da boss!”

“And that’s you, ork?” she raised an eyebrow at the ork as it batted aside another charging repentia and three of its own xeno scum with its massive whirring chainaxe.

“You don’t gotta know da name of Fistkicka, but you’ze gonna!” the Goff roared as it charged forward.

“IN THE GOD-EMPEROR’S NAME!” the Canoness screamed.

Greenkrump Dueling: Initiative
Margaret: 79
Fistkicka: 37

The celestials scattered to the side beneath the ork’s charge, firing their weapons constantly regardless, but their leader stood her ground. The crackling powerfields of the flamefists seemed to spark with greater intensity as she aimed them to fire burning promethium spewed out into Fistkicka’s face.

Fistkicka Attack: 63
Margaret Defense: 20

The ork bellowed in rage but continued on regardless, a massive overhead swing slamming into the corpse pile beneath them. While the sister of battle stumbled slightly, a vibrating knife covered in a greenish powerfield cut out at her, slicing through her armor and the vulnerable flesh within, gaining in return a rictus gritting of teeth. Fistkicka felt the blood from her across his burning front and chuckled.

Margaret Response: 100
Fistkicka Defense: 65

Margaret twisted her hip and uncoiled her arm in a strike to the ork’s jaw, the powerfield of the flamefist erupting as she did so. Bone snapped in the ork’s skull, one eye being mashed to pulp entirely while the other continued to melt like wax as the rest of Fistkicka’s front still burned. As Fistkicka stumbled, his chuckles cut off by pain and a broken jaw, she stepped forward again and slammed both flamefists into his side at once, sending him flying off of the corpse pile entirely to land several feet below. Leaping after him, she raised both fists and triggered twin concentrated streams of fire at a charging mega nob, scorching the vulnerable flesh still yet uncovered by its armor. The ork screamed, flailing in another direction, as she continued after the rising Fistkicka.

“Oh, you’ze a tough little humie, aintcha,” he growled before standing again, snorting deeply before spitting out a wad of blood and phlegm.

Then he sniffed, and turned in her direction.

“BUT I AIN’T DONE YET!”

Fistkicka Grapple Attempt: 14
Margaret Defense: 10

The speed of the ork, even after the damage it had taken, managed to take Margaret by surprise. With stomping feet, unerringly toward her, the knife was dropped from one hand just in time to grab her by the wrist, sending the attempted new scorching flamer blast into the sky in a wild gout. Fistkicka chuckled again before slamming an elbow the size of a krak missile into her other arm, sending the flamefist’s burst into the jungle floor. Fistkicka, only then, opened his maw to reveal the sharpened steel
fangs within, and strained against the sister of battle’s faith-driven strength to lower it towards her. Dripping fat and melted green flesh fell on the jungle floor and on top of much of the Canoness’ armor.

Margaret Grapple Cancel Attempt: 97
Fistkicka Grapple Kill Attempt: 24

Margaret snarled, and reared back her head as far as she could before ramming it into the bridge of Fistkicka’s burning nose. Her own hair, dyed white, was immediately set aflame as well, yet so too was Fistkicka forced to stumble back slightly in surprise as even more of his skull was broken. She reared back again, and slammed her head forward once more, and this time Fistkicka’s grip on her arms loosened slightly. It was enough. She ripped her arms free of the orks grip, and lifted them both up so that the nozzles on them faced Fistkicka directly.

“In the name of the Emperor, die ork!” she cried aloud.

Dem Snakebites Is Sneaky!
Slitherjaw Rescue: 76

The stomping was barely heard in time, the sounds of battle across the entire clearing and throughout the jungle around them canceling most any attempt at specificity. But the rumbling across the ground was more clear. Margaret turned and had enough time to swear again before the squiggoth swung its head in one ponderous swing and slammed into her with one of its protruding tusks, sending her flying over ten yards away. Atop the howling squiggoth, another massive ork covered in purple and blue paint chortled as it raised a spear high in the sky.

“Oy, Fistkicka, you almost got zogged, haha! Good thing ol’ Slitherjaw was here, eh?”

Fistkicka growled as he furiously wiped off the remains of the flesh on his face leaving exposed muscle and bone behind.

“Shaddup, I had ‘er where I wanted ‘er!”

“AHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH!”

Seraphim Delivery!
Seraphim Rolled: 92.
Margaret Landing: 65.
Squiggoth Avoidance: 11.

Both turned to look – or at least in the direction of the sound, in Fistkicka’s case – as two seraphim flying through the sky dropped their hastily gathered payload, a screaming Margaret. She landed – fists first – directly on top of the squiggoth’s back, smashing into the houdah which had been placed there. The various snakebites present were either knocked aside or just beginning to right themselves when she stood up again, the squiggoth reeling in pain from the attack on its spinal cord.

“You! The Emperor’s Will guides me, ork, your pathetic creature is nothing to Him!”

Slitherjaw’s ugly face grew uglier as his precious animal was insulted, raising his spear high.

“Oh, you’ze gonna pay for dat one, you flamey bint!”

From below, Fistkicka called up.

“Oy! Lemme up dere, I ain’t finished with ‘er yet!”

Margaret Tackle Attempt: 73
Slitherjaw Murder Attempt: 1

The zealot’s charge brought her across the entire houdah, swinging out her flamefists periodically with the eruption of its power fields sending the snakebites atop flying. In turn, Slitherjaw threw the first of his spears, and then the next, only for one to be knocked aside and the second ducked under. With a roll of his eyes, he pulled the axe on his hip free and held it at the ready.

“Yeah yeah, all roight, I get it, yer flamey and angry and-hurk!”

“DIE!”

Margaret’s last steps turned into a coiled jump as she tackled Slitherjaw off of his houdah, and off of his squiggoth entirely. The beast’s eyes tracked its master as he fell, raising its head up slightly in time for Slitherjaw’s back to be punctured and stabbed through by its massive pointed tusk, shearing the ork in two almost completely as Margaret’s weight was added to the ork, pressed close in a mockery of a lover’s embrace.

Margaret Survival: 80
Slitherjaw Survival: 15

As Slitherjaw wheezed his last, his lungs now thoroughly separated from his body – along with the rest of his organs, Margaret fell onto the ground, a side of her armor heavily impacted and cracked from where the tusk had rammed along it. Her hair, still on fire, had begun to fall out, while the white fur of a snowbeast killed in the ice fields of Tevalia. With a grunt, she leaned down, scooping up a large handful of jungle floor soaked in the blood of a fallen sister and let it cascade over her head, snuffing the flame instantly. Then her gaze snapped to a charging Fistkicka who had given up verbal sparring for the last combat he might ever have.

Fistkicka Blinded Assault: 24
Margaret Defense: 82

This time, she punched the chainaxe that two grown men would struggle to even lift aside, breaking it entirely. With her other flamefist, she rammed an uppercut up into Fistkicka’s now obliterated jaw, breaking up through thoroughly bruised flesh and heavily broken bone, directly into the underside of the ork’s brain case. There, the powerfield erupted once more, and the upper half of the ork’s head was exploded just as well.

Fistkicka’s headless cadaver fell to its knees slowly before falling to its side. Just as slowly, Margaret turned, cracking her neck, and faced the squiggoth which had seen it’s master fall, and violently so. It’s giant piggish eyes squinted at her, and the beast finally roared at her, deciding on angry slaughter to be the appropriate response. Margaret’s response was to scream right back, and go running at it.

Anti-Squiggoth Combat
Squiggoth: 55
Margaret: 50

A heavy swing of its tusks brought only a miss, while an attempted wild punch swung wildly through only air. The distance had been closed, at the least, allowing more immediately deadly combat to take place.

Squiggoth: 57
Margaret: 91

A hunching of the creature’s legs betrayed its intentions, and before its snaking poison-covered tongue could wrap around her, or its jaws able to bite down and swallow her up, Margaret had leapt for the left tusk itself and found purchase. Then, grasping it with one hand, she gathered her legs under her and leapt again, this time punching a fist into the exposed naval cavalry with one flamefist and grabbing one of its folds of flesh with the other. Blood and erupted flesh splashed out beneath the crackling weapons, all the while Margaret muttered a prayer to the Emperor.

Shaking Squiggoth: 40
Margaret Climbing: 60

The squiggoth panicked, as any creature would when part of its head disappeared with a punch. As the beast began to shudder and shake, rolling its head back and forth at high speed, knocking aside many in the battlefield or killing some outright while stomping about, Margaret climbed. Occasionally she paused to point and shoot out another blast of flame at the monster’s eyes, only panicking it further as it broke trees and bodies apart in its crazed and now blinded charging.

Final Blows: 68

Once finding enough of a proper purchase, requiring another punch and explosion of flesh, Margaret began to punch down again….and again….and again. The flamefists were triggered constantly, draining the promethium on the tanks she held entirely, as she went, until the pained squiggoth’s skull was broken open and fire licked at its brain. She continued to punch, until there was enough of an opening so that she could use both fists at once. The brains of the squiggoth were smashed to pulp, the skull around it, until she burst from the then fallen creature’s forehead in a wash of gore and fire as its corpse caught flame.

“News, my sisters?” was the first thing she said to the approaching celestians and seraphim.

“The hordes of Fistkicka and Slitherjaw are broken. Infighting has already begun within their groups, and they have begun fighting each other as well. Your plan…was a success,” one celestial shook her head slowly, “Despite my reservations.”

“You should have had more faith in the God-Emperor,” Margaret grunted as she pressed a finger to her side, feeling the broken bones within.

“I have faith in Him,” the celestial loomed over her, gaze inscrutable within the helm, “It is stunts like that,” the celestial pointed to the fallen squiggoth, “That I have my concerns with.”

Then the celestial turned away, and started shouting at the seraphim.

“Which of you idiots dragged her up into the skies and dropped her like a sack of potatos?!”

Cunnin' Brutality
88

Imperial Navy Defense: 8
Ork Assault: 36
Ork Reinforcements: 65
Converging Ork Fleets: 80

An eruption in the skies interrupted the lambasting, and the Order of the Lost Rosetta stared at once in the skies above where the completely clear skies showed exploding Imperial Navy ships. Ork ships rumbled their way out of the warp, and one cruiser which had come close to provide orbital fire was cracked in three pieces as an orkish ship rammed directly through it. The flaming debris fell down towards the jungle, and the sisters of battle turned to a growling Margaret Tenenbaum who had elected to thusly ignore her injuries at the moment in the Emperor’s name.

“Call everyone together. Now.” She hissed, her heart almost torn in two at the sight of so many faithful to the God-Emperor dying to the orkish fleet. “Go!”

As the Lost Rosetta began to marshal themselves, calls going out across the jungle as they organized a retreat, Margaret stared up at the sky. The battle appeared to have begun intensifying, more and more ork ships showing up out of the immaterium to attack the Navy. Another cruiser fell, and she cursed, until finally some of the ships began to wink out of the materium. The Imperial Navy retreated, and Margaret stared up into the stars which were now quite filled with orkish leering faces on the fronts of their ships. Smoke-spewing shuttles and outright large rocks fell out of their bellies, heading towards the jungle itself.

“Cowards,” she tossed her considerably burnt hair and marched away. “And will someone tell the Guard to link up with us already!? We’ll need the Catachans they have to help us prepare for the enemy!"

Stage 1 Greenkrump Results:
Boss Slitherjaw (Snakebites) dead.
Boss Fistkicka (Goffs) dead.
Imperial Navy forced into a fighting retreat from Greenkrump.
Orks possess total orbital superiority. Ork ‘Killa-team’ Packs Currently Consolidated Over Greenkrump!
Order of the Lost Rosetta and Imperial Guard left on Greenkrump!
Orks landing new forces on Greenkrump to hunt Lost Rosetta and Imperial Guard.

Estimated Naval Presences Across System said:

Greenkrump
- 4 Hammer Battlekroozer
- 19 Kill Kroozers
- 12 Onslaught Attack Ships
- 20 Savage Gunships
- 3 Ravager Attack Ships

Dustboom
- 1 Emperor-class Battleship
- 3 Overlord-class Battlecruisers
- 2 Mars-class Battlecruisers
- 10 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 13 Escorts (x10 Firestorm, x3 Cobra)
- 4 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Spinesnap
- 5 Looted Battleships (x2 Retribution-class, x2 Oberon-class, x1 Apocalypse-class [Flagship Vessel])
- 4 Looted Battlecruisers (x3 Overlord-class, x1 Mars-class)
- 10 Kill Kroozers [Strike Cruiser Hull Suspected In Usage For A Kill Kroozer Present]
- 10 Onslaught Attack Ships, 5 Terror Ships

Shinehole
- 1 Overlord-class Battlecruiser
- 5 Dictator-class Cruisers
- 7 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 19 Escorts (x7 Cobra, x7 Sword, x5 Firestorm)
- 5 Universe-class Mass Conveyors
- 1st Company Fleet
- 4th Company Fleet

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Current Plans For Stage Two Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One/Do Not Need To Head To Every Theater At Once]:

Greenkrump
[] Attempt To On The Ground: The Order of the Lost Rosetta and the Imperial Guard have been left behind on Greenkrump as the Imperial Navy was forced into retreat. Their current status is unknown, though the fact that the orks are currently deploying forces down to the world speaks to their continued existence. Your ships could attempt to brave the enemy and deploy troops, though they will certainly risk destruction in the progress and would have to retreat immediately afterwards. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Take The Sky: The Imperial Navy is currently concentrated over Dustboom and Shinehole, unsure of how to proceed. The danger is whether or not the orks might move out from over Greenkrump and attack the worlds that they move out from after the Imperial Navy leaves. You, however, could try to make an attempt. It would not be the easiest of combat, especially considering the forces on-hand, but if you are able to properly board the enemy ships you could potentially take down the orks. This would be, of course, an extremely dangerous course. They would need significant forces with them to make the required mass-boarding actions on-hand, for you could not match the enemy in flat void combat due to their sheer numbers. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: Write-In

Dustboom
-[] Continued Crushing: The Imperial Guard has taken a beating on Dustboom, but has delivered it in turn. Quality and quantity have turned the tide against the orks, pushing them back across the planet and opening up new avenues of attack. Even so, there yet remain plenty more orks running about in the wasteland, exploding out of mek shops hidden in scrap heaps or rolling out from the mountains, and more. They must be destroyed. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
-[] Destroy Orbital Defenses: With the Imperial Guard pushing the orks back currently, even considering the casualties they've taken, the Blood Ravens might turn to more specific courses of action. With concerted pushes, certain orbital guns might be reached, their defenses punched through, and destroyed soon afterward. Once this is done, ships might take better positions, and provide more accurate auspex scanning, orbital fire, and more to the forces on the planet. [Write-In Forces Deployed]

Spinesnap
[] Attempted Infiltration: You do not possess nearly the firepower required to break the ork fleet which hangs over Spinesnap, but you could attempt to at least temporarily draw their ire so that some troops might be inserted onto the planet itself to begin fighting against the orks on the planet itself. This would open them to the risk of orkish orbital bombardment, however. On the other hand, the information they could learn about Bonebreaka could be valuable for the rest of the fight.
OR
[] Wait: You are not yet strong enough to face this foe in open battle, but if you were able to aid the Imperials across the rest of the system they might gather their own strength enough to take the fight to the enemy here instead.
OR
[] Something Else: Write-In

Shinehole
[] Further Into The Dark: The beachheads have held, and the Imperial Guard is now pushing through with far greater success, their hearts emboldened by success. The orks are only fighting harder, however, using some of the most advanced weaponry you've ever experienced amongst their kind, and machines as well in the tunnels. But the majority of caverns are still held by the enemy. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: (Write-In)

Overall Theater:
[] Attempt To Marshal: The Imperial Navy has become paralyzed by indecision. If they consolidated themselves from either Shinehole or Dustboom over the other, and then moved on Greenkrump, they could definitely take down the enemy there. However, at the same time, if they left, then the ork fleets at Spinesnap or Greenkrump might attack the worlds they just left and enact the issue over Greenkrump anew elsewhere. You could attempt to convince the Navy to do this regardless - though this would not cancel out the risk of Warboss Bonebreaka moving his fleet out again and tearing apart your ships if left behind, or crushing the forces left on the planets alone.
OR
[] Something Else: (Write-In)

==================================

“Thank you, oh Red Raven Lords, thank you,” the king gasped out, tears in his eyes, as the titan of the stars marched past him.

All around them, the populace of the city wept or cheered…or both, as the Blood Ravens passed. Their mighty column of strange metal beasts rumbled as they passed, while from the stars above came meteors bearing the mark of the Red Raven Lords. The kings of the skies, who served the Star Emperor, and yet they had come here! For so long, they had taken heart in the knowledge that the worthy youths had gone up into the stars above to fight at the Star Emperor’s side. It was acceptable, even if it burned in the minds of some to know that these valuable lives were not fighting the Green Menace. But now, for the first time in centuries, they had spoken! Spoken to the people, and not just the kings and those who arrived for the Great Trials!

“Open the gate,” one of their two leaders said to the king, his one red eye gleaming with malice for the enemy, while the heavily scarred one next to him nodded as well.

“Thank you, thank you...,” the king said again.

In the depths of his heart, he was afraid, in truth. Open the gates? Allow the orks to see their target open to them? It seemed the height of foolishness. But he could not deny them. The last king who had tried that, in a city long retaken by the jungle over a thousand years ago, had been slain so violently his very name had been stricken from the histories. He could not refuse them. The great rumblings to the east spoke of their wrath being unleashed upon Pacemen. The astronomers said that their vast sky carriages spat down true and unyielding hell unto the orks, with enough light that he had to order them to cease looking after four men were rendered blind. Yet as the great gates began to swing open, to cries of jubilation from the orks, he felt afraid.

Then the Red Raven Lords walked out, and faced the teeming hordes without fear.

Deployed Defenses vs. Feral Orks
20 vs. 80
10th Company Hunting Feral Orks
11 vs. 1
5th Company Running Down Feral Orks
61 vs. 9

Afterwards, the king had learned true fear. Before was but a droplet of unease compared to the carnage unleashed. Spirits trapped in metal roared their anger, and the orks died. The Red Raven Lords disappeared into the jungles, and the orks died. The metal carriage-beasts ground into the jungle, and the orks died. The piles of dead orks were high enough, large enough, numerous enough to make him void his bowels as he walked among them. All night and all day explosions were heard out of the jungle, as they watched from the walls of the citadel-city. Occasionally they would return, the Crimson-Eyed Lord and the Scarred King, only to leave soon after. The Scarred King was kinder, and extoled their virtue in surviving and fighting and living their lives. The Crimson-Eyed Lord spoke little, and when he did, one always left quieter in one’s soul. The orks died in greater droves than they ever had. None of the great Crusades fought to reclaim the jungles and push back across the Black Archipelago had killed so many, and so quickly. Once, he even saw the Crimson-Eyed Lord stand steadfast against a rampaging squiggoth, as his forces dropped their swords and shields and ran, ran for safety. Yet he simply raised his hand, and the ground itself collapsed beneath the beast, bringing it to its knees. There, another raised finger, and a dozen cracks in the air seconded like muted thunder, and the beast was dead, its suddenly empty eye-sockets weeping openly.

Bombardment Against Zero Defenses Or Danger!
Blood Raven Operators: 92

The Angels of Death had come to Trontiux III.

The feral orks of the world had no defense against orbital bombardment. No spear they could throw could possibly harm the thunderhawks as they delivered endless bombing runs upon them. Vast amounts of ordinance were exhausted, as bomb after bomb after bomb was dropped upon the continent of Pacemen. The hills were cracked open and reduced to broken glass, the jungle burning over the entire continent from the sheer fury unleashed upon them from the skies. Shamans howled to their bestial Gods for aid, but there was nothing to be found. Even their strongest psyker shields collapsed as the bombardment cannons of the fleet above fired upon them. Ork holds that had lasted for over a century were turned to craters, piles of scrap and leather burnt to molten slag. Masses of fleeing orks were brought down, as seemingly invulnerable gunships rose up near them, firing off with every weapon they possessed to reduce entire hordes to slurry.

Even the mighty Orkeosaurus was nothing here. As close to a bio-titan as the orks had ever been able to breed in recent known history, they suffered the most. Their impossibly thick hides and powerful physiology allowed them to survive the initial attacks. They screamed in pain amidst the charred corpses of their caretakers and breeders, reduced to nothing but ash, until the bombardment cannons in orbit fired again. Thunderhawks spent extensive amounts of fuel simply flying back up to the ships and resupplying ammo banks before returning into the atmosphere. All the while, the orks threw spears or ran for cover. But there was none to be found. A once vast and lush jungle was being transformed into a blasted cratered land.

Stage 1 Trontiux III Results
All Orkeosaurus Breeding Grounds On Pacemen Destroyed.
Tremendous Culling To Orks On Petramis Complete.
Due To Presence Of Multiple Static Defenses, Orks Retreat From Citadel-Cities.
Pacemen Orks Have Sustained Immense Casualties, All Ork Holds/Watch Posts/Forts Eradicated.

Current Plans For Stage Two Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One]:

Petramis:
[] Continued Culling - Orks still teem within the jungles, despite your efforts. A continuous and concerted effort will be required to properly cull them. The bloody work must continue. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
[] Taking The Plateaus Back - The orks have been completely forced back from the cities. The greater threat now are the claimed plateaus where citadel-cities once stood. These must be cleansed, if not to be reclaimed later then at least to destroy what they protect. As a reminder, orbital strikes on the plateaus is extensively not recommended by records, for it would surely destroy the plateaus and weaken humanities presence on the planet near-permanently.
-[] Citadel A's Ork Hold has completed construction, and is as full of orks as ever, and more so now that orks from Pacemen have fled from across the Black Archipelago. It is now currently the most heavily fortified ork position left on Trontiux III able to be seen from space. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
-[] Citadel B's defenses have grown in number. This largely takes the place as more orks, who have spears and such to throw. Wounded animals able to be recovered from the fighting are resting here, while one Orkeosaurus remains here. Multiple squiggoths of both large and gargantuan varieties - i.e. battle tank sized and Imperial Knight heights. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
-[] Citadel C's orks have actually spread thoroughly out into the jungle, though a good number of them remain here. Initial auspex scans indicate that they are still in the area around Citadel C, but not on the plateau itself.
[] Fury From The Skies - For too long have the orks of this world assumed the sky held no major threat for them. It is time to change that. While orbital bombardments are not recommended lest the plateaus be collapsed or something similar, more concentrated and skillfully delivered bombing runs and targeted airstrikes could tear apart enemy positions across Petramis. This would allow you to obliterate the orks upon the plateaus, possibly creating the opportunity to claim them for yourself in at least some temporary measure as FOBs. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

Black Archipelago:
[] Take And Hold - From the skies, rain down destruction upon the various bridges connecting the islands and continents, and then deliver drop pods amongst the islands to scourge them of the greenskins upon them. In this manner, this vital choke-point between the two continents can be defended, potentially reinforced, and allow the feudal humans a way to strike back in the future. Just as well, fortifications built upon these islands will ensure that the orks will have a visible target to attack, and thus to die against. With the sheer damage dealt to Pacemen, many orks are fleeing across the Black Archipelago to get over to Petramis. This will mean that taking and holding the islands will be notably more difficult, by sheer numbers if nothing else. [Write-In Forces Contributed To This Action]
[] Obliteration - For too long has the Black Archipelago provided a passage point for the orks to arrive in Petramis. It must be dealt with, and here there is no worry of catastrophic geological damage. Initiate continual orbital bombardment and burn these islands out of existence. In the future, it will require that the orks travel to Petramis by sea, and there will be no main central funnel for them to travel across meaning that their arrivals would be more spread out, but in the immediate moment this will greatly aid in the current culling of the orks. The people of the world can adapt to the circumstances later on, with a hopefully much reduced orkish population. Black Archipelago destroyed. Orks will require alternate passage to arrive on Petramis in the future.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

Pacemen
[] Fear The Skies - Every major settlement and base has been destroyed by this point, their breeding grounds brought to ruin. However, plenty of orks remain here, either trying to put out the fires raging across the jungle or heading across the Black Archipelago. Those that remain must be killed as well. This is not merely a push back against the orks here. No. This is a culling! Besides which, the Black Archipelago could only sustain light orbital bombardment before collapsing, and enough has been said about the certain side-effects to Petramis as well. Here, the ships can continue to fire.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

Turn 19 (Part Three): By Duty, Bring Death

Spoiler: Plan: Bone Breaker

[X] Plan: Bone Breaker
-[X] The Navy is afraid of leaving planets open for attack in case they decide to consolidate their forces to attack orks on either planet? Then lets not give the orks a chance. The Navy forces on Shinehole will move to annihilate the orks on Greenkrump, while at the same time Navy forces on Dustboom will move to Spinesnap to engage the ork navy there, with the goal of locking them down in the system and stalling until reinforcements can arrive. If large amounts of ork ships are escaping from these battles, portions of the fleets are to be pulled off to reinforce Dustboom and Shinehole. As soon as ork navy on Greenkrump has been destroyed, most of the space forces there are to move to Spinesnap to support the Navy forces there, while the forces remaining will continue to supply the ground forces, including Blood Raven ground forces.
-[X] Instruct high ranking Navy officers to follow your lead and directly contact ork captains when arriving in system and insult and belittle them and their combat prowess in every way possible to both break their fleet cohesion and to draw their full attention, so that they wouldn't even think of leaving the battlefield.
--[X] 1st Fleet
--[X] 1st Company (sans dreadnoughts), Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chapter Master's Honor Guard
---[X] Naval forces left to defend Dustboom
----[X] 3 Lunar class cruisers, 4 escorts (3x Firestorm, 1x Cobra), 4 Universe-class Mass Conveyors
---[X] Naval forces left to defend Shinehole
----[X] 4th Fleet, 3 Universe-class Mass Conveyors
-[X] Continued Crushing: The Imperial Guard has taken a beating on Dustboom, but has delivered it in turn. Quality and quantity have turned the tide against the orks, pushing them back across the planet and opening up new avenues of attack. Even so, there yet remain plenty more orks running about in the wasteland, exploding out of mek shops hidden in scrap heaps or rolling out from the mountains, and more. They must be destroyed.
--[X] 4th Company
--[X] Land Raider Phobos Litany of Purgation
--[X] 1 Predator (Twin-Linked Lascannons)
--[X] 1 Predator
--[X] 1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Plasma Guns) [+Lascannon]
--[X] 1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons)
--[X] 1 Vindicator
--[X] 4 Assault Bikes (2x Multimelta, 2x Heavy Bolter)
---[X] Give our remaining Iron Halo to Captain Hadrian Priscus
-[X] Further Into The Dark: The beachheads have held, and the Imperial Guard is now pushing through with far greater success, their hearts emboldened by success. The orks are only fighting harder, however, using some of the most advanced weaponry you've ever experienced amongst their kind, and machines as well in the tunnels. But the majority of caverns are still held by the enemy.
--[X] All 1st Company dreadnoughts
--[X] Techmarine Calus, Techmarine Daedal
--[X] 3x Rapiers (Quad-Heavy Bolters)
--[X] 1x Rapier (Laser-Destroyer Array)
-[X] Taking The Plateaus Back - The orks have been completely forced back from the cities. The greater threat now are the claimed plateaus where citadel-cities once stood. These must be cleansed, if not to be reclaimed later then at least to destroy what they protect. As a reminder, orbital strikes on the plateaus is extensively not recommended by records, for it would surely destroy the plateaus and weaken humanities presence on the planet near-permanently.
--[X] Citadel A's Ork Hold has completed construction, and is as full of orks as ever, and more so now that orks from Pacemen have fled from across the Black Archipelago. It is now currently the most heavily fortified ork position left on Trontiux III able to be seen from space.
---[X] 5th Company
---[X] Land Raider Crusader Tarantulus Ultima
---[X] 6 Razorbacks (Standard Twin-Linked Heavy Bolter)
---[X] 1 Razorbacks (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons)
---[X] 2 Whirlwinds
---[X] Predator
--[X] Citadel C's orks have actually spread thoroughly out into the jungle, though a good number of them remain here. Initial auspex scans indicate that they are still in the area around Citadel C, but not on the plateau itself.
---[X] 10th Company
-[X] Fury from the Skies (Citadel B)
--[X] All available Thunderhawk Gunships
--[X] 3 Land Speeders (Standard)
--[X] 2 Land Speeders (Tempest)

By Duty, Bring Death
+030.M42+ To +035.M42+
+Pain Now! Reward In The Afterlife!+

Fleet Arrival At Greenkrump
83! No Complications.

When you arrive at Greenkrump, the orks begin turning immediately – and this is before you begin transmitting your various insults and challenges. They show zero hesitation at the arrival of a somewhat superior force, even with many of their ships still down on the surface. That is something you had relied upon, in fact, for while ork attack ships can be trouble in the void, they are also major troop transports for the greenskins that must descend to the planets below to fully release their compliments. Which means, in this case, that much of the Greenkrump ork fleet is still on the ground. Yet that does nothing to dampen their spirits as they charge toward you with almost reckless abandon. They are greenskins, after all. But then comes a surprise.

Lost Rosetta Rallying
66! Success!

“Scans are showing the Lost Rosetta moving on the surface of Greenkrump, with heavy Imperial Guard support. They are rallying!” a serf cries out from his console.

“Emperor be praised,” you nod, before turning your gaze to the rest of the battle. “If we are fortunate, we will be able to support them soon enough. Give me progress reports on them. If they require immediate aid, we need to be able to provide it.”

“Aye, Chapter Master!”

Greenkrump Rallying
21! Several attack ships struggling to lift off from Greenkrump surface!
- 3 of 3 Ravager Attack Ships remain on Greenkrump Surface
- 7 of 10 Land-bound Onslaught Attack Ships remain on Greenkrump Surface

“It looks like the xenos are trying to get their ships off the ground, but got too eager. Only three of them have lifted off,” the same serf from before says in surprise.

Ork Ship Charge: 75
Navy Assault: 56
Blood Raven Assault: 25

And then the orks are upon you. Every kill kroozer present clumps together to the point that two actually scrape against each other’s hulls, and punch through the initial Navy formation. Such is the speed shown by the ork ships that your own logic engines are incapable of finding proper drop pod insertion points! A lunar cruiser goes up in smoke as one of the hammer battlekroozers rams it directly, while a group of escorts is swarmed by ork attack ships. Your own ships begin firing off their own salvos, but no major discernable damage is done to the enemy. If anything, it is the Navy’s sole present battleship which does the most damage to the ork fleet.

Lost Rosetta Boarding: 90
- 5 Onslaught Attack Ships under control of Lost Rosetta and entering void combat!

“Um,” a serf speaks up.

“That’s generally not something you want to hear, crewman,” Doukas says from near you, tapping his fingers along the hilt of his blade. “The number of times ‘um’ was followed by something good happening when I was with the Explorator could be counted on one hand.”

“The…Order of the Lost Rosetta just boarded some of the ork’s ships down on the planet.”

That brings you to a momentary halt in your mind, many present on the bridge turning to stare at the serf, who is rubbing at the back of his head.

“And…now those ships are heading towards the ork fleet, firing every weapon they can.”

Indeed, you can see it on the tactical map which dominates the center of the bridge at the foot of the command throne. A small series of blips are rocketing up out of Greenkrump at speeds only ork ships would willingly use, and heading not towards any Imperial vessel to link up, but rather…at one of the enemy vessels.

“Other ships are trying to lift off after them!” the serf cries out, and your eyes snap to auspex scans blooming on the projection.

Greenkrump Liftoff Attempts
5! Some attack ships explode during liftoff!
- 3 of 3 Ravager Attack Ships lost!
- 4 of 4 Remaining Land-bound Onslaught Attack Ships lost!

“Multiple enemy ships on Greenkrump have…exploded? The Guard is still on the planet, and fighting!”

“Impressive,” Doukas notes approvingly, though you are more concerned as to what in the world the Order of the Lost Rosetta is even thinking at this point.

======================

Dustboom Combat (1)
Imperial Guard Vehicles: 3
Ork Vehicles: 40
Blood Raven Crushing: 90

A dozen Leman Russ tanks had died, proud machines turned smoking wrecks, just to bring down a force just barely equal in number to them. By the time the Blood Ravens had arrived, it had been too late. Yet they had only been late due to the sudden arrival of another ork armor column entirely.

“These orks have much to answer for,” Hadrian grunted as he gently ran a hand along the flank of the predator tank.

And it was a predator tank. The shape and feel was unmistakable; despite the tremendous damage it had suffered in its life it remained a predator tank. How many years had it languished under the hand of the orks? Long enough for great amounts of rust to set in, for any sign of its old heraldry to have been worn away or painted over into non-existence. Even the aquila on it was mostly worn away, but a little bit of water and wiping and it shined just a little bit. At the least, the ork crew that had been using it for their own personal transport were dead.

“Well, techmarine?” he turned to look at the quiet marine whose servo-harness whirred with each step. Various mechadendrites poked and prodded at the machine.

“It will require reconsecration, but I believe that with effort…this poor thing may one day ride again in its proper place,” the Blood Raven eventually said.

“Good enough for me,” Hadrian nodded, and walked away to where the Litany of Purgation rumbled. “Keep it safe!”

===================

Shinehole Tunnel Push (1)
Imperial Guard Attackers: 46
Ork Defenders: 10
Blood Raven Attackers: 95

“Come on, come on,” Daedal murmured from atop his rapier as it shot down one of the tunnels, yet the orks kept streaming through.

“Keep firing, keep firing!” Calus bellowed from atop his own rapier, a heavy bolter in his hands as he fired over the lip of his station shields. “Daedal?!”

“It’s ready!”

Once, it had been a proud machine. But years languishing in the muck, bits and pieces torn out for the insane usage of an ork mek or two, and various other desecrations had almost delivered it to the forges for breakdown entirely. Perhaps in the future its pieces would be used in another of its kind, the machine spirit reincarnated. But that had been before desperation, before near overwhelming, and before Techmarine Daedal of the Blood Ravens found it. With a few more sparks flying from the mechadendrites, suddenly a long-dead heart bloomed like a newborn star.

“DIE GREENSKINS!” he roared in exhultation, lifting up the plasma cannon which still possessed many a greenskin scrawl on its frame, and the ancient weapon coughed forth a ball of superheated death into the enemy.

“We have arrived,” boomed the dreadnoughts behind, and between the two rapiers stomped forth a moving tomb, both arms fitted with assault cannons. At the same time, the ammo blocks of the rapiers were shunted aside and refilled.

The volume of what followed next was literally deafening, even to space marine ears.

=====================

Lost Rosetta Ramming: 82
Ork Fleet: 53
Naval Assault: 73
Blood Raven Push: 57

“Love the Emperor
for He is the salvation of mankind
Obey His words
for He will lead you into the light of the future
Heed His wisdom
for He will protect you from evil
Whisper His prayers with devotion,
for they will save your soul
Honour His servants,
for they speak in His voice
Tremble before His majesty,
for we all walk in His immortal shadow.”

Margaret lifted her gaze from where it had been bowed, and stood from where she had kneeled while praying. Around her, the Lost Rosetta checked their weapons one last time, but all the while their leader stared straight ahead and unblinking. The controls of these ships were crude, but in their crudeness they had been made somewhat understandable. This lever to fly, this button to shoot, this pulley to launch other projectiles. All around them, the ships were rumbled and shaking themselves apart as they had since taking off, but they had faith. Faith in these ships, that while they were of orkish hands, they would serve for the Emperor’s purposes.

“Status,” she barked out to one of her celestials who wrestled with the ‘controls’ on the bridge.

“Blood Raven ships and Imperial Navy are currently assaulting the enemy, and have destroyed many, but have not yet broken through to our target, Canoness.”

“Very well then,” Margaret nodded, and inhaled deeply before immediately retching out the disgusting air that the ship possessed. “Full speed," she coughed, "Ahead!”

All five vessels shot forward, power shunted almost entirely to engines, and slammed directly into the side of one of the hammer battlekroozers. Only this one had been marked differently on the ridiculously childish ork ‘map, if it could even be called that, with glitching angry skulls around it on the primitive holographic projector which passed for an orcish tactical map. Therefore, it likely either held the leader or some powerful ork weapon or device. Or something. What mattered is that its destruction would serve the Emperor!

Dragging herself upright, Margaret growled as she helped other sisters to their feet.

“Onward! For the Emperor!”

=======================

Ork Cohesion: 19

“Roight, zog dis den,” Krarg grumbled, wiggling his fungus-cigar from side to side in his teeth.

The sounds of explosions in the ship – and not the good normal kind – only furthered his point. From here he could hear the humies exploderating their way through his beautiful ship, shooting and burning indiscriminately. He could appreciate that, really, and sometimes he’d been the one to do it. But it had been him, not humies. Especially not those burny ones that ran around draped in beakie armor. It was annoying, it was. With a grumble, he turned towards the ‘taktiks map’ held in the hands of one of his grots, and snorted at the symbols on it winking out.

“Boyz!” he screamed out on the speaking horn to all the ships left in his fleet. “Dis foight is dumb! We’ze getting’ outta here and back to Spinesnap, Warboss Bonebreaka is gonna sort all dese humies out real quick!”

A gretchin burst into the bridge, then, screaming and flailing as it burned to death, and Krarg turned slightly to stare at it with his one eye. It hopped and leapt about, some of the orks on the bridge chuckling at its misfortune, before finally tipping over and dying. Rolling his eyes, he slammed on the speaking horn’s button again.

“And will SOMEONE kill them burny humies already! Zog me, there’s only a few hundred of ‘em!”

Orks Fleeing: 79
Imperial Chasers: 7
- 2 Hammer Battlekroozers Escape
- 10 Kill Kroozers Escape

Anyone who had access to anything had heard the outbound broadcasts of the greenskins, heard Krarg's orders to flee.

“They’re trying to flee back to Spinesnap! Cut them off!” you call out, and while the ships turn as fast as they can, a mass of ork attack ships blocks the way.

They die, to be sure, to a vessel, but by the time the rest of the Chapter Fleet and the somewhat battered Navy is able to push through them all, the rest of the ork ships have disappeared into the warp. At the least, you know their location, for few are the orks who seem to realize that one does not need to broadcast on all channels possible just to speak to one another. Then again, that is preferable to them learning anything approaching operational security. Plans sift and dip through your mind, including what you had originally planned in case the ork ships tried to escape. Before you had thought they might try to arrive over Dustboom or Shinehole, but that clearly wasn’t the case here. No, you cannot rely on that plan any longer, and there is only one logical thing left to do. The Navy forces sent to Spinesnap are surely already dealing with much, and attacked from behind? No, you must go to them, and go to them now.

Not to mention the fact that one of the vessels that escaped was the one that the Order of the Lost Rosetta had rather suicidally boarded.

“Set course for Spinesnap!”

“For the Emperor!”

===================================

Dustboom Combat (2)
Imperial Guard Vehicles: 65
Ork Vehicles: 64
Blood Raven Crushing: 95

“How many tanks do these bloody orks have,” Gunner Teague wiped the sweat from his eyes as he squinted at the rangefinder.

“They’ve been here for centuries, gunny,” Sheila reminded him as she lifted up another shell. “We all got the briefing, remember?”

“Yeah, but – woah!”

Their Leman Russ abruptly shuddered as it came to a violent halt, sending Teague flying forward against the bulging muscles of Sheila. The gene-enhanced guardswoman rolled her eyes and pushed her back into her seat, cutting her eyes then to the driver.

“Well?”

“Sorry, Blood Ravens just showed up,” he explained with a shrug, “I figured…”

“WHY DID MY TANK JUST STOP!” their tank commander bellowed back down from the hatch, and seconds afterward the dustblown Marshal Reigns was glaring at them from behind his goggles. “Did you just stop my tank, Toombs?!”

“Sir, the Blood Ravens-,” was as far as Toombs got before Marshal slammed his boot into the man’s face, sending his skull cracking backwards.

“Excuse me? Frak that, you God-Emperor damned idiot! I don’t wanna lose out to some overjumped hunks of metal! GET US INTO THE FIGHT BEFORE THEY KILL ALL THE ORKS!”

To Tank Commander Marshal Reigns’ immense displeasure, a great many war trukks and an entire orkish battlewagon had been destroyed before his Leman Russ was able to mark off a kill.

==========================

Fleet Arrival At Spinesnap (Generally Concurrent With Beginning Of Greenkrump Assault)
86! No Complications.

“Oy, boss!”

Warboss Bonebreaka shifted slightly from the throne upon which he sat, made of the piled up loot of the great many things he’d killed in his life. With a grunt, he withdrew an eldar banshee’s mask from beneath his left buttock and tossed it to the side before focusing his attention on the ork who had spoken, entering into Bonebreaka’s personal shiny chamber. For an instant, the Warboss considered killing him, but eventually thought better of it and jerked his jaw at the ork.

“Yeah, well…the uh…the humies done showed up!”

Then Bonebreaka moved, off the throne and pile and grabbing the ork by the throat in a single burst of speed.

“THEN GET TO FOIGHTING!” he bellowed, throwing the ork to the side as he headed for the bridge. “Got ta tell every git meself to do what should come naturally, do I? Bah!”

Navy vs. Bonebreaka’s Fleet
Navy Assault: 8
Bonebreaka Counter-Attack: 60

Killtasticka rumbled with the victorious war chants of its gunners soon after. One of the enemy battlecruisers died a fiery death, blown to pieces almost immediately after the battle had become. It was something that Bonebreaka had learned from the Blood Axes and spindly runners elsewhere in the galaxy. What applied on the ground applied in space. If enough guns shot at one target? It died. No matter what. Grumbling, the Warboss snapped out a hand, choking the life of one of his gun-bosses, and threw him across the room with a crash.

“I SAID SHOOT WHERE I SAY, YA DUMB GIT! You,” he growled, pointing at a grot, “You gonna listen to wot I say and when I seyz?”

The gretchin nodded wildly, its ears and nose flopping wildly.

“Yez boss, I swear I will, yes!”

“Den get on the gunner set, and get to shootin’…dat one!” Bonebreaka roared as he pointed at another single ship on the screen, and his bellowing voice was transmitted across the entire fleet. “And kept dere tiny ships busy, zog it! Dere’s only nine of ‘em, we gotz…,” he paused for a moment, “We’ze got more den dat, so get on it!”

Navy Regroup: 31
Bonebreaka Avalanche: 69

The human tactical screen was considerably less fun than an orkish one, but a few years of tinkering had fixed that. Now it had proper snarling faces, shiny parts, little pleasurable splashes of color here and there. Yet still, the heavily modified projector still worked its magic, and showed the terrified human fleet trying to regroup in on itself after Killasticka had blown through their formation. Another two cruisers died, while the surrounded ‘escort ships’ – what stupid human naming system – were busy being shot to utter pieces by his own ships. That were tinier, yes, but also plenty good!

“Hurr hurr, they didn’t bring nearly enough dakka for dis fight. We’ze outnumbering them in every way! In tiny ships, in kroozers, in our bigga ships,” Bonebreaka chortled, rubbing at his chin with his power klaw. “Didn’t even need to get dat twiggies help for dis.”

“Uh, boss?” one of the bridge-gretchin called out for his attention, waving its entire boy at him.

“Yeah, wot iz it,” he growled as he came closer.

“Dem humie ships…says ‘ere dat de’re doin’ sumfin weird with dere power?”

“Loik wot?”

Desperate Navy: 96
Bonebreaka Blocking: 1

The answer came not a moment later. Engines drained of power, void shields dropped, and even life support and gravity temporarily suspended, every weapon that the Imperials possessed fired at once at every orkish target they could. A hefty number of orkish attack ships disappeared, lances and torpedos striking them at once. Two of the looted battlecruisers, of human design once upon a time, were cored completely, and while the orks on those ships continued to fire with what they could soon enough they began to suffocate at the loss of life support and the many holes in the ship.

“Zog me, wot was dat?” Bonebreaka groaned as he rubbed his head, squinting at where he’d been thrown by the impact. “Oh, great, I dun squashed one of me gunnerz. Get me some more gretchin,” he roared into the speaking horn before turning to face the tactical map.

Bonebreaka grinned, and licked slightly at the blood which trickled down from his forehead.

“Still…nice to see dey actually got some foight in ‘em. Didn’t want dis to be too easy.”

Greenkrump Runners Arrival
88!
+ 2 Hammer Battlekroozers Enter Spinesnap Void Combat!
+ 10 Kill Kroozers Enter Spinesnap Void Combat!

“Oi, ‘ooz dat den?” Bonebreaka squinted at the arrival of new orky symbols on the tactical map, behind the human ships. After a moment, he growled, and slammed a hand on a speaking horn, this time the one that went to other ships.

“OY! Krarg! Wot you doin’ ‘ere, you’ze supposed to be at Greenkrump!”

The response was considerably garbled, the sound of explosions and gunfire almost completely obscuring Krarg’s reply.

“We’ze wasn’t runnin, we’ze just making a ‘taktikul retreat’, figured we’d join up with you and go back at ‘em for annuver go!”

Bonebreaka sighed, and rubbed at the bridge of his nose.

“Fine,” he eventually grumbled, “Start zogging dem humie ships, and get right quick to it!”

Order Boarders: 63
Krarg’s Boyz: 20

The response from Krarg was entirely static, to which Bonebreaka grunted in confusion. After another moment he slammed his hand on the speaking horn again.

“Krarg? You still there?”

“Yes! Sorry, boss, just…dealin’ wivv some humie boarders!”

“On yer ship?!” Bonebreaka laughed, “You’ze gotta be kiddin’ me.”

“No boss, not at all. Dey are…very persistent! But we’ll get da boyz on it, real quick!!”

Surrounded Navy: 49
Bonebreaka Fleet: 90
Krarg Fleet Survivors: 65
Lost Rosetta Boarders: 81

Bonebreaka sniffed, rolling his eyes again at the sounds of fighting from Krarg’s ship, but the ships under his command moved forth regardless. The human ships had blown out their reactors by their desperate all-or-nothing attack, and while it had taken down quite a few ships and boyz with them, they were just grots in a barrel now. Shifting forward, he slammed his hands on the speaking horns, all of them at once, and gave a low laugh.

“All right boyz, start shootin’! We’ze got ‘em surrounded! Tear ‘em APART!”

Then he removed his hands from all but one of the buttons, one marked with a wrench scrawling rather than skulls or whatever else.

"Oy, howz dem ships comin, they gonna be joinin' us or not, mek?"

The speaker horn crackled loudly before the noise of cutters and fire could be heard. The ork on the other end gave a hacking cough before spitting, finally responding after a minute later.

"Dey'z ready boss! No worries! You'll see! I'll show Mekboss Killdakka wrong, I will!"

Spinesnap Ork Vessel Liftoff
94! All ships lift off!
+1 Ork 'Battleship'
+5 Ork Kill Kroozers join Ork Spinesnap Fleet!

A loud explosion boomed through the speaker horn, and Bonebreaka growled, before the tactical map registered several orky skull symbols rising up from his world's surface. Several warning signs in the language of humanity blipped about the red skulls, before he slammed his fist into the side of the tactical map. A second thump made it change to its proper place, the symbols nice and green with the stupid human warnings disappearing. In the center was a particularly large skull, this one with Mek Groz's personal mek-y heraldry on it.

"Hurr hurr...now dat's da way! Keep dis up, Groz, and you'll be me new Mekboss yet!"

====================================

Shinehole Tunnel Push (2)
Imperial Guard Attackers: 22
Ork Defenders: 54
Blood Raven Attackers: 56

"That is quite a lot of missiles," Daedal noted as he reversed the rapier back out of the way at breakneck speed, just in time to avoid the almost lazily slow projectiles.

Which then exploded and tore huge chunks out of the tunnel walls. A great chattering from orkish guns followed it up and turned the charging Guard platoon into wet chunks. From atop the rapier, the techmarine grunted and covered his eyes slightly to keep the continual flashes from blinding him. Within his helmet, a small beep indicated a comm-request.

"Yeah Calus?"

"Assault's stalled a bit there, Daedal," came the casual voice of his battle brother. "Everything all right?"

"Oh, it's fine," he grunted, "I'll just drive the rapier into certain destruction then, shall I?"

"Didn't say that," Calus began.

"You implied it though," Daedal finished.

"I bet you'd take a lot of them out, first, is what I mean to say, brother."

"Are the two of you always like this?"

Daedal turned to look at the venerable 1st Company Dreadnought before him, and though the marine's entire ruined body was obscured within, Daedal still felt as if it was giving him a disapproving look for some reason.

"Um. No?"

It was then that Calus commed him again, this time surely loud enough for the dreadnought to hear.

"Hah! I just fixed that power axe I found, what about you, did you get yours working yet? Probably not, eh?"

============================

Imperial Arrival
56! Minor complications, arrival position unfavorable.
Blood Raven Arrival
78! No complications.

The news is grim as you arrive at Spinesnap. The Imperial ships sent here to hold the enemy have done their job, though unfortunately this has taken the form of being too tempting of targets for the greenskins to go elsewhere. They have been badly ravaged by the enemy, whose numbers have swollen somehow despite the tallied kills, with reports coming in from the badly struck Imperial fleet which is currently completely surrounded by greenskin ships that the new ships arose from Spinesnap itself. With no presence on the planet, such constructions went without detection. There is little left to do but fight, now, though your gaze seems locked onto the orkish battleship which lumbers its way up into the atmosphere.

A good chunk of it falls off back down to the planet below, but by sheer mass it cannot be confused with anything else.

Worse is that the Imperial ships that accompanied you from Greenkrump have completely overshot, their ships emerging from the warp away from the battle entirely, leaving the battle itself behind. Now it is just the Chapter’s ships facing the slowly turning orks, with the beleaguered Imperial ships in the middle of all of them. But you steel yourself against the near overwhelming odds, and order the advance.

Greenskin Redirection: 33
Lost Rosetta Boarding Teams: 77
Navy Detachment 1: 37
Navy Detachment 2: 26
Blood Raven Assault: 48

The Omnia Arcanum is one of the biggest regular battle barges you’ve ever seen. It’s defensive shields and hull have protected it in entire protracted planetary sieges while under near constant bombardment. It is this which saves it now, protecting it as it charges forward as a bulwark, the strike cruisers shifting forward next to it while the escorts trailed behind. Lance blasts from the nova frigates slice holes into the enemy kroozers, while a single launched bombardment shell strikes against another kill kroozer and obliterates it instantly.

Naval Regrouping: 28
Greenskin Assaults: 93
Lost Rosetta Boarding Teams: 53
1st Company Fleet Assault: 65

While the Chapter does its best, and fires off many a shell, the distance is just too great for true damage to be done just yet. Minor damage is inflicted by the lance weaponry you have on hand, and while a few more salvos of bombardment shells and torpedos are shot out, the insane maneuvering of the orks keeps them from suffering much at all. Instead, it is the original Imperial Navy attachment which was sent in the first place that suffers the most, more and more of their ships being rammed, boarded, or shot apart. In one particularly unfortunate lunar-class cruiser, all three occur at once. The Navy ships that overshot spend all of their efforts on actually getting to the fight itself, meaning that in that time even more damage is taken.

Naval Regrouping: 8
Greenskin Assaults: 42
Lost Rosetta Boarding Teams: 90
1st Company Fleet Assault: 74

Desperate to get away, the will and nerve of the few captains remaining drives the surrounded ships to try and flee. But even that fails, as they struggle to link up with the incoming ships who are already unleashing their own salvos. At the least, however, the Blood Ravens are able to push forward truly, and smash forward into the enemy formations. The Omnia Arcanum rumbles throughout the hull as drop pods go flying out, crashing into the larger enemy ships, while thunderhawks begin flying out of their bays to drop bombs or transport other marines into gaping holes in the vessels of the enemy. In addition, two more ships are transformed into shattered molten ruins by bombardment shells striking them across unarmored bows.

==========================

Krarg Deflecting: 61
Margaret Flurry: 100

"Kaptin! Kaptin we'ze got a...uh...," the ork slowed to a stop as it entered the thoroughly ruined bridge.

All across it, the bodies of the slain lay where they had fallen, human and xeno alike. At the front of the bridge however, near the steering wheel, the self-styled Supa-Kaptin Krarg bellowed as his swung his power klaw back and forth at a wildly dodging woman whose entire armor seemed to have been set aflame. Various ork crew members, the effective equivalent of nobs amongst the Freebooters, grappled and fought in deathly hand-to-hand combat against wild women who wore little but the massive chainswords they bore. All around the bridge there was fire and smoke, sparks shooting endlessly out of the broken machinery all about the place. Celestials garbed in holy and yet terribly scuffed armors fired at others, with bolter shell and gouts of flamers, but it was their leader who fought Krarg himself. Once pristine armor had been splattered with a mixture of red and black on top of the paint, with blood from a hundred sources and the soot from the flames which filled the ship, while Krarg himself was losing chunks of his own body and armor with each of her wild swinging punches. As the ork stared, stupefied a passing celestial with a power sword in one hand and a bolt pistol in the other slaughtered him. Even so, yet more orks came, attracted to the sound of battle, demanding the attention of almost every sister of battle left alive.

"You iz one big pain in my keister, lady!" Krarg roared, tusks and teeth splattering on the ground after a punch which tore apart the left of his jutting chin.

"Emperor damn you to hell, die already!" Margaret growled, spitting blood from her lips.

Krarg Momentum Reversal: 2
Margaret Counter: 13

A punch missed, slamming into some long-broken and smoking console or another, while Krarg's power klaw discharged its own field on the ground next to the Canoness in a near miss. Margaret slammed her power-armor garbed elbow into the bloodied side of the ork Kaptin, before shoving her flamefist upwards and triggering a blast of flame directly into the open and bellowing maw of Krarg. The ork's resulting roar was transformed into a pained cough and gurgle, the soft tissues within suddenly filled with flame and charred flesh. Even then, the ork did not fall, slamming the side of his massive shoota into her side, cracking the armor further and some bones within besides, but only gained an oath to the Emperor for his troubles.

"GET! OFF! ME! SHIP!" Krarg snarled, each word punctuated with a slam of his power klaw, each barely dodged, each leaving craters in the floor of the thoroughly ruined bridge.

"YOU! FIRST!" Margaret screamed back.

Krarg Killing Blow Attempt: 80
Margaret Killing Blow Attempt: 98

Both fighters, screaming obscenities to their chosen deities, attacked at the same time. No defense was given, no counter attempted. Only every iota of strength and energy remaining in their frames channeled into a final blow. Bolter shells raked across Margaret's front, tearing her armor even further and obliterating ancient purity seals, while a continual blast of flamer outright melted the left half of Krarg's face down to the skull. One fist snapped out, powerfield striking powerfield, and the ork's power klaw exploded. Shrapnel flew, scoring hits across both of their bodies, while the limb within the power klaw was rent to pieces. Another final desperate finger on the trigger sent one further bolter shell into Margaret's shoulder, twisting the whole of her body with the force, before her outstretched right hand struck the blackened and exposed portions of Krarg's skull...and went through. The so-called Supa-Kaptin's eye twitched, managing to glance at the fist and forearm planted in his skull before the flamer burst triggered inside of it. Fire erupted from behind the ork's eye, melting out the eye instantly and spilling out from the nose.

With a wrenching pull and twist, Margaret dragged the corpse aside, all the while blinking rapidly to clear the blood from her eyes only to give it up for a fools game as the cuts on her face and forehead continued to bleed.

"Sound off!" Margaret screamed, her voice ragged.

"Celestian Squad Stands! Four casualties, one fatality. It was Sister Cecilia, Canoness," came the response through the smoke-clogged bridge, the voice loud and exultant despite everything.

"Repentia-7 Stands," another voice came from behind Margaret, this time acidic and reedy. "Four sinners still live, of ten."

"Aquila-4 Stands," a much younger voice, then, the zealotry blazing in the young woman's throat, "Six of us, of ten. Three have ascended to the God-Emperor's side, one will require medical aid."

"Then give it," Margaret grunted, "And if she expires...then she will have died doing the Emperor's work."

The Canoness threw the dead Kaptin further aside as she put her hands upon the ridiculously primitive steering wheel, somehow wired to the entire ship through orkish techno-heresy. Giving it an experimental tug and pull, the blazing vessel groaned and leaned...but in the direction she'd directed. Spitting up another small amount of blood and phlegm, Margaret tossed her head, and squinted through her own blood at the barely functioning tactical map. Once a proud piece of human technology, she could tell, only to have suffered such impossible indignities under orkish hands. And, once again, she saw the symbols upon it. A snarl reached her lips at the sight of so many dead Imperial Navy ships in the water, while a sneer replaced it upon seeing the close presence of so many mutant heretics bearing the garb of space marines. It was one, however, that was larger than any other. And it sat at the center of the formation, methodically blasting out broadsides of lance weaponry.

"There you are..."

Margaret raised one fist, and then slammed it down on the idiotically massive red button sitting just next to the steering wheel - which almost appeared to have been teleported from a primitive world's wooden nautical vessels - and the whole of the burning ship accelerated. Only orks would ensure that the engines worked even in such heavily damaged conditions. Only orks would want their ships to be capable of getting to grips with another enemy ship even in its death throes. It was that which signified just one of the infinite differences between holy humanity and their despicable race. But it was enough. It didn't matter what the ship had been called by the orks, or what it might have been long ago before being transformed into...this.

"May the Emperor's work be done," she murmured before turning around to face her sisters.

"Let us pray to the God-Emperor!"

==========================

Navy Group 1 Fleeing: 73
Navy Group 2 Assault: 100
Greenskin Defensive Posture: 42
Rosetta Ramming: 96
Rosetta Boarding: 80
1st Company Fleet Pushing Through: 85

It is too much, for some of the Imperials at least. Their warp drives spin up, and they are forced to flee. Some of the serfs call them cowards beneath their breath, but you know better. Those men and women were battered from all sides by the xeno, and torn to shreds. Their wills have broken, in this moment, and punishments will likely be handed out to lethal extent. But better that they preserve their ships, valuable as they are, for more worthy crews. Every loss of a battleship and battlecruiser is takes a long, long time to replace. As the shattered remains of the first Navy ships sent here warp out, the ships which accompanied your forces to Greenkrump finally arrive.

Their fury is made manifest. While the Overlord-class battlecruisers are not full battleships, their lance weaponry is highly powered enough to pierce the hulls of many an ork vessel. Floods of attack craft swarm out from the various carrier vessels amongst the Imperial fleet, a hundred bombing runs each tearing apart their smaller attack ships. Weapons emplacements along their larger vessels are reduced to slag, before the ships themselves are shorn to pieces by the close-range weaponry of the 1st Company’s fleet. Reports bark out from returning boarding teams, reactors detonated and crews slaughtered in ship to ship as they are driven from place to place within Thunderhawks or drop pod assaults.

“Chapter Master, the ship that the Lost Rosetta boarded, look!!” Apollo points at the ship in question.

As you watch, upon the tactical map the projection signifying the boarded hammer battlekroozer of which more appears to be on fire than is not, somehow, shoots forward of its own accord. The rest of the ships which fled from Greenkrump are almost all destroyed, save for that last vessel. But instead of charging towards one of your own ships or that of the Imperial Navy in some suicidal last ramming attack – something of which the Librarius has spoken of before – it heads directly for the Apocalypse-class battleship which sits at the center of the orkish formation. Even as the ship begins its death throes, the damage it has sustained clearly too much for prolonged existence, it approaches and slams into the side of the battleship, breaking void shields and hull in equal measure. A great amount of open cracks are rent open in the side of the ship, spinning it slightly on sheer momentum and removing the danger of its lance broadsides temporarily, while dozens of orkish boarding pods are noted by auspex scans to be flying directly into the breaches opened.

And then the battlekroozer explodes, signifying the end of every ork ship that had originally taken Greenkrump.

“I think…that these Sororitas…may be insane,” Apollo slowly says, staring at the tactical map and the sudden chaos that has ensued as the orks register that their flagship is under assault.

“They are merely dedicated to their service to the Emperor,” is Hannibals rebuttal.

Even so. You can feel it…that this is all coming to a head. The orks are all here. While the Navy is embattled, the battle has yet to truly be decided just yet. There is no time to call in the ships of the 4th Company, or those of the other Imperial Navy that were left across the system. Not truly, when the battle can be brought to an end here and now. And it is the Sororitas which have given you the opportunity. The rippling destruction caused by their open usage of an orkish vessel against what was once in human hands has created openings. The void shields are broken, the hull ripped asunder in the bow. Here, now, this can end.

“Close-range sensor readings have confirmed!” another serf speaks out, drawing your attention, his voice almost childishly exited. “That kroozer, there…its signature is that of a true strike cruiser! I cannot tell the heraldry, but it is a strike cruiser!”

The starship in question is highlighted upon the tactical map, and the desire for it burns like a small flame in your heart. So much of the Chapter’s fleet was destroyed in the Purge…the chance to rebuild it is certainly a valuable one. At the same time…dangerous. As the Navy continues in its movements, the danger is that it will be destroyed, more likely than not. Seeing their fellows so badly slaughtered means that if you do not take action that not only will it be lost, but so too likely will the other former Imperial ships.

Unless.

Unless you can oust the orks from the critical systems, and hold the ships against their greenskin masters. Unlike with normal ork ships, you know where the various control systems are for the vessels, where critical points for control are. If you can reclaim them for humanity, rather than have them be destroyed...

At the same time, it would be that much riskier, that much more dangerous for every space marine you send. Success could just as easily be bought, however, if you let their destruction go through. Easier, in fact, and with far less danger to the lives of the Chapter, limited as they so very much are.

Stage 2 Theater Results:
Greenkrump Ork Fleet Destroyed/Fled To Spinesnap.
Order Of Lost Rosetta Exited Greenkrump Battlefield On Ork Ships.
Greenkrump Imperial Guard Sustained Moderate Casualties.
--------
Shinehole Tunnels 45% Cleared.
Significant Imperial Presence In ‘Shinehole Loot Piles’ Noted.
Shinehole Ork Leader Remains Unknown.
Notable Imperial Guard Casualties On Shinehole.
No Blood Raven Casualties Taken On Shinehole.
2 Power Axes Recovered.
3 Plasma Cannons Recovered.
1 Multi-Melta Recovered.
------
Dustboom
Multiple Dustboom Ork Vehicle Formations Destroyed.
Multiple Stompas and Deff Dreads Destroyed.
Imperial Guard Casualties Middling.
No Blood Raven Casualties Taken.
4 Total Space Marine Predator Wrecks Recovered From Ork Hands. Condition Critical For All. Repair May Be Possible.
Mekboss Killdakka's Workshop Hunt Now Underway By Imperial Guard.
Dustboom Orbital Guns Now Heavily Exposed.
-------
Supa-Kaptin Krarg (Blood Axes) Dead Over Spinesnap.
Spinesnap Ork Fleet Workshops Confirmed!
Large Amount Of Imperial Navy Ships Forced To Flee Into Warp, Sustained Extreme Casualties!
Order Of Lost Rosetta Have Boarded Bonebreaka's Flagship!
Strike Cruiser Hull Identified Within Ork Fleet! Reclamation May Be Possible!
Bonebreaka's Flagship Has Sustained Breach In Bow! Void Shields And Point Defenses Offline In Breach Area!

Spoiler: Known Naval Presences Across System

Greenkrump
- 1 Lunar-class Cruiser
- 6 Escorts (x2 Cobra, x3 Sword)
- 2 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Dustboom
- 3 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 4 Escorts (x3 Firestorm, x1 Cobra)
- 4 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Spinesnap
- 3 Looted Battleships (x1 Retribution-class, x1 Oberon-class, x1 Apocalypse-class [Flagship Vessel])
- 1 Ork ‘Battleship’
- 3 Looted Battlecruisers (x2 Overlord-class, x1 Mars-class)
- 7 Kill Kroozers [Strike Cruiser Hull Confirmed As One Kill Kroozer]
- 5 Onslaught Attack Ships, 2 Terror Ships
vs.
- 1 Overlord-class Battlecruiser
- 5 Dictator-class Cruisers
- 7 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 15 Escorts (x7 Cobra, x3 Sword, x5 Firestorm)
- 1st Company Fleet

Shinehole
- 3 Universe-class Mass Conveyors
- 4th Company Fleet

Location Unknown, Fled Into Warp
- 1 Emperor-class Battleship
- 1 Overlord Battlecruiser
- 1 Lunar-class Cruiser
- 3 Escorts (x3 Firestorm)

Current Plans For Stage Three Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One/Do Not Need To Select Every One]:
(No Time To Transmit New Orders To 4th Fleet Or 4th Company! Said Groups Will Continue With Previous Orders)

Shinehole Void Combat
[] Let Them Die: You cannot risk your brothers lives needlessly. Attempting to force boarding and capturing of the various looted Imperial vessels, even to reclaim them for the use of the Imperium, will most certainly cost lives. Potentially many, depending on how many orks yet live on those ships. Allow the Imperial Navy to take its due from the orks, and while it may sting to see so many ships go blasted into the void, at least it will be alongside the deaths of their xeno crews. The loss of a potential strike cruiser will be a great one, but how much worth can a single ship be, compared to the lives of the veterans of the 1st Company who might be lost taking it? Perhaps if the Chapter was not on the brink of extinction, but it is.
OR
[] Take The Risk: Bonebreaka is there, on that ship. An Apocalypse-class Battleship is an incredibly powerful vessel, capable of full lance broadsides. A vast boon to the Imperial Navy if reclaimed for their purposes. In truth, that goes for all of the ships yet remaining. Especially considering the casualties that the Navy has taken in this battle. Each one reclaimed would be a great aid to them, for while smaller escort vessels and lunar cruisers can be built anew, it takes a great amount of resources to replace entire battlecruisers and battleships. Not to mention, the chance to reclaim a strike cruiser for the Chapter, away from ork hands? That alone could vastly improve the capabilities of any of your Chapter's fleets. It will be hard fought, but victory if won would be quite valuable indeed. If you can just get the guns off line on many of these ships, the Navy will be able to crush the rest of the ork ships and add their own boarding ships to the fight! But only if you can board and successfully assault the enemy positions within these ships. If your forces take too long, however, then that means Navy ships will likely be destroyed as they try to hold off. Or, worse, they go forward and attack the ships with your brothers on them.
-[] Looted Apocalypse-class Battleship [Flagship Vessel] (Hundreds of Adeptas Sororitas of the Order of the Lost Rosetta Present, Precise Location Unknown) (Bow of Vessel Exposed, No Void Shields/Point Defenses)
-[] Looted Retribution-class Battleship
-[] Looted Oberon-class Battleship
-[] Looted Overlord-class Battlecruiser
-[] Looted Overlord-class Battlecruiser
-[] Looted Mars-class Battlecruiser
-[] Looted Strike Cruiser Boarding And Reclamation - The orkish kill kroozers are being winnowed down at speed by the vengeful Navy. If you are going to reclaim the ship, it will have to be done fast, especially to reclaim the vital systems and thus remove the need for its destruction. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
OR
[] Something Else: (Write-In)

GM Note: IF the option to try to reclaim is selected, I've put in links. The links are to the pages of the ships in question. You may wish to review them to think about what resources should be allocated to reclaiming them based on what capabilities they have/what they could contribute to the Imperium if recaptured.

====================================================

Citadel A Assault Force vs. Ork Defenders
73 vs. 19

When the first whirlwind barrage arrived, the orks didn’t know what to think. They had heard of the explosions, some had even fled from across ‘Da Green Wurld’ to the ‘Fight Place’, but that was fire from the skies. Here, well, it was fire from the skies again but different at the same time. Regardless, towers collapsed on the outskirts of the perimeter defenses, grots and squigs bounding about found themselves squashed and turned to pulp on the treads of a land raider, while heavy bolters began to tear into the greenskins as they turned and charged. There were, for once, enough of them to actually reach the vehicles of the interlopers, but not enough to kill those who walked with them. At their head marched a helmeted one, yet it was obvious by how all deferred to him, a bolter booming in his hands.

“Do not ever underestimate the enemy, brothers, but bring them death all the same!” Tarkus called out.

Slowly, methodically, the 5th Company and its many vehicle attendants ground down the citadel and its defenders, until by the end the orks who had been so sure of a true and final victory over the entire world, were dead or gone.

Citadel B Bombing
43! Major targets not destroyed.

The orks were capable of learning, of course. They did so now. When the thunderhawks arrived over the vast pens of the enemy, they transmitted images of emptied cages. The largest of their targets, the Orkeosaurus, had been pushed into the concealing canopy of the jungle itself, and while the various structures themselves were destroyed, a great many of squiggoths had disappeared. Squigs were burned in their thousands by the bombs, true, and a few trainers still remained to be killed. Unfortunately, the truth of the matter is that the orks have fled into their jungle, and more concentrated searching will have to be done to find them, even with auspex scanning.

Citadel C Assault Force vs. Ork Defenders
66 vs. 11

“Report, scout,” Cyrus grunted as he pored over the maps of the area, both that of their own orbital scans and what the locals had painstakingly crafted over time.

“Yes, Captain,” the scout sergeant saluted. “It was as you suspected. When we detonated a large amount of explosives in the center of the camp, the orks began to emerge from the jungle and charge into the plateau. If we had attacked with a large force, we would have been surrounded upon taking the center – and possibly overwhelmed.”

“Hmph. How did your squads do?”

“Well enough. Enemy leaders killed, chaos taken advantage of, grenades amongst larger groups where a long-range and clear shot cannot be made…though they could use a bit more steel in their spines, yet.”

“Very well.”

Cyrus nodded, but did not lift his gaze from the maps.

Stage 2 Trontiux III Results

Citadel A: Completely destroyed, orks slain or fled into the jungles. Zero casualties.
Citadel B: Multiple squiggoths and single Orkeosaurus gone from Citadel B, location currently unknown!
Citadel C: Ork ambush attempt dismantled, defeated. Citadel C retaken.
Ork Warboss location and identity remains unknown!
Black Archipelago remains under ork control.
Orks from Pacemen continue to cross Black Archipelago!
4 Scouts [1st Stage] Injured At Citadel C, Will Be Healed By End Of Next Stage!

Current Plans For Stage Three Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One]:

Petramis:
[] Continued Culling - Orks still teem within the jungles, despite your efforts. A continuous and concerted effort will be required to properly cull them. The bloody work must continue. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
[] A Most Dangerous Game - The Orkeosaurus and multiple squiggoths have escaped into the jungle. If left without prevention, it is completely unknown what they might do, from remain hidden, attacking a citadel-city, or even going after the Black Archipelago to escape to Pacemen. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

Black Archipelago:
[] Take And Hold - From the skies, rain down destruction upon the various bridges connecting the islands and continents, and then deliver drop pods amongst the islands to scourge them of the greenskins upon them. In this manner, this vital choke-point between the two continents can be defended, potentially reinforced, and allow the feudal humans a way to strike back in the future. Just as well, fortifications built upon these islands will ensure that the orks will have a visible target to attack, and thus to die against. With the sheer damage dealt to Pacemen, many orks are fleeing across the Black Archipelago to get over to Petramis. This will mean that taking and holding the islands will be notably more difficult, by sheer numbers if nothing else. [Write-In Forces Contributed To This Action]
[] Obliteration - For too long has the Black Archipelago provided a passage point for the orks to arrive in Petramis. It must be dealt with, and here there is no worry of catastrophic geological damage. Initiate continual orbital bombardment and burn these islands out of existence. In the future, it will require that the orks travel to Petramis by sea, and there will be no main central funnel for them to travel across meaning that their arrivals would be more spread out, but in the immediate moment this will greatly aid in the current culling of the orks. The people of the world can adapt to the circumstances later on, with a hopefully much reduced orkish population. Black Archipelago destroyed. Orks will require alternate passage to arrive on Petramis in the future.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

Pacemen
[] Fear The Skies - Every major settlement and base has been destroyed by this point, their breeding grounds brought to ruin. However, plenty of orks remain here, either trying to put out the fires raging across the jungle or heading across the Black Archipelago. Those that remain must be killed as well. This is not merely a push back against the orks here. No. This is a culling! Besides which, the Black Archipelago could only sustain light orbital bombardment before collapsing, and enough has been said about the certain side-effects to Petramis as well. Here, the ships can continue to fire.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

Turn 19 (Part Four): By Duty, Bring Death

Spoiler: Reclaim What Is Our's

[X] Plan: Reclaim What Is Our's

Shinehole Void Combat
-[X] Take The Risk
--[X] Looted Apocalypse-class Battleship
---[X] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chapter Master's Honor Guard
--[X] Looted Retribution-class Battleship
---[X] 1st Company
----[X] If they haven't been destroyed by the time either ship has been reclaimed, forces from the reclaimed ship are to move reclaim the any remaining ships in following order: Strike Cruiser -> Oberon-class Battleship -> Overlord-class Battlecruiser -> Overlord-class Battlecruiser -> Mars-class Battlecruiser

Petramis
-[X] A Most Dangerous Game - The Orkeosaurus and multiple squiggoths have escaped into the jungle. If left without prevention, it is completely unknown what they might do, from remain hidden, attacking a citadel-city, or even going after the Black Archipelago to escape to Pacemen.
--[X] 10th Company, all Thunderhawk gunships
---[X] The primary mission for the 10th company is to locate and destroy the remaining Orkeosaurus and all squiggoths, preferably by locating them and giving bombing and assault coordinates for Thunderhawks.
Black Archipelago:
-[X] Take And Hold - From the skies, rain down destruction upon the various bridges connecting the islands and continents, and then deliver drop pods amongst the islands to scourge them of the greenskins upon them. In this manner, this vital choke-point between the two continents can be defended, potentially reinforced, and allow the feudal humans a way to strike back in the future. Just as well, fortifications built upon these islands will ensure that the orks will have a visible target to attack, and thus to die against. With the sheer damage dealt to Pacemen, many orks are fleeing across the Black Archipelago to get over to Petramis. This will mean that taking and holding the islands will be notably more difficult, by sheer numbers if nothing else.
--[X] 5th Company
--[X] Land Raider Crusader Tarantulus Ultima
--[X] 6 Razorbacks (Standard Twin-Linked Heavy Bolter)
--[X] 1 Razorbacks (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons)
--[X] 2 Whirlwinds
--[X] Predator
--[X] 3 Land Speeders (Standard)
--[X] 2 Land Speeders (Tempest)
--[X] 13 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Twin-Linked Heavy Bolters)
--[X] 13 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Twin-Linked Lascannons)
--[X] 8 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons)
--[X] 5 Tarantula Sentry Gun (Multi-Melta)
Pacemen
-[X] Fear The Skies - Every major settlement and base has been destroyed by this point, their breeding grounds brought to ruin. However, plenty of orks remain here, either trying to put out the fires raging across the jungle or heading across the Black Archipelago. Those that remain must be killed as well. This is not merely a push back against the orks here. No. This is a culling! Besides which, the Black Archipelago could only sustain light orbital bombardment before collapsing, and enough has been said about the certain side-effects to Petramis as well. Here, the ships can continue to fire.
---[X] Fleets are to conduct bombardments on any large concentrations of orks and ork structures

By Duty, Bring Death
+030.M42+ To +035.M42+
+Pain Now! Reward In The Afterlife!+

When you reveal your plan to the forces of the Navy, their response is remarkably unified.

“You want to what?! Are you mad, Blood Raven!?” one rear admiral shouts, a sentiment echoed by many others.

“Would not these ships be a boon for your forces if properly reclaimed?” you respond while marching towards the breaching torpedoes.

“Obviously, but the issue is, space marine, is that we might as well all die before you finish your work! Losing ships to take ships is a losing proposition!”

You hear a sigh from Apollo, listening in as you moved, as he takes his position within the torpedo along with the rest of the Honor Guard. Doukas and the rest of his squad begin to murmur a litany to the Emperor.

“We are not assaulting all of them at once, and are forwarding you our list of priority targets in the case of success.”

You do not know which one of the captains speaks next, but his words do make you narrow your eyes.

“I will not be held responsible for your deaths if you take this course of action. If a ship explodes with your space marines on it…”

“We are aware of the danger, captain. Now, if you will excuse us,” you switch off the comm array and join in with Doukas and Hannibal.

A great resounding set of booms signifies the steady launching of the breaching torpedoes, while elsewhere across the Chapter Fleet thunderhawks lift off from their bays and rocket into the void. The set of booms come closer, closer, until finally you feel the one you have taken for yourself rumble in a screech and thump as you leave the Omnia Arcanum behind.

“Torpedoes engaged. Emperor be with you, Chapter Master,” Martellus broadcasts, before you are set out of range.

Navy Encirclement: 57
1st Company Boarding Operations: 96
Boarding Torpedo Command-Primaris: 4

A sudden ‘clang’ is the only warning that something has gone wrong before the entire torpedo is struck by some outside force. Whether a piece of scrap, another ship, or something else, you do not know. What you do know is that all of a sudden the innards of the boarding torpedo are exposed to the open void, a vast rent torn in it right down the side. Blinding lights from the intense close-range void combat going on shine on you in a wildly changing kaleidoscope, while a dozen different warning klaxons attempt to screech out their words while the atmosphere is vented.

The Hand Of Gravity
23! 2 Honor Guard Marines Lost To Void!

“Emperor’s Blood!” Doukas swears at the sudden visceral careening.

Swirling at high enough speeds to flatten an unenhanced heart, you can do nothing more than cry out in outrage as two of the honor guard are sucked out of the torpedo by sheer velocity and damage done to their restraints. They do not even manage to speak a word before they are left entirely out of immediate suit-to-suit vox range, and all sight of them disappears immediately as the torpedo careens wildly, its original course lost entirely.

“Warning. Original trajectory unviable. Heavy damage sustained,” the logic-engine placidly informs you, as if you were not entirely unmoored in the void. “Attempting to reach secondary breaching point.”

Reorienting Rockets: 49
1st Company Critical System Targeting: 76

Several flaring blasts of fire herald the slowing of the torpedoes wild rotations, but cannot stop them. After a few more tense seconds the glow of a rocket that you can in fact still see through the tear in the hull of the torpedo explodes soon after. A muted burst, sound gone now that the atmosphere has fully vented, is all that marks its passage save for a shake that is near indistinguishable from the general shuddering that has taken hole of the entire torpedo. All the while, Hannibal booms out a litany of faith and strength, a nearby explosion in the void shaking the torpedo further off course.

========================

Lost Rosetta Boarders vs. Ork Defenders
98 vs. 48

An entire squad of nods thudded their way into the vast chamber. Whatever it might have been, a vast mess hall for the crew or the menials which once languished in its depths, it was now a charnel-filled battlefield. Margaret leapt over a rusted metal slab that might once have been a table, hand snapping out to grasp around the massive horns on the helmet of one of the nobs, before slamming her free fist into the back of its neck to explosively decapitate it. From around the bend of a fallen and flaming penitent engine, its pilot butchered, a howling mass of sisters repentia came, their blades held high. The impact was as brutal and vicious as the orks could ever desire, with screaming death-seekers clashing against ones who desired only battle.

Pausing to catch her breath, Margaret straightened and let loose a gout of flame into the face of an ork commando as he leapt out of the shadows to try and stab her. Purple paint and flesh peeled away in equal measure beneath the flames, the Canoness Superior stomping onto the blazing ork’s throat and then bringing both fists down in a hammer blow upon its skull. High above, flying recklessly, came the seraphim, their jump packs as twin stars on their backs with pistols booming out upon the orks below. Steadily, the orks were driven back, not by cowardice or tactical retreat, but by simple fact that too many of them were dead to hold their positions.

One, a large mega nob, died trying to fight against such fortune, and for its trouble found Margaret climbing over its corpse to point at the dying orks who hunched ever more by their primitive barricades, haloed by the flames of the dead and dying.

“FORWAAAAAAAAAARD!” she screamed. “IN THE EMPEROR’S NAME!”

======================

“Secondary breaching point unviable. Attempting to reach tertiary breaching point.”

The torpedo still swung wildly back and forth in the void, but no longer was it without a general direction to its movements. By this point, all helmets had been fully secured, the inner atmosphere gone completely. What rockets remained were still firing, though far more had been destroyed that remained. You had heard nothing of the two honor guard who had been dragged out by the explosive decompression, but hopefully they possessed their helms locked in place. If that fails…well, there are other things that the Emperor’s grace granted your kind for such events. At the least, this specific machine spirit deserves recovery and placations from Martellus once this is over…if it survives.

Tertiary Breaching Attempt: 77

From one instant to the next, your sight out of the torn hole in the side of the torpedo is obscured by the scarred and rusted alloys of an Imperial ship. From one eye-blink to the next, you see a statue of the Emperor himself that has been utterly desecrated in the images of the greenskin gods. Then, the torpedo fulfills its function, the blazing plasma ignited at the front of the torpedo smashes directly through another weakened piece of hull. The void shield around this section had been knocked down, briefly, by some ships fire or another, allowing you to progress forward. The sudden re-introduction of atmosphere fills your ears with screaming metal being torn asunder to make way for you, before the torpedo comes to a very violent smashing stop.

“Well.” Hannibal stands immediately, his crozius held in hand as he kicks open the dented and torn exit door from its hinges, “Let us get to work.”

“Does anyone have a reading on our position?” you ask while exiting the heavily damaged torpedo. “Are we near the Lost Rosetta, any of them? Or a critical system?”

Apollo manages to salvage a data-slate connected to the boarding torpedo’s not quiet logic-engine, and curses.

“We’re nowhere near the bridge, but…we are near the engines. We could shut them down, prevent the ship from escaping.”

“It will do, for now,” you grunt before hefting Godsplitter on your shoulder. “Let us move!”

============================

1st Company Progression: 64

“Get the wounded to the thunderhawk!”

They called him The Scarred, and it was an apropos term for him. Once, a meagre simple marine, nowhere near deserving of the title of Captain. Much less Captain of the 1st Company. But phosphex burned all things, including weakness and naiveté away. Now, he stood, a bulwark in front of his fallen brothers as they defended the shredded gun consoles. With each blast of his graviton pistol, whole portions of the corridor twisted and shunted about, crushing and impaling the orks that attempted to charge through. Those that managed to make it through were met with his blade, the powerfield shearing through them like a scythe to wheat. A dozen heavy slugs slammed into his armor, cracking the ceramite, and he stood unbowed.

If it had been just one squad, attempting to shift here and there about an entire ship filled with the enemy, then this would have taken longer. But this was no single squad, as was more typical in ship-to-ship engagements. This was an entire company, and the 1st at that. Marcus fired again and again as the orks as they came, a roaring mega nob’s massive set or armor turned against it, the flesh within being crushed by what should have protected it. Around him, the rest of the 1st Company fought, leaving boarding torpedoes behind on their way to the thunderhawks that had come in the breaches behind them.

1st Company Withdrawal: 80

“Detonate the charges,” he boomed before leaping into a charging mob of orks, Wisdom flashing back and forth as he fought. “Move on to the thunderhawks!”

Fighting every step of the way, the 1st Company withdrew leaving a series of rippling explosions in their wake. Much of the ship was damaged in the wake of their work, but the superstructure itself remained viable. Finally, Marcus stepped back, just within the lip of the thunderhawk ramp while it lifted off, blazing out into the stars above, leaving the battleship behind it entirely. Tactical information routed itself to the Captain’s helm, of the sudden deadening of the ship they left behind, as well as the fact that two extremely enterprising lunar cruisers had come close, ships flying out of them as they sent armsmen into the depths of the now gun-less and shield-less ship.

“Captain,” the serf in the pilot’s seat greeted as he approached, “Next target?”

“The strike cruiser,” Marcus pointed his finger at where it sat, hanging remarkably still compared to all the other ork ships around it.

Navy vs. Ork Fleet
20 vs. 9

He then had to shield his eyes from the sight before him as light erupted out of the kill kroozer’s prow, scrap metal that had been haphazardly added to its front shaking off with the exertion. The shot went wide, thankfully, and while the Navy continued its own advance with many a weapon targeting the ramshackle and fully orkish ‘battleship, the thunderhawks of the 1st Company flew forward. After all, it was a strike cruiser despite all the orks had done to it. Still….

“Was that from a lance?” Hamul questioned from behind them.

“…I think it was.”

1st Company Boarding Strike Cruiser Target: 85

“Point-defense guns near the hangar are either firing uselessly in the direction of the Navy’s ships from far out of range, or completely rusted over, Captain,” the serf called out, eyes flicking back and forth along the screens available to him.

“Then take us in.”

“Yes, Captain!”

Ironic. There were few vessels that a space marine might know how to disable better than a strike cruiser. And here, now, that was exactly what they were planning to do. Behind him, on the ground of the troop compartment, Constantius finally rose, his arms bloodied from the treatments demanded to preserve the lives of his brothers.

“Brothers Tariq and Theral are dead. I have recovered their gene-seed,” he finally said, his voice low. “They will be remembered as the Emperor’s Finest.”

“Indeed, brother,” Marcus placed a hand on his brother’s pauldron, rocking the white-armored marine slightly. “Stay strong yet. We are not done.”

“I know.”

The serf’s voice was broadcast, now, to all on the thunderhawk flight.

“Get ready! We’re entering the hangar now!”

Marcus nodded, and marched towards the end of the compartment, standing directly before the ramp. The thunderhawks began to tremble, their whole frames moving as their unleashed the weaponry they possessed to clear the hangar as completely as possible. Only once that was done did they open their ramps, allowing the Blood Ravens within to leap out and charge forth into the corridors of the ship.

“NONE SHALL FIND US WANTING!”

1st Company Kroozer Clearing: 82

=======================

Dustboom Combat (1)
Imperial Guard Orbitals Assault: 20
Ork Orbitals Defense: 56
Ork Vehicles: 12
Blood Raven Crushing: 99

Atop the Litany of Purgation, the Captain of the 4th Company surveyed the newest graveyard that his forces had wrought from the hands of the greenskins. A hundred burning vehicles, from small wartrukks to battlewagons to three full gunfortresses had been brought low, surrounded, and turned to so much slag. The 4th Company itself was busy spread out across the entire place, accompanied by techpriests on their cataloguing efforts. Once, then twice, did a squad return, dragging a particular hulk behind them as a techpriest stood atop it or near it, wringing their mechadendrites.

“Report, Chaplain,” Hadrian barked as he faced the wasteland, smoke and dust mixing equally in the air making it nearly impossible for the naked eye to manage much.

Behind him, Ateren consulted the data-slate and the information compiled within.

“Three viable rhino hulks, what might be five assault bikes forcibly fused together into one overly massive motorcycle of some sort, and one whirlwind that had been on top of a gunfortress as a weapons emplacement have been recused back into the care of the Company. The Guard will be having much more fortune here. From what I could hear from the muttering techpriests there are multiple Leman Russ tanks that were in the hands of the enemy,” the chaplain recited quietly.

“They do seem to favor those amongst their looted weaponry,” Hadrian mused. “How goes their assault on the orbital guns?”

“Badly.”

Hadrian raised an eyebrow and paused for a moment before realizing that Ateren could not actually see his face and turned about.

“Explain.”

“The orks at one of the major guns unveiled the pet project of the mek in charge of the place. It was one of their battlefortresses – specifically of the ‘Skullhamma’ variety – and it tore much of their initial vanguard to pieces.”

“Another baneblade, gone into the hands of the xeno. Does the Mechanicus not keep precise records of each of those venerable machines?” Hadrian mused, eyes unblinking as he looked down at the chaplain.

“They do, and I believe they were making quite the noise about the Guard doing as little harm to it as possible while disabling it, otherwise they won’t be able to check the records properly.”

Hadrian grunted, before lifting his eyes to the sky again.

“Did they at least keep their anti-air back? I’m getting tired of those buzzing runs that they keep trying to pull off.”

“They did, and are marshalling for another assault as we speak.”

“Mmmph.”

But they had waited there long enough, and once it was confirmed all else remaining would either be reclaimed for the Guard’s purposes or were totally unviable, there was no point in remaining. Hadrian stood, and around him the rest of the 4th Company assembled together once more, driving back into the whirlwind of battle across the scrap wasteland of Dustboom.

============================

Shinehole Tunnel Pushing (1)
Imperial Guard Attackers: 74
Ork Defenders: 29
Blood Raven Attackers: 12

“Cover me, Calus!” Daedal yelled, leaping from his rapier as he did so.

In the center of the tunnel, the smoking ruin of the dreadnought was riddled with further fire, enough volume behind it that it tipped over completely onto its back. Throughout the rest of the large cavern, the Imperial Guard were charging forward, and bravely so, but they had come later than hoped. The dreadnought smoked and hissed as Daedal’s mechadendrites went to work on it, further tools pulled from his servo-harness in his hands as he did everything in his capacity to repair the dreadnought, and if failing that to preserve the life within.

“Hold on, hold on,” he hissed, sparks flying before him, “Please endeavor to do your best to not die, brother.”

Dreadnought Occupant Preservation: 51

“Okay, the overall shell is blasted to the warp, muscle-sheathes slagged,” he muttered beneath his breath, before a final plunge of his mechadendrites into the holes pierced into the hull resulted in a faint whining noise as the life-preserving sarcophagus within restarted.

Behind the techpriest, the Guard advanced, their commissars leading the way, but Daedal only had eyes for the elder one. Calus approached, his rapier set on sentry mode, and without speaking the two of them went about their work.

Dreadnought Repair: 20

“It can’t be done,” Daedal finally said as he stood back. “The overall structural integrity is ruined. I am sorry, brother,” he tapped the smoking hull, “But it seems you will have to get a new one.”

“He can’t respond you know,” Calus called out as he began walking back to his rapier. “The broadcasting vox was shredded. All he can do is hear.”

Daedal exhaled forcefully, turning to his brother techmarine with his hands on his hips.

“I know that, and you know that, but the point is that I am reassuring our venerable brother here that he will possess another body soon enough.”

“I think I got that, yes,” Calus’ dry voice was audible above his re-engaging rapier as it trundled forward.

“Then why did you feel a need to bring it up!?”

“Oh, dear me, I apologize, we are under an Oath of Silence, aren’t we, how could I – oh wait, we’re not!”

Daedal looked about, and, upon sighting a lasgun which had fallen out of the nearest pile of ill-begotten ork loot grabbed up the old weapon and threw it directly at Calus’ head. Unfortunately it instead hit one of his mechadendrites, and the ancient rotted wood of the weapon practically evaporated as it struck the device. Calus, in turn, steadfastly ignored his compatriot, and drove his rapier forward.

“We’ll have you back onto the ships soon enough, brother,” Daedal finally said, reassuringly tapping the shell, before getting onto his own rapier.

A series of thumping noises marked the arrival of another of the 1st Company’s dreadnoughts, who paused at the sight of his brother in half-death’s state.

“What happened here?”

“Do not worry, Brother Cassius, Brother Relian’s dreadnought was disabled, but he lives within. I will join the push, and then return to oversee his transport back to the ships.”

Then Daedal was speeding ahead, leaving one dreadnought to stare at the other.

“You know. It’s running into enemy fire like that which is why you are in a dreadnought at all, Relian.”

In a stunning display of still-active machinery despite everything, the dreadnought managed to raise one of its assault claws and flex it in vaguely rude fashion if one squinted and replaced the metal claw with a human hand.

“Such pique does you a disservice.”

================================

Engine Room Attackers vs. Engine Room Defenders
61 vs. 60

“We are getting nowhere, here,” Doukas grits his teeth, popping up to fire at the entrenched orks at the engine room.

Somewhere within was mek in charge of the engines of the vessel. You had seen him, in fact. But that was before he retreated before your assault, calling up his guards and blasphemous ork machinery to defend against your push. For every ork or machine you broke, another arrived from the various pathways hacked into the ship’s innards. Occasionally orks appeared from behind you, ensuring that you could not even properly set up a field of fire against the enemy. Hannibal, in this very instant, was dealing with such a rear assault, as the ork crew of the ship advanced in the direction of the sound of a good fight.

Push vs. Pushback
22 vs. 24

Time stretches on, and barely any progress is made. You advance past two barricades, before appropriated lascannons nearly cut you in half despite your armor. Hannibal strides forth, and is brought low, suffering dozens of minor wounds as he is overwhelmed by enemy fire. Bolter shells boom into the skulls of the enemy, striking down one minor mek as it attempts to lob forth some arcane xenos device which explodes amongst their own ranks. But despite the bodies piling up and the various wounds accumulating, you have not pushed forward much at all. It is more than a little frustrating. It is outright enraging.

Aggression vs. Aggression
66 vs. 94

It is the orks that charge, just when you were planning to. A great horde of them bursts from the engine room, and in but a moment they are upon you. Their leader, an ork more cybernetics than flesh, batters aside one of the honor guard with a fiery power klaw, cutting the marine in half entirely and sending the pieces flying. Laughing as it does so, it advances upon you, lighting sparking off of its armor in bizarre shapes and sizes. Around you, the rest of your brothers are similarly engaged, if not by individuals than the great mob.

“You fink you ken come on our ship? NUFFIN’ DOIN’, BEAKY!” it bellows, spittle flying from a mostly metal jaw.

“It was the Imperium’s once, beast. And it will be again,” you growl, lifting Godsplitter high.

Blow For Blow
69 vs. 70
Gabriel Angelos vs. Mecha-Nob
76 vs. 56

It’s first swing misses, a single step backwards taking out just barely out of range. The force behind the blow was considerable, however, allowing you to take advantage of a sudden stumbling step to slam your hammer into its arm, shattering the bone and metal in equal measure. The ork roars, stumbling backward before pointing its other arm – this one replaced with a good many guns at once – and begins firing wildly, spitting brass out on the floor.

Fighting Off Mobs
50 vs. 51
Gabriel Angelos vs. Mecha-Nob
87 vs. 44

The shots pass harmlessly upon your armor, leaving nothing more than superficial damage. You, on the other hand, use the time to close the distance and manage a massive upright swing of Godsplitter into the ork’s chin, snapping their head backwards and forcing the body to be lifted off the ground entirely for a brief second before falling down once more. Much of its spiked metal jaw replacement was crushed to scrap, the bone beneath now exposed to open air. Growling, it gets up to its feet at a speed that is high in excess of what such a bulk should normally be capable of.

“Oh I iz gonna have fun guttin’ you!”

Ongoing Struggle
17 vs. 13
Gabriel Angelos vs. Mecha-Nob
94 vs. 2

You do not gut your opponent, but you do obliterate his insides as you plant Godsplitter into its stomach again and again, until a great blast erupts from its back with your hammer’s head poking out the other end. The ork stumbles forward, struggling to swing at you one more time with one more insult dribbling out of its broken face, before you end it with another swing against the top of its head, bringing the entire body down with the strike. That, of course, ends it, before you turn to the rest of the fighting.

Leader Slain: 10

At the sight of their leader so conclusively slain, the orks scatter. Even the ones who had been winning their fights take to running, where they are gunned down in the back. Wounds aplenty, though none of your brothers have died just yet – save perhaps for the two who were lost to the void. Even so, as this goes on, even those of the honor guard cannot simply go on without aid. It is fortunate, then, that Falkor Ryll was not torn out of the boarding torpedo and can go about his own work while the rest of your brothers accompany you into the engine room.

“The cowardly mek fled, Angelos,” Hannibal reports to you as you set about sabotaging the engines.

At the least, this ship will not be allowed to flee. Bonebreaka will be trapped here.

============================

Penitent Engines vs. Deff Dreads
28 vs. 2

“Die! Die! Die!”

“AHHHHHHHHHH!”

Across the corridor the machines clashed, each with their pilots fused forever with their machines, each slamming into one another. Purity seals flapped upon chainfists as they grappled just beneath spinning sawblades daubed in greenskin paints. The ork within one deff dread was cooked within his machine, even as the penitent engine’s insane dribbling pilot stomped over it, heading endlessly towards the next target. Amidst the feet of the small giants ran orks and sisters of battle alike, firing towards one another with whatever weapon they could find.

Forward Push
62 vs. 15

Bereft of enough height to fly, the seraphim instead stalked forward, bolt pistols booming one after another. Around them came squads of sororitas, plasma guns and flamers bursting again and again. The heavy bolters held in the hands of some were of especially potent use, shredding cackling gretchin who leapt upon the deff dreads to try and effect repairs. Others, like the celestian squad, had grouped together in a tight formation that brought death to each and every target they sighted. Ahead of them all, the Canoness Superior brought her fists against the legs of another deff dread, bringing it low before angrily tearing open the casing to reveal the ork who had been wired in the machine. The ork died screaming.

In an image that would be recorded in the annals of the Order, regardless of whether she lived by the end of the battle or not, would be of Margaret Tenenbaum rising up from the body of the thoroughly destroyed deff dread, utterly drenched in red. Like the Patron Saint Mina, for whom their parent Order of the Bloody Rose had been formed, the Canoness was utterly painted red by the blood of her enemies. Around her, the blood of the xeno had thoroughly coated the ground, just as the shrine where Saint Mina had fallen had been covered in the blood of the assassins who murdered her. For a moment Margaret paused, but it was only to take a breath.

“ADVANCE!” she bellowed, and the Lost Rosetta obeyed.

The orks had fought hard, and dozens of sisters died with each push through every zone, but not nearly enough had fallen just yet. Far more remained behind, setting up chokepoints, killing fields, and traps for the many thousands more orks who still lived on the ship and would be coming for them.Through corridors, through chambers, and areas of the ship that had been hacked open in the mad designs of the ork meks who had reigned over the ship’s fate for far too long, the Lost Rosetta had pushed. Not towards the gun emplacements, nor the void shield emitters, or even the life support systems. There had only ever been one place, one location, which the Order had fought towards in all their concentrated strength.

Pushing past some her sisters, Margaret glared at her target, and took a running start before slamming both of her flamefists into the large doors which blocked the way. The same ork face which adorned so much of greenskin creations, dedicated to either the god Gork or Mork, shattered inward, and collapsed onto the ground. Dust and rust filled the air equally before clearing out, revealing the large bridge required for the running of an Apocalypse-class Battleship. In the center, brooding over a tactical map which bled a dozen different colors and marked out a hundred different warning signs in gothic, stood a massive ork practically the size of the penitent engines themselves.

“BONEBREAKAAAAAAAAAAAA! FACE ME!”

The warboss turned, and glanced down from his platform to look at the humans below, and snorted.

“And Zurn sed ‘ee could kill ya. Well, Face-eata,” Bonebreaka turned to shove one of his nearby nobs in the shoulder. “Looks like yer getting’ yer chance anyway. Go KILL DEM!” he suddenly shouted before turning back to the tactical map. “I’ze got a battle to run ‘ere!”

The nob in question took a running start and leapt from the platform, landing heavily on the deckplates below with enough weight to dent them, and raised his whirring chainaxes. From across the rest of the bridge, a great many other orks who had nothing else to do but watch grots and ‘betta orks’ poke at consoles began to gather behind him. On the other side of the sisters of battle, Margaret distinctly heard the noise of approaching mobs from behind, which squads turned about to deal with. In her ear, reports from the entire staggered approach of her remaining sisters reported similar attacks hitting all points.

“The Emperor protects. Let the darkness be rent by noise and flame, and be broken by it,” Margaret hissed as she moved forward.

=======================

Imperial Navy vs. Ork Fleet
11 vs. 4

In the void above Spinesnap, the battle raged on. A new swarm of resupplied bombers blew great holes in the kill kroozers and ork battleship, while lance weaponry tore apart those ships who had maneuvered away from initial assaults. Torpedoes, vast in their number, fell against the enemy, hulls cracking and breaking beneath them. In the center, an immovable rock, was the fleet of the Blood Ravens.

1st Company Operations: 79

“Whatever happened to this noble vessel’s crew, we have taken vengeance for them!” Marcus cried aloud, holding Wisdom aloft in one hand, and the head of a particularly vicious ork nob in the other.

The 1st Company cheered as they continued setting their explosives, previously set ones being detonated in short order. As the engines of the ship died, along with its guns, Marcus took a small amount of pleasure in marking its new status in the shared tactical information being passed between all of the allied ships. The orks on this ship had been particularly proud of their craft, as well one should be when in possession of a strike cruiser, but they had not been prepared for the fury of a space marine company. Which, in and of itself, was curious all things considered. Perhaps it was a severely understrength company that had been taken by surprise.

Stranger things had happened in the galaxy.

“Let us move on, brothers! This ship is disabled enough for the Imperial Navy to take it from here.”

Spinesnap Void Combat
75 vs. 18

“It appears that we’ll have to remove the Mars battlecruiser from the list, Captain,” the helmsman informed Marcus through grit teeth while maneuvering through the battle. “It just got cored, and then blasted to further pieces by the Navy.”

“I see. Well, we will just have to do our best, then,” Marcus murmured. “The enemy kroozers have been largely overwhelmed as well…but that pile of scrap they call a battleship is still functional.”

“Somehow,” Hamul grunted from next to him. “I hate ork ships. They make no sense at the best of times.”

“We have a problem, enemy point defenses around the hangar are active, initiating evasive maneuvers!” the serf pilot suddenly shouted, and all the marines who heard immediately grabbed onto what handholds they could.

All of the thunderhawks present began to dip and careen wildly in the void, dancing this way and that in an effort to avoid the incoming fire. Orks, finding targets up close for once, eagerly slammed on the buttons of their consoles and stuffed grots into firing tubes in an effort to score a kill against the thunderhawks. Or just to hear the sound that their guns made. In many cases, the motivations were twinned in significance.

Battleship Boarding vs. Active Defenses
97 vs. 64

Remarkably, all of the thunderhawks made it through without being scuffed. Some enterprising gunships even twisted sideways to rake the point defenses on the way in, while one transporter thunderhawk went through the somewhat excessive effort of slamming its hull down on top of an ork mob while sliding into the chamber. Almost immediately, to Marcus’ surprise, he could hear bickering amongst the vox channels between the pilots of the gunships and the transporters. Apparently they were comparing the relative merits of their vehicles, having been trained by either one techmarine for the gunships and by another for the transporters.

As it was, the hangar they had chosen as their egress point had been cleared by the efforts of the thunderhawks themselves before any of the 1st Company actually managed to get out.

“To battle, my brothers,” Marcus called out, “Guns first, then engines, then shields! As before! Let none find us wanting!”

“LET NONE FIND US WANTING!”

==========================

Dustboom Combat (2)
Imperial Guard Orbitals Assault: 83
Ork Orbitals Defense: 85
Ork Vehicles: 8
Blood Raven Crushing: 53

Hadrian fired again and again down into the stompa’s insides. Atop the wildly swinging machine, he burned a hole wide enough to drop a handful of krak grenades inside. Bikes roared their way along the narrow passes between different scrap piles, while razorbacks trundled forward, punishing each and every greenskin who dared to rise up from the heaps with guns in hand. There were not dozens, but hundreds of them, seemingly firing outright boxes of metal and haphazard screws as guns…and it worked. Not well enough, but regardless.

Eventually, however, the stompa fell…or at least collapsed slightly. Its bulk and design was such that it could not outright fall over without much more significant force, but the drivers and loaders within were little more than bloody chunks or melted meat. It was enough for Hadrians’ tastes, and he leapt off of it to land in the dust below.

“Apparently the Guard made another run at the orbital towers. Just one this time, concentrated force,” Ateren said upon his completed descent.

“Did they meet with success?”

“Apparently not. Nor did they lose…it appears to be a bit of a stalemate.”

Hadrian sighed, before looking out at the rest of the 4th Company.

“Some of our battle brothers are injured, but none so far gone as to be on deaths door. A few of our razorbacks are starting to feel the wear and tear of this place, and need maintenance…but we’ll keep pressing, I think.”

“Of course, Captain.”

========================

Shinehole Tunnel Pushing (2)
Imperial Guard Attackers: 13
Ork Defenders: 20
Blood Raven Attackers: 21

“They might as well hang back, this intersection is utterly impassible,” Calus grumbled, occasionally firing with his rapier whenever he thought he had a clear shot.

Which, as it turned out, was not actually that often.

What with the Guard continually rushing in, the threat of commissars blowing off heads right behind them.

“If you have time to complain, you have time to work on what we’ve recovered,” Daedal called over from where he had given up on firing his rapier entirely for the multi-melta he’d pulled from the muck.

“Bloody stalemates,” Calus groused, before turning away from his rapier and taking up the assault cannon he’d found.

“The orks are entrenched, Calus, its part of their nature when their precious ‘gubbins’,” Daedal quoted the air, “Are in danger.”

“We’re all aware of a Bad Moon ork’s proclivities, Daedal!” Calus waved his arms in the air for a moment, as if grasping at the heavens themselves in his frustration. “Or at least I am. I still remember Cyrus’ lessons when I was but an initiate.”

Both shuddered slightly at the memory of the one who had trained them, back when he possessed two eyes of flesh.

“For the Emperor! Stop dying, and start killing the enemy!” a commissar shouted, before his head was blown off by the orks who were firing down the tunnel from behind visible sparking shields.

Sahprize Tellyporta Attack!
15!

A great explosion of light and gore behind their positions and amidst the guardsmen waiting for their chance to run to their deaths nearly bowled Calus and Daedal over. As both rose up, they heard the screaming start from the Guardsmen who were now unfortunately covered in ork entrails. Rolling to a stop in front of Daedal was a surprised ork mek’s head, large tesla coils still sticking out of its skull. There was enough blood and offal which had erupted from the apparently failed teleportation for an entire mob of orks. Daedal coughed, and immediately turned back to his assault cannon, grumbling as he had to wipe the barrels clean of blood.

======================

Taking Some Guns: 99

Amidst the bodies of the slain, you marched over various ork corpses towards where the honor guard were setting the latest explosives. Hannibal was, as it turned out, giving last rites to a group of dead sisters of battle, their armor broken and bloodied where they had fallen. You have no idea where the Order of the Lost Rosetta is – though you have your suspicions – but these ones seemed especially broken by their foes. It was unlikely that their boarding attempt would result in every single boarding pod landing in the same place. Cut off, alone, they had apparently made a run for the weapon systems of the battleship, and had died for it.

“Weapon systems are still intact, for now, Chapter Master,” Doukas saluted to you. “If I may…”

“Speak, Captain,” you tell him while scanning the entrances to this place.

“We have control, here, of at least the port broadside lance turrets. We could…try to fire them, to aid the Navy?”

Your raised eyebrow is all you need to inform him of your need for clarification.

“The port broadside lance turrets are facing the ork battleship. They wouldn’t be expecting it.”

Hmm. It could potentially greatly aid against the ungainly yet gargantuan beast. And it is not as if you are not going to destroy the controls to these guns after you leave, removing them from the ability of Bonebreaka to control at all. It will enrage the techpriests, but they will just as likely be placated by the ability to repair the damage in the first place.

“Attempt it, Captain.”

“Very well, Chapter Master.”

Lance Broadside Attempt: 92

The entire battleship trembles faintly as the lance fires, and you can see upon the screens available that the ork battleship is struck fully along its flank. The sheer power behind the lances bore holes directly through the entire vessel, leaving holes capable of seeing through to the other side unhindered. Almost immediately guns from the battleship respond, attacking at the one that attacked them, which in turn makes ork gunners on the vessel you are onboard begin firing right back. What a pleasant result. You nod at Doukas, who grins in turn, before all of your brothers ready themselves to leave.

“This should break up their ability to fire the larger weaponry of the ship, and we can move on. With the engines destroyed, we could go for the void shields, Chapter Master,” Apollo informs you as you head away through the corridors with a series of detonations going on behind you.

“No, this fight must end here and now. We shall head for where the enemy is strongest which is – I suspect – where the sisters of battle are as well.”

“Hopefully the Navy can take advantage of our actions.”

Navy Taking Advantage: 54

============================

Lost Rosetta vs. Bridge Forces
42 vs. 45

All about the bridge, greenskins lay dead or dying, with more sisters moving onto the bridge the whole while. At the same time, the orks were continuing to flow in, some crawling through the ships’s body in haphazardly made tunnels and hatches just to get at the fight. At the foot of the staircase leading up to the tactical command platform upon which Bonebreaka stood, however, another fight still continued.

Margaret vs. Nob-Guard Face-Eata
57 vs. 54

Each blow was either deflected, blocked, or relegate to minor wounding status. Ork snarled at woman who growled at ork. Both fought relentlessly, and recklessly, their only goal being the death of the immediate foe in front of them. A blast of flame set a green shoulder aflame, while a chainaxe dragged a ragged line in Margaret’s stomach armor, flecks of blood spilling out from within.

Margaret vs. Nob-Guard Face-Eata
53 vs. 13

Until Margaret grabbed at the chainaxes themselves, and with the additional strength granted by her flamefists, shoved them forward until they were ripping and tearing away at their wielder’s throat. As Face-eata sputtered from a suddenly opened throat, a hand coming up to try and hold it closed, Margaret punched forward and out the other end of the ork’s neck, the erupting powerfield from her blow obliterating hand and spinal cord simultaneously.

Dodge!
36

She only just barely managed to fall backwards from the incoming bulk of Bonebreaka, who uncaringly squashed the corpse of his subordinate beneath steel-shod boots. An enormous hammer swung down, lighting and small gouts of flame bursting out of it as it struck the ground. The shockwave sent Margaret tumbling further, her body slamming along the ground as she was thrown clear, the ceramite of her armor cracking further even while she struggled to stand.

“Now dis, dis is the foight I wanted. What twiggy promised, ‘e did,” Bonebreaka said casually, hefting the hammer over on its shoulder with casual strength that a space marine in terminator armor would struggle to replicate, “E’ said, e’ did. ‘Go dere, and wait, Bonebreaka, and dem humies’ll come runnin’. You spent too long krumpin’ away from dat ‘Imperium’ ov deres.”

“You do not even care that your forces are failing, that your followers are dead,” Margaret spat as she knelt, wobbling slightly on her feet, a hand pressed to her side.

Bonebreaka laughed.

“Why wud I? THEY DIED FOIGHTIN! An’ now…,” he chuckled deeply, “So iz you!”

“I will die…,” Margaret stood, “When the Emperor desires it…and NOT BEFORE!”

Canoness Superior Margaret vs Warboss Bonebreaka
92 vs. 12

Bonebreaka passed through the twin blasts of concentrate flame sent his way without a single pause, only to blink as Margaret ducked under his arms and slammed both flamefists into his side, the heavy metal plating buckling beneath her strikes. Roaring, he spun, slamming the hammer down again and tearing apart more deckplates, the shockwave nearly knocking the woman down again on sheer concussive power, only for her to leap up and grasp onto one of the hanging spikes on the armor and punching against one of the few bare points of flesh on Bonebreaka’s body. As the flesh and bone exploded, the ork gave a mixture of a roar and laugh, before spinning about again and attempting to pluck the canoness off.

19 vs. 47

Which, despite her best efforts, he managed to do, dropping his massive gun in order to do so. Margaret howled as a massive green hand tightened around her torso, only for it to be cut off as Bonebreaka slammed her face first into the deck, shattering the cartilage of her nose and creating a pleasing – to an ork – crunching noise in her left shoulder. Margaret screamed again as he lifted her up and slammed her down again.

85 vs. 52

With a growl, and the ceramite armor over her pauldron thoroughly destroyed, Margaret scrabbled for a purchase with her feet and then with a bloodcurdling scream twisted and wrenched herself about – dislocating her shoulder entirely in the process – so that she could aim her flame fist in Bonebreaka’s eye. The blast, so close, burned through the orb entirely, blazing promethium licking at the ork’s frontal lobe while scorching Bonebreaka’s green flesh black and dead. The Warboss roared, releasing her entirely, while he stumbled backwards, still laughing.

Another wrench and pop, and Margaret slammed her shoulder back into its socket, and stomped after Bonebreaka who had already recovered. All the while they circled, the fight continued across the rest of the bridge.

93 vs. 20

“You iz wun crazy humie,” Bonebreaka guffawed before charging in again with a series of wild swings.

“Faith in the Emperor is not insanity,” she hissed back, dodging beneath each heavy swing with the warboss’ weapon, each strike sure to kill her outright if it struck her head-on. “Dedication to the death of the xeno is not insanity!” she began to yell, punching and tearing at Bonebreaka’s armor.

“SUFFER NOT THE XENO TO LIVE?! THAT IS NOT INSANITY!”

Both flamefists smashed into Bonebreaka’s chest, flames triggering immediately afterward after the powerfields erupted. Bonebreaka stumbled back, yet that was not nearly enough to kill him, the warboss settling on his feet once more soon enough.

5 vs. 67

Suddenly flipping the grip of the hammer, Bonebreaka stabbed out with the thick spike at the bottom of his weapon, impaling Margaret through the stomach entirely and sticking out the back. A surprised wheeze left her lips as she was lifted high in the air, Bonebreaka laughing all the while before a finger pressed against the side of his hammer which ran lighting through the entire weapon. The thickened leather and natural constitution of his race kept the electricity from hurting him, but with the spike embedded in her stomach, Margaret had no such protection. She screamed aloud, entire body spasming wildly. Any weapon she might have held would have fallen off, and yet her flamefists remained secure on her body. Then Bonebreaka flipped the hammer again, and slammed the hammer’s spike – and its occupant – into the floor of the deck again.

78 vs. 23

“Well, dat was fun, but-,” Bonebreaka began to saw before he felt his own hammer wriggling in his grip.

“RrrrraaAAGGGGGHHH!” Margaret screamed as she writhed, before she began wildly punching at the deckplate itself, smashing downwards again and again before the divot was wide enough for her to kick and twist herself free in a gout of blood.

A swinging hammer blow of one of her flamefists pulped Bonebreaka’s left foot – or at least the front half of it – before she steadily got to her feet, bleeding freely from the hole in her stomach. Another blast of flame, and another punch directly to Bonebreaka’s left knee exploded cartilage and snapped the joint backwards with its force, the front half of the knee simply gone entirely.

39 vs. 74

Even as Bonebreaka fell forward slightly, he was striking out with his hand, heavy metal studs embedded along the knuckles which backhanded Margaret across almost the whole of her body. The canoness was sent skidding to the side, stumbling as she released a cough of blood from her lips before they twisted into a snarl once more. She had barely begun to rise, however, when Bonebreaka brought his hammer down, guarding his ruined leg behind him, releasing a flowing shockwave of force through some sort of ork techno-sorcery. Despite her best attempt, Margaret was sent flying once more, this time her back slammed into one of the gun consoles on the bridge where a grot had once sat, shattering the machinery completely.

100 vs. 30

“And lo,” Margaret called out, her voice impossibly loud and clear despite the wounds she’d taken, all the while pulling herself free and standing. “Did the Saint Tevalia RISE UP! From her wounds and the depravities of her enemies, from her funeral bier and unto the last black day of the heretics who had ruled her world!”

She pulled herself free entirely, uncaring of the shrapnel that had embedded itself all along her body and set her to bleeding even further.

“From the lowest of places, cast from the high spires of her father, to wallow in the muck…only to learn that it was in that place away from true corruption where the truly faithful were found!”

Bonebreaka slammed his hammer down again, only this time Margaret dodged out of the path of the shockwave.

“FROM THE DEPTHS, DID THE SAINT TEVALIA RISE UP!” Margaret screamed, running forward now.

“With the aid of the Emperor, and his divine grace, did Saint Tevalia RISE! UP!”

Dodging past his attempts to stop her, the canoness swung a haymacker punch to the side of Bonebreaka’s jaw, snapping his head back as the powerfield erupted. A second punch found its way into his throat, blowing through the armor there and tearing at the fleshwithin.

“Against the ALIEN! Against the HERETIC! Against the MUTANT!”

“What in Mork’s name,” Bonebreaka snarled before he was punched in the stomach again.

“AGAINST ALL THE ENEMIES OF MAN! DID THE SAINT TEVALIA! RISE! UP!!!!!”

Bonebreaka lifted his arms, punched, swung, kicked, snarled, snapped his teeth at, roared, and bellowed all the while as he was beaten to death. The warboss fought every step of the way, hands finding knives and blades on his person to try and hack away at the woman who had knocked him onto his back and began pummeling him. He did this until enough punches and their subsequent explosions had rendered his arms into useless meat. Then he moved to trying to use his head, to use anything he could, even his still functioning leg.

Trying To Throw It Off: 67

For a wonder, he almost managed it, swinging her almost aside, before she dug her fingers into Bonebreaka’s eyesocket, fingers ripping around the bridge of his nose and pulling until she had outright removed Bonebreaka’s entire face and the front of his skull. His tongue lapped uselessly at the open air, tusk broken, as she continued to bring her fists down again and again.

Just as their parent order, the Order of the Bloody Rose, the Lost Rosetta wore armor of black and red. Over the course of the fighting, from Greenkrump to ship to ship, that paint had been marred by blood and soot in equal measure. Not so, here, as Bonebreaka died. Here, the blood of the alien so completely drenched the canoness’ body, from head to toe, that the only color on her was red. From hair to exposed flesh, was only crimson.

Only her blue eyes remained untouched, though the whites were bloodshot, and though only Bonebreaka would see it before his death, for the last seconds of the ork’s life the blue had become shot through with blazing gold…which only faded when the warboss breathed his last.

Chest heaving, slowly Margaret rolled off of the still twitching corpse into the hands of her celestians.

“The Emperor prevails! For the Emperor!” one of them shouted, fist raised high, a call carried across the whole of the Lost Rosetta, while Margaret was slowly lowered to the ground, already gone limp.

=================================

“I think…that we have arrived a bit late,” Doukas murmurs as you pass the various forbidding expressions of the sisters of battle, the sound of a cheer starting up only a moment after you are within hearing range of the bridge.

“FOR THE EMPEROR! FOR THE EMPEROR! FOR THE EMPEROR!”

The cheer is slowly taken up but with increasing speed as it reaches the ears of more sisters of battle, surrounded as they are with the bodies of their own slain and many, many orks. When you finally do reach the bridge, the cheering lowers in volume quite significantly, as a horrifically blood-slathered Canoness Superior Margaret Tenenbaum stands upright – barely – with an arm slung around the shoulder of one of her celestians. The great green bulk, practically torn open at the chest and skull, can only be Warboss Bonebreaka.

“Ah,” the canoness says as you sees you, “The Blood Ravens. Huzzah. We are saved,” she terminates her words with a hacking cough, and it is only then that you see that there is, in fact, a large hole in her middle. It was hard to see her own blood amongst all of the other blood.

“Lady Tenenbaum,” you finally say, bowing your head to her and her accomplishment.

“Where is the rest of your…chapter?” she grunts, her voice thin and waspish as her celestians struggle to keep her upright. “Mmm? Marching across the bodies of my slain sisters to steal glory?”

You can feel Apollo stiffen next to you, but you raise your hand to forestall his immediate acerbic response.

“Nay, Canoness. We came to strike out at this vessel, hoping to disable its various systems to allow the Navy to reclaim it…as well as offer what aid to you that we could. The rest of our Chapter is still on Dustboom, Shinehole…or amongst the fleet combat even now, attempting to preserve as many Imperial vessels as possible from destruction.”

She squints at you, for a moment, before scoffing.

“Well…your help is appreciated,” comes her reply, as drenched in sarcasm as she herself is in blood.

“Our breaching torpedo was damaged on entry,” you explain, “We were forced to land at a tertiary breaching point – and on our way here we disabled the engines and weapon systems of the ship, to prevent its escape and ability to continue firing upon the Imperial Navy.”

That at least, seems to get an interested noise from her, before she finally grunts as she is helped to sit on the steps leading up to the command platform on the bridge.

“I see. Good for you.”

“I see you are wounded, Canoness Tenenbaum,” Falkor suddenly says, “Can I offer any assistance?”

His step forward is matched with the cocking of many, many bolters in the hands of the Lost Rosetta, while Margaret props her arm upon her elbow to rest her chin in one hand. Her other hand, of course, is busy holding itself against the hole in her stomach.

“We have chirurgeon's tools of our own, space marine. Sister Agatha?”

One of the celestians approaches, pulling tools out from specially designed compartments from her armor. One of the Hospitaller, then. You know that occasionally the sororitas from those orders might come to work alongside their militant cousins. Unfortunately, Falkor’s offer only seems to have incensed some of the Lost Rosetta further, perhaps as a perceived insult to their own abilities at healing. Despite the glorious victory they have clearly just one, your very presence is slowly gathering a knife-edge tension into the bridge once more.

“But your offer…,” Margaret finally says, wincing slightly at Sister Agatha’s ministrations. “We have many more wounded than Hospitallers to aid them. You may see to them, so long as some of our own sisters watch you.”

“Chapter Master?” Falkor turns to you.

“Do the Emperor’s work, brother,” you give him a short nod.

Immediately he moves towards one of the more heavily injured seraphim, who twitches at his approach before being reassured at the sight of two bolters pointed at the back of his head as he kneels to begin his own work. After that, you simply bear the aggressive silence that has engulfed the bridge with consummate stoicism. Margaret is peeled out of her armor, then and there, at the urging of her healer, and after using holy promethium to scorch out and sterilize a portion of the ground, Sister Agatha outright begins performing some minor surgeries as you watch.

================================

1st Company Efforts: 90
Navy vs. Orks
88 vs. 45

“You cannot withstand us!” Marcus boomed out, firing his pistol into the most heavily massed ranks of the enemy.

Here, surrounded by metal on all sides, he truly could appreciate the sheer devastation that his weapon was capable of. What destruction must the Legions of old been capable of with such devices being more common? He could scarcely imagine it. Then he fired it, and crumpled an incoming mega nob within their own precious armor, and then he could imagine it quite well indeed.

“Trigger the detonations,” he called into the vox, and the battleship shuddered as the 1st Company’s efforts bore their explosive fruits. “Hamul, do we have information on our next target?”

“Well it’s gone, Captain,” the Champion replied.

Marcus paused.

“What?”

“They’re gone. Both of the Overlords are gone. So is the Mars. This…is the last ship. We’ve done the best we could,” Hamul waved the dataslate in his direction. “The Navy did not much care for waiting…as we knew they would not.”

“Hmmph. Then they are beginning their boarding parties?”

Hamul pointed at the approaching troop transport heading for the hangar bay.

“Indeed.”

“Hmph. What of the ork battleship?”

“Apparently either the Lost Rosetta or the Chapter Master took control of Bonebreaka’s flagship temporarily, and blew it almost completely apart with a close-range lance broadside. Or, rather, they hit it, and it began to break apart quite rapidly indeed.”

Marcus did not possess eyelids to blink any longer, but he was also wearing a helmet and so did not need to affect the facial movements. He could not stop himself from tilting his head regardless.

“…the Apocalypse-class has stopped firing entirely?”

“Yes, Captain.”

Considering the insanity the sisters have shown thus far, and the fact that the Chapter Master was surrounded by the honor guard, Hannibal, and Apollo Diomedes himself…

“Then we wait for new orders.”

Stage 3 Theater Results:
Shinehole Tunnels 50% Cleared.
Shinehole Ork Leader Remains Unknown.
High Imperial Guard Casualties On Shinehole.
Brother Cassius Of 1st Company Requires New Dreadnought Shell For Continued Operations
2 Plasma Cannons Recovered.
2 Assault Cannons Recovered.
------
Multiple Dustboom Ork Vehicle Formations Destroyed.
Multiple Stompas and Deff Dreads Destroyed.
Imperial Guard Casualties High.
No Blood Raven Casualties Taken.
3 Rhino Hulls Recovered, Were Being Used As Ork Transports.
1 Whirlwind Hull Recovered, Was Being Used As Component Of A Gunfortress
5 Assault Bikes Recovered, Were Being Used As Single Massive Bike.
Dustboom Orbital Guns Still Undamaged!
Mekboss Killdakka's Workshop Remains Hidden!
-------
Warboss Bonebreaka (Deathskulls) Slain Over Spinesnap!
Order Of Lost Rosetta Have Sustained 73% Casualties Of Battle-Group Contributed To Crusade
Looted Strike Cruiser Reclamation Underway
Looted Apocalypse-class Battleship Reclamation Underway
Looted Retribution-class Battleship Reclamation Underway
Looted Oberon-class Battleship Reclamation Underway
4 1st Company Marines Dead (+8 Gene-Seed Reclaimed)
2 Honor Guard Marines Lost To Void (Status Unknown)
WAAAAAGH!! Bonebreaka Broken!

Confirmed Naval Presences In System said:

Greenkrump
- 1 Lunar-class Cruiser
- 6 Escorts (x2 Cobra, x3 Sword)
- 2 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Dustboom
- 3 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 4 Escorts (x3 Firestorm, x1 Cobra)
- 4 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Spinesnap
- Looted Apocalypse-class Battleship [Reclamation Efforts Underway-Weapons And Engines Disabled]
- Looted Retribution-class Battleship [Reclamation Efforts Underway-Weapons And Engines And Void Shields Disabled]
- Looted Oberon-class Battleship [Reclamation Efforts Underway-Weapons And Engines Disabled]
- Looted Strike Cruiser [Reclamation Efforts Underway-Weapons And Engines Disabled]
vs.
- 1 Overlord-class Battlecruiser
- 7 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 8 Escorts (x2 Cobra, x3 Sword, x3 Firestorm)
- 1st Company Fleet

Shinehole
- 3 Universe-class Mass Conveyors
- 4th Company Fleet

Location Unknown, Fled Into Warp
- 1 Emperor-class Battleship
- 1 Overlord Battlecruiser
- 1 Lunar-class Cruiser
- 3 Escorts (x3 Firestorm)

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Current Plans For Stage Four Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One/Do Not Need To Select Every One]:

Greenkrump
[] Attempt To Own The Ground: The Imperial Guard remains in place on Greenkrump, and managed to fight quite well while being aided by the Order of the Lost Rosetta. They could use more aid in this, though the world itself is in plenty of turmoil besides. The orks lost both of their leaders and are warring against one another, as well as the Guard. The chaos could be quite the advantage if taken soon. You have learned the Order of the Lost Rosetta still alive will be heading for Greenkrump, to return to the forces they initially landed with. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: Write-In

Dustboom
[] Continued Crushing: The Imperial Guard has taken a beating on Dustboom, but has delivered it in turn. Quality and quantity have turned the tide against the orks, pushing them back across the planet and opening up new avenues of attack. Even so, there yet remain plenty more orks running about in the wasteland, exploding out of mek shops hidden in scrap heaps or rolling out from the mountains, and more. They must be destroyed. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Destroy Orbital Defenses: With the Imperial Guard pushing the orks back currently, even considering the casualties they've taken, the Blood Ravens might turn to more specific courses of action. With concerted pushes, certain orbital guns might be reached, their defenses punched through, and destroyed soon afterward. Once this is done, ships might take better positions, and provide more accurate auspex scanning, orbital fire, and more to the forces on the planet. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Hunting Killdakka: Mekboss Killdakka is one of the few remaining major leaders of the orks of Bonebreaka's cadre. You have not yet found his workshop, and who knows what insanity he is building in there. If he was slain, then surely it would help break the orks on Dustboom faster? [Write-In Forces Deployed]

Spinesnap
[] Honor Guard Retrieval: A space marine lost to the void is not necessarily dead. The Sus-an Membrane may have activated properly. You will need to contribute one of your vessels to track them down - if it is possible at all. [Write-In Ship(s) Dedicated To Search]
[] Planetary Workshop Obliteration: You know the general location of the ships which launched off of Spinesnap's surface. That is more than enough to find them once you look closer. Of course, they should be heavily protected considering their purpose, and the orks on Spinesnap itself have not yet been harrowed much at all compared to any other planet in the system. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Ship Reclamation Aid: Disabling critical systems is not the same as totally clearing the ships, or even close to it. The orks might well be in their thousands, or tens of thousands, across the vessels you managed to reclaim before the Navy destroyed them. Floods of Navy Armsmen are swarming through the innards of these ships, but you can aid them just as well.
-[] Apocalypse-class Battleship [Write-In Forces Deployed]
-[] Retribution-class Battleship [Write-In Forces Deployed]
-[] Oberon-class Battleship [Write-In Forces Deployed]
-[] Strike Cruiser [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: Write-In

Shinehole
[] Further Into The Dark: The beachheads have held, and the Imperial Guard is now pushing through with far greater success, their hearts emboldened by success. The orks are only fighting harder, however, using some of the most advanced weaponry you've ever experienced amongst their kind, and machines as well in the tunnels. But the majority of caverns are still held by the enemy. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: (Write-In)

==========================

Tarantula Dropping
81! No complications.

Drop Spiders: 97

The Snakebites of Trontiux III had been forcibly acquainted with the utter devastation possible by fire from the sky. Upon the Black Archipelago, they are introduced once again, to the deathly powers that the stars above could inflict. In this case, drop pods which crashed down amongst them, only to reveal their machinated contents. Multiple drop towers across the islands found themselves crushed from above, and while the orks deigned to investigate, they found it a fool’s errand as the tarantula turrets within began to fire out with ruthless calculated aggression. Small huts were obliterated, while larger nobs who had made the mistake of growing to notably large size were squashed beneath uncaring metal.

Logic engines blazed with energy, rapidly firing and exchanging information amongst themselves in a small coordinated network. Each time the orks began to try to unify, or one leader began to make itself known in an effort to restore order, a hailstorm of shells ended it. Spears of starlight burst from multi-melta barrels, while the most heavily armored of them all found their protection for naught when columns of lascannon fire bored massive holes in their torsos. What had been firmly under control by orkish hands became utter confused and terrified anarchy.

5th Company Advance: 76

Some of the orks tried to flee west, into the jungles that had not been set utterly aflame. These found themselves confronted by the armored fist of the 5th Company. Captain Tarkus slowly and methodically blocked off any egress points, and then drove the tanks of his forces forward in an unfeeling advance. Calls to the orkish gods went unanswered, charges of boar riding orks slaughtered as they drove forward with complete contempt. A wave of squigs was run over, and while the orks were fearless now that they had a target that they could actually fight, there was only so much that they could do with stone tools and simple beaten metal armor. Most did not have even that, sufficing with bone and slathered paint.

“Now, onto the islands themselves!” Tarkus called out, and behind him the 5th Company obeyed.

===========================

Pacemen burned. Every ork who lived there, died. Or close to it, it seemed. The jungles were consumed by flame, from coast to coast, fires set aflame by continual blasts from the skies. The hills were flattened, valleys turned to canyons, and paths trod by greenskin feet for centuries vaporized. Every great concentration of orks on the continent was sighted and found. With all the time in the universe to precisely fire here and there, to reload and carefully shoot, there was little to no room for failure. If a bombardment cannon ceased, due to one issue or another, there was plenty of time to solve the problem and placate the machine spirit. Hidden caves were collapsed, secret paths gone from the ground and history itself, the continent slowly scoured by the waiting blasts of utter destruction above. The starships of the space marines were dedicated planetary assault, and in a place where no challenge could be made to them, they went about their work without pause.

================================

The Search For Squiggoths
Scouts: 81
Scout Sergeants: 30
Cyrus: 39

“I am impressed, my brothers,” Cyrus’ voice came from just behind where the scouts had positioned themselves in the canopy, causing at least four of the squad to jump slightly. “Where I and your sergeants failed…you succeeded.”

In an admittedly cleverly carved divot into one of the jungle valleys, the grunting noises of the squiggoths were kept from escaping by the unique acoustics and attempts by the orks to keep them gagged. All around them all, the orks hacked away at the rock face, attempting to craft for themselves a new cave or five to hide away their precious warbeasts. By now they had learned the painful lesson of what their endless assaults on the humans of this world had brought them. Most of them enjoyed the fight, it was in their nature, but few enjoyed being slaughtered without the ability to even get close. Something that Cyrus was only too happy to keep from happening. If a scout was forced into melee combat against these orks, then they had failed in their basic training or they had bad luck. Either or both.

“T-thank you captain,” one of the scouts finally replied, flinching slightly as Cyrus turned his scowl towards them. “And…we think the warboss is down there too!”

“What?” Cyrus somehow loomed without moving or coming close to betraying their position, “Where?”

The proffered sniper rifle was offered, and Cyrus glared down the scope to where the largest of all the ork creatures slept. The orkeosaurus had fallen asleep, apparently exhausted after a long march away from its pens without a fight to keep its energy up. But atop it…yes, there he was. After all this time, even without a known name, an ork that could only be the warboss of all of those on Trontiux III stood. Upon the creature’s howdah, it tinkered at its massive stone axe, a primitive version of the sorts of weapons that a more advanced ork might use. A thousand small spines of bone had been driven horizontally through its own back, fluted in fashion as they went from the neck to the base of the spine. By size alone, against all other orks that had been sighted across the planet by the naked eye, auspex, and scans from the ships, this had to be the ork.

“Wait here.”

And then he disappeared.

Explosive Planting: 55

Some of the scouts swore they saw him, in the flash of his camo-cloak, planting explosives about the immediate valley. Thick patrols of orks, discipline created out of fear, marched about endlessly, and with that it was impossible for a full spread to have been dropped. But still, the telltale blink of a few detonation packs and others appeared in visors, Blood Raven codes transmitting to them. As the 10th Company slowly filtered in from across the area, surrounding the valley on all sides, the thunderhawks in the skies above sat at the ready. At least once, they thought they saw the warboss rouse himself, sniffing a few times, before he went back to work on sharpening the obsidian chips that had been embedded along his axe’s edge.

Final Planting: 89

From one blink to the next, Cyrus appeared, this time once more in the trees which had become that much fuller of scouts in the meantime. There were no grand proclamations, no warning, no speeches at all. Not even a whisper. The Captain of the 10th Company and Master of Recruits simply pressed the triggers, and explosions began to ripple across the previously hidden enemy camp. Two squiggoths collapsed outright as their entrails were blasted across the area, while the orkeosaurus roused itself immediately, bellowing at the new scorch marks along its humongous feet. The warboss roared as well, though partially because it was thrown somewhat by the sudden movement and explosives.

“This is Cyrus-Actual to all squads. Fire upon the enemy, and prioritize your targets properly.”

High above, the thunderhawks began their descent.

10th Company Barrage: 13
Thunderhawk Bombing Runs: 7
Cyrus Sniping: 96

It was, certainly, not the best display the 10th Company had ever achieved. The explosions going off had kicked up a significant amount of dust, while the orks themselves ran in all directions firing what few guns they had all over the place. Boars squealed and ran back and forth, bowling over their masters and plenty more orks besides, while the squiggoths began to trample all before accidentally slamming into one another. The thunderhawk bombs failed to hit anything significant amongst the enemy, and instead did just the opposite. A tree blown from its bottom collapsed, bringing with it the scouts who had taken it for their own perch, and though none died the snapping of bone and limb were audible to one with ears as finely trained as Cyrus’.

As the warboss roared for order, for a foe to fight, for the simple act of roaring, it revealed itself as the orkeosaurus revealed itself by rearing upwards and pawing in the direction of the thunderhawks. Cyrus narrowed his still organic eye, before sighting and firing in a single snap-shot of his sniper rifle. The open mouth of the warboss, leaning back to scream, atop a rearing orkeosaurus, was perfect enough. The small brain within the ork’s skull disappeared, along with the crown of his head, as the bullet shot directly up through the gullet and into the brainpan. As the ork toppled off of his mount, the death alone seemed to be sensed somehow by the orks as they panicked even further.

Ork Leadership: 55
Surrounded On All Sides: 86

Thankfully, after the initial series of incredibly disappointing shots from his Company, Cyrus felt his spirits lift ever so fractionally as the scouts and neophytes alike re-sighted. More measured blasts started to come from those equipped with bolters, while those who had been granted the usage of sniper rifles started to actually manage to pick off their targets. Squiggoths above were blasted by thunderhawks who actually managed to hit their targets for once, while Cyrus continued his own brutal campaign against every ork possible. A nob with a hammer rose up, thumping its fellows and pointing in the direction of the trees, before the nob’s head was forcibly removed. And so it went, across the entire valley, the orks releasing their pets and creatures in all directions, only to have their precious companions die.

Some of the orks, regardless, managed to reach the treeline, only to find out that simply getting to the vast examples of divergent arboreal life harder to destroy than they might have hoped. Purpled leaves fell as the orks hacked away at the trunks, only for them to be easy targets for the scouts above. Some, Cyrus noted clinically, managed to swing down to the lower branches, firing shotguns at those greenskins who attempted to climb up. It was always good to see space marines that did not forget that it was entirely possible to kill the enemy in more than one way. Too many times had he seen assault marines forget about the possibility of a full bolter, or devastators remiss on their close-combat training. It was why he preferred those of the general populace of a Chapter, the tactical marine, over almost all others.

Almost.

“Cyrus, come in,” Tarkus’ voice crackeld through the vox. “We’ve taken the Black Archipelago, the orks are fleeing in both directions, to Petramis and Pacemen alike.”

“Enemy warboss down, and we are dealing with what appears to be the last core strength of his forces. Hold your position Tarkus.”

“Of course. Fight well, brother.”

“And you.”

Cyrus glared down at the orks, before disappearing into the dust and blood once more. He’d killed the warboss, yes, but needed to capture at least one ork capable of speaking. After all, the Chapter’s records thrived on thoroughness, and without a name…well. It was why he was going to get said name.

Stage 3 Trontiux III Results
Snakebite Warboss Boneback Slain! Core Of Nobs Slain!
Black Archipelago Taken, No Casualties.
8 Scouts [1st Stage] Injured In Orkeosaurus Hunt, Will Be Healed By Next Turn.
Pacemen Ecosytem Devastated, Ork Populace Largely Obliterated.
Trontiux III Snakebite WAAAGH!!! Completely Broken/Survivors Scattered.
Ork Population Of Trontiux Reduced To Somewhat High From Extremely High.

Current Plans For Final Stage Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One]:

Trontiux III
[] Continued Culling: The back of the orks here have been broken tremendously. Pacemen is set aflame, from coast to coast, the lush jungle which once granted the orks of this place cover and a rich environment to grow their numbers burning to ash. The orks of Petramis are still high in number, but are on the run as well with the death of their leader and a resurgent human populace. However, more can be done. The orks must continue to be brought low, and while total extermination is likely not fully possible, you may be able to push them to that point. All the better for humanity to grow stronger here. [Write-In Forces Contributed]
[] Leave: Your work is here is done. The Warboss slain, WAAAGH!! broken, Pacemen an inferno. The orks have sustained heavy casualties on Petramis as well. The human lords now have their chance to push back against the threat, and reclaim their citadel-cities. It is time to return to Aurelia…or, perhaps to join up with Chapter Master Angelos. It is highly unlikely that that conflict will be over by the time you get there.
-[] Aurelia [Write-In Forces Sent]
-[] Angelos [Write-In Forces Sent]

Turn 19 (Part Five): By Duty, Bring Death

Spoiler: Begin Cleanup

[X] Plan Begin Cleanup
-[X] Destroy Orbital Defenses: With the Imperial Guard pushing the orks back currently, even considering the casualties they've taken, the Blood Ravens might turn to more specific courses of action. With concerted pushes, certain orbital guns might be reached, their defenses punched through, and destroyed soon afterward. Once this is done, ships might take better positions, and provide more accurate auspex scanning, orbital fire, and more to the forces on the planet.
--[X] All ground forces currently deployed to Dustboom
-[X] Honor Guard Retrieval: A space marine lost to the void is not necessarily dead. The Sus-an Membrane may have activated properly. You will need to contribute one of your vessels to track them down - if it is possible at all.
--[X] 1st Fleet Strike Cruiser Spiraling Fury, 2x Thunderhawks, 1x Hunter Destroyer + 2x Thunderhawks from Omnis Arcanum
---[X] Assist with Orbital bombardment of suspected Snipesnap Workshops when done or if opportunities present themselves
-[X] Planetary Workshop Obliteration: You know the general location of the ships which launched off of Spinesnap's surface. That is more than enough to find them once you look closer. Of course, they should be heavily protected considering their purpose, and the orks on Spinesnap itself have not yet been harrowed much at all compared to any other planet in the system.
--[X] 1st Fleet elements not on Honor Guard Retrieval or transporting to Shinehole transit from Snipesnap begin Orbital Bombardment of suspected locations unless threatened by orbital defense guns
-[X] Ship Reclamation Aid: Disabling critical systems is not the same as totally clearing the ships, or even close to it. The orks might well be in their thousands, or tens of thousands, across the vessels you managed to reclaim before the Navy destroyed them. Floods of Navy Armsmen are swarming through the innards of these ships, but you can aid them just as well.
--[X] Strike Cruiser
---[X] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chapter Master's Honor Guard
----[X] If they finish fast, move to assist with reclaiming further ships at their discretion
-[X] Further Into The Dark: The beachheads have held, and the Imperial Guard is now pushing through with far greater success, their hearts emboldened by success. The orks are only fighting harder, however, using some of the most advanced weaponry you've ever experienced amongst their kind, and machines as well in the tunnels. But the majority of caverns are still held by the enemy.
--[X] Current forces maintain orders
--[X] 1st Company elements not Reclaiming Strike Cruiser transit from Snipesnap onboard Strike Cruiser Ravenous Spirit (+2 Thunderhawks) + 1x Nova Frigate
-[X] Continued Culling: The back of the orks here have been broken tremendously. Pacemen is set aflame, from coast to coast, the lush jungle which once granted the orks of this place cover and a rich environment to grow their numbers burning to ash. The orks of Petramis are still high in number, but are on the run as well with the death of their leader and a resurgent human populace. However, more can be done. The orks must continue to be brought low, and while total extermination is likely not fully possible, you may be able to push them to that point. All the better for humanity to grow stronger here.
--[X] 10th Company, 10th Fleet Thunderhawks + orbital observation from rest of 10th Fleet + 2x Land Speeders (Standard) + 1x Razorback (Standard)
-[X] Leave: Your work is here is done. The Warboss slain, WAAAGH!! broken, Pacemen an inferno. The orks have sustained heavy casualties on Petramis as well. The human lords now have their chance to push back against the threat, and reclaim their citadel-cities. It is time to return to Aurelia…or, perhaps to join up with Chapter Master Angelos. It is highly unlikely that that conflict will be over by the time you get there.
--[X] Angelos
---[X] 5th Company, 5th Fleet, all vehicles not left for 10th Company

By Duty, Bring Death
+030.M42+ To +035.M42+
+Pain Now! Reward In The Afterlife!+

Spinesnap Imperial Bombardment: 32
Spinesnap Blood Raven Bombardment: 89
Spinesnap Void Search: 97
Void Survival 1: 17
Void Survival 2: 82
Secondary Spinesnap Blood Raven Bombardment: 24

Spinesnap becomes dotted with destruction soon after the battle is complete. Unfortunately, the Imperial Navy is rather busy with delivering its void armsmen onto the captured ships to clear out the orks there, and do not make it into proper firing positions very quickly at all. The ships of the Blood Ravens, on the other hand, push forward to what has always been their intended purpose. Bombardment cannons begin to fire immediately unleashing fury upon the orks below. Nothing like an Exterminatus has been ordered, of course. These worlds are to be claimed for the Imperium’s purposes. It is simply frustrating that the Navy spends so much time poring over their new rewards that they cannot aid you greatly.

More pleasantly, you locate your two lost brothers, swallowed up by the void during the initial engagement. Rather than being strung out into nothingness, the sensors finds one clutching at a piece of broken fuselage from a shattered fighter, the other hand wrapped tightly around the second. Unfortunately, only one is still alive. Brother Barius knew that brother Gaius was dead the moment they were sucked out of the boarding torpedo, a super-heated metal fragment impacting the marine’s skull all the way through entirely. But grimly he held on, knowing that his brother’s legacy would live on through his progenoid glands. The search took long, long enough for bombardment to be completed, but at least you have one brother back, and the other’s gene-seed for the chapter’s due.

There remains plenty of orbital guns left on Spinesnap, though a great number of workshops were destroyed regardless. There should be no more ships rising up from the planet from this point on. Hopefully. Unless the orks do something unexpected. In any case, it will be down to actually landing troops on the planet and taking care of business there. Thankfully the rather public slaying of Bonebreaka has had shockwaves across the rest of the WAAAAGH!!. While orks will never surrender, infighting has been noted to have begun across Spinesnap. But before that, the ships must be fully reclaimed.

Strike Cruiser Reclamation (1)
62 vs. 15

The orks infesting the strike cruiser are numerous, but pale before your fury. They cannot stand against the Blood Ravens as they stalk through the corridors. While you are in few in number, single space marine squads have done more with less on greater targets. A devious mek leads Apollo on a chase through the lower decks, while you personally crush the orkish psykers who had dared to set up a strange ritual site upon the bridge. Hannibal exercises extreme prejudice as he reconsecrates the various training chapels and contemplation alcoves with the blood of the xeno, and the rest of the honor guard assist in all of it. Including brother Barius, who takes particular pleasure in slaying the orks in an effort to make up for fate demanding he be stripped out from the fight earlier. His recovery period is fast, it is noted by the apothecaries, but to you it is obvious that determination draws him to the fight.

Strike Cruiser Reclamation (2)
92 vs. 5

The orks certainly outnumber you on the strike cruiser, but you know the battleground better than they ever could. You have spent a great amount of your life on strike cruisers, they are the noble transports of space marines across the galaxy. As such, despite however long the orks may have possessed this vessel, they could never truly master it. They are brought low, again and again, each and every one of them slaughtered, down to the last gretchin and grot. Squigs are smashed to pulp beneath your hammer, and every spot of greenskin life left on the vessel is gathered up in the troop bays, set aflame, and shunted out into the void. The only thing left for it now is for it to be properly reconsecratated.

Of course, one of the issues at hand regarding just that, is the fact of what the orks have done to it. The last of the ork leaders on the ship, a mek, had attempted to sabotage their prize addition out of spite, but was slain before any damage to it could be done whatsoever. It is something that was observed on the ship as it was fighting by many a space marine, and something that can be seen even now. Servitors picking over the device only confirm what close-range extensive scans have stated. The orks, in their insanity, somehow did something to the strike cruisers reactors to supercharge them. Enough to allow them to install an ill-begotten lance weapon on the vessel’s belly. Enough to let its various ad-hoc guns function as well. Whereas strike cruisers and battle barges are not meant for full void combat – their purpose of planetary conquest being more important – the orks had no particular care to remain within the Imperium’s guidelines for such ships. And with your killing of the orks in such number, a great number of their strange ‘modifications’ remain. The Mechanicus is likely to be…upset…at such desecration.

=========================

1st Company Transit: 25
Warp Complications: 73
Extremely Sluggish Warp Travel, 1st Company Does Not Arrive At Shinehole This Stage!

“Isn’t the 1st Company supposed to be coming to help us?” Daedal yelled, forced to use the vox simply because regular yelling wouldn’t possibly be heard due to everything else.

“That’s what I heard,” Calus bellowed back, clutching as his rapier’s firing studs, sending a hailstorm of heavy bolter fire at the enemy.

Shinehole Tunnel Pushing (1)
Imperial Guard Attackers: 20
Ork Defenders: 71
Blood Raven Attackers: 41

“Well I sure wish they’d show up already!” Daedal yelled, forcing the rapier into reverse as the orks advanced down the tunnel.

Great bubbles of constrained lightning blazed over the fronts of the chuckling mega nobs, their own guns firing back and tearing into the retreating Imperial Guard. Occasionally an ork or ten would charge past the mega nobs, outside of the overlapping protective shields, and would be torn apart as a result, but many more stayed behind thanks to many a thump to their skulls. Daedal cursed as he saw a commissar utterly fail to ‘inspire’ his troops by gunning down five of them as the entire platoon ran as fast as they could, the Guard forced into retreat rather than simply be cut down. Even the dreadnoughts were more being used as stopgaps than anything else, scoring kills but never enough, and never the right ones.

“This isn’t going well,” Calus noted, his voice remarkably calm as he attempted to cover the retreat.

“WHAT WAS YOUR FIRST CLUE!?”

=======================

Dustboom Combat (1)
Imperial Guard Orbitals Assault: 5
Blood Raven Crushing: 20
Ork Orbitals Defense: 100

“Behold! DA GREATEST FING, WOT EVA DONE GOT MADE!”

Broadcast across all of Dustboom, the words of Mekboss Killdakka heralded the deaths of thousands. Exploding out from one of the orbital gun sites, left too long, given too much time, the Mekboss had completed a devastating creation. Practically the size of a gargant, the battlefortress had crushed one baneblade entirely, blown apart another Guard tank division, and shredded the air-support from the skies. The ‘hidden’ workshop had been inside of one of the orbital guns, but with no investigation attempts made, it had been utterly untouched throughout the fighting on Dustboom. Treads from a dozen and more other vehicles dragged it forward at ludicrous speeds – for a bulk that size – while entire tanks had been installed on its body as weapon emplacements. Dangerous and exotic ork weaponry sprawled out from a dozen hard points, ripping entire tanks up and smashing them down, blasting others out of existence entirely.

Hardrian grunted as he struggled to lift the flipped and broken razorback that had once been a proud Blood Raven tank. The space marine which had been trapped beneath it quickly scrabbled free, their armor pockmarked and sluggish from the damage it had taken. The space marines which had exited the shattered and childishly thrown aside hulk just in time slowly gathered, but one of their number was clearly dead, the body simply being taken along to ensure the chapter received its due. The Captain of the 4th Company snarled as he sighted the ‘Ultra Fortress’ roar off into the distance, leaving behind only shattered or thrown aside wrecks in its wake.

“This is Hadrian, pull our forces back, we can’t match its strength yet. Preserve all points, and regroup!”

“We’re not going after it?” one of the marines asked, a young one, just elevated to full battle brother a short time ago.

“No,” Hadrian shook his head, “Not yet. Not like this. Not with our forces as they are.”

=================================

Greenkrump Arrival: 70

The crewman, to his credit, did not interrupt despite the fact that he should have returned to the bridge a full thirty minutes ago. It had been a simple job, to pass along the message, but unfortunately that simply was not happening. After all, one did not interrupt the sisters of battle in prayer in such a situation. If the ship was under assault, perhaps, but no, not here. Not now. Instead, he waited, as the sororitas prayed within the chapel with a volume and fervor that made his very bones shake in his body. Finally, at the very front of the congregation and at the statue of the Emperor’s feet, armor cleaned, wounds treated, did their leader rise. Immediately she turned, and with her did the rest of them, all staring at him.

“Canoness,” he squeaked before clearing his throat. “Ah, Canoness. We’ve arrived over Greenkrump. Your transports are ready to go.”

“Thank you, crewman,” the Canoness smiled at him, “Please, return to your duties. I would not wish to infringe upon them, forgive us our tardiness.”

“Uh, no, no trouble at all!” he squeaked again, fleeing before it happened thrice while cursing himself all the while.

“Sisters!” Margaret called after he left, “To battle once more. FOR THE EMPEROR!”

==================================

Shinehole Tunnel Pushing (2)
Imperial Guard Attackers: 1
Ork Defenders: 97
Blood Raven Attackers: 14

“Brother Ithacan!” Daedal screamed, roaring his fury at the enemy even while firing until the quad heavy bolters glowed with the heat. “Damn you xenos!”

“He’s dead, Daedal, the whole dreadnought got cored! He’s gone!”

“No, I can still save him!” Daedal hissed, leaping off his rapier and running forward, ignoring the lascannon blast which nearly removed everything above his waist entirely. “I can-gah!”

Calus ignored Daedal’s defiant roaring, letting the angry mechadendrites stab at him while he dragged his brother with him in retreat, shaking his head all the while. A half-dozen screens inside his helm screamed for attention, and all the while his hands tapped along the control-feed forcing all of the rapiers present into retreat, firing all the way as they backed out along the tunnels. Rocks began to shudder and shake as they were purposefully collapsed. Dreadnoughts throughout the cavern slowly stepped backward, hitting the targets he marked, trying to push back the shielded orks. At their head was the one who had done all of it, an ork with a half-dozen electrified coils rippling about his armor at random placement, stomping forward with three lascannons welded together in one massive gun as a replacement for a more standard slug-weapon. Guffawing, the ork slammed his power klaw on the ground repeatedly as he stomped forward.

“Come on, boyz! Dat’s right, get ‘em with the shiny bits! Harharhar! Bonebreaka is dead! NOW IT’Z TIME FOR WARBOSS DAKFLASH!”

“Shut up,” Calus growled, before rearing back and throwing what he’d carried forward.

Toss: 62
The Boom: 94

Raising his hand, a whispered apology to their fallen brother, Calus triggered the thrown detonation packs, synched up with the half-melted reactor off the dreadnought’s shell.

“NO!” Daedal roared as the orks were obscured by nothing but white. “What have you done?!”

Scrabbling up from where he’d been dragged, Daedal slammed his helmet against his brother techmarine’s, a growl on his lips.

“Bought us time,” Calus replied calmly. “Now come on. The fight isn’t over yet. There’s no chance that killed them all, or even most of them. Those power shields of theirs are modified void shields, and I think that Dakflash had a stolen Warhound void shield stuck to his chest.”

Daedal seethed, fists clenched tight enough for the ceramite to creak, before he finally followed after Calus.

====================

Imperial Boarders: 100
Orkish Inhabitants: 9
Blood Ravens: 89

“They barely needed us,” Hannibal notes approvingly, “The Emperor favors them this day.”

“It seems so,” you cannot help but admit. “The battle was hard, but they seem most eager.”

“I can sympathize,” Apollo speaks from behind you, where he watches the cheering armsmen as they pass by, weapons held high. “They spend all their lives in these berths, and during battle it is all they can do to simply wait for boarders – where they can have no hand in their own destiny but faith in the ship’s captain and crew. Now they rise, and take the fight to the enemy.”

It is not entirely correct to say that that Navy did not require your aid in retaking the Apocalypse-class battleship, formerly under the personal hand of Bonebreaka. You slew a few orks, here and there, appearing in the corridors to support the armsmen where possible. But they flooded the ship, and without your aid they would have succeeded all the same. Faster, of course, with your aid. But still. One should not detract from their own accomplishments, and you spare the time to inform many a passing sergeant so when they pause to gape at the looming Blood Ravens who watch them. Many of them are clearly exhausted, but happy, the ship soon to fly back to the heart of the sector where they can be properly revived – after some lengthy reconsecration of course.

“How goes the efforts on the other ships?” you turn, looking towards Apollo who seems to have become just as much an aide as a bodyguard, who checks over his various data slates.

Retribution Boarding Operation
67 vs. 19
Oberon Boarding Operation
93 vs. 62

“The Oberon is almost fully reclaimed, and as for the forces here,” he gestures at the passing crowds on their way to the troop transports which brought them – meals and medicine waiting. “They are going to be heading to the Retribution soon. I highly doubt that the orks can withstand them at this point – though I would not count out the orks just yet, ever. They are forever capable of…unpredictable things when pushed into a corner.”

========================

Lost Rosetta Invaders: 95
Imperial Guard Invaders: 75
Infighting Orks: 70
Infighting Orks: 24

“Zog me, stop shootin’!” the ork roared as it shot across the burning workshop.

“Oh, no way Begrum, I know you! Yer gonna shoot me ta deff iffin’ I don’t kill ya first!”

“Gork and Mork, boy, dem humies is comin! We’ze gotta foight ‘em togetha!”

“Da boyz ‘ill foight em…when YER DEAD!”

Both orks and their warbands disappeared beneath the earthshaker rounds of the basilisks which had been trained on their position. Across the rest of the valley, orks in the middle of fighting to determine who would be the next leader died, catachan killers slaughtering patrols and seraphim wresting control of the skies. A valkyrie drop ship landed in the valley, as they were doing across the immediate hundred miles, from which more troops flowed. Singing a song of the Emperor’s glory and humanities duty to Him, the Order of the Lost Rosetta steadily killed their way across the continent, the Imperial Guard beside them.

===========================

Dustboom Combat (2)
Imperial Guard Holding Action: 7
Blood Raven Reversal Attempt: 45
Ork Surge: 91

“Well,” Hadrian spat blood onto the ground, wrenching the rebar which had slammed through his stomach out of his body to use as a crutch. “That didn’t go well.”

“We can’t beat that thing like this,” one of his marines shook their head, “We do not have the equipment or numbers to do so. The Guard is in retreat across the entire planet, they’re building new orbital guns out of nothing but scrap, and we’ve lost another razorback.”

“We haven’t lost yet,” Hadrian growled. “Not yet.”

The 4th Company huddled within one of the hollowed out piles of slag left on the planet, their remaining vehicles brought to them, simply trying to regroup. Outside, they could hear the sounds of the Guard being slaughtered as they ineffectually tried to hold out against the orks. Every single time they attempted to build a proper defensive line, the Mekboss would show up with his monstrosity, and destroy it. After the land raider had suffered a heavy scoring across its front, the internal mechanisms being melted by the sheer heat of the ‘deff beam’ shot out by the giant orkish leering skull at the ront of the machine, it too had been pulled back before it was destroyed.

“What are we going to do, Captain?” another marine asked.

“We’re going to fight,” he shook his head. “With their forces surging like this across the damn planet…they’re leaving the rear orbitals unguarded. That’s where we’re headed.”

“By ourselves?”

The Captain glared down at the marine, and nodded only once before slamming the side of his fist against the Litany of Purgation.

“Everyone load up! We’re moving out, now! Not on foot, on the vehicles. Look to your wargear, we leave in five minutes!”

============================

Killdakka chortled as he sat back in his squig-leather throne, a meaty finger reaching out to swipe a few screens aside to make way for ammo counts and power levels. Grunting to himself, he reached for one in particular, dragging it forward on its stand, and stared at it with his four cybork eyes, his right and still fleshy eye squinting as well. All around him, the Ultrafortress rumbled and shook, every gun it possessed firing at once at the retreating humies. Another bevy of their tanks tried to roll up, but the Ultrafortress either picked them up and flung them elsewhere, melted them, shot them full of holes, or simply crushed them and ran them over. His contented sigh was interrupted by a loud beeping.

“Urgh, wot iz it, grottie?” he growled, finger turning the intercom on.

“Uh, boss! Remember dem beakies?” the gretchin simpered.

“Uhhhhh,” Killdakka murmured before snapping two of his augmetic fingers, “Yeah! I remember dem! Dem Blood Raven boyz. Hoy, dey killed a lotta our tanks, dey did. Good foight. What about ‘em?”

“Gunboss Rattla says de’re at his Big Gun!”

“WOT?!” Killdakka roared, slamming one of his other arm’s fists onto the big red button with ‘NO’ scrawled on it.

All across the Ultrafortress, greenskins were thrown from their stations as the titanic machine came to a sudden halt, skidding forward on sheer weight for a moment.

“Wot you mean de’re at his Big Gun! Tell ‘im ta zog ‘em!”

Hadrian’s Gamble vs. Gunboss Rattla’s Defenders
87 vs. 59

“He seyz he can’t! He seyz-,”

One of the dozen screens lit up, this one marked with dozens of orkish skulls over a badly drawn map. Killdakka roared as he saw one of the skulls blinked red, then disappeared. In the far distance, farther than he certainly could hear from deep within the Ultrafortresses, one of the orbital guns collapsed, multiple tanks firing upon its support struts in tandem on top of a mass of slain orks. The Mekboss growled, and flicked the intercom on again. The only reason that skull would have disappeared like that was if the shiny bits he’d put in it had been destroyed – and if Rattla wasn’t dead…then he would be soon.

“Tell dah others ta get ready for them beakies! I’ze got humies ta break, for Gork’s sake!”

“I-I will boss! Yes boss!” the gretchin squeaked before turning off the radio.

Killdakka growled again, previous contentment forgotten as he leaned forward in his chair, slamming another fist on the big red button labeled ‘YES’. The Ultrafortress surged with power once more, sending its dozens of attendants flying once more though many immediately scrambled back into their seats.

“All right boyz, listen up!” he roared into the Ultrafortresses tubes, “Them beakies got around us, and are taking out da Big Guns! So wez gotta break dem humies right quick, so we can get back around, yeah?! WAAAAAAAAGH!!”

Hadrian’s Gamble vs. Gunboss Zogbreak
94 vs. 27

Killdakka’s roar only grew more indignant as another proper green skull disappeared from his map.

=======================

Hadrian’s Gamble vs. Gunboss Hellkraka
53 vs. 44

“You will begin landing your troops at the marked locations at this instant, do you hear me, General!?” Hadrian roared into the vox as the last of the utterly massive orbital gun’s defenders were ground beneath the Litany’s treads.

Intimidation: 70! Success

“I hear you, space marine,” the Imperial - a General Dominic - growled, “But only because you cleared the landing zone. We’re on our way."

From the skies orbital support was already coming, bombing runs and bombardment coordinates being offered up freely. Ships, able to move without fear even if only a small slice of the planet, rushed to the point, flooding the comparatively small amount of territory with a bevy of fresh troops. Others, elsewhere, merely were raised up in their own transports before being dropped off in the new location, old firebases and depots destroyed or taken by the greenskins. Only once did the orks attempt to retake the lost ground, only to find that without the danger of being shot down, the Imperial Navy’s vengeance was swift and terrible. The only reason they continued to make attempts was the fear they felt from Killdakka’s rage, the threat of the Ultrafortress rolling over them making them run into the lines of the Imperium’s hastily put together defenses.

But it was precarious, none the less. With original landing zones being taken, new orbital guns being constructed practically out of thin air by the insanity of the ork mechs, the Imperial Guard’s forces on Dustboom were abruptly highly concentrated – but just as unable to strike outwards with impunity as they had once done. Hadrian stalked back and forth across the rapidly devolving ‘no-man’s land’ which marked the distance between looted and Imperial guns, riding atop the Litany all the while, an unforgiving guardian who had been bloodied more than one. All the while, the rest of the Guard elsewhere attempted to simply put a stopper to the Ultrafortress itself, which seemed as of yet still unstoppable.

=====================

5th Company Theater Transit: 79

"Entering realspace now," Damion cried out, his body thrumming with power.

The 5th Company arrived, the warp practically belching them back into the materium, with their flagship at the head. Tarkus gave Damion a small nod before approaching the tactical map, the exhausted epistolary barely managing a salute before he fell into his recuperative meditations, and frowned at what he saw. Handshake protocols did not need his authority to be given, not at this moment, and the information given unto them was not favorable whatsoever. The amount of ships fallen was disconcerting, though the death of Bonebreaka was welcome news. It was the sight of various warnings being thrown about the system between the Imperials which happened to bounce through the 5th Company astropaths which he did not care much for at all. Isolated forces, broken down, a full retreat on one world, an entire company - if reduced - completely surrounded on another. Clearly they had arrived at quite a tumultuous tipping point in the war going on here. Not enough ork ships to fully win, but the longer it stretched on the more damage the Imperium's efforts would suffer.

"Open communications with Chapter Master Angelos, and request our orders."

Stage 4 Theater Results:
[General]
- 5th Company has arrived, warp turbulent but no complications!
----------------
[Spinesnap]
- Void-Combat ‘Orktimized’ Strike Cruiser Fully Reclaimed!
(Modifications Not Sabotaged/Destroyed: Lance weapon, torpedo launchers, makrocannon broadsides, orkish powerfields, void shields, ‘Supa-Reakta’)
- Apocalypse-class Battleship Fully Reclaimed!
- Oberon-class Battleship 90% Reclaimed!
-Retribution-class Battleship 60% Reclaimed!
- Spinesnap spaceship workshops destroyed!
- Imperial Guard landing on Spinesnap, targeting orbital guns and planetary shields!
-1 Honor Guard Marine (+2 Gene-Seed)
+1 Honor Guard Marine recovered!
--------------------
[Dustboom]
- 1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons)
- 1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Plasma Guns) [+Lascannon]
- 4 Assault Bikes (2x Multimelta, 2x Heavy Bolter)
- 7 Blood Ravens (+14 Gene-Seed Recovered)
- Imperial Guard in retreat over much of planet! Orks in resurgence over much of planet!
- Small Amount of Orbital Guns destroyed by Captain Hadrian behind enemy lines! Imperial Guard landing in area, orbital support in area, orks pushed out!
- Mekboss Killdakka revealed, riding in Gargant-sized Battlefortress variant ‘Ultrafortress’ from Orbital Gun Workshop!
- Rearmost Guard Positions heavily defended, orbital support present. Orks cannot advance on Rearmost Guard Positions just yet, marshaling strength!
----------------
[Greenkrump]
Greenkrump greater pacification complete!
Lost Rosetta leaving Greenkrump to head to Spinesnap for planetary assault!
Greenkrump full pacification process to begin upon campaign completion.
-------------
[Shinehole]
1st Company Tomb-Brother Ithacan Slain!
1st Company Tomb-Brother Cassius re-entombed! 1 Castraferrum Chassis Used!
Shinehole Leader Revealed: Big Boss Warboss Dakflash, Bad Moon Klan! Anti-Armor/Vehicle Weaponry Noted!
Shinehole Ground Forces In Full Retreat!
Shinehole Tunnel Control Reduced To 38%!
Orks utilizing stolen Imperial Void Shield technology!

Spoiler: Naval Presences Across System

Greenkrump
- 1 Lunar-class Cruiser
- 6 Escorts (x2 Cobra, x3 Sword)
- 1 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Dustboom
- 3 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 4 Escorts (x3 Firestorm, x1 Cobra)
- 4 Universe-class Mass Conveyors

Spinesnap
- Looted Retribution-class Battleship [Reclamation Efforts Underway-60%]
- Looted Oberon-class Battleship [Reclamation Efforts Underway-90%]
vs.
- 1 Overlord-class Battlecruiser
- 7 Lunar-class Cruisers
- 8 Escorts (x2 Cobra, x3 Sword, x3 Firestorm)
- 1st Company Fleet
- Reclaimed Strike Cruiser
- Reclaimed Apocalypse-class Battleship
- 1 Universe-class Mass Conveyor [Carrying Lost Rosetta, Slated To Arrive At Beginning Of Stage Five]

Shinehole
- 3 Universe-class Mass Conveyors
- 4th Company Fleet
- Strike Cruiser Ravenous Spirit (+2 Thunderhawks) + 1x Nova Frigate [Arrival Estimated At Start Of Stage Five Of Engagement]

Location Unknown, Fled Into Warp
- 1 Emperor-class Battleship
- 1 Overlord Battlecruiser
- 1 Lunar-class Cruiser
- 3 Escorts (x3 Firestorm)

Newly Arrived In System, Near No Single Planet
- 5th Company Fleet

Current Plans For Stage Five Of Engagement [Can Select More Than One/Do Not Need To Select Every One]:

Dustboom
[] Hold Your Ground: Three orbital guns went down, and Hadrian has begun attempting to fortify what has been taken with the aid of the Imperial Guard. A small amount of territory, open to orbital support, remains somewhat inviolate to Killdakka's Ultrafortress...so long as the gargantuan vehicle does not turn on them. The furthest Imperial Guard bases on the planet are similarly protected, but more troops need to be properly directed - and for that the 4th Company must remain in a defensive posture over what they've taken. The better this is done, the more troops can be brought together, the more might be done to prepare something to take down Killadakka. There are rumors - only overheard by space marine hearing - that the Guard is negotiating with the Mechanicus to be allowed to deploy something they think might take down the Ultrafortress. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Striking Out: The Guard is getting torn apart, but they are quickly fortifying what has been taken by Hadrian. Now might be the time for more aggressive action, to take down more of the orbitals. The faster this is done, the more of Killdakka's inner territories might be taken from him, isolating him between the most heavily defended Guard positions and what has just been taken. A dangerous proposition indeed, but one that if successful might wrest the momentum away from the ork. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: Write-In

Spinesnap
[] Orbital Gun Destruction: The anti-orbital weaponry which was clearly developed by Mekboss Killdakka are present here as well, albeit in lesser numbers. The orks on Spinesnap are currently undergoing significant infighting as a result of Bonebreaka's death. It is said that the Lost Rosetta is coming here to destroy these and kill as many orks as possible, along with much of the Imperial Guard. You could assist in this as well. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Ship Reclamation Aid: Disabling critical systems is not the same as totally clearing the ships, or even close to it. The orks might well be in their thousands, or tens of thousands, across the vessels you managed to reclaim before the Navy destroyed them. Floods of Navy Armsmen are swarming through the innards of these ships, but you can aid them just as well.
-[] Retribution-class Battleship [Write-In Forces Deployed]
-[] Oberon-class Battleship [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: Write-In

Shinehole
[] Holding Actions: The orks are swarming up from the depths of Spinesnap with much looted Imperial technology, allowing them to withstand the forces brought against them and further overwhelm them. Defenses must hold, as best they can, the better for everyone else to try and regroup. To stand in the face of these orks is to face near-sure death, but it must be done regardless, many say. Few Guard forces are volunteering - or rather it is their commanders which are making them volunteer. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Fortification Actions: The Imperial Guard is known for holding the line, but they need help. Much of their gear and turrets are failing to be properly deployed for damage or lack of support. The more of them set up, the better the orks might be pushed back - or at least held. Which at this point, is the best that can be done. [Write-In Forces Deployed]
[] Something Else: (Write-In)

============================

The Trontiux Lords: 78
The Culling: 96
Broken Orks: 8

"A good kill, initiate, but you have not yet earned your place," Cyrus informed the previously exuberant child, who sighed as he once more sighted his sniper rifle.

As Cyrus moved away, watching over all, he heard them speak to one another once they thought he was out of earshot.

"Does anything actually impress the Captain?"

"Depends. Have you ever walked into an enemy camp, and out again, and blown up the camp without them seeing you?"

"Would that do it?"

The Scout Sergeant, of the 1st Company, formerly of the 5th, formerly a scout of the 10th, rubbed at his chin for a moment. He considered, strongly, his memories of his time there, of his tutelage under Cyrus, who had trained space marines for decades, and been alive for centuries longer than him. Finally, he shrugged.

"Probably not."

Trontiux Results:
Cyrus satisfied with culling efforts on Trontiux III. Remaining orks are pushed back across Black Archipelago to Pacemen, jungles of Petramis mostly cleared. Remainder of orks allowed to live to ensure proper foe for Trontiux Lords to fight, and keep themselves sharp upon. Ork population reduced to Medium High.

Current Plans For Conclusion Stage Of Engagement

Trontiux III
[] Leave: Your work is here is done. The Warboss slain, WAAAGH!! broken, Pacemen an inferno. The orks have sustained heavy casualties on Petramis as well. The human lords now have their chance to push back against the threat, and reclaim their citadel-cities. It is time to return to Aurelia…or, perhaps to join up with Chapter Master Angelos. It is highly unlikely that that conflict will be over by the time you get there.
-[] Aurelia [Write-In Forces Sent]
-[] Angelos [Write-In Forces Sent]

Turn 19 (Part Six): By Duty, Bring Death

Spoiler: Plan Forward Unto Conclusion

[X] Plan Forward Unto Conclusion
-[X] Hold Your Ground
--[X] All ground forces currently deployed to Dustbloom. Once the 5th lands, if local IG defenses have held, coordinate timing with them to switch to offense to start taking down orbitals again.
--[X] 4th Company Fleet transit from Shinehole to begin assisting with orbital bombardment
-[X] Something Else
--[X] Deploy the 5th Company into the Rearmost Guard Positions to fortify and support a second front. Once they have landed, if local IG defenses continue to hold, coordinate timing with the 4th to switch to offense to start taking down orbitals again.
-[X] Fortification Actions
--[X] All currently landed forces
-[X] Holding Actions
--[X] 1st Company to take to the front when they finish landing.
--[X] 1st Company Fleet w/ Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chapter Master's Honor Guard (all forces remaining there) transit from Spinesnap. When they arrive, link up with 1st Company and begin a new offensive push, and try to engage and eliminate ork leadership
-[X] Leave
--[X] Angelos - All forces

By Duty, Bring Death
+030.M42+ To +035.M42+
+Pain Now! Reward In The Afterlife!+

Dustboom Combat (1)
Imperial Zone 1 Defenses: 64
Imperial Zone 1 Ork Attackers: 47
Imperial Zone 2 Defenses: 25
Imperial Zone 2 Ork Attackers: 22
4th Company Defenders: 50
5th Company Reinforcements: 91
Imperial Negotiations: 100

Dustboom is a hellish planet, and the sands and dust of the place are painted red by the fighting. Hadrian drives his troops back and forth at weak points across the line, but there are not in fact that many to find. That is not to say the fighting is not brutal, but the commissars in charge here are skilled at whipping their troops into shape. Mechanicus adepts work frantically to set up their turrets and machine defenses, while suicidal troops pile up wire and bunker building materials. Elsewhere on the planet, the rear-held positions on the other side of the orbital cannon field of fire begin to waver under the vicious leadership of Killdakka. It is the successful intervention of the newly arrived 5th Company which pushes them back, Tarkus adding more armor to the defense, and shoring up positions that melted under fire.

But all of that pales compared to a series of transports that soon arrive, heavy Mechanicus heraldry upon them, openly broadcasting prayer-cants to the Omnissiah. From these, stomping out as Tarkus watches, come three of the mightiest machines to ever exist on Dustboom’s surface. Three Imperial Knights, their armor and heraldry cleaned and gleaming, bearing the crests of the Houses of Legrin, Aerian, Xerult. There is little sign of the damage they sustained once, long ago, when the Blood Ravens accompanied the Mechanicus to their world, from an ork WAAAAGH!!! All three salute Tarkus as they pass, guns booming once, before they head out into the wastes, their target obvious with even a small amount of casual thought.

================================

Shinehole Combat (1)
Beachhead Holding: 74
Blood Raven Holding: 30
1st Company Reinforcements: 25
Ork Attackers: 50

The Imperial Guard are no strangers to dying en masse. But neither is victory foreign to them. Anger and zealous hatred, purifying and powerful, burn bright in their souls. The orks may have pushed the Imperials and the Blood Ravens back, but as the fighting continues their progress begins to slow. The Guard knows how to hold a position, even to the death, and their fortifications around the incredibly important beachheads into the tunnel systems are proof of it. While the Blood Raven dreadnoughts are forced back, heavy bolter turrets and heavy weapon emplacements ensure that they survive the fighting though the damage is considerable. Repairs will be needed, certainly, in the long run. When the 1st Company arrives, they are, to Marcus’ considerable consternation, unable to push the orks back any further either, and instead end up locked into a stalemate against the orks. At the least, the momentum build-up has been crushed.

Warp Travel: 89

But hopefully this will all change, when you arrive in orbit above the planet and proceed to deploying to fight alongside your brothers.

===============================

Warp Travel: 95

“That was fast,” Cyrus murmured, his eyes just to the side of Maphar, the Epistolary’s psychic light blazing out of him.

The witchlight demanded that the serfs shy away, one unfortunately staring directly at the blaze the Librarian had become surrounded by and soon after having to be taken away from going insane. But the effects were undeniable. The 10th Company had practically shot through the warp, it almost felt like, even with the Gellar fields holding strong. Still, Cyrus knew well that even the shortest trip through the warp could become lost instantly, while longer trips could instead only take but a few months in the materium. There was truth behind the idioms of ships arriving four months before departing, sometimes arriving months or even generations before or after they were meant to originally arrive.

“Is that a problem?” Maphar grunted out as he slowly and carefully released the power he had drawn to himself.

“Not at all.”

===================================

Tracking And Hunting: 77

“KILLDAKKAAAAAAA!”

The broadcast was cast across all of Dustboom, on every channel possible. It was impossible to ignore, impossible to miss. A great wave of orkish vehicles, trundling along, came to a violent halt as the supermassive machine in the middle of all them did the same. All around them was a dust storm kicked up by the weaponry being unleashed over and over again by the planet, reducing visibility even further. Scattered piles of scrap and hills of broken rusting metal were barely visible at all, even with the various appropriated scanning systems in Killdakka’s Ultrafortress. But these were unneeded as the source of the broadcast revealed itself.

“You mongrel …dare you face a Knight of Trontiux!?”

An Imperial Knight emerged from the dust, weapons bared and glowing with heat, as it came to a halt before the entire column. Three trukks charged immediately, only to be stomped and blown to pieces. For a moment, there was no response, before Killdakka’s voice crackled onto the vox.

“Oh, I iz gonna do more den face you. Yer stompa is gonna be extra flash for me Ultrafortress!”

Twitching its weaponry slightly, the Knight flourished and let loose a cheery laugh.

“Then come forth, and face me!”

“WAAAAAAAGH!!!”

The entire column exploded with the yelling, all charging forward and firing at the Knight who began to charge forward as well. A half dozen of the smaller vehicles were destroyed instantly, but there were far more than that. The weapons firing from Killdakka’s Ultrafortress struck hard against the Knight’s ion shielding, scoring superficial marks against its adamantium plating almost immediately.

Crossfire Assault: 91

Which was when two more knights emerged from the sides, both assaulting from flanking positions where they had hidden around the bend of two piles of heavy scrap. Weapons firing wildly, all three Knights Errant-patterned machines crashed into the orks, enough light blooming from every weapon present to blind anyone watching with the naked eye. Three thermal cannons boomed, turning a dozen blowing waves of dust into glass which fell and shattered upon the earth. A massive reaper chainsword scraped low, catching a looted Leman Russ low and tearing it apart immediately upon rising. But far more of the tanks, trukks, and deff dreads were ignored for the true target.

Forward Charge (Legrin)
68 vs. 10

While the back and sides of the Knight’s hull began to glow red from the weapons assaulting it, pockmarks being torn out of the adamantium from tank cannons striking it, the front remained inviolable. The directional ion shield sparked wildly as Killdakka’s gunners pointed as many guns as they could at it, but they could not stop its charge. Even as the Mekboss roared in dismay, the Knight of House Legrin slammed into the front of the machine, chainsword revving as it hacked and chopped at the Ultrafortress. Once its forward power shield bubbles popped, the thermal cannon began to fire at the same time. The Knight stumbled as the huge orkish face at the front of the Ultrafortress fired, a forcebeam nearly knocking it over entirely before it reset its stance.

Pincer Crash Attempt (Xerult)
9 vs. 30

While the underlying mechanisms behind ‘lifta droppa’ technology were unknowable, their effects were undeniable. From two gigantic claw-like prongs fired green lightning, dragging the Knight to its feet and sending it sliding left onto its side. Traktor cannons fired as well, humming columns of strangely colored light wrapping onto the god-machine and sending it skidding directly into a scrap pile, while a dozen sponson weapons fired on its sparking and failing ion shield. A frustrated scream could be heard coming from the Knight’s operator at the mistreatment of their machine.

Pincer Crash Attempt (Aerian)
69 vs. 55

More success was found as the third Knight made its way forward, if only just. Still, as its chainsword pierced the hide of the Ultrafortress, ramming it with enough speed to send its bulk skidding sideways, Killdakka grew only more furious. Power was rerouted from engines and their power fields, instead rerouting everything to the weapons. Firing rates grew faster and faster, barrels growing cherry red, while the traktor weaponry still functioning continued to make a mockery of the Xerult Knight’s efforts to get into the battle properly.

======================

Shinehole Combat (2)
Ork Attackers: 4
Blood Raven Counter-Offensive: 79
Imperial Guard Counter-Offensive: 17

“SHOW ME WHAT PASSES FOR FURY AMONGST YOUR MISBEGOTTEN KIND!”

Your roar is only matched by the combined throats of the 1st Company, bolters firing and blades growling.

“NONE SHALL FIND US WANTING!”

No longer do these greenskins face but two techmarines and a scattering of dreadnoughts. Now they face the might of the 1st Company. Of a Chapter Master. Of Hannibal. Of Apollo. Of the Honor Guard. Waves of orks die to your bolter fire, Marcus pushing ahead and firing his relic graviton pistol upon the most heavily armored mega nobs. In one cavern, a series of deff dreads are torn apart by missile launchers and power weapons, with yourself bringing one low by obliterating its knee with a single strike from Godsplitter and then smashing apart the armor between you and its cybernetically fused pilot.

“Push forward, brothers! Onwards onto glory in the Emperor’s name!” Hannibal booms from atop the corpse of another ork, his crozius covered in the gore of the slain, a fist raised high.

Behind the Blood Ravens come the Guard, cheering and firing as they come as well.

=========================

5th Company Orbital Assaults
55 vs. 42

“Hadrian, we are making our move now. Are you ready?” Tarkus called into the vox, though he knew the aggressive Priscus was likely already on the move as well.

“Always, Tarkus. We’ve been ready since setting foot on this world. May the Emperor go with you.”

Both spoke at the same time, a roar from both 4th and 5th Companies as they rode out into the wastes, leaving the Imperial Guard behind. These were no feral orks of Trontiux, these had shootas and rokkit launchas aplenty, and the fighting grew hard immediately as the 5th Company made its way deep into enemy held territory. While orbital fire lashed down at any greenskin armor which dared to leave their protective fielding, the Guard trying to rebuild their own defenses, the Blood Ravens forged ahead. But the orks were strong, in number and in looted or hand-built equipment. Nevertheless, they were ground back over time. Tarantulus Ultima was almost eager, it seemed, to face a worthy opponent rather than endlessly slaughtering feral orks on Trontiux.

4th Company Orbital Assaults
69 vs. 28

On the other end of the ork-held territories of Dustboom, the 4th Company ranged out again. Hadrian cared little for the methodical slow approach that the Codex recommended against unknown territory, preferring far more to bring the fight to the enemy as quickly as possible. This was what Brother Pellam told himself repeatedly as the Captain drove the land raider up a scrap mountain and off of it, to land on top of a stompa to send it crashing onto its back, only then reversing and firing with all weapons upon its newly broken open innards. The marine instead elected to fire with the twin-linked lascannon with unerring aim, despite his misgivings about his captain. Frankly, Pellam was pleased enough to have made it out of the 10th Company and the unnerving and never-blinking scowl of Captain Cyrus. Still, there would likely be quite a few angry words exchanged between Master Martellus and Captain Hadrian about his regard for safety regulations on what he demaned from the Litany.

====================

Engaged Knights Against Killdakka’s Column
97 vs. 24

“Ee’s cutting the rolla up, boss! He’s cut through a ‘ole mess ov da Ultrafortress!”

Killdakka roared and fired his Gorkeye, the energy beam turning the little grot to ash, slamming on every button around him. More and more guns sprouted out of the Ultrafortress, firing in the vague direction of the three Knights which were attacking his precious baby. With every blast of their Mork-damned cannons huge chunks of his Ultrafortress were melted away, vaporized, while their mega-choppas shredded their way further in. Dozens of orks in suddenly exposed hallways and gun-loading bays fired wildly to no avail, while the tanks wheeling about outside fired and failed to make it through the humie shields.

Last Knight Against Ultrafortress
82 vs. 48

Things only got worse as the Ultrafortress was struck by a third massive bulk, sending the entire hulk scraping to the side. Then the third humie stompa, which had finally made its way up close, began broadcasting to Killdakka’s ever-escalating fury.

“HA HA! YOU CANNOT STOP HOUSE XERULT! ‘EVER RELENTLESS’!!!”

Killdakka yowled as his entire command center was broken open, the front of it where a half dozen passages leading elsewhere into the Ultrafortress melting completely from one of the humie cannons, the rest of it exposed to the screaming skies of Dustboom by the humie mega-choppa. From up close the noise erupting out of the growling weapon was loud enough to explode Killdakka’s eardrums entirely. Even then, he shifted his bulk and began firing with his looted flash-cannon, the welded human lasweapon screaming as it fired again and again upon the Knight which carved more and more slices of the Ultrafortress to pieces.

“No, get off of me baby, you humie scum! I’ll zog ya! I’ll zog all of yaaaaa!!!”

Two dozen guns all over Killdakka’s body began to fire, wired to his brutish mind, and fired relentlessly at the Knight of House Xerult, two solid inches of shells coating the ground at Killdakka’s feet within a minute.

Angry Knight vs. Angry Ork
8 vs. 10

When the massive whirring blade swung down, Killdakka barely dodged out of the way, being thrown a dozen feet away by the sheer shockwave that resulted from the weight crashing down at high speed. Worse, the command throne was completely destroyed, making the Ultrafortress, already heavily damaged, go haywire. But Killdakka didn’t care, at the moment. He only had eyes for the Knight which was visible to him. That was soon enough extended to the other two machines, who had torn apart the Ultrafortress he had put so much work into for so long. Roaring, he fired in all directions, guns erupting from beneath his skin and bionic systems going into overdrive, the generator on his back going into overdrive as he tried to kill everything he saw.

Three Knights And One Ork: 75

In the end, Mekboss Killdakka died how he lived; quickly and violently. Despite his extensive bionic replacements, how much of his body was covered in metal, and how much of it was gun, he melted away beneath a carefully targeted blast from a thermal cannon. The Knights continued on their way, tearing apart the entire Ultrafortress before turning away and facing the quickly fleeing orkish vehicles, the knowledge of what had just happened quickly propagating outward on panicked calls on primitive radios and stolen vox communicators. The Knights met in the middle of what was once the Ultrafortress, and faced each other.

“Well, good for you. You finally showed up,” the House Legrin Knight broadcast, the pilot’s voice teasing.

“Shut up. Let’s finish this fight,” the House Xerault Knight growled, stomping away.

The remaining two Knights shifted slightly, facing each other, before following behind.

=============================

Shinehole Combat (3)
Red Seeking Green: 51
Combined Assault: 80
Greenskin Defenders: 63

“Status report!”

You punctuate the yell with the slamming of Godsplitter against another ork, sending the pulverized corpse flying to the side. Waves of bolter fire tear apart the enemy, but they fight without a care for how many of their own die. Filthy xenos, but bolstered somehow by the knowledge that their Warboss – only just given into the role after Bonebreaka’s death. Apollo slams his own hammer against another ork, before turning to you, the Honor Guard surrounding you and providing a bulwark of ceramite and flesh.

“We have found no sign of this new self-proclaimed Warboss,” Apollo shakes his head. “I spoke with the last two to see him, the techmarines Calus and Daedal. Apparently they collapsed the cavern on top of him in their retreat. Perhaps he is injured.”

“Perhaps,” you nod, before ducking slightly as a missile goes flying off course and lands nearby, showering you in shrapnel. Superficial damage at the most, and thus you ignore it.

“For the Emperor!”

Both of you turn to look at a passing charge of Guardsmen. Heedless of the casualties they’ve suffered, pursued doggedly behind by a commissar with a whip crusted in the blood of his subordinates, they charge forward firing all the while. Perhaps to the surprise of some of your youngest battle brothers, they are successful, a wave of grenades preceding them leaping into the orkish gun nest and bayoneting the enemy who survived. They fight, and fight well, here and now. Those that are too injured to fight on are slowly dragged away for the medicae to treat, while those that survive each successive push move forward. But soon afterward you return to the fight yourself. The orks are being pushed back once more, and you must find their leader before he can enact some insane plan or another, if the ork leaders of this WAAAGH!! have been any indication.

Speshul Delivery By Tellyporta!
89!

An explosion of green-yellow lightning and some explosive decompression heralds the arrival of a great mob of orks. Several dozen guardsmen are slain instantly on sheer proximity, their bodies twisted inside and out by the torn immaterium before it is stitched back together. There is zero hesitation from the orks as they immediately charge out in all directions, firing and hacking away at all they can reach. Their appearance in the direct middle of Guard and Blood Raven alike makes for quite a few favorable targets for them indeed. On the other hand, they have brought themselves in reach of you. In the middle of all of them, both arms replaced with gigantic tri-barreled megashootas, an orkish nob fires in every direction, even killing some of the orks directly in front of him, cackling all the while.

“HAHA! Dat tellyporta worked! Kill ‘em all, boyz!”

Teleported Ambush Force vs. Guard
13 vs. 2

The Guard seems wholly unprepared for the fight, losing a core of their troops and cut down from the sides as they try to turn inwards. Crossfire between the Guard firing across the center of the cavern kills more, while the greenskins take advantage of the chaos their sudden arrival has caused. On sheer volume of slugs being fired at them, a dozen within your immediate field of vision are reduced to mulch before they can properly scream. Their leader alone is the cause of much death indeed, head not even snapping back when a lasbolt crashes directly into his forehead. The only mark of the shot is a slightly smoking crater on his green flesh, and a bout of laughter erupting from his throat.

Teleported Ambush Force vs. Blood Ravens
18 vs. 70

That laughter stops when your Master of Sanctity throws his crozius arcanum directly into the orks skull. Bearing two combat knives in his hands, Hannibal barrels his way deep into the entire ork mob, slashing apart many and simply tossing others aside through his speed and mass. As the ork begins to recover, he leaps upon him, stabbing down again and again upon the ork’s skull, dropping the knives to sweep up his crozius once more and obliterate the ork nob’s skull and upper torso entirely. The rest of the Blood Ravens can do no less, firing carefully into the mob, engaging with bolter and blade where necessary. Two blasts from the rapiers and a concentrated series of burst fire from the dreadnoughts and their assault cannons ends the rest of the mob entirely, taking advantage of the frozen moment immediately after seeing their leader slain.

“Do not falter, children of Emperor! Have faith in yourselves, for you are humanity, you can do nothing but stand above these despicable xenos!” Hannibal booms across the cavern, crozius raised high.

His words are inspiring enough for the Guard, who cheer and steadily begin to regroup, where just before they had seemed ready to retreat.

=============================

Dustboom Knightly Cascade: 87
Dustboom Guard Cascade: 36
Blood Raven 5th Cascading: 20
Blood Raven 4th Cascading: 72
Blood Raven Recovery: 85

Hadrian grunted as he and a squad of his marines slowly dragged the wreck away from the ruined Ultrafortress, which even now glowed hotly on thermal sensors. Tarkus, on the other side of the destroyed machine, oversaw similar efforts. Both paused in their work at the distant boom and faint quake which rumbled along the ground, Tarkus nodding firmly and Hadrian grinning within his helmet. The Captain of the 4th Company slapped one of his newest marines on the shoulder, laughing slightly. It was not the first nor would it be the last. While the Guard itself was struggling mightily to bring down the remaining orkish orbitals, the Knights had no such difficulty. Each of the three which had been deployed was capable of simply ramming into a tower, their shields and armor proof against even the greatest remaining orkish weapons. With every tower fallen, more Guard could be deployed, more orbital fire and bombing runs were possible upon scattered orkish forces.

“You hear that, brother? Those Knights are eager indeed, that’s another tower that’s gone down,” he barked out another laugh before returning to dragging the predator hulk free of the wreckage.

As such, in a lull between one tower and the next, Tarkus and Hadrian had come together to see if the reported auspex readings were true. Or at least, that had been the plan, before Tarkus' forces were blocked off and surrounded by a particularly clever ork big mek. Hadrian had slammed into the enemy from behind, rescuing Tarkus, but the damage was done by the time victory was achieved. On the other hand, to the benefit of the Chapter, the Ultrafortress possessed numerous hard-points which were crafted out of astartes vehicles. As much as it would likely drive Martellus to apoplexy, a hefty number of astartes wargear and vehicles had been part of the Ultrafortress, likely explaining its sheer power and deadliness. None of it was graviton weaponry, unfortunately, despite the first thought some might have had on the orkish capabilities displayed. On the other hand, multiple weapon hard-points had not been simple turrets, but outright entire vehicles. Some had been basilisks or leman russ tanks, but others…others had been different.

“Hadrian, this is Tarkus, come in.”

Hadrian stilled the sigh that welled up in his chest, and responded to his much elder and more experienced battle brother.

“Yes, Tarkus? You’re right over there, if you need help I can walk to you.”

“No, nothing of the sort. I have just received the latest reports. The last of the orbital towers have fallen, orbital superiority is achieved, and the Guard is moving out in force. With the orks of this place broken as they are, our work here is effectively done. I believe we should move for Shinehole, to support the rest of the Chapter.”

Hadrian grunted, glancing at the recovered predator hulls they’d retrieved.

“I…suppose. I think there might be more to recover here, though. Clearly these orks have had these hulls for quite some time. Who knows what else they might have on this planet. The longer we wait, the more likely more might become unrecoverable, or claimed by the Mechanicus for their own purposes.”

“The vehicle pool of the Chapter was heavily depleted in the Purge…,” Tarkus mused.

“If all we were finding was rhinos, then I’d feel differently. But these ones have guns on them. Actual offensive capabilities.”

He felt Tarkus sighing at him before he actually did.

“Rhinos have explicit tactical value, Hadrian. Without them, we could not support the transport of our brothers to the front line.”

But this time, he had a response.

“This is true. But if we had enough predator and hunter tanks, then we could transport our forces and bring along a much greater allotment of death for the Emperor’s foes.”

“And by transport you mean crewing said vehicles.”

“…yes, that is correct.”

“Captain!”

Hadrian turned to see one of his marines, waving for his attention. Suddenly the shredded metal that the marine was standing upon began to crumple and fall, the marine barely leaping free in time before rolling to their feet.

“What is it, brother?”

“We’ve found another hull, but…it’s different.”

Different was certainly correct. The chassis was somewhat known, but the weapon upon it was certainly not something that Hadrian had encountered before. That did not mean he could not tell what it was though. Part of him greatly despaired at the state of it. The majority of the tank itself was in terrible rusted condition, though the weapon was somewhat better maintained. About what he could expect from an ork’s hands, he knew well enough. Still, a valuable find indeed. Even if the tank itself was non-functioning, he hoped it would be possible for Martellus to reattach the weapon to a newly made hull if necessary. The idea of having such a weapon in the arsenal of the Blood Ravens warmed his hearts. It was a conflicting thought to hope that a land raider might be found amongst the wreckage, because if it was there then that meant a great tragedy had occurred to have it placed as such. On the other hand, they would have another land raider. Eventually Hadrian sighed, and elected to simply try and drag the hull free without damaging it any further than it had been since the destruction of the Ultrafortress.

========================

Shinehole Combat (4)
Red Seeking Green: 75
Guard Assault: 5
Ork Defenders: 43

“The Guard is being torn apart!” Apollo roars from where he fights at the forefront of the latest cavern to be fought through.

“Move to support them Apollo,” you order him, voice steady and calm all the while. “I have a target in mind.”

In the end, you did not need to keep looking for Dakflash. For he came looking for you. The chance at looting the wargear of the Blood Ravens was too tempting a target for his greedy mind to stay away from. As such he forced his troops to rend a hole through the Imperial Guard to find you, chasing you down in an effort to slay you as quickly as possible. While much of his personal guard found themselves being killed or left behind entirely, the self-proclaimed Warboss stands before you, now, firing at one of the dreadnoughts of the 1st Company. His sparking power shield glows strongly, but you charge him all the same. Apollo, in the meantime, heads off to support the utterly crumbling Guard positions. The cavern itself is monstrously large, a clear nexus point amongst the orks of this place, a full layer of broken weaponry, looted gear, scrap metal, and general refuse coating the ground from end to end.

“Hoy! You is a shiny beakie!” Dakflash roars upon seeing you, turning to face you with an ugly grin on his face. “But all dat cyborky flash ain’t gonna save ya, cause I’m DAKFLASH!”

You do not bother with responding with words.

Angelos vs. Dakflash
91 vs. 81

The fiery corona surrounding the ork’s power klaw flares as you approach, before you sidestep out of the way of a sweep that would have allowed it to clench and crush you between it. Before Dakflash can fully react you slam Godsplitter against the weapon to send it flying away even further, slamming your pauldron against his opened jaw to knock against him slightly. Teeth go flying, blood pooling from torn gums, as the ork bellows in rage at you not dying immediately upon facing him.

43 vs. 54

Gun ports open up in Dakflash’s chest, small stubby barrels firing at your front with a fusillade of slugs which crackle against your armor. Jerking his chin, he sends the massive heavy metal jaw-protector common to orks against you, the crash a bone-jarring impact.

94 vs. 44

You ignore the inconsequential hits upon your chest to swing Godsplitter against his jaw, shattering the metal and snapping his lolling jaw shut, severing his tongue with the hit. Switching your grip, your hammer then flies downwards to crack against the side of Dakflash’s left knee, breaking bone and metal in equal measure. The Warboss roars, trying to smash you apart with his lascannon abomination, the barrels glowing with the heat of repeated firing.

86 vs. 33

Worse strikes have been weathered. It does not even drive you to your knees, or make you stumble. Instead your hammer smashes the lascannons away, the power field shearing the metal apart and sending scattered white-hot fragments flying away. Beneath, you can see the mangled remnants of the hand within the creation which was triggering the firing studs, before stepping back to avoid another wild swing of the power klaw.

“GRAAAAAGH! STOP NOT…DYIN’!”

96 vs. 65

Once again you break Dakflash’s face, pounding it inward further. The ork was not a true warboss, though he had certainly grown compared to the last recorded sightings provided to you. Given enough time and opportunity, Dakflash would certainly grow to that point. You would not allow that. Not here. Not now. As lightning bolts began to fire out from the massive coils attached to Dakflash’s back, in all directions, you struck at him again. Then again, and again, and again. He stumbles back, bleeding profusely, skull broken open, but every weapon his possesses is firing still.

“Ya ain’t…got me yet! Got me one more surprise for ya! YAAAAAAAAAAAGH!!”

Da Last Laugh
34 vs. 9

You are clad in terminator armor, and thus not the most agile of all space marines. But you are plenty fast enough to dodge backwards and to the left as the Warboss charges, lightning crackling all over his body in greater and greater amounts. Light continues to pour out of Dakflash as he attempts to wrap you in a grapple, only to fail to his roaring consternation. Swinging about, the ork reaches out with his power klaw desperately before you are blown backwards by the ork’s explosive disappearance. Lightning erupts from the open hole in the warp, and you realize abruptly that he had somehow wired some form of primitive vortex device into himself.

“Chapter Master!”

Saving From Vortex
55!

Apollo’s hand wraps around your own, and he holds you firm as you get to your feet, the open hole to the warp screaming wildly for an instant before it ends just as quickly as it began. The cavern does not have a moment of silence, the orks fighting all the while, before realizing just what has happened. Only then do they start trying to run, the Guard cheering wildly as they are reinvigorated by the fight. The Blood Ravens join them in this glorious exultation, if less vibrantly, focusing more on killing the enemy than anything else. Hannibal strides at the front of them all, battering down every ork which dares to approach him, a bulwark in front of the Guard as well. His compassion does him credit.

================================

Spinesnap Ground: 93
Spinesnap Void: 80

“LET! THEM! ALL! BURN!”

Margaret roared, surrounded by the war-chants to the God-Emperor, as she set the orks before her aflame. One ork nob, braver or tougher or simply stupider than the rest, charged through the inferno she set only to be obliterated as she leapt upon them and began beating her fists upon its skull. The ork tumbled down the hill, Margaret on top of him, as the sky was lit by inferno and bolter barrages falling upon the orks. Soon enough, the greenskins broke, their bastion burnt to a crisp, and their leaders slain from afar. But they could not run quick enough, or far enough, for waiting on the other end of the tree line that the orks retreated to, waited a dozen more penitent engines, their screaming heretical pilots driven to seek holy repentance through death.

Boiling hatred for the alien filling her, the Canoness slowly stomped back up the hill, hand going to her ear as the vox implant crackled.

“It is done. The valley is cleared. We are moving out across the rest of the planet now, separating into teams.”

“Thank you for your hard work, Canoness.”

“I have no accomplishments to my name, General, only service to the Emperor. How goes your work upon the ships reclaimed for the Emperor’s service?”

“Well enough Canoness. More troops will be landing upon Spinesnap shortly.”

Stage 5 Theater Results:
[Spinesnap]
- All Looted Battleships Reclaimed
- Spinesnap orks in total disarray, complete defeat imminent!
- Lost Rosetta fully deployed onto Spinesnap, obliterating enemy!
--------------------
[Dustboom]
- 3 Imperial Knights deployed on Dustboom surface.
- All orbital cannons destroyed, orks entirely exposed to orbital support.
- Mekboss Killdakka slain! Orks on Dustboom in full retreat, total disarray noted!
- Guard resurgent across Dustboom!
- 4 5th Company Marines Lost On Dustboom (+8 Gene-Seed Recovered)
-------------
[Shinehole]
Warboss Dakflash Slain!
Shinehole Orks In Complete Disarray, Retreating!
Shinehole Tunnel Control Advanced To 65%!
-------------
[General Summary]

10th Company Arrived Ahead of Schedule! No complications!

- 2 Notables Identified:

Techmarine Daedal – [Machine Spirit Speaker/Thunderhawk Transporter Specialist]
Techmarine Calus – [Adepta Exotica/Thunderhawk Gunship Specialist]

Blood Raven Overall Casualties:

1 Honor Guard Slain (+2 Gene-Seed Reclaimed)
4 1st Company Marines Slain (+8 Gene-Seed Reclaimed)
1st Company Dreadnought Ithacan Slain (Gene-Seed Unrecoverable)
7 4th Company Marines Slain (+14 Gene-Seed Recovered)
4 5th Company Marines Slain (+8 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Vehicle Pool Overall Casualties:

1 Predator Wrecked. Repair Possible.
1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Assault Cannons). Repair Not Possible.
1 Razorback (Twin-Linked Plasma Guns) [+Lascannon]. Repair Not Possible.
4 Assault Bikes (2x Multimelta, 2x Heavy Bolter). Repair Not Possible.

Salvage/Recoveries said:

Dustboom Space Marine Recoveries Deemed Possible To Repair After Reconsecration By Martellus.
+4 Predator Hulls. All being used as orkish tanks.
+3 Rhino Hulls. All being used as orkish transports.
+5 Assault Bikes. Fused together into one monstrous vehicle by ork meks.
+1 Whirlwind Hull. Former component of a Gunfortress.
+2 Hunter Hulls. Former weapon hard-points of Mekboss Killdakka’s Ultrafortress.
+1 Vindicator Laser Destroyer. Former weapon hard-point of Mekboss Killdakka’s Ultrafortress.
+5 Predator Hull. Former weapon hard-points of Mekboss Killdakka’s Ultrafortress.

Shinehole Recoveries (Repaired To Functionality By Techmarines Calus And Daedal)
+5 Plasma Cannons.
+2 Power Axes.
+3 Multi-Melta Gun.
+2 Assault Cannons
+3 Power Swords
+2 Lascannons
+5 Plasma Pistols

Void Salvage Deemed ‘Reclamation Possible’ By Martellus
+1 Looted Strike Cruiser. Was being used as ork ‘kroozer’.
Multiple modifications: (Lance weapon, torpedo launchers, makrocannon broadsides, orkish powerfields, void shields, ‘Supa-Reakta’)

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Current Plans For Final Stage Of Engagement [Select One]:

[] Return To Aurelia: Your work here is essentially done. The ork leadership are all slain, the orks themselves scattered, with the vast majority of the work remaining being that of the colonists and those who will clear the way for them. There remains yet more in the galaxy to be done, and the Chapter has done much here. None can say otherwise, with Hadrian's masterful if reckless assault upon the orbitals on Dustboom, your defeat of Dakflash on Shinehole, and the work you did to reclaim the battleships above Spinesnap. This would certainly preserve the Chapter's forces completely, and as dangerously depleted as the Blood Ravens are, every casualty taken is damaging to the Chapter as a whole.
[] Recovery Efforts: None can deny what the Blood Ravens have accomplished in this Crusade. You should use this time, and focus the Chapter on recovery efforts for whatever astartes wargear and vehicles might be reclaimed for the purposes of the Chapter. So much was lost in the Purge. The chance to rebuild those stores in such an environment is a rare one, and should be taken advantage of. Your Blood Ravens might not be contributing as much to the fighting, but they still will be fighting as only space marines can as they traverse the theater.
[] Focus On The Enemy: While there are few great foes to slay now, what leadership remains fighting amongst themselves, there remain great swathes of the enemy still present. The chance to further prove yourselves to the rest of the Imperium before the Emperor's eyes is one you should take wholeheartedly. Though your wargear and vehicle pool was depleted, there remains more fighting to be done. While what might be recovered could be lost forever, you can build anew someday, while focusing on killing the enemy here and now. This will mean plunging into the remaining enemy territory.

Turn 19 (Part Seven): By Duty, Bring Death

Spoiler: Focus On The Enemy

[X] Focus On The Enemy: While there are few great foes to slay now, whatleadership remains fighting amongstthemselves, there remain great swathes of the enemy still present. The chance to further prove yourselves to the rest of the Imperium before the Emperor's eyes is one you should take wholeheartedly. Though your wargear and vehicle pool was depleted, there remains more fighting to be done. While what might be recovered could be lost forever, you can build anew someday, while focusing on killing the enemy here and now. This will mean plunging into the remaining enemy territory.

By Duty, Bring Death
+030.M42+ To +035.M42+
+Pain Now! Reward In The Afterlife!+

Greenkrump (Guard): 92
Shinehole (Guard/Mechanicus): 79
Spinesnap (Guard/Sororitas): 20
Dustboom (Guard/Mechanicus): 54

"Brothers. You fought well, all of you, regardless of where you were or why. None found you wanting. For the glory of the Chapter, we have driven back the alien!"

This is not Fenris, with its raucous celebrations. Nevertheless, the Blood Ravens stand tall, and though the expressions are somewhat mild among most, there is a fierce joy in your heart whether mechanical or not at the destruction you have levied against the enemy. A Recruiting World saved, and a new star system given into the light of the Imperium. Even as you left, you saw ships arriving carrying the specialized equipment and personnel to take the worlds reclaimed from the greenskins and transform them into proper bastions for humanity. Though you lost a precious tomb-brother, and more besides that without the chance for the sarcophagus, victory was achieved regardless. Further, based on the extremely wary approval of Cyrus, he believes that many of his scouts will be worthy of promotion to full battle brothers soon. Not immediately, but soon. You also find it heartening to say that for all of the distrust and hatred levied upon the Blood Ravens, the Imperial Guard is at least less struck by throttling hatred of you. Past disagreements and open violence between Blood Ravens and the Guard are a shameful thing, Victory Bay and Kaurava bringing naught but dark memories. The Navy is pleased that they have new battleships to their name, though the greater acknowledged heroes of the void battle - in boarders at least - over Spinesnap was the Order of the Lost Rosetta. They showed their fury on Spinesnap just as well.

Upon Greenkrump, the Blood Ravens appeared again and again out of the skies or through the jungles, saving Guardsmen as they fought against the orks infesting the world. Scouts weaned on Trontiux found their skills tested again, highly, by the battles against orks that could properly shoot back for once. They were not found wanting. Some Chapters might have ignored the Guard entirely during the battles, but you are the Blood Ravens. Time and again, you have seen the true worth of humanity, beyond the arms of the space marines. Hannibal too, believes this strongly. He does not profess a worship of the Emperor as a God, but he hails the Emperor's flock as his own. In his own words, 'Are they not the sons and daughters of the Emperor, as all humanity is? Are we not all his servants unto death?'. This serves you well on Greenkrump, where he openly interacts with the Guard, speaking freely with their priests and commissars, a giant of faith and devotion who leads and protects with both hands. For all that you are known in the Sector as tainted by Kyras' legacy, perhaps it is the fact that Hannibal's armor is black as the void, his helm a skull, heraldry of the Blood Ravens themselves sparse compared to his brothers. The fact that he does not immediately appear as a Blood Raven serves him well.

Upon Shinehole, the fighting in the tunnels went on. But the Blood Ravens have fought there for quite a while, and the Guard whisper of the mighty dreadnoughts who stomped forth bellowing litanies of hatred and strength against the alien, providing their own bodies as bulwarks. They talk of the two techmarines who were so much more...human, joking and laughing at each other. Never before has a guardsman of the Korianis Sector seen the Blood Ravens as such, so divergent from the aloof and distant stance taken by Kyras for centuries. Where they fear the psyker and mutant, something Kyras has only inflamed into barely concealed hatred for your Librarians, two techmarines conversing as they do was apparently comforting somehow. Or at least, that is what the scouts report from where they watch the Guard on rotated patrols. The Mechanicus is less pleased at their near-flippant nature, though they cannot do anything but respect the skill that these techmarines, Calus and Daedal, showed. From the various piles of stolen weaponry upon Shinehole, they strove to repair and reactivate numerous weapons that had found their way there over the centuries. Some were caked in decades of muck, others had been haphazardly attached to the equipment of ork meks. By now, whatever heraldry might have existed on these recovered weapons is completely worn away. Hopefully the machine spirits will be placated by being put into use once more. The fact that both Calus and Daedal showed themselves fully capable of becoming deathly serious when it comes to said machine spirits and sanctified technologies mollified many a tech-priest.

Upon Spinesnap, you found only grim silence rather than cheers from the Order of the Lost Rosetta. The Guard here were the most zealous of all encountered across the theater, practically screaming their throats bloody in chants to the Emperor alongside the sororitas. They took their cues of treatment for you from the Canoness as well. Things almost came to a head when an assault upon one of the few remaining ork holds resulted in the death of several scouts. When you came upon the scene, it was of a bloodied Margaret standing just over their bodies, unflinchingly staring at you as the apothecaries came forward to retake the bodies and retrieve their holy Gene-Seed. She offered no apologies, though it seemed that artillery fire came down at danger close, and offered no words of reverence for their death. On the other hand, she did not spit and curse your name, or purposefully damage the bodies of your slain brothers, at least as far as you could tell. In truth, it does not appear that it was an attack by the Lost Rosetta's artillery upon the Blood Ravens personally, but rather that they did not care to communicate with your forces at all - thus they were unaware of the incoming barrage and died for it. You did not demand that she answer for it, because it was just as likely that the ork explosives and mines in the area were responsible, as leading up to that point multiple ork explosives had been raining down across the entire valley. Whether it was the Guard, the Lost Rosetta, the Orks, or all three, scouts died. But the sheer violence inflicted in that place makes knowing who was responsible with certainty impossible, ork warpheads preventing any truly accurate scrying into the past.

Dustboom was...a middling effort. For the most part, Hadrian simply drove his tanks over the enemy, but the vast majority of attention on Dustboom was upon the Knights there. It is not a matter of hungering for glory like an aspirant would, but that your efforts were simply...marginalized somewhat. That, and the Mechanicus was not entirely pleased with how hard Hadrian pushed his company and their vehicle pool. The Guard was grateful as well, but overall the efforts there did not change much when it came to how the Blood Ravens were perceived compared to elsewhere across the Zemel System. Nevertheless, it was a good few years fought well.

"Chapter Master...?"

All of you turn to see a serf that quails at the sudden attention of almost the whole of the Chapter's leadership upon him. His face is pale in the extreme.

"Speak, young one."

"A...a message from Captain Hadrian, he says that...he needs to speak with you, all of you."

Slowly, one of your eyebrows raises, and you glance at the boy and back at the rest of your brothers.

"And he could not come himself?"

The serf jerkily shakes his head.

"Yes. He is...engaged in talks."

"With who, exactly?"

"The...Administratum and Mechanicus, Chapter Master. They have come to take the tithe."

Your cheer disappears entirely, and you can feel it leeching out of the rest of the room as well. Soon enough you are on the bridge where a sighing Hadrian sits upon the Command Throne of the Arcanum, facing the impassive and utterly unfeeling face of the Administratum's representative, who is joined by the Magos Biologis who has come as well. Two vessels, surrounded by escorts, hanging as a most unwelcome specter above Meridian.

"Chapter Master...Angelos," the adept pauses to check your name for the records, "As you know, at regular intervals all space marine chapters are to be compliant in giving away approximately 5% of their gene-seed stocks to check for purity. However, you have been remiss in your tithe for twice the normal interval - with the first missed interval taking place when your Chapter was under the control of the traitor known as Azariah Kyras. Furthermore, elements within the Inquisition have made it known that your chapter is to be held in suspect standing in certain regards. As such, we will require a full 20% of your gene-seed stocks; 5% for the first interval you were remiss in, another for this current interval, as well as another 10% due to additional concerns over the purity of your Chapter."

Their lack of faith in the Blood Ravens is infuriating, but you school your features. It would do nothing to protest this, only worsen matters for the Chapter if you resisted. That does not mean you are happy about it. Worse is when the adept and magos cluck their tongues at the state of your ships, as if seeing the heresy you forced out in every angle. You can only watch as their ships depart soon afterward, unfeeling gaze watching over you as you presented your entire precious stock, and suffered underneath their pointed questions about whether or not you were hiding more away. You are not Huron. This is not Badab. But it is a struggle you will be fighting likely into and beyond your own death, to restore the good name of the Blood Ravens to those forces who might otherwise destroy you. Instead, you elect to focus on the positives of the end of all of this.

There is more. There is always more, of course.

The Polonius Liberation Crusade is not yet done, for all that its first major phase has completed. There is yet more to be done in Subsector Polonius. The next target is the xeno civilization known as the Slaughra Swarm, which has...become interesting in the past few years. Originally a classified civilization, apparently this was done to ensure no interference was done during investigations by the Inquisition. An investigation that completed just as a nearby warp storm dissipated, revealing another star system which was lost to time and space for an unknowable stretch of time. The Slaughra Swarm are a strange tripod race, organic technologies, star ships, and ways were disturbingly reminiscent of tyranids. Apparently they may possess a genestealer cult in the depths of their government, or at least one system. The other recently revealed system bears the Slaughra Swarm as well, but unlike their more known peers, their ships are emblazoned with the sigils of Chaos. A civil war has begun between their race almost immediately, with the original system's Slaughra committing to war against the bloodthirsty Chaos-aligned Slaughra of the newly returned System Z04Y.

End Of Turn Results:
- 5 Scouts [1st Stage]. +10 Gene-Seed Recovered.
- 30 Gene-Seed For Tithe Purposes. Gene-Seed Stock Now At: 121
+ Polonius Liberation Crusade Objective: System Zemel Claimed. Relation Improvement Amongst Korianis Sector Command And Battlefleet Korianis
+ Polonius Liberation Crusade Next Objective: Slaughra Xeno Civilization Extermination And World Reclamation (Set To Begin At Start Of Turn 22)
+ Talon-Squad Patrols Meridian Underhive: Patrol highly productive, beasts and mutants cleansed. +1 Minor Favor From Governor Derosa.

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (Write-In Amount) [Note: Those selected will be unusable for any other purpose during the turn this option is selected i.e. 5 years.]
[] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien: The Deathwatch is being strained to the breaking point, by their own secretive messages to all Chapters in the galaxy who can hear them. Watch Fortresses and Stations are under assault, alien civilizations are rising in ever higher number, deadly threats are growing in severity and breadth. Normally only the best of the best marines would be given over to the Deathwatch, but out of sheer desperation the Ordos Xenos is loosening their standards in an uncharacteristic display of acceptance. That is, apparently, how bad the problem has gotten across every single Segmentum. Ordo Xenos Inquisitors are calling in favors, the Deathwatch is calling upon nearly every Chapter possible to send someone, anyone, as many space marines as possible. With such threats as the Black Crusade, the War for Armageddon, the Hive Fleets, all of the Deathwatch cannot hope to fight back against the apparent thousands of full-scale alien invasions of the Imperium going on across the galaxy without help. How could you possibly stand by and do nothing, in the face of this? (Write-In Additional Forces Sent To The Deathwatch)
[] Strike Cruiser Decision - The Strike Cruiser you retook from the orks has been tremendously modified, to a heretical extent. On the other hand, it is functional. You could not possibly simply use it again, it must be reconsecrated, and that means bringing it to the attention of the Mechanicus directly. However, who knows what they will require in exchange for its repair and reconsecration...or if they would allow its armaments to remain without change. You could attempt to bring it to Zerann or Aerus, both with the facilities you lack to rebuild it. It simply depends on which Fabricator General you believe would be better off seeing just what the orks have done. It is likely that they will require something in exchange. But there is little else to be done - you do not have anything yourself which could possibly handle the repair of an entire strike cruiser in such a state. (Select either Zerann or Aerus to be contacted for purposes of reclamation/reconsecration of reclaimed Strike Cruiser)
[] Zemel Continuation - While WAAAAAAGHH!!! Bonebreaka was stopped in its tracks, many orks remain within the Zemel System. The vast majority of the work is nothing nearly as intense as slaying Warbosses, Big Bosses, retaking Battleships, or otherwise. It is a painstaking culling, step by step, across four whole worlds. The Order of the Lost Rosetta is assisting in this, but the Blood Ravens could still contribute some forces there, though that would be entirely up to you. It might be better to try and preserve your brothers for the next step of the Polonius Liberation Crusade. [Write-In Forces Contributed For This Turn]
[] Polonius Communications - When you last arrived in Zemel, you had been explicitly not invited. Information on their plans were not shared. Sheer chaos demanded that you start providing rather forceful assistance and orders to get things moving once more. Hopefully your aid there regardless of anything else is enough for Sector Command to actually communicate with you on their plans for the next stage of the Polonius Reclamation Crusade, and things that the Blood Ravens could do to assist. Given what you have heard about the Slaughra Swarm, it would be prudent to see just what the Blood Ravens might be able to do against them to aid in the Crusade's efforts before something disastrous happens.
[] Regular Specialist Search - By now, you know well enough that rebuilding the ranks of the specialists of the Chapter is important indeed. Every time you gather aspirants from the Recruiting Worlds, it simply makes sense to regularly inspect them for candidates amongst the ranks of the apothecaries, techmarines, and chaplains. Making it part of the process should only help you in the rebuilding your chapter. [Specialist search becomes automated whenever recruitment is performed, as well as during progression along categories up to Scout [1st Stage] and beyond. Will include this turn if selected this turn.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (15 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (3 Total) with Gene-Seed.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- The Arcanum may have the largest of our Apothecarium, but it is the Potentia that possesses the most advanced, as befitting its name. This should aid in the works of the Apothecarium for its purposes in the future.

Justinius Probalis - Chief Librarian (LOCKED):
[] Request to recruit and train potential psyker aspirants from the Adeptus Astra Telepathica. High likelihood of successful training and implantation for recruits made in this manner.
[] Begin in-depth studies of the remains of the various eldar Avatars of Khaine possessed by the Chapter [Note: This will mean that all non-Company Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.] Will Complete At Start Of Turn 21 (045.M42 To 050.M42 Period)
[] Anti-Anti-Psyker Study: The Split Heart Kabal made strange xeno advances in the baffling, diffusing, and blocking of psyker powers and abilities. By making a study of such things, the Librarius of the Blood Ravens would be able to train its forces against such things, improving their ability to defeat such things in the future while providing an additional aid of likely effectiveness against the vile Eldar specifically. [Note: This will mean that all non-Chapter Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.]

Things To Consider - Justinius Probalis
- The latest combat against the daemons of the Judgement of Carrion has made me think on the daemonhammer that the Chapter Master wields. We could, perhaps, use more of such weapons. It was created using a shard of the weapon of an Avatar. Perhaps we could make some ourselves, if we studied it enough?
- The Chapter's greatest advantage was its Librarians. I know that they were used for...ill purpose in the past by Kyras, but I will not allow such a political character to be assigned to them ever again. We were meant for more than that. For the betterment of the Chapter, for its coming battles, and the maintenance of the Sanctorium Arcanum, we must rebuild our ranks, and soon.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (625 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/750] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Construct Forge Facilities On Company Flagships (Current/Former)
- [] The Faith's Horizon [0/500] to recieve an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Howling Hatred [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Rapier For Potential Learning Of Design To Allow Replication (WARNING: May end up losing some Rapiers as a result of the study) [355/???]
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [0/????]
[] Repair Disabled Predator Damaged On Dustboom [40 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [1]
[] Recovered Rhino Hulls Reconsecration And Repair [90 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [4]
[] Recovered Vindicator Laser Destroyer Reconsecration And Repair [50 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [1]
[] Recovered Looted Tank Predator Hulls Reconsecration And Repair – [250 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [7]
[] Recovered Ultrafortress Predator Hulls Reconsecration And Repair – [235 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [5]
[] Recovered Whirlwind Hull Reconsecration And Repair – [35 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [1]
[] Recovered Hunter Hulls Reconsecration And Repair – [80 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [2]
[] Recovered Assault Bikes Reconsecration And Repair – [50 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [5]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- Tremendous damage and desecration has been lambasted upon what we recovered from the orks of Bonebreaka’s WAAAGH!! They will require much work to remove the taint of the alien and reconsecrate, let alone repair. But if done, then the Chapter would benefit indeed.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- Thank goodness the Potentia has returned to service. Amongst the rest of the ships within the Chapter Fleet, it possesses the most advanced forge facilities, as befitting its name. This will surely aid me in construction of more advanced technologies in the future, as well as their study!
- THE RAPIER! Praise be to the Omnissiah! It is as if a Tarantula Turret which can move and maneuver, greatly increasing its chances of survival! Please, Chapter Master, allow me to study it, to learn its secrets, so that the design is not lost should they be destroyed!
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon The Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive
[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- With the arrival of many experienced 1st Company Sergeants, more Blood Trials can be enacted without Cyrus' direct observation.

Turn 20: Gathering Flock

Spoiler: Plan Lick Our Wounds

[X] Plan Lick Our Wounds
-[X] Chapter
--[X] Strike Cruiser Decision - Zerann
--[X] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage - Apothecary Constantius Romallius
--[X] Beneath Blood Raven Wings - Maintain 1st Company Squad Posting on Meridian
--[X] Zemel Continuation - Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos + Honor Guard, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, 1st Company & 1st Fleet, 5th Company & 5th Fleet, 10th Company & 10th Fleet + All vehicles as desired by Company Commanders
--[X] Polonius Communications
--[X] Regular Specialist Search
--[X] Use 1 Major Favor to gain 16 Thunderhawks (4 transport, 12 gunship) from Governor Derosa
-[X] Training
---[X] Angelos: Weapon Skill with Apollo
---[X] Chapter Main: Agility with Cyrus
---[X] Chapter Secondary: Weapon Skill with Apollo Diomedes
---[X] Chapter Secondary: Ballistic Skill with Hadrian
-[X] Apothecary
---[X] Implant Test-Slaves with 90 Geneseed
[x] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (15 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (3 Total) with Gene-Seed.
-[X] Librarius
---[X] Locked: Begin in-depth studies of the remains of the various eldar Avatars of Khaine possessed by the Chapter [Note: This will mean that all non-Chapter Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.] Will Complete At Start Of Turn 21 (045.M42 To 050.M42 Period)
-[X] Forge
--[X] Repair Disabled Predator Damaged On Dustboom [40BP]
--[X] Construct Castraferrum Dreadnought Chassis x2 [120BP]
--[X] Recovered Looted Tank Predator Hulls Reconsecration And Repair [250BP]
--[X] Recovered Vindicator Laser Destroyer Reconsecration And Repair [50BP]
--[X] Relic Plasma pistol for Hadrian Piscus [10 BP]
--[X] Study The Rapier For Potential Learning Of Design To Allow Replication [155BP]
-[X] Master of Recruits
--[X] Train the 10th in Zemel.
--[X] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds - Calderis, Meridian, Junius

Spoiler: 035.M42 To 040.M42

7 5th Company Battle Brothers Seconded To Deathwatch Slain, Gene-Seed Returned To Chapter. +5 Gene-Seed Recovered.

3 5th Company Veteran Battle Brothers Seconded To Deathwatch Slain, Gene-Seed Returned To Chapter. +6 Gene-Seed Recovered.
3 Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 3 to Lexicani.
15 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 10 To Scouts [1st Stage], Remainder Mutated Extensively, +2 Gene-Seed Recovered.
74 Scouts [1st Stage] Advance: 70 To Scouts [2nd Stage]. Remainder Expired. +8 Gene-Seed Recovered.
Intense Combat Has Proven Some Scouts [2nd Stage] Worthy Of Advancement. 20 Scouts [2nd Stage] Advance To Full Battle Brothers.
60 Aspirants Recruited -> 55 Aspirants Advance: 50 To Neophytes [1st Stage], Remainder Expired
50 Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 44 To Neophytes [2nd Stage], Remainder Expired/Given To Serfs/Servitorization Authorized. Gene-Seed Implantation Required Immediately.
10 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Notable As Specialist Possibles: 2 Apothecary/3 Chaplain/5 Techmarine. To be seconded if they survive gene-seed implantation.
7 Scouts [2nd Stage] Notable As Specialists: +4 Techmarine, +1 Apothecary, +2 Chaplain, All Sent To Training.
19 Psyker Aspirants Recruited -> 19 Psyker Aspirants Advance: 19 to Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage].
19 Psyker Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 15 Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage]. Remainder executed for mutation/corruption. Gene-Seed Implantation Required Immediately.
90 Gene-Seed Given To Test-Slaves. Harvest Available At Start Of Next Turn.
2 Techmarines Return Earlier Than Estimated: Brother Hestior And One Other.
[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 539+54+Apollo(29)=622/800]
[Chapter Training – Agility 4 To 5: 392+62+Cyrus(29)=483/500]
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill 4 To 5: 274+14+Apollo(29)=317/500]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill 5 to 6: 141+25+Hadrian(25)=191/600]
x16 Thunderhawks (x4 Transporters, 12 Gunships) Produced By Angel Forge

Gathering Flock
+035.M42+ To +040.M42+
+There Is No Darkness That The Emperor's Light Cannot Burn Away+

Hestior had barely put down his meager belongings before a wrench was tossed in his direction, though one of his mechadendrites still managed to catch it. He stared at the blazing heat of the forges, dozens of servo-skulls bouncing past with various tools in their attachments. Upon a predator, one techmarine slammed against it again and again, performing the holy percussive rites, while another fiddled with its treads. He didn't know which one of them had thrown the wrench, but he approached regardless. His companion who had been with him at Mars was similarly thrown at, and pointed towards one of the various vehicles strewn across the forge. For a moment he didn't see master Martellus anywhere, until he did. Atop a machine that Hestior only knew through story and pict-captures, the Master of the Forges was stabbing down with each of his five mechadendrites, illuminated by a shower of white hot sparks that almost completely obscured him. All of the techmarines in the forge slowed to a stop on their own work, before finally turning towards a noise that was at first barely audible which soon grew louder and louder. It was something not often heard in the forges of the Blood Ravens.

Martellus laughed, and laughed, and laughed.

"I. HAVE. DONE IT!"

He boomed his victory from atop the rapier, which began to shudder and glow as it activated successfully. A freshly painted Blood Raven was emblazoned just beneath the quad-bolter attachment. Leaping down hard enough to make the ground boom, Martellus raised his fists in victory before turning around so he could face his apparent creation. For a moment he chuckled before turning towards Hestior.

"Brother Hestior! Welcome home. I would have greeted you alongside the Chapter Master but...as you can see, I was somewhat distracted. Gather your tools, we have yet more to do."

Spoiler: Forge Results

Rapier Research Complete: 355+155=510/505.
+1 Quad-Bolter Rapier To Vehicle Pool.
Rapiers Are Now Possible To Build.
(62/100) Disabled Predator Restored Successfully.
x2 Castraferrum Chassis Built
(31/52/40/59/78/85/69 Out Of 1d100) of 7 Looted Predators Restored. 1 declared irreparable.
(80/100) Vindicator Laser Destroyer Restored.
Relic Plasma Pistol Crafted For Hadrian Priscus: 10/BP Cost. 1d100=95. Relic Crafted: The Hand Of Aggression. Details added to Hadrian's character sheet/Relic Page.

In Zemel, the Blood Ravens come, hailed by its colonists as heroes. On Veridius, once known as Greenkrump, the entire might of the Chapter – such as it is – destroys almost any chance for the greenskins to rally at all. Orks are killed in great droves. There are dozens of scout ambushes, tank assaults, and gunship bombing runs which tear apart the disorganized orks. By the end, there are almost no feral orks left alive on the planet, completely eradicating the threat of the Snakebite-aligned orks upon the world. Those of the Goffs are given similar treatment. From the thanks of the Imperials involved, you learn that through your actions the Blood Ravens have leapfrogged colonization completion estimation by several decades. However, tearing apart the entire jungle is something that you have no equipment at all for, much less plowing fields. With the Guard and Order of the Lost Rosetta thusly able to turn themselves to focus more fully upon Pella, Palmyra, and Aigai – formerly known as Dustboom, Spinesnap, and Shinehole.

During this fighting, you also receive information from grateful leadership amongst the Guard about what the plans are for the rest of the Polonius Subsector. The Slaughra are a vile xeno race – as all xeno are – and must be put down. However, there is almost no information on this new section of the Swarm which has sworn to Chaos. With the warp storm dissipating and revealing a new star system, estimates and plans have thoroughly been thrown out the window to make way for new ones. Decades of information gathering had been prepared for what was assumed to be the only Slaughra in existence, but almost no information has been gathered – or can be – on this new section of the Swarm. The Guard made subtle – for them – remarks that such a dangerous task might be something the Blood Ravens could assist with. In addition, there are numerous high priority targets in the section of the Swarm which has been confirmed to be controlled by an extremely widespread genestealer cult. What you do with this information is, of course, entirely up to you. Some amongst the 10th Company are even worth promoting to full battle brother as a result of their experiences, Cyrus tells you. Of less favorable news, however, you receive a remarkably low crop of aspirants from your Recruiting Worlds for some reason. Apparently too many children were above or below the right age to partake in the Blood Trials. Hopefully the next cycle will prove better.

Spoiler: Polonius Results

- 1d4=3. Greenkrump/Viridius
- 87. No casualties. Multiple victories.
- 10th Company Training: 69.

=======================================

“By the Omnissiah, damn those xenos! Damn them to the depths of cogitator cascades!”

Phokas slams a fist against the wall, only to nearly wretch in disgust at the flaking ork paint which comes off as a result of the physical assault. The Fabricator-General had made it just inside of the reclaimed ship before falling to his knees from the sheer desecration it had suffered. A dozen engineseers disappeared into the depths of the ship as well, while five magos did the same, leaving the Phokas alone with his two dozen servo skulls. Though you suppose he cannot actually retch without having a throat, he did make the noise of a machine equivalent. After another rude noise from his vocoder, he stands, dusting himself off, and strides over to you.

“This vessel has been transformed into an abomination. The modifications obscene. However…”

“However,” you repeat, knowing what is coming.

“Zerann is completely inundated with repair orders have that fiasco of a void battle that occurred in the Polonius Subsector. We are the premier shipyard in Korianis, after all. Aerus might have begun immediately, but of course you came here instead,” Phokas says with pride before pausing.

He scrapes at the ground for a moment with a metallic claw that has replaced his foot, before looking up at you again.

“However. If the Blood Ravens were to grant us some aid in protecting our shipments to and from elsewhere across the Sector throughout this repair process, it would make things more efficient and certain for us. There have been a mixture of orkish pirates and eldar corsairs in the area – striking just after they sent a fleet to Zemel.”

Ah.

“In point of fact, Chapter Master, given the nature of our ongoing relationship, we might wish to speak of a more permanent posting in exchange for diverting our own resources to a mutually appreciable conclusion.”

The translation being the exchange of favors. As it always is.

Reconsecration And Repair Of Recovered Strike Cruiser Cost
2 Major Favors From Forge World Zerann and/or Aerus.
OR
5 Minor Favors
OR
1 Major Favor And 3 Minor

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (Write-In Amount) [Note: Those selected will be unusable for any other purpose during the turn this option is selected i.e. 5 years.]
[] Assign 20 New Battle Brothers To Companies (Write-In Battle Brother Allotment)
[] Assign 16 Thunderhawks (x4 Transporters, x12 Gunship) Within Chapter Fleet (Write-In)
[] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien: The Deathwatch is being strained to the breaking point, by their own secretive messages to all Chapters in the galaxy who can hear them. Watch Fortresses and Stations are under assault, alien civilizations are rising in ever higher number, deadly threats are growing in severity and breadth. Normally only the best of the best marines would be given over to the Deathwatch, but out of sheer desperation the Ordos Xenos is loosening their standards in an uncharacteristic display of acceptance. That is, apparently, how bad the problem has gotten across every single Segmentum. Ordo Xenos Inquisitors are calling in favors, the Deathwatch is calling upon nearly every Chapter possible to send someone, anyone, as many space marines as possible. With such threats as the Black Crusade, the War for Armageddon, the Hive Fleets, all of the Deathwatch cannot hope to fight back against the apparent thousands of full-scale alien invasions of the Imperium going on across the galaxy without help. How could you possibly stand by and do nothing, in the face of this? (Write-In Additional Forces Sent To The Deathwatch)
[] Zemel Continuation - While WAAAAAAGHH!!! Bonebreaka was stopped in its tracks, many orks remain within the Zemel System. The vast majority of the work is nothing nearly as intense as slaying Warbosses, Big Bosses, retaking Battleships, or otherwise. It is a painstaking culling, step by step, across four whole worlds. The Order of the Lost Rosetta is assisting in this, but the Blood Ravens could still contribute some forces there, though that would be entirely up to you. It might be better to try and preserve your brothers for the next step of the Polonius Liberation Crusade. [Write-In Forces Contributed For This Turn]
[] Slaughra Swarm Sabotage (Genestealer-Affliliated): Before the warp storm faded away, this was the only potion of the Slaughra Swarm known to be in existence. Inquisitorial information gathering has confirmed the presence of a genestealer cult in command of this portion of this xeno race. While the forces of the Sector ready themselves, they have allowed for the possibility that sabotage efforts against their shipyards would be most welcome before the actual assault begins in a few more years. The current greatest threat to the Crusade will be coming from their space-borne assets, and denying the enemy of as many of them as possible would do well. With the Swarm distracted with their Chaos-affiliated cousins, this is an opportune time to take advantage of their backs being turned. [Write-In Forces Contributed This Turn]
[] Slaughra Swarm Subterfuge (Chaos-Affiliated): Recently revealed by a warp storm dissipating, this portion of the Slaughra Swarm is potentially even more dangerous than their genestealer-led cousins. Daemons walk on their worlds, and their ships are notably tainted by the Dark Powers. There is little information on their force projection capabilities, nor what they have back on their worlds. Information gathering would be incredibly dangerous, but dangerous deeds such as these are exactly what the space marines were made for. Sector Command cannot know how much forces will need to be committed without that information. [Write-In Forces Contributed This Turn]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Requests On Hand To Have Strike Cruiser Repaired (Repairs Do Not Begin Without Accepting At Least One Of The Below):
(2 Major OR 5 Minor OR 1 Major and 3 Minor)

[] In-Sector Fleet Protection (Major): While the ships of the space marines are not meant for much void combat, they are still a powerful multiplier thanks to their own boarding teams. Recent pirate attacks across the sector mean that the Mechanicus would appreciate the seconding of one of the Chapter’s Company Fleets – 1st, 4th, 5th, or 10th – to protect convoys of vital war material to ensure the repair and rearming of both the Guard and the Navy. The Company chosen would be unable to participate in other matters, obviously, until the task is done, and the next phase of the Polonius Crusade begins. It would also provide chances for assigned Company to assist in other matters as required. (Write-In Company Chosen) [Assignment Lasts Until Start Of Turn 22] [May also result in gaining Minor Favors too]
[] Explorator Exchange (Major): Another of Zerann’s three Explorator Fleets is finally ready to depart into the unknown across the galaxy. Last time, Doukas and his brothers made for a fine aid to said fleet in its dangerous journeys. Another squad could be seconded again, though their time of return – or return at all – would be unknown. They would require an apothecary to go with them, if only to ensure that any lost gene-seed is properly preserved. [Assignment Duration Unknown]
[] Other Minor Favors: The secondment of squads to other purposes of which might be unknown at this time would also work. There is always work to be done, and once given a squad the Fabricator-General will surely figure out something for them to be doing that can benefit the Mechanicus well. Perhaps a specific convoy protected, an outpost checked up on, etc. The survivability of the squads is not necessarily guaranteed, as rogue machines, pirates, etc. might become involved at any moment. (Write-In 2 Squads Per Minor Favor Wished To Be Gained, i.e. 2 Squads = 1 Minor Favor Completed)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (44 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (15 Total) with Gene-Seed.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- The Arcanum may have the largest of our Apothecarium, but it is the Potentia that possesses the most advanced, as befitting its name. This should aid in the works of the Apothecarium for its purposes in the future.

Justinius Probalis - Chief Librarian (LOCKED):
[] Request to recruit and train potential psyker aspirants from the Adeptus Astra Telepathica. High likelihood of successful training and implantation for recruits made in this manner.
[] Begin in-depth studies of the remains of the various eldar Avatars of Khaine possessed by the Chapter [Note: This will mean that all non-Company Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.] Will Complete At Start Of Turn 21 (045.M42 To 050.M42 Period)
[] Anti-Anti-Psyker Study: The Split Heart Kabal made strange xeno advances in the baffling, diffusing, and blocking of psyker powers and abilities. By making a study of such things, the Librarius of the Blood Ravens would be able to train its forces against such things, improving their ability to defeat such things in the future while providing an additional aid of likely effectiveness against the vile Eldar specifically. [Note: This will mean that all non-Chapter Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.]

Things To Consider - Justinius Probalis
- The latest combat against the daemons of the Judgement of Carrion has made me think on the daemonhammer that the Chapter Master wields. We could, perhaps, use more of such weapons. It was created using a shard of the weapon of an Avatar. Perhaps we could make some ourselves, if we studied it enough?
- The Chapter's greatest advantage was its Librarians. I know that they were used for...ill purpose in the past by Kyras, but I will not allow such a political character to be assigned to them ever again. We were meant for more than that. For the betterment of the Chapter, for its coming battles, and the maintenance of the Sanctorium Arcanum, we must rebuild our ranks, and soon.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (575 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/750] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Construct Forge Facilities On Company Flagships (Current/Former)
- [] The Faith's Horizon [0/500] to recieve an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Howling Hatred [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [0/????]
[] Recovered Rhino Hulls Reconsecration And Repair [90 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [4]
[] Recovered Ultrafortress Predator Hulls Reconsecration And Repair – [235 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [5]
[] Recovered Whirlwind Hull Reconsecration And Repair – [35 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [1]
[] Recovered Hunter Hulls Reconsecration And Repair – [80 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [2]
[] Recovered Assault Bikes Reconsecration And Repair – [50 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [5]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- Tremendous damage and desecration has been lambasted upon what we recovered from the orks of Bonebreaka’s WAAAGH!! They will require much work to remove the taint of the alien and reconsecrate, let alone repair. But if done, then the Chapter would benefit indeed.
- We should probably build more Tarantula turrets.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- Thank goodness the Potentia has returned to service. Amongst the rest of the ships within the Chapter Fleet, it possesses the most advanced forge facilities, as befitting its name. This will surely aid me in construction of more advanced technologies in the future, as well as their study!
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon The Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive
[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- With the arrival of many experienced 1st Company Sergeants, more Blood Trials can be enacted without Cyrus' direct observation.

Turn 21: To Go And Vanquish

Spoiler: Plan Back To Work

[X] Plan Back to Work
-[X] Chapter
--[X] Train Falkor Ryll In Terminator Armor Usage
--[X] Assign 20 New Battle Brothers To 4th Company
--[X] Assign New Thunderhawks to Fleet (Summary: All Flagships to 3x/3x Gunships and Transports, all other ships to 3x Gunships)
---[X] Assign 1x Gunship, 1x Transport Thunderhawks to 1st Fleet Battle Barge Omnis Arcanum
---[X] Assign 1x Gunship Thunderhawk to 1st Fleet Strike Cruiser Ravenous Spirit
---[X] Assign 1x Gunship Thunderhawk to 1st Fleet Strike Cruiser Spiraling Fury
---[X] Assign 2x Gunship, 1x Transport Thunderhawks to 4th Fleet Battle Barge Scientia Est Potentia
---[X] Assign 1x Gunship Thunderhawk to 4th Fleet Strike Cruiser Burning Seeker
---[X] Assign 1x Gunship, 1x Transport Thunderhawks to 5th Fleet Battle Barge Litany of Fury
---[X] Assign 1x Gunship Thunderhawk to 5th Fleet Strike Cruiser Rage of Erudition
---[X] Assign 1x Gunship Thunderhawk to 5th Fleet Strike Cruiser Great Father's Fist
---[X] Assign 2x Gunship, 1x Transport Thunderhawks to 10th Fleet Strike Cruiser Faith's Horizon
---[X] Assign 1x Gunship Thunderhawk to 10th Fleet Strike Cruiser The Howling Hatred
--[X] Contact Fabricator-General/Magos Prime Theodosia|Forgeworld Aerus in hopes of negotiating work starting 045.M42 for construction of suits of Terminator Armor
--[X] Slaughra Swarm Subterfuge (Chaos-Affiliated) - 10th Fleet, 10th Company + Leadership, 1st pick of necessary vehicles as requested by Company leadership
--[X] Other Zerann Strike Cruiser Minor Favors - 10 Squads for 5 Minor Favors, begin and fully pay for Strike Cruiser repair
---[X] 1st Company Squad + 4th Company Squad + 1st Company Apothecary Constantius Romallius + Chaplain + Codicier + 1 1st Company Dreadnought
---[X] 1st Company Squad + 4th Company Squad + Apothecary + Chaplain Antonius + Lexicanium + 1 1st Company Dreadnought + 1st Company Captain Marcus Crixus
---[X] 1st Company Squad + 4th Company Squad + 4th Company Apothecary Caeser + Chaplain Ravius + Codicier + 1 1st Company Dreadnought
---[X] 1st Company Squad + 4th Company Squad + Apothecary + 4th Company Chaplain Ateren + Lexicanium + 1 1st Company Dreadnought + 4th Company Captain Hadrian Priscus
---[X] 1st Company Squad + 5th Company Squad + Apothecary + 1st Company Chaplain Ares Actus + Lexicanium + 1 1st Company Dreadnought + 1st Company Champion Uriel Hamul
--[X] Zemel Continuation - Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos + Honor Guard, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, 1st Fleet, 5th Fleet + Unassigned 5th Company + Leadership, Specialists with no other assignment. Vehicles assigned as requested by Company/Chapter leadership.
-[X] Training
---[X] Angelos: Weapon Skill with Apollo
---[X] Chapter Main: Weapon Skill with Apollo Diomedes
---[X] Chapter Secondary: Agility with Cyrus
---[X] Chapter Secondary: Ballistic Skill with Hadrian
-[X] Apothecary
--[X] Implant Specialist Neophytes [2nd Stage] (10 Total) with Gene-Seed.
--[X] Implant Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (15 Total) with Gene-Seed.
--[X] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (27/34) with Gene-Seed.
-[X] Librarius
--[X] Locked: Begin in-depth studies of the remains of the various eldar Avatars of Khaine possessed by the Chapter [Note: This will mean that all non-Chapter Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.] Will Complete At Start Of Turn 21 (045.M42 To 050.M42 Period)
-[X] Forge
--[X] Recovered Rhino Hulls Reconsecration And Repair [90 BP]
--[X] Recovered Assault Bikes Reconsecration And Repair [50 BP]
--[X] Recovered Whirlwind Hull Reconsecration And Repair [35 BP]
--[X] Recovered Hunter Hulls Reconsecration And Repair [80 BP]
--[X] Construct 3x Psychic Hoods [30 BP]
--[X] Relic Construction
---[X] Crozius Arcanum for Hannibal Palrun [38 BP]
--[X] Construct Forge Facilities On The Faith's Horizon [252 BP]
-[X] Master of Recruits
--[X] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds - Calderis, Meridian, Junius

Spoiler: 040.M42 To 045.M42

90 Implanted For Test-Slave Harvest In 035.M42. Harvest At Beginning Of Turn 21. Harvest = 180 Gene-Seed Harvested. Full Harvest!
Avatar Of Khaine Study Complete! Details Within Rest Of Post.
200 Aspirants Recruited -> 200 Aspirants Advance: 170 To Neophytes [1st Stage], Remainder Expired/Given To Serfs.
165 Neophytes [1st Stage] Advance: 147 To Neophytes [2nd Stage], Remainder Expired/Given To Serfs/Servitorization Authorized. Gene-Seed Implantation Required Immediately.
27 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 25 To Scouts [1st Stage], Remainder Expired. +2 Gene-Seed Reclaimed. 7 Neophytes Too Old For Implantation, Removed To Serfs.
10 Scouts [1st Stage] Advance: 10 To Scouts [2nd Stage].
33 Scouts [2nd Stage] Advance: 25 To Full Battle Brothers, Remainder Expired In Turn Operations. +16 Gene-Seed Reclaimed.
15 Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 12 to Lexicani. Remainder Fell To Mutation/Corruption. Gene-Seed Unreclaimable.
10 Specialist Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 1 Apothecary/2 Chaplains/3 Techmarines Seconded To Training. Remainder Expired. +4 Gene-Seed Reclaimed.
6 Lexicanum have shown increased strength and aptitude to control it. Promoted To Codicier.
Nero Achillian has shown improved control and power, and has been promoted to Epistolary. Has further shown aptitude as a Daemonologist due to specifics of study and promotion.
[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 622+10+Apollo(29)=661/800]
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill 4 To 5: 317+14+Apollo(29)=360/500]
[Chapter Training – Agility 4 To 5: 483+30+Cyrus(29)=549/500] Current Agility Cap Reached.
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill 5 to 6: 191+42+Hadrian(25)=258/600]
2 Apothecaries Complete Training. 2 Chaplains Complete Training.
Strike Cruiser Reconsecration/Rebuild Begun: Completion Estimate: Start Of Turn 23.
NOTE: Polonius Reclamation Crusade To Continue Starting Next Turn.

To Go And Vanquish
+040.M42+ To +045.M42+
+Pain And Death Are Illusions Of The Weak Mind.+

The 10th Company did its grim work, and did it without complaint.

Five worlds, an asteroid belt that seemed to be conflicted between being simple rock and an organic massive rope which stretched across the entire system, and a fleet of locust-like ships. Daemon vessels flitted through the void alongside more mundane ships that were nonetheless steadily being corrupted simply by exposure. One planet had become a full daemon world, the ‘capital’ of these Chaos-worshipping xenos. The dual corruption of the Slaughra and the touch of Chaos were more than enough for the Guard and Navy and Inquisition – which Cyrus tells you he suspects will be present – to authorize Exterminatus upon that world.

Upon those worlds, factories where endless amounts of Slaughra were entered, and few came out. Flesh and metal fused together, daemons throughout, and a significant amount of warp taint. Xeno sorcerers bend the lands to their will, erecting portals to summon forth more of their daemonic masters. There is no sign of humanity on these worlds, not any longer if there ever had been, nor of the Traitor Legions. Somewhat frustratingly, they serve Chaos Undivided, as near as Cyrus can tell. While the 10th lost some to their efforts, the information is crucial when it comes to the coming extermination. The Capital World possesses numerous temples to all of the Chaos Gods, with the other four worlds given over to one God each.

One world is dedicated to Khorne, with vast arenas upon it made from the bones of its gladiators, where they clash endlessly in an orgy of violence. They hone their skills upon these worlds, and eagerly await the ships which will swoop down to allow them to board, and then throw themselves into battle against their cousins from the other half of the Slaughra Swarm. Their cities are violent places, but factories as well. Industrious xenos, the Swarm is, whether controlled by Chaos or a gene-stealer cult.

Another is dedicated to Nurgle, one to Slaanesh, and finally one to Tzeentch. All reflect the nature of the God who rules the world most strongly, yet there is little sign of the usual infighting that one might hope for. Something to be concerned with in the long run, more likely than not. Cyrus also managed to note the presence of multiple shipyards, with each world possessing a small smattering of ships above them as well. With the powers of the Warp on their side, they do not need to follow the laws of physics when it comes to material production and application, with ships actually growing out of the rotting hulk of flesh which might once have been a void whale which sits above the world which clearly worships the Plague God. On the world which worships Tzeentch, there are crystalline spires channeling endless storms of lightning and thus obscuring the world below.

Cyrus did not dare try to force his scouts closer to their capital world, not with the defenses it possesses and the size of his Company. But he could observe enough. Orbital defenses, sorcerous and technological shielding, and factories producing both weapons and vehicles from within bastions of blighted stone and steel. It will certainly be a harder fight than Bonebreaka might have been, you think. But this new information has been welcomed by Sector Command, which is going to be upgrading the threat response levels accordingly. Unfortunately, the 10th Company wasn't able to perform much sabotage works, with simply too many ships and defenses present for him to think it would be anything but pointless suicide. If there had been a point, you know he would have done it immediately. But the end point is this, the Slaughra Swarm under the control of Chaos is actually capable of defeating their cousins, and will likely do so if not stopped eventually. They have more ships and more troops, but Cyrus recommends letting them get further. In point of fact, if they actually do over-extend, then they would leave their worlds exposed, and their rear to be taken apart. Something to that effect, at least.

The Reclamation Crusade is set to advance soon, you know this. This new information has divided Sector Command somewhat, however, and you do not know for sure what they intend to do with this new information. In five years time, however, you suppose you will find out.

=======================================

The Librarius have always kept certain secrets close to their chest. It is in their nature. Some things must be known only by those who can withstand the knowledge itself. Still, much of that secrecy worked against them when Kyras came to corrupt and kill all he could in the service of Chaos. A few orders, proclamations of missing and slain Librarians instead simply being in ‘seclusion’ or ‘meditation’, and much of the Chapter’s most notable feature was stripped from it. But Justinius has proven himself time and again since the Purge. And now, he has called you and much of the rest of the Chapter’s higher leadership to see the results of his work. As you approach the Librarium, the air chills, and frost appears to have coated the walls along with sigils which have been engraved in the halls themselves.

With a whining hiss, the bulkhead door, similarly engraved, slowly opens. The temperature here is unnatural, likely even below what is normally best for preservation of texts and artifacts. Yet perhaps that is the point of things. With the closing of the door, a palpable wave of power washes over you. It is joined by one you recognize, a psychically reactive cloth wrapped about his head to cover his eyes. Despite possessing bionic replacements, Nero Achillian does not necessarily need them. He hasn’t for quite some time now. Regardless, the Codicier – no, not a Codicier. He is…more than that, now.

“Chapter Master,” he bows to you slightly, “Welcome.”

“Brother Nero. Tell me…have you advanced in rank?”

“Well spotted, Chapter Master,” Nero smiles slightly, “Yes. I was promoted to Epistolary on the authority of the Chief Librarian for my aid in…well. Our work.”

Martellus’ mechadendrites close about his body as you enter, the sensation of psychic power filling the air an uncomfortable one. You ignore the sensation of something crawling just beneath your skin, a minor manifestation of what has been done here for years now. As you approach a side chamber, away from all of this, you see a bevy of Lexicanum wandering past, chattering to themselves in an endless drone as they catalogue and review every single piece of information that exists in the vast Librarium of the chapter’s flagship.

“Justinius,” you nod at your Chief Librarian, who nods back in turn. “What have you discovered?”

“Power,” is his simplistic reply, before he pulls off a cloth and several chains from a large black slab of stone.

They lie before you, five blocks of strange psychically charged material, something akin to stone and steel in equal measure.

“We studied the construction of Godsplitter, and with such…an excess of the Avatars,” Justinius’ voice is somewhere between incredulous and awestruck, “Believe that we can replicate it. In limited number, of course, but it…should be possible.”

The power of Godsplitter simply cannot be understated. It is a daemonhammer, made for and with the intent of shattering the powers of the warp. It excels in this, and is thus far removed from a simple thunder hammer. The possibility of the Chapter having access to similar weaponry is something valuable indeed. Or, though you loathe to think of such politicking, as something worthy of trade with others. Perhaps with the Inquisition. Perhaps. Still, another thought strikes you.

“But there were far more than just the remains of the Wailing Dooms,” you murmur.

Justinius simply smiles again.

“Indeed. We believe…that…with careful hands, we might create…well, something similar.”

“Anti-daemon armor?”

“Talismans, marks, perhaps. Nero posited if we could perhaps create a network about a ship’s hull to resist the Warp itself during travel to allow faster and less risky delvings into the immaterium out of it’s armor.”

The newly promoted Epistolary coughs at the mention of his name, and looks away when you turn to look at him.

“It was an idle thought, Justinius. And I only had it because of the sheer abundance of materials.”

“Regardless,” Justinius presses a hand against the slab, “These five shards can be used safely. Much was used up or destroyed in the process of our study, but with these I believe we can create something of note indeed.”

===============================

"So what happened here," Martellus ground out, holding the terrifyingly loud crozius in his hands.

He was no Master of Sanctity or Chaplain, but that didn't mean he didn't know how to hit things with the end of the weapon meant for violence. The techmarines quailed before the audible creaking of ceramite against metal, the noise coming from a tightening grip on the crozius. Like a looming god, the Master of the Forge stood atop the Whirlwind he'd restored personally and stared at his subordinates. There was no sign of Daedal or Calus, for they had successfully completed their own works without utterly ruining it. But these ones...no. He let out a bark of angry binary cant, and finally they responded. Of misplaced components, of missing tools, of accidents, and of proclaimed unseen structural weaknesses. Some were legitimate excuses, others were not. The end result, even if he bludgeoned them all to death, would be the same despite the grief their actions had brought him. In the end, he sent them away to scrub the walls and floors with actual bristle brushes, servitor work in essence. Sighing, he left the forges and headed for another section of the ship, hefting the weapon he'd crafted in his hands repeatedly.

"Martellus, my brother, how fares the day?" Hannibal greeted him with a boom - or rather it might be better to say that he simply spoke at the volume to which the orator was accustomed.

"Worse than I'd hoped, better than I'd feared. I present something to you as well, my friend."

"Magnificent," Hannibal murmured.

Spoiler: Forge Results

(5/24/46/39 Out Of 1d100) of 4 Looted Rhinos Restored. All 4 Declared Irreparable.
(80/100) Looted Whirlwind Restored.
(58/3 Out Of 1d100) of Looted Hunters Restored. 1 Declared Irreparable.
(28/77/62/15/53 Out Of 1d100) Of Looted Assault Bikes Restored. 2 Declared Irreparable.
In total: 1 Whirlwind, 1 Hunter, 3 Assault Bikes Given To Chapter Vehicle Pool.
x3 Psychic Hoods Built.
Relic Crozius Arcanum Crafted For Hannibal Palrun: 38 BP Cost. 1d100=92. Relic Crafted: Thunder Blood. Details added to Hannibal's character sheet/Relic Page.
252 BP To Faith's Horizon Forge Construction: 252/500

============================

Pella. Or, once upon a time, Dustboom. Here, Hadrian Priscus made his first name as a Captain, leading his forces in a series of crushing assaults and daring strikes across the surface of this world. Yet he also showed his intelligence, despite not being the most cool-headed of Blood Ravens after losing forces to the Ultrafortress of Mekboss Killdakka, and instead elected to preserve the greater theater by assaulting the orbital cannons. Where he found success, so too do the Blood Ravens once more. Victory here is a bit more difficult to achieve considering what the orks possess, at least compared to the orks of Viridius. Still, you possess a stronger core of vehicles than you did before, and even some of the reclaimed tanks are used in this. Predators once forced into service by the orks are able to wreak vengeance. Their Machine Spirits slake their rage on the blood of the greenskins thoroughly. The Guard appreciates your efforts here considerably, though the Order of the Lost Rosetta does not. They are even managing to find themselves leaving the planet and heading towards Palmyra and Aigai in force as your forces arrive in system. Is it because of their sheer distaste for you, or because they simply thought they would be better off contributing elsewhere? Something tells you it is a combination of the two. At the least, they are not outright shooting at your forces.

The planet that was once Dustboom is set to become quite the industrious world, given enough time. That you have aided in this course is a welcome thought, compared to the darkness that surrounds much of the rest of the galaxy.

Spoiler: Polonius Results

- 1d3=1. Dustboom/Pella
- 76. No casualties. Some victories.

========================

“Die, heretic!”

The dreadnought may not have pronounced the word precisely correctly, but none took the time to correct them. For the screaming blasphemer of the Omnissiah was technically a heretic. While the traitorous techpriest flailed about, the dreadnought slammed them down, and then applied the prodigious weight of their entire massive sarcophagus to stomp down and crush them entirely. All around them, the Blood Ravens fired without pause into the oncoming daemon-machines, and slaughtered them in turn. Constantinus fired his bolt pistol carefully, whirling about and dragging his chainsword through a possessed menial’s body.

“Inform the techpriests that we found their erstwhile peer,” he called on the vox, voice as calm as the grave.

Heretek Killed On Zerann, Minor Heretek Cult Exterminated.

===================================

“Aw, come on! It wuz supposed tah be easy!”

The Kaptin died lamenting the destruction of his ‘beautiful’ kroozer when Marcus shot him in the face. All of the thickened armor and heavy metal jawplate crunched inwards, crushing the ork’s head to pulp. All across the rest of the bridge, the orks died or fled before the unrelenting fury of the Blood Ravens. A steady pulse of planted explosives across the ship were a welcome tempo, and soon enough the squads began to retreat for the thunderhawks. A Lexicanium screamed in fury, lightning exploding out of his fingertips, their first time out of the Librarius a mighty crucible for them indeed.

“Status on the transports?”

“Preserved, Captain. The Magos passes on his thanks for our boarding and distraction allowing them to flee.”

Valuable War Material Transport Escorted. Ork Pirate Kroozer Destroyed.

=================================

"What...oh. Those are my organs," the marine gurgled, surprise in his voice.

Newly promoted from the 10th Company, not a single year as a true battle brother, and his chest had been split open like an egg. The screaming machine had turned away, however, forced to in fact by the gripping claws of the dreadnought it now grappled with. For a wonder, the marine simply stared, holding one of his hearts in one hand and a lung in the other, before the apothecary approached at a loping gait. The surface of Aerus was pacified, yes, but occasionally some small remnant of past came to the fore. For instance, in manners such as this. A small incursion compared to what was once suffered, and there are fewer every year, but this happened to be near where the Blood Ravens had come. It was not precisely possessed by a daemon, but rather had been transformed by errant scrap code, still floating here and there in the noosphere despite repeated scrubbings by the Mechanicus.

"Hello brother Caesar," the marine said far more casually than he probably should have, "I appear to be...hmm. Am I dying?"

"Only a little," Caesar growled, shoving the held organs back into the body, tools whirring to life on his armor. "Now hold still. This is going to hurt."

"I just had my chest cavity opened, how - GNGAAAGGH!"

Minor Corrupted Machine Incursion On Aerus Cleansed.

==============================

"Captain, the parade is over, I believe that our job here is done."

"...Captain?"

Hadrian blinked and turned to look at Ateren, and then back at where the parade ground was no longer as full and loud as it had been before. Slowly he dialed the settings back to default on his helmet, allowing the previously deafening crowds to return to his ears, though he was happy to note they were not as deafening as before. The marching Titans had finished, and there was no longer any need for the Blood Ravens to appear as ornamentation beneath the twinned banners of Aerus and Zerann. While neither of the Forge Worlds actually possessed a Legio of their own, they did, after all, have a closer friendship with an honest-to-the-Emperor space marine chapter as allies. What Hadrian was less keen on was the fact that he and his forces were being used as saber rattling...or whatever passed for it amongst the Mechanicus. Besides which, it was a smaller Titan Legion, eager for glory, hence why they had come at all and would soon be delivering themselves to the Polonius Subsector.

Diplomatic Balance Maintained Between Local Mechanicus Elements Against Foreign Mechanicus Elements.

=============================

Hamul didn't particularly care what the Mechanicus was doing out here, or about how suspicious the Magos was being. He'd been sent here for a reason, and intended to do it. One would think, he mused as he cut down the ork in front of him, that they would be grateful that the Blood Ravens had shown up at all. There was little doubt that there really were plenty of 'shiny bits' within the isolated station, but he had no intentions on them. Perhaps it was the way the skitarii guards had been slaughtered by the orks that was why they were so wary. At least the codes given to him by Zerann were enough to prove their identity and allow them to provide aid. Pistol booming, he dodged back from one wild swing from a nob and drove his chainsword along its throat at the same time.

"The orks should be cleared out soon, Magos. So either you open the bay doors, Hal-2124, or we will be forced to open them ourselves and then tell Zerann what kept us."

Mechanicus Outpost Safeguarded.

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (Write-In Amount) [Note: Those selected will be unusable for any other purpose during the turn this option is selected i.e. 5 years.]
[] Assign 25 New Battle Brothers To Companies (Write-In Battle Brother Allotment)
[] Assign Epistolary Nero Achillian To A Company (Write-In Company Designation)
[] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien: The Deathwatch is being strained to the breaking point, by their own secretive messages to all Chapters in the galaxy who can hear them. Watch Fortresses and Stations are under assault, alien civilizations are rising in ever higher number, deadly threats are growing in severity and breadth. Normally only the best of the best marines would be given over to the Deathwatch, but out of sheer desperation the Ordos Xenos is loosening their standards in an uncharacteristic display of acceptance. That is, apparently, how bad the problem has gotten across every single Segmentum. Ordo Xenos Inquisitors are calling in favors, the Deathwatch is calling upon nearly every Chapter possible to send someone, anyone, as many space marines as possible. With such threats as the Black Crusade, the War for Armageddon, the Hive Fleets, all of the Deathwatch cannot hope to fight back against the apparent thousands of full-scale alien invasions of the Imperium going on across the galaxy without help. How could you possibly stand by and do nothing, in the face of this? (Write-In Additional Forces Sent To The Deathwatch)
[] Zemel Continuation - While WAAAAAAGHH!!! Bonebreaka was stopped in its tracks, many orks remain within the Zemel System. The vast majority of the work is nothing nearly as intense as slaying Warbosses, Big Bosses, retaking Battleships, or otherwise. It is a painstaking culling, step by step, across four whole worlds. The Order of the Lost Rosetta is assisting in this, but the Blood Ravens could still contribute some forces there, though that would be entirely up to you. It might be better to try and preserve your brothers for the next step of the Polonius Liberation Crusade. [Write-In Forces Contributed For This Turn]
[] Slaughra Swarm Sabotage (Genestealer-Affliliated): Before the warp storm faded away, this was the only potion of the Slaughra Swarm known to be in existence. Inquisitorial information gathering has confirmed the presence of a genestealer cult in command of this portion of this xeno race. While the forces of the Sector ready themselves, they have allowed for the possibility that sabotage efforts against their shipyards would be most welcome before the actual assault begins in a few more years. The current greatest threat to the Crusade will be coming from their space-borne assets, and denying the enemy of as many of them as possible would do well. With the Swarm distracted with their Chaos-affiliated cousins, this is an opportune time to take advantage of their backs being turned. [Write-In Forces Contributed This Turn]
[] Slaughra Swarm Sabotage (Chaos-Affiliated): These worlds are dangerous in the extreme. Daemons and sorcerers ensure that any attempt to sabotage their forces will be exceedingly dangerous, even for space marines. There are two specific things that would require the efforts of those of a stealthy nature, and Cyrus knows this well. If one were to target one of these, death is likely certain for some. On the other hand, victory would be of great aid in the battles to come. Of note, of course, is that you can not simply send in a Company Fleet. That would be foolish, and a death sentence. There are too many enemy ships to possibly survive. These will have to be squads, inserted, and hoping for the best.
-[] Void Capabilities [Write-In Forces Contributed To Sabotaging Ship Yards/Material Transports/Supply Lines]
-[] Land Capabilities [Write-In Forces Contributed To Sabotaging Factories/Destroying Columns/Supply Lines]
[] Terminator Exchange: Theodosia is willing to produce some Terminator Armor for you, having gotten those forges and designs online. But she will, one, require a full squad of marines with at least one psyker amongst them to safeguard the area - not that she doesn't trust the defenses and holy blessings of the Omnissiah, she just wants to ensure protection for your own equipment. And the hexagramic wards of the Blood Ravens should be especially valuable. Second, for each set of five terminator suits you desire built, she will require aid in other things, allowing her to free up production systems for what you desire. [1 Squad+Librarian Required To Help Oversee Production Whenever Selected. 1 Squad Required For Minor Favor Works In Exchange Per 5 Suits]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness/Agility Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (147 Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (0 Total) with Gene-Seed.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- The Arcanum may have the largest of our Apothecarium, but it is the Potentia that possesses the most advanced, as befitting its name. This should aid in the works of the Apothecarium for its purposes in the future.

Justinius Probalis - Chief Librarian (Choose One):
[] Request to recruit and train potential psyker aspirants from the Adeptus Astra Telepathica. High likelihood of successful training and implantation for recruits made in this manner.
[] The Raven's Talons: Justinius believes that it should be possible to craft weapons that would be highly effective against daemons and the malefic powers of the Warp itself, as Godsplitter is. With five usable shards taken from Wailing Doom of the Unknown Craftworld's Avatar of Khaine from Typhon Primaris, he believes he could make similar weapons. Whether another daemonhammer, a blade, axe, maul, or spear, he thinks it possible. [100 BP Per Raven Talon, Powerful Anti-Daemon Power Weapons, x5 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Weapon. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] The Raven Aegis: The powers of the Warp and the daemons of Chaos are things that you know for a fact the Blood Ravens will face in the future. Creating talismans which would protect against such things would be incredibly valuable indeed. Justinius' successful efforts at using the materials of the fallen Avatars of Khaine has made him believe it possible to create such things. [50 BP Per Raven Aegis, Powerful Anti-Daemon/Warp Protection Talisman. x10 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Talisman. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] Anti-Anti-Psyker Study: The Split Heart Kabal made strange xeno advances in the baffling, diffusing, and blocking of psyker powers and abilities. By making a study of such things, the Librarius of the Blood Ravens would be able to train its forces against such things, improving their ability to defeat such things in the future while providing an additional aid of likely effectiveness against the vile Eldar specifically. [Note: This will mean that all non-Company Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.]

Things To Consider - Justinius Probalis
- The latest combat against the daemons of the Judgement of Carrion has made me think on the daemonhammer that the Chapter Master wields. We could, perhaps, use more of such weapons. It was created using a shard of the weapon of an Avatar. Perhaps we could make some ourselves, if we studied it enough?
- The Chapter's greatest advantage was its Librarians. I know that they were used for...ill purpose in the past by Kyras, but I will not allow such a political character to be assigned to them ever again. We were meant for more than that. For the betterment of the Chapter, for its coming battles, and the maintenance of the Sanctorium Arcanum, we must rebuild our ranks, and soon.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (575 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/750] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Construct Forge Facilities On Company Flagships (Current/Former)
- [] The Faith's Horizon [252/500] to recieve an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Howling Hatred [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [0/????]
[] Recovered Ultrafortress Predator Hulls Reconsecration And Repair – [235 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [5]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- Tremendous damage and desecration has been lambasted upon what we recovered from the orks of Bonebreaka’s WAAAGH!! They will require much work to remove the taint of the alien and reconsecrate, let alone repair. But if done, then the Chapter would benefit indeed.
- We should probably build more Tarantula turrets.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- Have we considered building more Tarantula turrets? Deploying them to aid our forces in the upcoming Crusade fighting would be most valuable indeed.
- Thank goodness the Potentia has returned to service. Amongst the rest of the ships within the Chapter Fleet, it possesses the most advanced forge facilities, as befitting its name. This will surely aid me in construction of more advanced technologies in the future, as well as their study!
- Our Chapter will remain low in number for quite some time yet. I believe that one of the best ways to alleviate such issues is the noble Tarantula turret.
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon The Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive
[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- With the arrival of many experienced 1st Company Sergeants, more Blood Trials can be enacted without Cyrus' direct observation.

040.M42 To 045.M42 Interlude: Apocalyptica

040.M42 To 045.M42 Interlude: Apocalyptica

Cadia waited.

Ships, torn asunder by lance and daemon, in their dozens. Pickets shredded apart as they desperately fled the system for safety even though they would find none. Disappearing into the warp was naught but a death sentence, such was the turmoil in the Immaterium caused by the tumultuous arrival. On its arrival to the edge of the star system alone, eighty-one psykers both active and latent upon Cadia screamed out in terror before they erupted in bursts of blood and bile. Nine of the powerful Librarians of the space marines fell to corruption, their formidable defenses falling like sand beneath a tidal wave, and the daemons which burst from their corpses killed dozens more of their superhuman brethren. Seven astropaths died laughing, tearing their own skin off and devouring all they could before expiring, leaving their ships floating uselessly in the void. Eight regiments of the Imperial Guard fell to instant madness, attacking everyone and everything around them, including each other.

Inexorable in the extreme, to the terror of those who were first sent against it, it came, ruthlessly through the darkness. Fears grew to new heights, for no matter the strength of a fortress upon the planet’s surface, none could possibly have stood against it. Shattered defenses, a Saint in retreat, a thousand, thousand screaming souls demanding salvation and receiving it from darker powers, and so the turmoil spread. Daemon armies, glorifying in their existence maintained by the sheer volume and breadth of emotion, cried with delight at the knowledge of what was coming. Pylons shuddered and shook, vibrating and cracking along their seams even as desperate teams of Mechanicus adepts worked to repair them. What was meant to be the most defensible of worlds in the entire Imperium outside of the Sol System itself was truly, inescapably vulnerable. The anticipation was a delight, a feast, a wonder, and all who served the Despoiler reveled in the knowledge of what was to come even as they advanced.

As it advanced further, the worlds it passed exploded with warp rifts and daemonic manifestations. What few resisting soldiers that existed there died, leaving every world it briefly passed wholly in the grip of Chaos. Every single resisting fingernail was ripped out and smashed, every desperate last hope quashed and drowned in darkness. Kasr Partox’s last defenders swore eagerly to their new Gods, their minds wiped and souls devoured as the last temple to the God-Emperor fell. A final resisting cell of Sororitas on the world of Solar Mariatus were slaughtered in the shadows with their final prayers going unheard. Five hundred loyal astartes fell on the world of Kasr Holn, tens of thousands of daemons manifesting in all directions, their precious gene-seed lost forever as it was devoured and destroyed. The rest of the world fell soon after, roaring World Eaters plunging out of the skies and shedding rivers of blood out of its citizens.

Then came the Hive World of Macharia, largest of all the planets in the Cadian System. There, the great ship stopped for the first time. Millions screamed in terror, and hundreds of thousands finally broke and begged for mercy from the Dark Gods, yet the one in command of that ship cared nothing for their desperate devotion. It would amount to nothing. If anything, he savored it. Now, when his enemy had finally been forced to scatter beneath the great grinding might of Chaos, he would ensure that nothing would stop him. The vast world, and its many people, who had fought and died and worshipped for generations to their distant God, died. There would be no miraculous rescues. No sudden reveal of hidden forces upon the world, no rescue fleets that would come in the nick of time. No one would come, and no one did. Macharia died screaming, a world destroyed completely and utterly. The warp shuddered with the screams of the souls who had all been damned by that destruction.

Only then, as the white hot remnants of Macharia tumbled outwards, did the trap spring.

Only in the brightness of a world’s death could the approach have been made. Sensors made of metal and flesh alike failed. One from the destruction flooding all with radiation and the splinters of Macharia. The other from the absolute flood of millions of souls flooding past and towards the Eye where they would be devoured eagerly. Only in those moments could the trap have sprung at all, and for all that many had screamed at the idea of it, the ones making the demands held the highest authority in the entire Imperium. Second only to the God-Emperor, of course. Yet he did not speak, and he had not saved Macharia. Instead, it would be his flock who would attend to avenging it.

From three sides, they came, around the sides of the rapidly disappearing remnants of Macharia and from below it. A vast number of ships, deliberately withheld despite the protests and executions of a dozen admirals. Despite the surety of death for so very many elsewhere throughout the theatre once abandoned by their battlefleets. But for a chance such as this they would be considered worthy sacrifices in the name of victory. It is said that thousands of lesser cultists simply died on the worlds that the ship had passed above from the rage of the one who had corrupted them. But despite that rage, and the fact that over a dozen ships on both sides died within the first few moments of engagement, the incredible exertion and strain to the ship’s systems in destroying Macharia had been turned against it. A scant split second of ‘vulnerability’ – though the ability for that word to apply turned fallow when considering the fleet defending the ship as well as its own defenses.

Freed from the dangers of the Green Kroosade, Battlefleet Scarus advanced. With the death of the one who had had led the orks against them, they had rearmed, repaired, rebuilt, and regrouped.

By the orders of the High Lords, Battlefleet Gothic came, far and away from their own sector which had faced this same vessel in the past. None who fought it had faced the ship, yet they remembered the stories. Some had family who had died in the war fought in what seemed to be another age, such was the violence unleashed in the here and now.

Vengeful Battlefleet Agripinaa, despite their wounds from the hands of Chaos, demanded blood in their continual volleys of lances and torpedo volleys in numbers to empty their stores utterly. Too long had they been alone, separated, picked off, and brought to ruin by the enemy. But now they were unified in one purpose.

Flying their own ships was a truly powerful task force made up solely of the mighty space marines. While ships carrying multiple fresh preceptories of sororitas arrived upon the world of Cadia itself as well as what few worlds remained at least partially Imperial in-system, the astartes drove forward. Fifteen companies, uprooted from battlefields across multiple burning sectors set aflame by Chaos, one from different chapter’s each, all drove forth in their strike cruisers surrounded by escort vessels. But at the head of all of these came another fleet in and of itself, a single battle barge escorted by ten further strike cruisers all bearing the bronze sigil of the Minotaurs. A flood of Nova-class frigates flew alongside them, lance weapons firing as they came.

In turn, the Chaos fleet turned and split to face the oncoming fleets, rage and fury guiding their purpose. Ships crafted out of the malefic forges of the Dark Mechanicus and formed by the Daemon Primarch Perturabo’s will fired every gun they could, while daemonships who were only barely kept in check by the will of the Despoiler did the same. Crews thousands of years old and as fresh as a few months ago when they emerged from the cloning tubes frantically worked at their consoles, or died as they hauled missiles and weaponry to cannons only to die from the igniting back blasts.

But for once, the Imperium had numbers on their side. For once, they were on the offense. For once, they were the ones who utterly overwhelmed the enemy. Ships were left burning and damaged in the ceaseless charge yet were quickly replaced by those behind them. Where one ship fell, two more filled the gap. A ceaseless, endless amount of fire. Enough torpedos that the sorcerers who attempted to deflect them burnt themselves to cinder, lance fire to boil away armor and vaporize daemon and damned crew alike. All of this and more simply to peel away the defenses present both sorcerous and otherwise. Five frigates, carrying massive sets of vortex bombs in their berths, sacrificed themselves in suicidal ramming attacks against the vessel’s engines, erupting in horrific explosions that released a thousand daemons into open space before they were quickly consumed back as fuel for the ship’s weapons. A strike cruiser blazed its final death in glory, wreathed in flames, as it slammed its armored bulk into an array glowing with terrible purpose and power.

All of this, for the final strike. The Minotaurs sacrificed their strike cruisers as spilling water, ablative armor while the final preparations were made. Some, knowing that their death would come soon, released their entire company in boarding torpedos and drop pods onto the torn open surface that was so many miles long to fight and die in battle. Others abandoned their ships entirely, heading for those that yet remained viable. Finally, after ten thousand men died and a hundred more astartes were slain and lost forever, did the battle barge and remaining strike cruisers fire their weapons. No mere bombardment shells were these that were loosed, no. For these were weapons meant for, in a stroke of what perhaps might be irony, the very same purpose of the target they fell upon.

The destruction of entire worlds.

Shields broken open, hull boiled away in more than a dozen locations to reveal splits in space and time such was the half-way nature of the warp and that which it had claimed so tightly, and yet only a single fourth of what was launched made it to their target. Lashes of pure warp energy flew out from unseen arrays, sorcerous blasts sent others flying elsewhere into the void where they would dissipate uselessly, and daemons themselves were sent in great flying flocks like spewing bile to stop what they could. Re-erected void shields slammed into place, joined by other more exotic things crafted by the Dark Mechanicus to block other vulnerable portions of the ship from what was coming for it.

Yet still, virus bombs fell into the myriad corridors of the Planet Killer. One managed to erupt inside of a weapons array, killing all within instantly. Single-stage cyclonic torpedoes pierced into blown open portions of the ship which had cost whole squadrons to reveal, quickly followed behind by their more exotic two-stage cousins. Weapons built to crack planetary crusts and violate the cores of worlds exploded within the endlessly warping maze that was the ship’s innards, obliterating miles and miles more of flesh and metal than could possibly have been contained in any ship not drenched in the powers of the warp since its construction. A mighty conflagration erupted in one portion of the ship which slew a mighty cabal of sorcerers who had not been able to flee in time. In another, the chaos space marines within did not even have time to contemplate running through portals to some unknowable place in the warp when a bombardment shell of immense power exploded half a mile away and destroyed the entire section.

The Imperium did not cease, did not falter, did not pause, until the Planet Killer was completely and utterly destroyed. There was no chance for it to flee, too drained as it was from destroying Macharia. Though the pylons on Cadia itself had vibrated, and a dozen shattered entirely, as the warp roiled from some mighty power attempting to strain and perhaps save it, there was nothing to save. The great defensive fleet which had been built around it, some of the eldest traitor ships in the galaxy, had not survived the great charge. So too, had many an Imperial ship either. But far more lived than had died, and as those ships spread out across the rest of the Cadian System, unleashing their terrible fury on the worlds that had succumbed or reinforcing those that had not, for a short time there was hope. Perhaps the Despoiler had died with his ship, instead of fleeing into the warp. Perhaps he would have been slain by the almighty power of the Exterminatus.

Until the news came that the Agripinaa Sector had fallen, leaving only scant few desperate remnants of the Imperium. Without their battlefleet to protect them, worlds had collapsed under orbital bombardment and deployments that came without prevention. Of Chaos forces pushing back all until the Imperium’s defenders were left with no recourse but to fight to the death, most of those that could retreat doing so. Rituals that summoned daemons and new, fresh chaos space marines from elsewhere in the galaxy that fought against an ever weakening and ever smaller number of Imperial Guard and space marines. Of sororitas cut down in their hundreds, whole missions gone awry and torn apart.

Until the news that Cypra Mundi was under assault, this time from an entirely new front, not by the forces of Chaos, but by the alien. Greenskins under the leadership of the Arch-Dictator of Gathrog had unleashed themselves in vast numbers, threatening that most vital of bases for the Imperium in all of Segmentum Obscurus. That they were desperately requesting ships that they had sent to Cadia return to aid them lest they be overwhelmed entirely. Already smaller groups of castoffs had begun to filter into the Belis Corona system, inflaming the fight there further. Tyranids, Chaos, and greenskins all poured forth against one another, reducing Battlefleet Obscurus’ primary base to a single star system which just barely held out against the enemy. In stripping so many ships for one target, a half dozen more had been opened to the predations of the alien and the traitor.

Worse news came when Abbadon revealed himself on the world of Cadia once more, ever more furious, such that he slew the finally returned Saint Celestine another time before being forced to retreat by the forces arrayed against him once more to the half of Cadia that remained within the grip of Chaos. He had not been slain alongside the Planet Killer, and for all a wonder his forces continued to move against the Imperium without any pause at all. New champions of Chaos rose to prominence as their elders died, and more daemons continued to spawn, feeding on the cornucopia of violence and turmoil unleashed. Occasionally, even, marines appeared from the rifts whose origin could not be conceived, time and space itself bending to the past and future. They too fought with all the ferocity that those who served the Dark Powers possessed. Against all of these and more, the Imperium fought and bled as it ever had, and ever would.

The 13th Black Crusade ground on.

040.M42 To 045.M42 Interlude: Era Of A Thousand Flames

NotteBoy97 said:

Are you planning on doing a DeathWatch interlude next Torroar? Since I think it would help us understand how undermanned they are at the moment.

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

you asked for this

040.M42 To 045.M42 Interlude: Era Of A Thousand Flames

A hundred ships hung above the world, delivering its tens of thousands of soldiers. The Governor’s Palace which had once sat above the world, a judging fortress in the stars above, burned as it fell towards the planet surface. Upon impact, pushed there by primitive directional rockets, it would crash into and destroy one of the greatest capitals that the feral folk had managed to build over thousands of years. Sword and shield, beaten out of iron and steel, were absolutely worthless against chemical-propellant weaponry, bullets and the rare laser weapon scorching entire battalions entirely. The dozen separate Guard recruitment outposts, kept secretive and hidden, fell to sheer numbers, their lasguns and more advanced weaponry taken for study be eager five-eyed scientists, whose multiple limbs clacked against each other’s chitin.

One single kill-team, all that could have been spared, died. They slew thousands, and they died. Bombarded from orbit, with weapons that were barely understood by a race that had only reached the stars a century ago. The rest of the star system would fall within the year, one Feral World after another, a single small picket fleet torn apart by overwhelming numbers and boarding parties, their hulks used for research and study. For too long had they been building up in their home star system, and the need to expand had finally pushed them to the brink. Fears of reprisal were quashed, for there would be none coming, not before they could fortify and entrench.

============================================

Ravaged by a WAAAAGH!!, the depredations of the Dark Eldar for a generation, and with the majority of its defenders gone to distant and supposed ‘greater’ battlefields, there was little chance for them to be stopped. They came on ships of rock and shaped stone, alien sorceries and psykers shaping them into the vessels they required to fly through the void from their dimly lit home. Three entire kill-teams, carrying weapons built specifically to kill them, bombs to destroy their ships from within and exterminate populaces, succeeded. A dozen marines died simply to perform the action, doing what an entire Chapter might not have. They died in glory, and yet those that remained felt the inklings of despair which their transhuman hearts had not touched since their transformation when a second fleet appeared.

Clad in basalt stone, blazing with eldritch power granted by their sorcerer-kings, they came bearing weapons that bore the slightest resemblance to Imperial weapons. In the distant past, once upon a time, the flesh-skins had tried to exterminate their kind simply for existing, but had failed. A single decimal point had changed later on, and they had disappeared from history and records. Safe to build and strengthen themselves for the oncoming vengeance. Already two worlds burned, all organic life being slowly churned to dust beneath crystalline feet. The third had held out, armies stymied at every turn by frantic movements, insane maneuvers, suicidal strikes, and yet still they came. The asteroid field itself was their ally, becoming new life, new warriors, as the months went on.

Another system fell, leaving only one remaining Subsector that still bore the flag of the God-Emperor. It would fall soon too if another kill-team, alone, without reinforcements, could not somehow do what a quartet of kill-teams had failed to do.

======================================

Its eye was shot out, and the creature died, and the last of Kill-Team Epsilon-994 breathed hard as it finally fell. Reptilian beasts, writhing in vast numbers on continent-ships, and coming from a completely different direction. Their weapons were primitive, comparably, yet in large enough numbers even ceramite could and would break before them. That hadn’t been the problem, the problem was that it had simply kept coming despite everything they’d thrown at it. Regenerative capabilities that smacked closer to tyranids than anything else, and even then only as a comparison to the only other species which seemed capable of it. At the least there were few of them amongst the rest of their more easily slain cousins, acting as single-creature spearheads rather than as generals or anything else. The rest of the city burned, as flak cannons turned the sky white with smoke and blood as thousands of more drop ships landed.

Grunting, the kill marine pushed his way past the corpse, sparing one glance towards the rapidly liquefying remains of his brothers, and smashed through the debris which had filled the hall. The governor was dead, his supporters were dead, and the walls were falling. Stopping the assassination attempt had failed. Stopping the enemy invasion had succeeded…at first, before a second ship had arrived with its own defensive flotilla. Barely able to beat a Sector Battlefleet, but there would be no Sector Battlefleet coming. Another WAAAAAGGH!! on one end of the Sector, reports of a Tyranid splinter fleet on another end, and not enough forces to spare here, for this, other than what the Deathwatch had been struggling to provide.

He stopped, then, shoving aside shattered masonry and the broken remains of the Imperial aquila which had been knocked from the palace walls, to stare up at the sky unblinking.

Already he watched as the enemy turned on one another. The entire star system had barely survived one race emerging from its kingdom from beyond the borders of the Emperor’s light. It would certainly not survive a second. Lights in the dark of the smog-choked sky as fission engines exploded, nuclear bombs being fired without a care across the void at ships of another race that dared to come and interrupt conquest. The kill marine died as the atmosphere itself was ignited, species caring only for the planet below and its resources, not its vegetation or its original inhabitants.

================================

One invasion blunted. Two ship yards destroyed. Five armies destroyed in their camps with bombs and poison. Six leadership equivalents to generals assassinated. Eight defensive hard points kept from destruction.

It wasn’t enough.

Two capital ships infiltrated and turned against the rest of the invasion fleet. Eighteen massive transport ships sabotaged to explode upon reaching atmosphere. Twelve refueling points set with explosives and destroyed to kill what ships were present. One bomb destroying the capital city on their capital world, turning vast structures of glass and steel into broken fragments.

It wasn’t enough.

One kill team, veterans of a hundred battles, who had each lived for over three centuries each.

It wasn’t enough.

Too many targets, too little time, not enough damage done within a small enough time frame.

Ships landed, troops landed, and the Imperium surrendered like a drunken giant. It swung, it fought, it armed its citizens, but they could not stop what came for them. Hulking creatures, horns sprouting from their heads, with hard calcified bone-flesh to guard over pockmarked leathery hides. They bore guns which boomed and rocked the earth as they fired. One marine died outright, ceramite exploding as everything above their waist was destroyed. There was no chance of gene-seed being recovered. The rest of the kill team fought on, and killed in vengeance the one they had lost.

It wasn’t enough.

They died, torn limb from limb, by a thousand xenos who finally surrounded them after they had destroyed nearly half of the entire invasion force, colony ships included, who had come to take and settle what they pleased. In the end, there was not even scraps of meat or metal left behind, such was the brutality inflicted upon them. They had fought well, with some of the most advanced weapons in the Imperium’s arsenal. They had followed the Emperor’s Tarot with every movement. They had set bombs enough to end lesser civilizations.

It wasn’t enough.

=====================================

He was…exhausted. Which didn’t sound right, it didn’t sound right at all. Never before had an Imperial Fist claimed fatigue, at least openly. But it was the truth. Twenty years he had been fighting ceaselessly, and it was not the fighting which had exhausted the marine, but the constant movement. From this solar system to this solar system, from this Subsector to this Sector, back and forth again. Always putting out fires, but never dousing the entire inferno. Never the opportunity to do so. For every thorn plucked or blunted, another arrived. Reduced to piecemeal defenses rather than anything that would have been strong enough to truly shock the enemy into a momentary pause. His bolter had run dry, his chainsword out of fuel, his armor’s power pack burnt out by exertion. Three things which had never happened before despite over two centuries of battle.

And now…this.

“A splinter fleet from Hive Fleet Behemoth, here,” the Inquisitor spoke quietly, highlighting another subsector. “A splinter from Leviathan there,” he highlighted a second section. “WAAAAGH!!! Durgorka has finished burning its way through the Aegean Corridor – despite our best efforts and that of Battlefleet Lerek - and has arrived here, here, and here,” he highlighted a further series of sections. “The alien civilization of the Peridians have continued their advance here, and have managed to reach orbit over the capital planet there. They have, based on our observations, overstretched themselves somewhat. They had just enough supplies to branch out from their home system and reach a ‘sector’ equivalent in control size, but are now struggling to maintain their newest gains.”

“Where do we fight, Inquisitor,” the kill-captain finally asked, his voice grim.

“Everywhere,” the Inquisitor replied, deep bags beneath his eyes as he glared at the holo-image. “You are but one kill-team, but we must do our duty. The Emperor demands it. We do not have the sheer military strength required to otherwise blunt these foes, and so must do what we can.”

It was true, it was their duty. They would succeed or die trying.

Turn 22 (Part One): An Unkindness

Spoiler: Plan: Terminator Stockpile Forge Upgrade

[X] Plan Terminator Stockpile Forge Upgrade

-[X] Lead Your Chapter
--[X] Assign 25 New Battle Brothers To Companies
---[X] 11 to 4th
---[X] 14 to 5th
--[X] Assign Epistolary Nero Achillian To 4th Company
--[X] Assign Tomb-Brothers Relian and Aeneas to the 4th company
--[X] Assign 10 members of the 1st Company as Veteran sergeants to the 4th (5) and 5th (5)
--[X] Use 1 Minor Favor to gain 8 Thunderhawks (6 gunships, 2 transporter) from Governor Derosa.

--[X] Zemel Continuation - Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos + Honor Guard, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, 1st Company + Company Leadership, 1st Fleet. Vehicles assigned as requested by Company/Chapter leadership, after 10th Company selection.
---[X] Have Librarius support divine where Blood Ravens can do the most good and locations of wargear or vehicles left available for reclamation, biasing towards Space Marine usable equipment.

--[X] Slaughra Swarm Sabotage (Genestealer-Affliliated) - 10th Fleet, 10th Company + Company Leadership. 1st pick of necessary vehicles as requested by Company leadership.
---[X] Have Trajan Maphar + Librarius support divine for the best opportunities to gain necessary intelligence or perform sabotage.

--[X] Terminator Exchange
---[X] 5th Company squad + Epistolary Damion Tyrin + 2 Lexicani + Chaplain (equipment protection)
---[X] 4th Company squad + Codicier + Apothecary Caesar + Chaplain + Tomb-Brother Relian
---[X] 4th Company squad + Epistolary Nero Achillian + Apothecary + Chaplain Ateren
---[X] 4th Company squad + Codicier + Apothecary + Chaplain Uther Volkoss
---[X] 4th Company squad + Codicier + Apothecary + Chaplain Ravias + Tomb-Brother Aeneas
---[X] 4th Company squad + Codicier + Apothecary + Chaplain + Captain Hadrian Priscus
---[X] 5th Company squad + Codicier + Apothecary Medici + Chaplain + Tomb-Brother-Captain Davian Thule
---[X] 5th Company squad + Codicier + Apothecary + Chaplain Antonius + Tomb-Brother Nathan
---[X] 5th Company squad + Codicier + Apothecary + Chaplain + Company Champion Kaius Jacobus
---[X] 5th Company squad + Codicier + Chaplain Tarion + Captain Tarkus Varianus

-[X] Training
--[X] Angelos: Weapon Skill with Apollo Diomedes
--[X] Chapter Main: Weapon Skill with Apollo Diomedes
--[X] Chapter Secondary: Ballistic Skill with Hadrian
--[X] Chapter Secondary: Strength with Hannibal Palrun

-[X] Apothecary
--[X] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (147 Total) with Gene-Seed.
--[X] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. - 55 Gene-Seed

-[X] Chief Librarian
--[X] 2x The Raven's Aegis [100 BP]

-[X] Forge [525 BP Total]
--[X] 12x Psychic Hoods [120 BP]
--[X] 2x Tarantula Sentry Gun [Twin-Linked Heavy Bolter] [20 BP]
--[X] 2x Tarantula Sentry Gun [Twin-Linked Lascannons] [20 BP]
--[X] 2x Tarantula Sentry Gun [Hyperion AA] [20 BP]
--[X] 2x Tarantula Sentry Gun [Twin-Linked Assault Cannons] [20 BP]
--[X] Relic Construction
---[X] Scout Armor for Cyrus Octavius [20 BP]
--[X] Construct Forge Facilities On The Faith's Horizon [248 BP]
--[X] Construct Forge Facilities On The Howling Hatred [7 BP]

-[X] Master of Recruits
--[X] Train the 10th against the Slaughra

Spoiler: 045.M42 To 050.M42

55 Implanted For Test-Slave Harvest In 040.M42. Harvest At Beginning Of Turn 22. Harvest = 100 Gene-Seed Harvested. Nearly Harvest! Remainder Unviable For Implantation
147 Neophytes [2nd Stage] Advance: 140 To Scouts [1st Stage], Remainder Expired. +12 Gene-Seed Reclaimed.
Warning: Scouts Exceed Scout Armor Supply By 20, 82 Scouts Exceedingly Vulnerable During Operations.
5 Scouts [1st Stage] Manifest Psyker Talents Upon Gene-Seed Implantation, Seconded To Librarius as Lexicanum. -5 Scouts [1st Stage], +5 Lexicanum
23 Scouts [1st Stage] Advance: 23 To Scouts [2nd Stage].
20 Scouts [2nd Stage] Advance: 20 To Full Battle Brothers.
11 Unassigned Battle Brothers Dedicated To 4th Company.
14 Unassigned Battle Brothers Dedicated To 5th Company.
10 1st Company Veterans Dedicated to 4th/5th Companies as Veteran Sergeants (5 Each)
1 Minor Favor (Derosa) Used: 8 Thunderhawks (x6 gunships, x2 transporter)
[Training With Apollo – Weapon Skill From 7 to 8: 661+14+Apollo(29)=704/800]
[Chapter Training – Weapon Skill 4 To 5: 360+7+Apollo(29)=396/500]
[Chapter Training – Strength 4 To 5: 43+28+Hannibal(25)=96/500]
[Chapter Training – Ballistic Skill 5 to 6: 258+31+Hadrian(25)=314/600]
3 Techmarine Trainees Return From Mars as fully ordained Techmarines!
+1 Minor Favor (Derosa): Details In Post
-1 Deathwatch Marine, 5th Company, Tremendously Injured! Dreadnought Installation Required For Survival. Gene-Seed Unrecoverable.
-1 Deathwatch Veteran Marine, 5th Company. Gene-Seed Unrecoverable.

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

On the world once known as Shinehole, you can see the efforts of the Imperium bearing fruit already. A great number of the tunnels have been completely cleared out, fortified, and settled by transplanted folk who shall live and die here as miners. The many valuable mineral resources of this planet shall be put to good use by the Imperium, and here beneath the earth, they shall be well shielded from the deadly radiation that blasts this largely atmosphere-less planet. With the addition of a few cavern-based radiation shields and oxygen production through machinery and plant-life, these people shall be able to bring much bounty indeed. Especially now that you have assisted in the destruction of the last few remnants of the greenskins within the tunnels. They are stubborn xenos, to be sure, but they are completely broken here, and they know it. No more Warbosses rise, and their nobs are smaller and smaller as the fighting goes on, until it is over and done with. Smaller grots and gretchin are hunted down by tracker machines of the Mechanicus, the psychic powers of your librarians and the Guard's own sanctioned psykers, with heavy flamer cleansing over their breeding grounds. When you exit the tunnels you receive further news, that of the world of Palmyra, once known as Spinesnap. The Order of the Lost Rosetta might have burned two thirds of the planetary jungle down, but one cannot really argue with the results. The orks of the world have been fully broken, scattered, and for the most part exterminated.

Zemel may never be utterly and totally free of the ork for generations more, but your work here, as well as that of the Lost Rosetta, Guard, and Navy have ensured that humanity shall have a fair chance here. Which is more than can be said for many.

Spoiler: Polonius Results

1d2 = 2 = Shinehole/Aigai
82 = Significant victories, no casualties.
9= No wargear/vehicles salvageable.
Palmyra cleared out as a result of Order of the Lost Rosetta/Guard/Navy efforts.
Zemel Cleared! Further action declared superfluous, small Guard and Rosetta elements will remain behind for basic security procedures for the colonists.

====================================

"Has anyone seen Martellus?"

"Ah...no, Master Calus," one of the newer techmarines shook their head. "We've been working in shifts to properly replicate the forge facilities onto the cleared berths within the-,"

"Yes, yes, I'm aware," Calus waved them away. "That's fine with me."

Covertly, and only after they'd left, did he dare to comm Daedal on a secure line.

"He doesn't know. He's busy with the tarantulas, as you suspected."

In a crackle of static, both techmarines sighed.

"Good. Then he'll be too distracted to know about the-,"

"WHAT IN THE NAME OF THE OMNISSIAH IS THIS?!" Martellus' voice exploded out of Daedal's side of the vox, and sent Calus to wincing at the same time from the feedback.

Elsewhere, in another section of the forges entirely, the Master of the Forges loomed over Daedal. In one hand, he vigorously shook a slightly more artistically designed piece of scout armor, with some whorls upon the pauldrons. Other than that, there was little that was truly notable about the armor. Which was expected when it came to a mis-mixed alloy attempt, and a failed expenditure of circuitry and electrical systems.

"It is..not what you wanted, yes," Daedal slowly spoke as he uncrouched, "But it was the best that could be done. Something went wrong with the heat, a minor tweak to the forges, and...well. Yes."

"This is not going to Cyrus," Martelllus sighed, his fury abating as quickly as it had come, "We will simply have to tell him that there was a mistake, and we will try again some other time."

Spoiler: Forge Results

x12 Psychic Hoods Built.
x8 Tarantula Sentry Guns (x2 Heavy Bolter, x2 Lascannons, x2 Hyperion AA, x2 Assault Cannons)
248 BP To Faith's Horizon Forge Construction: 500/500. +50 BP/Turn
7 BP To The Howling Hatred Forge Construction: 7/500
Relic Scout Armor Crafted For Cyrus Octavius: 20 BP Cost. 1d100=10. Relic Creation Failure! +1 Scout Armor To Armory

=======================

"You have been most helpful, my friends, most helpful indeed," Theodosia boomed, her massive dreadnought-esque frame shaking with the volume.

Heavy pneumatic steps herald her coming closer, and proffering a highly advanced assault claw, one which Tarkus knew could run with a tremendously advanced power field when activated properly, which was in turn shaken ever so carefully by Captain Thule. The good Captain had truly come to life over the years, the danger and damage caused by the potent Tyranid toxins gradually being excised over the years by the on-board systems and efforts of the forges and apothecarium. Tarkus did not smile at the sight of it, but did feel his hearts gladden at the sight. Despite being reduced, as some might consider, to a dreadnought frame, Captain Thule remained a potent ally and friend. The various tasks that had needed the dread touch of the Blood Ravens across this world were not necessarily the same as Kronus or a hundred other worlds or battles, but Tarkus knew that it would have taken a great number more of skitarii. In exchange for freeing up the resources of Aerus, in turn more power could be put towards the production of the precious Terminator Suits. The fact that Aerus could produce them, but Zerann could not, was a hearty boon indeed. In the past, every suit was to be jealously guarded and exceedingly rarely used. Whenever they were lost, great effort had to be put into reclaiming them. It was unlikely for that to change, but it was besides the point at the moment.

"I wish the Omnissiah's blessings upon you, and to your Librarians as well," the Fabricator-General dipped her chassis slightly in a bow, "With their aid, we were able to isolate a great amount of scrap code and remaining taint and remove it from my world's flesh and forges. Go in peace, and may you bring much war to our enemies!"

Excess of Librarians On Aerus Prevent Taint To Equipment Production, Assist In Removing Taint From Aerus.
Aerus Fully Purified!
x45 Terminator Armor (Indominatus-Pattern) Added To Armory.

=========================

"Did you even think about what would happen after you had me killed, Lord Byron?"

Derosa's arched eyebrow had been feared before. But now, now it was far worse, for when she did so before the rest of the court she held there were five silent red and black specters who stood behind it. The threat of House Derosa's own forces were one thing, but far more than Vandis ever had exercised his relationship with Azariah Kyras did Derosa wield the Blood Ravens on Meridian. They were a scalpel against the cults that had been discretely allowed for fun and profit. They were a hammer to the Ganger Games, which had been previously allowed under Vandis to allow betting on the eternal warfare in the depths of the Underhive. Where they walked, the rumors quieted. Corruption - at the level it had been before - would no longer be tolerated. But now, after all this, the Lord Byron, whose family had owned one of the spires for generations, knew he had stepped too far. Every skirting, of course, but now as the rest of the court gasped and delighted in the intrigues, two of the Blood Ravens stomped forth. Derosa herself sat ramrod straight on her throne, one bearing the Imperial Aquila far higher and more proudly than Vandis' ever had, apparently uncaring of the blood which covered her dress or the exposed bone on her left forearm.

"For your crimes, your corruption, your idiocy, and ordering the assassination of the God-Emperor's chosen Governor of this world, I sentence you to the hands of the Blood Ravens you sought to bury in the Underhive."

Byron turned, and got as far as a single foot before his arms had been grabbed hard enough to tear at the skin and muscle.

"No, no, Lady Governor, no, I see now the error of my ways, I was foolish and weak, please!" Byron's cries went very well heard, but not answered as he was dragged away, the rest of the Blood Ravens in the court slowly filtering out afterwards.

More than a few lord and ladies strained their ears, and clapped in delight at the sound of a booming single bolter round just on the edge of their hearing.

Assassination Attempt On Governor Derosa Foiled By Talon Squad.
+1 Minor Favor From Governor Derosa!
Meridian Nobility Growing Unruly Against Derosa...?

=======================================

"Behold," Justinius murmured, offering forth the talisman which glimmers with power, "The Raven's Aegis."

It is shaped just as the crest of the Blood Ravens, completely black with a red center, and yet the whole of it radiates the strange power that your hammer possesses if...different slightly. Once installed upon the armor of whichever battle brother is elected to bear it, you know for a fact staring at it that they shall be protected well by the vagaries of the warp and dark sorcery. Perhaps not utterly immune, but certainly protected against most things. You know that such an item will be valuable indeed, for whoever is able to possess it. Or, you know, its twin. To hear Justinius tell it of course, the forging process of these twinned talismans nearly collapsed entirely, the energies and its interactions with his own psychic powers nearly turning to disaster or at the least failure and ruination of the materials used. The point of the matter is that he succeeded, though. It will be up to you to decide how they are applied now.

+2 Raven's Aegis (Powerful Anti-Daemon/Anti-Warp Effects On Bearer)
Added To Armor Tab Of Armory Post.

=======================================

The Slaughra engineers exploded, along with the rest of the facility, with no warning given whatsoever. Cyrus slowly rose from beneath the camo-cloak which had been utterly coated with sand, a previously flat patch of the desert giving birth to the Captain of the 10th Company. The scouts, busy watching the tower collapse, spun and fired wildly at his approach, failing to strike him once. The entire squad whirled, searching for the one who had surprised them, only to find Cyrus standing before them, now silhouetted by the collapsing tower. A final burst of alien technosorcery burst out of it, black and purple lightning sparking, before the shield tower fell. A full mile of the desert ground was suddenly bereft of its protection, and with raucous cheers and a deafening blast of the god machines, a pair of warhound titans advanced, sprinting forward to scout the new area of enemy territory. The scouts stared up at him, bionic eye gleaming, before he gave them a single grunt.

"Your situational awareness was lacking. Your explosive placements were...acceptable. Your next task is to infiltrate the enemy territory, and attack any and all supply dumps available. Do not fail the Chapter, scouts."

And then he turned, and headed in. The scouts glanced at one another before scrambling after him. Few of them truly understood the boon that had been granted to them by Trajan Maphar's scrying rituals, but they did not question it. A tower falling here, a supply dump there, mines and detonation packs along this roadway, some nonsensically placed before the enemy would arrive far later, and others part of a greater bulk. The 10th Company followed their leader, and the alien suffered greatly for it. For too long had the Slaughra lived here, on worlds that should rightly be serving the Imperium's needs. The rich resources of the world, just barely tapped by the aliens who had evolved here, compared to elder worlds of the Imperium at least. Even when a full half of their civilization had been cut off by the warp storm a thousand years ago, they had continued to work on their own civilization, barely aware of the Imperium within whose borders they had been born. Worse, when the genestealer cult had taken control, they had worked instead to the dread purposes of the other. Better that they should be killed, in the here and now.

Spoiler: Polonius Results

Libarius Scrying And Planning: 95
10th Company Operations: 88+Critical Success Of Librarius Efforts. Extremely significant victories. No casualties.

Lead Your Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus’s presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (Write-In Amount) [Note: Those selected will be unusable for any other purpose during the turn this option is selected i.e. 5 years.]
[] Assign 20 New Battle Brothers To Companies (Write-In Battle Brother Allotment)
[] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien: The Deathwatch is being strained to the breaking point, by their own secretive messages to all Chapters in the galaxy who can hear them. Watch Fortresses and Stations are under assault, alien civilizations are rising in ever higher number, deadly threats are growing in severity and breadth. Normally only the best of the best marines would be given over to the Deathwatch, but out of sheer desperation the Ordos Xenos is loosening their standards in an uncharacteristic display of acceptance. That is, apparently, how bad the problem has gotten across every single Segmentum. Ordo Xenos Inquisitors are calling in favors, the Deathwatch is calling upon nearly every Chapter possible to send someone, anyone, as many space marines as possible. With such threats as the Black Crusade, the War for Armageddon, the Hive Fleets, all of the Deathwatch cannot hope to fight back against the apparent thousands of full-scale alien invasions of the Imperium going on across the galaxy without help. How could you possibly stand by and do nothing, in the face of this? (Write-In Additional Forces Sent To The Deathwatch)
[] Poloinus Reclamation Crusade - Crusade Assistance (Genestealer-Affliliated): Before the warp storm faded away, this was the only potion of the Slaughra Swarm known to be in existence. Inquisitorial information gathering has confirmed the presence of a genestealer cult in command of this portion of this xeno race. The Imperial Navy and Imperial Guard have invaded here in force, while the majority of the Swarm itself is weakened from the sudden rear assault. Busy as they are with their Chaos-aligned counterparts, they cannot properly engage the Guard's forces which have already landed on all five worlds they possess, including the capital. There are rumors of the Officio Assassinorum being responsible for the destruction of the Swarm's leading creatures, causing further disarray. The Knights of Trontiux and a Titan Legion are also present. For all of this, however, the Blood Ravens might send some further forces to aid in the fighting. [Write-In Forces Sent]
[] Polonius Reclamation Crusade - Slaughra Swarm Extermination (Chaos-Affiliated): A daemonworld for a capital, and four more worlds besides that are largely corrupted. They are now fully aware of the Imperium, who elected to go ahead with their planned invasion of their 'purer' cousins as they had planned for quite some time. In turn, the Blood Ravens and Order of the Lost Rosetta have been requested to head to the Z04Y System and make war against the forces of Chaos - xeno they may be - and ensure that when Sector Command is finished with one they can turn to the other. You will possess far less help here, and your only 'ally' will be the Lost Rosetta. However you do know that Canoness Margaret has returned from the Romana System with a mighty host drawn from all of the Order of the Lost Rosetta, and the Imperial Navy is dedicating a battlefleet to aid you in holding your positions. With the Swarm busy fighting with their own race, a great amount of their naval strength which would have otherwise made such an assault unfeasible has been expended. Of course, you don't have to do this, they Sector Command cannot actually order you to do this, but they strongly, strongly desire it. [Write-In Forces Sent]
[] Terminator Exchange: Theodosia is willing to produce some Terminator Armor for you, having gotten those forges and designs online. But she will, one, require a full squad of marines with at least one psyker amongst them to safeguard the area - not that she doesn't trust the defenses and holy blessings of the Omnissiah, she just wants to ensure protection for your own equipment. And the hexagramic wards of the Blood Ravens should be especially valuable. Second, for each set of five terminator suits you desire built, she will require aid in other things, allowing her to free up production systems for what you desire. [1 Squad+Librarian Required To Help Oversee Production Whenever Selected. 1 Squad Required For Minor Favor Works In Exchange Per 5 Suits]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training With Apollo
Select One Of The Below To Train With Apollo’s Aid
[] Weapon Skill
[] Ballistic Skill

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Toughness And Agility Characteristic Has Reached Its Cap And Can No Longer Be Selected]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

[] Select Two Secondary Characteristics (1d50+Trainer Each)
- [] Specify Teacher(s)

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest in 5 years. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use.
[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (0Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (0 Total) with Gene-Seed.
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- The Arcanum may have the largest of our Apothecarium, but it is the Potentia that possesses the most advanced, as befitting its name. This should aid in the works of the Apothecarium for its purposes in the future.

Justinius Probalis - Chief Librarian (Choose One):
[] Request to recruit and train potential psyker aspirants from the Adeptus Astra Telepathica. High likelihood of successful training and implantation for recruits made in this manner.
[] The Raven's Talons: Justinius believes that it should be possible to craft weapons that would be highly effective against daemons and the malefic powers of the Warp itself, as Godsplitter is. With five usable shards taken from Wailing Doom of the Unknown Craftworld's Avatar of Khaine from Typhon Primaris, he believes he could make similar weapons. Whether another daemonhammer, a blade, axe, maul, or spear, he thinks it possible. [100 BP Per Raven Talon, Powerful Anti-Daemon Power Weapons, x5 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Weapon. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] The Raven Aegis: The powers of the Warp and the daemons of Chaos are things that you know for a fact the Blood Ravens will face in the future. Creating talismans which would protect against such things would be incredibly valuable indeed. Justinius' successful efforts at using the materials of the fallen Avatars of Khaine has made him believe it possible to create such things. [50 BP Per Raven Aegis, Powerful Anti-Daemon/Warp Protection Talisman. x8 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Talisman. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] A Personal Request: Justinius has proven to himself, and to you, that he is capable of manipulating the unique materials of the fallen Avatars of Khaine to produce powerful items. He wishes to produce one for himself, though he knows it is a somewhat selfish request to do so. It would be a boon to him, he knows, and would require the usage of one of the Avatar Shards currently available. [50 BP For Justinius Creation Attempt. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] Anti-Anti-Psyker Study: The Split Heart Kabal made strange xeno advances in the baffling, diffusing, and blocking of psyker powers and abilities. By making a study of such things, the Librarius of the Blood Ravens would be able to train its forces against such things, improving their ability to defeat such things in the future while providing an additional aid of likely effectiveness against the vile Eldar specifically. [Note: This will mean that all non-Company Epistolary Librarians and Justinius Probalis are unusable for other tasks for 2 turns i.e. 10 years.]

Things To Consider - Justinius Probalis
- The latest combat against the daemons of the Judgement of Carrion has made me think on the daemonhammer that the Chapter Master wields. We could, perhaps, use more of such weapons. It was created using a shard of the weapon of an Avatar. Perhaps we could make some ourselves, if we studied it enough?
- The Chapter's greatest advantage was its Librarians. I know that they were used for...ill purpose in the past by Kyras, but I will not allow such a political character to be assigned to them ever again. We were meant for more than that. For the betterment of the Chapter, for its coming battles, and the maintenance of the Sanctorium Arcanum, we must rebuild our ranks, and soon.

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (625 BP Available)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/750] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Construct Forge Facilities On Company Ships (Current/Former)
- [] The Ravenous Spirit [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Spiraling Fury [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Burning Seeker [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Rage of Erudition [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The The Great Father's Fist [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Howling Hatred [7/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [0/????]
[] Recovered Ultrafortress Predator Hulls Reconsecration And Repair – [235 BP Cost] Note: May not succeed. [5]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- Tremendous damage and desecration has been lambasted upon what we recovered from the orks of Bonebreaka’s WAAAGH!! They will require much work to remove the taint of the alien and reconsecrate, let alone repair. But if done, then the Chapter would benefit indeed.
- We should probably build more Tarantula turrets.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We have proven, now, our techmarine cadre to have the ability to properly construct the forges on our ships. We should continue this practice, for the Chapter is dangerously under-equipped compared to the strength it once possessed before the Purge.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- Have we considered building more Tarantula turrets? Deploying them to aid our forces in the upcoming Crusade fighting would be most valuable indeed.
- Thank goodness the Potentia has returned to service. Amongst the rest of the ships within the Chapter Fleet, it possesses the most advanced forge facilities, as befitting its name. This will surely aid me in construction of more advanced technologies in the future, as well as their study!
- Our Chapter will remain low in number for quite some time yet. I believe that one of the best ways to alleviate such issues is the noble Tarantula turret.
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon The Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive
[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- With the arrival of many experienced 1st Company Sergeants, more Blood Trials can be enacted without Cyrus' direct observation.

Turn 22 (Part Two): An Unkindness

GM NOTE: As we leap into the rest of the Polonius stuff, the training/neophyte gains/etc. etc. will be collated at at the end so we can focus on this bit first.

Spoiler: Polonius Divisons

--[X] Poloinus Reclamation Crusade - Crusade Assistance (Genestealer-Affliliated)
---[X] 10th Fleet & Company
----[X] Scouts without armor are to beheld in reserve until armor has been freed or produced.
---[X] 1st pick of necessary vehicles as requested by Company leadership. [Zero Vehicles Taken From Armory]
---[X] Have Trajan Maphar & Librarius support divine for the best opportunities

--[X] Polonius Reclamation Crusade - Slaughra Swarm Extermination (Chaos-Affiliated)
---[X] Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos, Apollo Diomedes, Master of Sanctity Hannibal Palrun, Chief Librarian Justinius Probalis
---[X] Honor Guard, 1st Company & Fleet, 4th Company & Fleet, 5th Company & Fleet, all unassigned specialists.

An Unkindness
+045.M42+ To +050.M42+
+Never Falter, Never Surrender+

"Will someone please tell me why I have Blood Ravens on my battlefield!?" Lord General Cervantes roared, his bolt pistol booming as it sent another of the filthy xenos to the grave. "Did we not, as an act of good will, direct them towards a target 'better befitting their abilities'?!"

His power saber hummed as it cut through another of the Slaughra, and only once the three who had leapt towards him died did he turn to his terrified vox officer. A dozen multicolored eyes glazed over as the tri-legged creatures collapsed, their hard carapaces cracked and splintered by bolter and blade alike. The young man had barely even been able to fire his lasrifle before the General charged foward, his personal retinue of veteran stormtroopers right alongside him. Cervantes, two centuries old and half made entirely from bionics at this point, towered over the younger man who had not yet seen his second decade. Great hisses escaped his body from fluted exhaust ports, the golden aquila on his chest glowing in the heat of the sun which burned overhead. He did not even flinch as a chunk of masonry falling from one of the xeno buildings that surrounded them deep within the xeno hive, though the vox officer certainly did. Around him, hundreds of Imperial Guard charged forth, firing into the defensive lines of the Slaughra who fired back with their own strange bio-weaponry, now known to be at least partially inspired by the disgusting tyranids.

"Well?!" He boomed, looking at the officer. "Get me that boneheaded front-line idiot on the line!"

"Y-yes sir, I-I will contact General Bonaparte immediately," the vox officer mewled, and frantically began tapping and twitching at the dials on the device he carried on his back.

In the meantime, Cervantes turned towards the most recent thing to catch his ire in the past ten minutes, and spat down on the broken pauldron of the Blood Ravens which had almost been completely obscured beneath the smoke and blood filling the air. There was much blood scattered about, but no body, which Cervantes knew for a fact meant that the space marine had gotten away. With a final vengeful grinding of his augmetic leg against it, shredding the remaining ceramite entirely, he turned about to hear as the vox crackled.

"General Cervantes, what can I do for you," Bonaparte's nasally voice was clogged, either with phlegm or blood, but Cervantes didn't particularly care to find out.

"Blood Ravens, Bonaparte. There are Blood Ravens on my Emperor-be-damned battlefield!" Cervantes snarled. "The bastards are here, now, and I swear to the God-Emperor if their incessant actions ruin our battle plan I am going to give hell to that Chapter Master of theirs! Or whoever the hell is in command of that bunch of mongrels here on-world!"

"You do your brother's memory credit, sir. I'm sure you would succeed where he failed on Meridian," Bonaparte was barely audible under the sound of an explosion nearby drowning almost everything else out. "Ah. The...Blood Ravens appear to have destroyed the enemy supply depot that we were assaulting. Or at least most of it, given the fires. Excuse me, my eardrums have ruptured from the nearness of the explosion, I cannot hear. I shall attend to the medicae, and see if anything can be done."

The vox clicked off, and Cervantes' face purpled in fury. Once upon a time, there might have been a healthier fear for the space marines who even now skulked across the planet, but that had been dashed away quite well by the advent of Kyras and the arrival of the Inquisition. They had faltered, they had failed, they had murdered. The greater majority had been corrupted, and so what could be pleasantly said about the remnants? Nothing good, for Cervantes, nothing good whatsoever. He swore to the God-Emperor, then throttled that rage into purpose as he demanded an ever greater acceleration to the conquest of the world, and the extermination of every last Slaughra bioform. It would not be the last time that the Blood Ravens utterly ruined his timetables, or that of the other commanders, and it would not be the last time that they caused logistical nightmares as a result as targets disappeared, materials sent to one location were suddenly needed in another as a new avenue suddenly opened up, and worse. The Blood Ravens had come.

But they were not welcomed.

Spoiler: Slaughra Swarm (Z04X)

Libarius Scrying And Planning: 34. Negligible Effects.
Going Against Sector Command Wishes: 17. Exceedingly Irritated Local/Sector Command. Effects: Communication Breakdown/Aloofness.
10th Company Efforts: 98! Critical Success. Effects: Extremely Deleterious Effects To Swarm defenses!
Conquest Progress:
Slaughra Capital World - 27% Imperial, 73% Slaughra
Slaughra Ice World - 18% Imperial, 82% Slaughra
Slaughra Desert World - 30% Imperial, 70% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Primaris - 20% Imperial, 80% Slaughra
Slaughra 'Civilized' World Secundus - 33% Imperial, 67% Slaughra
Z04X Space Control: Contested - Imperials Somewhat Dominant, Swarm (A) In Full Retreat Over Theater, Swarm (B) Assaulting Both

Decisions For 10th Company (Choose One):
[] Focus On Civilian Centers - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. But this is not a simple military crusade, it is a total reclamation of worlds that should be for humanity's purposes, not the alien. Once, ages ago, they were, and now, they will be again. Thus, genocide. The vast majority of the Swarm, like many species, are either not military or being conscripted. As time goes on, this will continue. The more conscripts there are, the harder the fight will be. It would be better to kill them before they are properly armed, and to hopefully also cause significant morale damage.
[] Focus On Military Targets - The Imperial Guard, Imperial Navy, Trontiux Knights, and a Titan Legion are all focused largely on breaking the military capabilities of the Swarm. The Blood Ravens can aid in this, for there are few amongst any of those mighty forces who can manage the same stealth and capabilities of a properly trained and equipped scout. The more military positions, bases, supply dumps, barrier towers, shield towers, and more that are taken down, the faster the military will be destroyed, and thus, the faster the military can properly begin exterminating the civilian populace of the Slaughra.
[] Something Else - (Write-In)

========================================

Spoiler: Imperial Navy Arrival

Imperial Navy Efforts: 55
Daemonships: 23
Swarm Ships: 5
Lost Rosetta Boarding Parties: 84

The great majority of the Chapter slid out of the warp to a scene of carnage in the void. Tumbling through the darkness, in-depth sensor scans reveal the presence of multiple utterly destroyed Slaughra vessels, with numerous fully possessed daemonships of xeno design burning out entirely. Warpflesh is already melting off of metal and circuitry, no longer capable of maintaining their shapes without the guiding daemonic intelligence behind them. Even so, what remains must be destroyed utterly lest it taint anyone or anything else. Something that is already occurring as you arrive, small flotillas of cruisers doing their best to spread out and destroy all they can presumably before the Swarm returns with renewed strength. Already the advanced sensor arrays that your ships possess bounce across the system,

"Chapter Master, we are being hailed by the lead vessel," Hadrian speaks from the command throne, his eyes glazed over from the myriad streams of information that he's processing.

"Open communications, Hadrian."

Flickering into shape by holo-image, you are greeted by the sight of a remarkably scarred and muscular man with numerous medals pinned to his chest from the waist up. To his side is the bloody dervish that is the Canoness Superior of the whole of the Order of the Lost Rosetta, Margaret Tenenbaum. The former smiles at the sight of you, though it is a small one, and makes a short bow. Margaret does neither of these, and instead simply narrows her eyes as she glares imperiously. Hatred burns in that one as easily as blood pulses through her veins. Flecks of blood are on her face already, and if you are not mistaken you can hear the crackle of her fist's power fields. Her once shoulder length hair is gone, cut short, likely to even it out after she was set aflame during her battles in Zemel. Yet it is not her, but the Admiral who speaks first, one hand folding behind his back while the other rests easily on the hilt of his saber.

"Chapter Master Angelos, I am Admiral Graves of Battlefleet Korianis. I bid you welcome to the fight."

"Admiral," you nod to him, "Canoness."

Margaret doesn't quite sneer at you, and instead appears to struggle and barely manage a slight upwards jerk of her chin.

"As you can see, we have scattered the initial fleet sent against us, and well enough that they've been forced into a defensive posture over their worlds," Graves' image shrinks slightly as a map of the system blinks into being, numerous targeting symbols upon it and the worlds present. "Though as of yet, we've been unable to make any approach upon their daemonworld just yet. The defenses there are simply too strong for us to make an approach. Instead, I would recommend that we-,"

"Skulk about," Margaret interrupts, growling and rolling her eyes simultaneously. "Poking at the other four worlds and simply hoping that they will exercise enough strength upon defending those places so that the Blood Ravens might swoop in and send their scouts forth, sabotage the defenses, and unleash Exterminatus upon that tainted world, breaking their leadership instantly."

Graves blinks at her almost owlishly.

"Something approaching that, yes. Though I also would point out that that is not necessarily what we have to accomplish here, merely harry the enemy present, weakening their forces, until it is possible for the rest of Sector Command and Battlefleet Korianis to come here and complete the extermination," he raises an eyebrow at her flickering image, "We are not required to completely destroy the enemy here - and I'll remind you that we are here to claim the remaining four worlds present. Even if they will require much purifying, four new worlds for the Imperium's use cannot be denied."

Margaret glares at him, the sound of her grinding teeth audible through the comm.

"If you have not noticed yet, Admiral, they have none of their 'vaunted' scouts for your plan to work," she sweeps a hand out at you, one finger from a powerfist pointing, "There is no evidence of their 10th Company in the fleet they have brought. As such, it is my course which shall be what we must fall to. All four of the Swarmworlds must fall before we are able to move onto their capital world. If we do not, then they will surely utilize the damned sorceries of Chaos against us, doing who knows what, potentially even summoning new forces forth from the warp itself!"

"All the while, milady," Graves rebuffs her, "They will be allowed to build up their forces on their daemonworld all the same. I will not sacrifice the fleet I have been given to utterly spread out across this entire system. And lest I remind you again, you do not command my ships here, and it is by Cardinal Huberto's request only that I ferried so many of your sisters forth."

"Then don't," Margaret raises her arms in mock surrender, "Send them only to the worlds where we are going, and let the Blood Ravens pick their own targets. They have a fleet, do they not?"

Grave's frowns at her, rubbing at his chin.

"There is no possible way for us to exterminate them all."

"We do not need to, at the moment, though be assured that we shall partake in such glorious xenocide when the time comes," Margaret's voice is breathily reverent at the thought, "We need only break them. Shatter their shipyards, break their fleets, and crush their strongest military bases along the ground. Enough that they cannot resist us when we move upon the daemonworld."

Graves huffs and turns to you.

"What are your thoughts, Chapter Master?"

World Information said:

Swarmworld Kappa: The world clearly dedicated to Khorne. Their cities are massive alien arenas, where bloodsport is constant, the aliens engraving the symbols of Chaos into their own carapaces as they fight longer and harder. The most successful are powerful champions of Chaos, it is clear, and they favor the close combat of their chosen God's favor. While there are plenty of factories present here as targets to be struck, where Slaughra arms and abominations are churned out, they are far fewer than on any other world. The primary 'tithe', if one could consider it such, is purely warrior stock meant for the Slaughra Swarm's armies. Their defenses are horrific biological monstrosities, formed into the shapes of turrets and roving patrol beasts, vomiting warp energies forth in a horrifying mirror to the same bio-mechanical technologies of their cousin sect of the Swarm against whom they have fought for quite some time. There is no central leader here, no main powerbase, nothing but pure numbers against which the Slaughra have industrialized training and raising armies, great rituals of bloodletting allowing for rapid breeding as time goes on. Each arena-city appears to possess strange bone and skull towers from which great warp energies crackle, perhaps as a shield or weapon though it is uncertain at this time.

Swarmworld Theta: Little information is possible to be gained of the world dedicated to Tzeentch. Vast crystalline spires arc up into the atmosphere and just beyond, from which a great blanket storm covers the entire surface from view and sensors - clearly sorcerous in nature. Bringing down those spires will take an unknown amount of force and violence, and yet it must be done to reveal the rest of the planet for further conquest. At the least, the most advanced scanning possible has revealed that the planet is not truly a daemonworld just yet, but it will surely become one given enough time and lack of destruction of the Chaotic temples and spires which dot its surface. There is no discernible purpose to this world, unlike with Kappa, Nu, and Sigma. As befitting a world clearly dedicated to the Dark God of such things. Still, an unknown world is one that must be dealt with, and quickly.

Swarmworld Nu: Here is where a great many of the Swarm ships are, and more are being...grown out of a mutated mass of flesh which hangs above the world in torturous existence. Scans show it might once have been a void whale, only now it has been transformed into a mixture of a shipyard and defense platform. Pustules in the shape of turrets that the Librarius has records of in similarly Nurglite-tainted vessels are sprawled across its frame. Smaller ships from escort to cruiser tonnage are clearly being grown out of its body, some form of reverse-parasitism allowing flesh and metal to grow out and into the shape of Slaughra ships. The actual exact shapes may vary wildly, little sign of uniformity amongst the ships other than their origin, but they are ships regardless. Battle data from the battle just fought shows how powerful these ships can be, matching Imperial ships despite their lower technological level with Chaos-tainted 'blessings' and mutations. The entire world is almost a Forge World in purpose, rotten flesh endlessly blooming over in their factories to be harvested and shaped into weaponry and vehicles.

Swarmworld Sigma: Most of Sigma is actually untouched by Chaos, comparatively to everything else. A single massive city, a Swarm hive looped endlessly on itself again and again mindlessly, sits in the center of one of this planet's three continents. It is clearly a producer of troops and arms, though with the disturbing particular flavor of Slaanesh. Sonic-based weaponry fills their walls and spires within the hive. Warp energies curl between the spires with audible vox transmissions reaching across the entire system of screams from both Slaughra and human throats. They are completely and utterly concentrated in this bastion they have crafted unlike Kappa, Nu, and perhaps Theta. Thus, to fully dislodge them would require taking and burning down that entire place. If the fleet above that world could be removed, and its own anti-orbital defenses broken apart, then you could unleash great and terrible fury from the skies. Not total Exterminatus, but enough to break that entire hive down entirely, you know your ships possess enough capacity for that.

Daemonworld - Name Incomprehensible To Human Ears: Aspects of all of its four attendant worlds are present here, from crystalline spires, smaller arena-cities, bio-farm factories, and twisting architectures which no longer conform to physical laws in the name of the aesthetics of the alien mind and madmen alike. Temples exist on all of the worlds, but here they are largest, with palpable amounts of power radiating from them that Justinius can feel like a looming itch at the back of his mind. It is a daemonworld, and thus almost sure death for any who walk across its surface no matter who they are. Almost. For most. Here, daemons spawn in numbers untold, in great roiling masses, in shapes that have been recorded in the Librarius amongst newer daemonforms, shaped by the flesh and belief of the xenos that they have corrupted. Great orbital cannons exist here, arching towards the sky in almost supplicatory shapes. Shields of bio-mechanical origin exist to put great chunks of the world in relative safety from orbital fire, with other zones being created by sorcerous clouds and barriers which burn at the eye to look at. The amount of fire it would take to break them down from the outside would be incredible, and would require continuous fire without reprisal for some time. In this, Graves and Tenenbaum spoke correctly, there is no way to conventionally assault this world. It would and will take extremely careful insertions of assault forces onto its surface to try and bring down the towers, barrier arrays, and shield generators down within

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Confirmed Naval Presences In System said: said:

Imperial Navy Present In System
1 Emperor-class Battleship (Flagship of Admiral Graves)
2 Retribution-class Battleships
1 Apocalypse-class Battleship
3 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Mars-class Battlecruisers
25 Lunar-class Cruisers
33 Escort Squadrons (x21 Firestorm, x6 Sword, x6 Cobra)
50 Imperial Transports, Dedicated To Order Of Lost Rosetta Transportation

Blood Raven Void Assets
1st, 4th, 5th Company Fleets

Swarmworld Kappa
12 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
5 Daemonships (Cruiser-tonnage/Nurglite-leaning)
2 Daemonships (Cruiser-tonnage/Tzeentchian-leaning)
5 Swarmship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages)

Swarmworld Theta
1 Daemonship (Battleship-tonnage/Tzeentchian-leaning)
12 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
7 Swarmship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages)

Swarmworld Nu
1 Nurglite Rotwomb
4 Daemonships (Battlecruiser-tonnage/Nurglite-leaning)
8 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
10 Daemonship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages/Nurglite-leaning)

Swarmworld Sigma
1 Daemonship (Battleship-tonnage/Slaaneshi-leaning)
2 Swarmships (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
14 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
7 Daemonship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages/Slaaneshi-leaning)

Daemonworld/Capital
1 Daemonship (Batteship-tonnage/Undivided-leaning)
2 Swarmships (Battlecruiser-tonnage)
12 Swarmships (Cruiser-tonnage)
15 Daemonship Squadrons (Escort-tonnages/Undivided-leaning)

Click to expand...

Click to shrink...

Set Heading For Stage One Of Engagement [Recommendation: One Location Only, To Concentrate Chapter Strength. However, Not Required.]:
Note - Out of respect/inability to do otherwise, the Navy and Sororitas will head to the other three worlds after the Blood Ravens have selected their own targets.

[] Kappa: This world is heavily beset by the grip of Khorne, and compared to the other worlds visibly possesses the largest land-based troops out of all of them save perhaps the capital world itself.
[] Theta: None will be better suited to remove the Swarm's grip from this world than the Blood Ravens, where your Librarius can bring its might against the dark sorceries present there. The veil will be pierced, and what lays beneath set to ruin.
[] Nu: Here is where the Swarm is producing new ships, with their horrifying powers. It must be removed, lest further ships be birthed into being for battle during the rest of this fight.
[] Sigma: One extremely powerful bastion. It must be brought low.
[] Capital World: It would be risky and dangerous to the utter extreme, potentially meaning that all of the enemy fleets could surround the Chapter Fleets and obliterate them utterly the moment they become aware of the assault. But, if landings could be successfully made, and the enemy defenses brought low, and the troops sent down retrieved, Exterminatus could be unleashed, surely breaking the Swarm's leadership immediately. Graves refuses to risk his ships in this unless the other ships throughout the system are damaged enough, and the worlds they protect at least somewhat harried. The Blood Ravens would be utterly alone.